<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=content&amp;type=forums_topic_post</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 03:56:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Question: What is &quot;Astral Projection&quot; form the POV of Actualized.org?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24539-question-what-is-astral-projection-form-the-pov-of-actualizedorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273615</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11312" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/" rel="">@CreamCat</a> Shamanism has methods for accessing lower and upper realms. As but one example.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 02:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273615</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question: What is &quot;Astral Projection&quot; form the POV of Actualized.org?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24539-question-what-is-astral-projection-form-the-pov-of-actualizedorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273610</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	It's a non-ordinary realm of reality.
</p>

<p>
	Since reality is a hallucination at all times, the hallucination can have various domains or realms like waking, dreaming, astral realms, DMT hyperspace, mushroom realms, computer simulations, schizophrenic hallucinations, hellscapes, heavenly realms, etc.
</p>

<p>
	There's really no limit to what The Great Mind can hallucinate.
</p>

<p>
	"Ordinary physical reality" is just one realm out of many. It only seems "real" because you haven't experienced any other realms yet, so you have nothing to contrast it with.
</p>

<p>
	Well... you experience the dream realm every night, but your mind dismisses that as "just dreams".
</p>

<p>
	See, it's hard to experience the non-ordinary realms if you don't take them seriously. That's where openmindedness comes in handy.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 01:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273610</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, how have you done it?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24538-leo-how-have-you-done-it/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273608</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="273603" data-ipsquote-contentid="24538" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534986472" data-ipsquote-userid="12614" data-ipsquote-username="The Mystical Man">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		31 minutes ago, The Mystical Man said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I have never seen myself as a businessman. I've never liked selling. I just wanted to create but I didn't care too much about the marketing side of it.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yeah... I thought that way too. I still basically feel that way. But life also forced me to learn what is necessary for survival.
</p>

<p>
	Business is a survival activity. It's the modern-day equivalent of hunting in the forest for squirrels. Squirrels are smart and you have to learn how to outsmart them or you will go hungry.
</p>

<p>
	Just don't go using your skills towards devilish ends. Do it in service of your art, in service of raising consciousness.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 01:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273608</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From green to yellow</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24499-from-green-to-yellow/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273606</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="273323" data-ipsquote-contentid="24499" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534935871" data-ipsquote-userid="5317" data-ipsquote-username="How to be wise">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		14 hours ago, How to be wise said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> In the book ‘spiral dynamics’, it says that blue and green are the most rigid of the stages. Should we expect the Scandinavian countries and maybe Canada to make it up to yellow anytime soon? How long would you give it?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	If anyone evolves to Yellow, it should be them.
</p>

<p>
	I have no idea how long. Probably not in our lifetime.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="273360" data-ipsquote-contentid="24499" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534942494" data-ipsquote-userid="5244" data-ipsquote-username="Outer">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 hours ago, Outer said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Sorry man, this entire <span>"</span>grouping people into colors" thing is unbelievably shallow. I've never seen an enlightened being do so. Do you know of any?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You categorize and group reality all the time. That's pretty much what all knowledge, language, and science is. You just take it for granted.
</p>

<p>
	You group people in male vs female, black vs white, conservative vs liberal, moderate vs radical, conscious vs unconscious, sane vs insane, friend vs foe, etc.
</p>

<p>
	What you're really objecting to is a new set of categories which you are not comfortable with yet.
</p>

<p>
	For some reason you have no problem when a scientist groups subatomic particles into quarks, leptons, antimatter, etc.
</p>

<p>
	Ken Wilber is enlightened and he talks about Spiral Dynamics and other groupings all the time in a very healthy and reasonable way.
</p>

<p>
	Without grouping, there is no science or math.
</p>

<p>
	Spiral Dynamics is a complex and nuanced set of categories which requires many hours of study to understand.
</p>

<p>
	It would help if you distinguished between healthy and unhealthy application of categories. And also if you remained mindful that all categories are human projections.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 01:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273606</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24198-jordan-peterson/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273594</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7756-brivido/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7756" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7756-brivido/" rel="">@Brivido</a> Once you become conscious enough, you can pick up a book, read a few pages of it, and you will immediately know the quality of the mind who wrote it and how conscious it is.
</p>

<p>
	I read a few pages of Maps Of Meaning but couldn't bother reading any more. It would be a waste of my time. Hundreds of pages of academic talk which sound deep but are actually pretty shallow.
</p>

<p>
	I have hundreds of books on my bookshelf which I have to be very selective about. These days, most of the books I buy I cannot read because they are just written by people who are too low consciousness for me. I read a chapter or two and basically throw it away.
</p>

<p>
	Once in a while I stumble upon a really brilliant book written by a genius. But this is getting rarer and rarer. I sometimes wonder why I even read at all, since at this point I can basically derive all the deepest truths of life simply through contemplation using my journal.
</p>

<p>
	But I still read, holding out hope for some rare brilliant gem.
</p>

<p>
	It's possible to know and not read, and to read and not really know. Most of modern academia is just book smarts without any deep wisdom.
</p>

<p>
	Just consider, the time you invest watching JP videos about Biblical myths might be better spent contemplating your direct experience. Or not. Discover what works for you at your level.
</p>

<p>
	If JP works for you, have at it. Personally, I have bigger fish to fry.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273594</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, how have you done it?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24538-leo-how-have-you-done-it/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273589</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I understand where you're at. I was in a similar place about 10 years ago when I started doing business.
</p>

<p>
	It's not really important what my business was. Business is basically all the same: you look for new opportunities in the marketplace which are emerging, and you seize on them. It's not a good idea to copy others in business, since your success in biz depends very much on you innovating and finding new opportunities. You cannot do the things I did 10 years ago today. You need to find new opportunities. There are always tons of new biz opportunities emerging every year. But people get so preoccupied doing what everyone else is doing that they miss it. They overlook that simple point that business success is about leadership, not following the herd. Those who follow the herd in business ultimately fail.
</p>

<p>
	The whole key to business is to do lots of research and be creative and original. You must connect new dots.
</p>

<p>
	You can take various seminars, workshops, and video courses to learn the fundamentals of biz, sales, and marketing. That is very important. But then you must have the courage to go find your own unique niche. Business-in-a-box solutions do not work. If they did, every fool would be a millionaire. The whole point is that you cannot do that. You must bring something truly new to the table, which takes cleverness, which is rare.
</p>

<p>
	Be very careful doing business purely for money. Find a way to align yourself with your life purpose as soon as humanly possible.
</p>

<p>
	You'd be surprised! People actually can pay you to sit in darkness. Ever heard of Dark Room retreats? Someone's making money off that. You can literally earn money locking people in a dark room as long as you know how to convince them its good for them <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	The best advice I can give to entrepreneurs is: learn the theory of biz & marketing and then do tons of research. If you do enough research, you will eventually stumble upon your niche.
</p>

<p>
	P.S. The highest income I ever earned came AFTER I fully aligned myself with my life purpose, not when I was chasing money.
</p>

<p>
	P.P.S. I have a video about Small Business advice: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/the-psychology-of-small-business-success" rel="external">https://www.actualized.org/articles/the-psychology-of-small-business-success</a>
</p>

<p>
	Starting a business will be the one of the hardest things you'll do in your life. But the rewards more than compensate for it. Business is not for everyone. To succeed in business you must be a bit of a wolf and you must have ambition.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273589</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Heard of Ormus? Consciousness Tool Or Total Scam?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24525-heard-of-ormus-consciousness-tool-or-total-scam/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273584</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	With stuff like this, you will never know until you try it.
</p>

<p>
	That's what experimentation and research is. It always involves risks, but also potential for great payoffs.
</p>

<p>
	I do use colloidal silver and colloidal gold. Not sure about the above product though.
</p>

<p>
	In this case it would be very easy to validate or falsify this product. Buy it and try it for a month and see if you notice any changes. If your mindfulness skill is high you should notice some changes. If not, then it doesn't work and you can move on to testing other stuff.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 23:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273584</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>If everything is The Truth, then falsehood doesn't exist</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24524-if-everything-is-the-truth-then-falsehood-doesnt-exist/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273549</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	You have to distinguish between verbal/conceptual truth and Truth as Being.
</p>

<p>
	There is no opposite to Truth as Being.
</p>

<p>
	Falsehood is a concept, which results from the imagination imagining something which is not currently present in direct experience, without being aware that that imaginary thing is actually an existing object (an idea) within direct experience, and is therefore technically a part of Truth.
</p>

<p>
	The only reason you can say that a unicorn isn't true is because it is True, but your mind is confusing what a unicorn is.
</p>

<p>
	A classic example of confusing the map for the territory.
</p>

<p>
	In Truth, there are no maps. There is only pure territory.
</p>

<p>
	The pure territory is the Truth.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 22:14:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273549</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From green to yellow</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24499-from-green-to-yellow/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273318</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="273285" data-ipsquote-contentid="24499" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534929670" data-ipsquote-userid="2835" data-ipsquote-username="Anton Rogachevski">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Anton Rogachevski said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Thank you for your replies!
		</p>

		<p>
			So one could easily say that hippies that dress like homeless people are not green but more like blue. Reminds me of christian monks who dress with a bag and a rope.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No, hippies are not Blue at all. They are Green.
</p>

<p>
	Blue dresses formally, properly, in uniforms and clean cut suits and dresses. Blue is all about maintaining up-tight order.
</p>

<p>
	Green is much more laided back and easy-going, wearing flip-flops and loose clothing.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 10:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273318</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From green to yellow</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24499-from-green-to-yellow/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273317</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5317-how-to-be-wise/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5317" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5317-how-to-be-wise/" rel="">@How to be wise</a> Very roughly, happiness should increase as one goes higher up the Spiral, but this won't be the case for every individual. It's a rough average and depends a lot on circumstances. A stage Yellow person could be diagnosed with cancer while a stage Green person might find a great job, etc.
</p>

<p>
	Scandinavian countries rank some of the highest on the world happiness index.
</p>

<p>
	There are no stage Yellow societies or governments so we don't have a ranking for countries above Green. The prediction is they will rank higher than Green when they do emerge.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 10:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273317</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24198-jordan-peterson/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273314</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11668-brittany/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11668" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11668-brittany/" rel="">@Brittany</a> It's obvious to me that Peterson does not have a direct consciousness of God/Absolute.
</p>

<p>
	He speaks of God way too theoretically and indirectly. As if he read about it in a book.
</p>

<p>
	He is not a mystic, he is an academic with some Christian leanings.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 10:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273314</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ideology Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24381-ideology-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273256</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	This one's a real doozy:
</p>

<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
	<div>
		<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dsZqeB_Iznk?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
	</div>
</div>

<p>
	 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 07:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273256</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Building Backlinks - Question</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24485-building-backlinks-question/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273242</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/826-emerald/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="826" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/826-emerald/" rel="">@Emerald</a> Getting quality backlinks is hard. That's the whole point. It's a full-time job and it's quite tedious to do.
</p>

<p>
	I would focus more on content and other forms of marketing. For example, getting on popular podcasts is good for getting your name out there. Or writing guest blog posts. Or giving public speeches.
</p>

<p>
	There is no easy solution to marketing. Marketing is hard, time-consuming, and expensive because it is so valuable.
</p>

<p>
	It's also very hard to market something which isn't Purple Cow. Make sure you're bringing something new to the table.
</p>

<p>
	Success in business requires extreme creativity. You cannot just copy what other people did. You must innovate. You are being paid to innovate, and if you cannot do that, then your business will not succeed.
</p>

<p>
	Your job, as CEO, is to come up with new original strategies. That's why they pay you the big bucks (or at least they will if you succeed). This is why only highly ambitious and extraordinary people can start businesses. Most people only know how to paint by numbers and follow others. Entrepreneurship is about leadership. You gotta find cutting-edge emerging opportunities in the marketplace and creatively exploit them.
</p>

<p>
	No one can tell you what these new original strategies are. Because if they knew, they'd have your job. You gotta do lots of research and connect dots.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 06:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273242</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>It makes no sense to earn money/make a living</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24129-it-makes-no-sense-to-earn-moneymake-a-living/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273241</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="268688" data-ipsquote-contentid="24129" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534066678" data-ipsquote-userid="12246" data-ipsquote-username="non_nothing">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 8/12/2018 at 2:37 AM, non_nothing said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> I remember you quit game design which was your dream, so once you've believed that was your purpose, was it? So what or when was the point so clear that made you have it distinct on your path?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It was my passion and purpose for many many years.
</p>

<p>
	Then when I actually started doing it, I saw that it didn't quite suit me. I had a thirst for something deeper. Game development is fun and very interesting (and I'm still passionate about it to some extent), but I needed something deeper. Which turned into my quest for metaphysical understanding, self-actualization, and enlightenment.
</p>

<p>
	Life purpose evolves. It never starts out clear and perfect. You start with your best guess, you pursue it, and then you adjust on the fly. Sometimes large adjustments are needed, like quitting your entire career. Which is what I did. Twice!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 06:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273241</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From green to yellow</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24499-from-green-to-yellow/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273230</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11312" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/" rel="">@CreamCat</a> That's right, Orange will only care about price, not about gallons burned. Because he has not yet developed eco-consciousness so the health of the environment is beyond his circle of concern.
</p>

<p>
	Green's care for the environment goes beyond just saving money. Green actually cares about the environment for its own sake. Green has developed heart, which Orange cannot understand because Orange is too self-centered.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 04:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273230</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What is the difference between &quot;thinking&quot; and &quot;becoming aware.&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24508-what-is-the-difference-between-thinking-and-becoming-aware/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273229</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	No point in asking us, contemplate it in your journal.
</p>

<p>
	You cannot become aware by talking about it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 04:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273229</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Building Backlinks - Question</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24485-building-backlinks-question/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273216</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Building artificial backlinks is not a good idea these days. Google is smart about catching you and penalizing you for it.
</p>

<p>
	You can actually get your website blacklisted forever if you build too many artificial backlinks.
</p>

<p>
	That era to do that kind of stuff was 10 years ago. Google has gotten a lot smarter.
</p>

<p>
	No-follow links don't count at all, and making links on blog comment sections is a no-no these days. Google knows what you're doing. Quality links must come from the body of the page, not the comment section.
</p>

<p>
	These days I would assume that almost all social media links are no-follow. Which means they don't count.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 03:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273216</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From green to yellow</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24499-from-green-to-yellow/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273215</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="273178" data-ipsquote-contentid="24499" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534898354" data-ipsquote-userid="12145" data-ipsquote-username="Feel Good">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Feel Good said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/2835-anton-rogachevski/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="2835" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/2835-anton-rogachevski/" rel="">@Anton Rogachevski</a>
		</p>

		<p>
			I tend to think of green as a mental illness and yellow as opening ones eyes again to understand that there was no need for green to try to change what is. Green is like that dark night of the soul <img alt=":)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/smile.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/smile@2x.png 2x" title=":)" width="20" />green are quite dysfunctional in lots of ways. Im green and im starting to see how i demonise all stages and how its a self defeating stage to be at despite my shallow pluralistic values. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You are misunderstanding Green.
</p>

<p>
	Don't give Green a bad name.
</p>

<p>
	Green can be very healthy. In fact, mostly it is. Only in rare exceptions does it get toxic. These days people in the political sphere love to demonize Green and over-exaggerate Green's excesses. If you use the news or YT political commentary to judge Green, you will get a very distorted picture of Green.
</p>

<p>
	80%+ of Green people are moderate and easy-going.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 03:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273215</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From green to yellow</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24499-from-green-to-yellow/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273214</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="273065" data-ipsquote-contentid="24499" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534885291" data-ipsquote-userid="2835" data-ipsquote-username="Anton Rogachevski">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		6 hours ago, Anton Rogachevski said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Could he be back to buying nice things for himself once he reaches yellow?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Green never really stops buying nice things. If anything, Green buys fewer but nicer things. Green people love expensive Apple products and expensive yoga pants, for example.
</p>

<p>
	Green just realizes that happiness is found more in relationships than in material objects.
</p>

<p>
	Don't over-simplify Green as being against material objects. Healthy Green is not against those things. In fact, Green should realize that life cannot work without material objects. It's just that Green understands that material objects are not what life is about.
</p>

<p>
	Green is also conscious of how buying up useless material objects affects the environment in unhealthy ways. So Green will be mindful of what they consume whereas Orange doesn't give a shit as long as it suits them.
</p>

<p>
	For example, Orange will drive a Hummer and doesn't care about how much gas he burns. Green will prefer to drive a Tesla. Tesla is a nice, expensive material object. But it is also eco-friendly.
</p>

<p>
	Green buys nice material objects, but for different reasons than Orange.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 03:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273214</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24198-jordan-peterson/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273206</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="273204" data-ipsquote-contentid="24198" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534903583" data-ipsquote-userid="1012" data-ipsquote-username="WaveInTheOcean">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 minutes ago, WaveInTheOcean said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Reality is meaningless indeed. But it's also full of meaning, just look around.
		</p>

		<p>
			What I'm saying is that reality is <"insert anything"-less> , i.e it's nothing, but it's also everything. 
		</p>

		<p>
			Yes objectively speaking there is no deeper meaning.<br />
			But, there exists no objective viewpoint.<br />
			Subjectively speaking there exists meaning everywhere.<br />
			<br />
			So to say it more directly, reality has infinite potential for an infinite multitude of meanings exactly cos it is completely meaningless.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's one thing to say that, it's a totally nother thing to actually realize that in your life.
</p>

<p>
	The real test is when the shit hits of fan. When someone tells you your child was run over by the bus. How conscious will you be of the fact that you create meaning?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 02:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273206</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24198-jordan-peterson/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273201</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272960" data-ipsquote-contentid="24198" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534874945" data-ipsquote-userid="6183" data-ipsquote-username="hundreth">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, hundreth said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Could you speak in more detail about this? I've seen you promote this idea of diving deep into the nihilism in several posts and I'm never quite sure why. Perhaps do a video about nihilism. 
		</p>

		<p>
			Aside from some of these Neo-Advaita teachers who encourage spiritual bypassing, you don't really see nihilism propped up in traditional spiritual practice. For example, the Buddhist middle way is precisely finding a balance between eternalism and nihilism. So what gives?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Well, it's very simple. All that nihilism really boils down to is that being is meaningless. Which is what nonduality reveals.
</p>

<p>
	That's all.
</p>

<p>
	But the ego-mind don't want to accept that. To the ego-mind it seems negative or depressing or chaotic.
</p>

<p>
	You gotta be very careful though. Meaninglessness does not mean what you think it means!
</p>

<p>
	You don't need to dive deep into nihilism per se. You just need to become conscious that ego-mind constructs all meaning for the purpose of its survival. Once you become deeply conscious of this, life will cease to have meaning for you (at least for a while) and it will feel like a deep depressing nihilism as you realize that all your life motivations were predicated upon lies and illusions of the deepest sort. But keep pushing past that, surrender all your illusions, and you will eventually get to pure being, liberation, divinity.
</p>

<p>
	This is what they call the dark night of the soul. It's really more accurate to call it: the final death-throes of the ego.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 01:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273201</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24198-jordan-peterson/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273171</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272789" data-ipsquote-contentid="24198" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534850789" data-ipsquote-userid="10087" data-ipsquote-username="MarkusSweden">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 hours ago, MarkusSweden said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			What's up with young guys today? They seem to see a hero in JP. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	JP is serving a valuable function for young college-aged males.
</p>

<p>
	He is giving them a sense of stage Blue discipline and direction which their culture never gave them.
</p>

<p>
	Basically, at his best, what JP is proposes is having a sense of Life Purpose. Which is basically what my LP course is all about.
</p>

<p>
	The only thing I would stress about that is that it's very important to realize that Life Purpose is a conceptual construction. It is not objectively true in any way. It's something one creates for oneself to live a good life and have a sense of focus. And to develop mastery in some field.
</p>

<p>
	And that there is a higher level beyond life purpose, which is awakening.
</p>

<p>
	One of the excesses of stage Green relativism is that it can leave people feeling lost, directionless, nihilistic, unwilling to engage in building a passionate life. JP seized on this Green excess and is building a public identity around it.
</p>

<p>
	But reacting against excess tends to produce more excess of another kind.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273171</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lesser Jihads vs Being a Carpet</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24482-lesser-jihads-vs-being-a-carpet/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273163</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11818-etherial-cat/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11818" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11818-etherial-cat/" rel="">@Etherial Cat</a> Describe what exactly your situation is. Be concise and factual, without finger-pointing or opinionating.
</p>

<p>
	What is this porn poster and why can't you ignore it?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273163</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How can i achieve success if i don't even know what success is?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24501-how-can-i-achieve-success-if-i-dont-even-know-what-success-is/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273153</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8790-recursoinominado/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8790" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8790-recursoinominado/" rel="">@Recursoinominado</a> Visualize for 10 minutes every day for the next 30 days yourself being hardworking and successful.
</p>

<p>
	Visualize it hardcore, like your life depends on it. Put full confidence and feeling into each of those 10 minutes. Forcing all negative thoughts and doubt out of your time for those 10 minutes.
</p>

<p>
	That will fix it.
</p>

<p>
	But only if you actually do it every day.
</p>

<p>
	Don't make the excuse: "But I can't visualize it because I've never seen it." That's nonsense. You have an imagination which can visualize all sorts of things you haven't seen, like a flying rainbow mammoth. Your imagination is how you bootstrap success.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 23:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273153</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Meaningless Reality and Solipsism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24484-meaningless-reality-and-solipsism/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273149</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	It just requires surrender, and dropping all sorts of old ego expectations and desires.
</p>

<p>
	The ego-mind is transitioning from living for survival to living from Being. This is a radical shift and the ego-mind has a hard time coping with it.
</p>

<p>
	The freedom that comes from meaninglessness is very radical, but also beautiful. It is an acquired taste after decades of living in a conceptual fantasy land under all the artificial meanings that society programmed you with.
</p>

<p>
	Just give it time. The depression will pass and give way to emptiness, joy, freedom, and being-love.
</p>

<p>
	To truly awaken you are going to have to change your entire attitude towards life. Basically, life as you knew it will end, and a new life will begin. You have to have courage to surrender your old life. If you cling to it, that will produce suffering and depression.
</p>

<p>
	With awakening, you must go ALL-IN. Half-measures will produce lots of suffering.
</p>

<p>
	To try to awaken but keep your old life intact will produce lots of suffering.
</p>

<p>
	Just remember this: depression is ALWAYS temporary. It's something the mind is ACTIVELY doing, and the mind can't keep it up forever. Use this little bit of truth to weather the storm. Keep reminding yourself that this is just temporary. The ego is just acting up like a child.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 23:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273149</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tired of seeking Will KILL myself</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24495-tired-of-seeking-will-kill-myself/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273148</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/6-serious-emotional-problems/">Serious Emotional Problems</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Do not make a travesty out of this process. Do not give spirituality a bad name which such egotistical stunts.
</p>

<p>
	Seriously give Kriya yoga a try. Do it every day for 1 years straight. Then see how you feel.
</p>

<p>
	The reason you're not getting results is because you don't have a serious regular daily spiritual practice, so you are getting lost in the mind.
</p>

<p>
	The lesson is simple: discipline yourself to develop a serious daily practice.
</p>

<p>
	That's all. No need for hysterics.
</p>

<p>
	Either do that, or forget this whole awakening business and just go back to living an ordinary life.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 23:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273148</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>about absolute infinity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24489-about-absolute-infinity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273146</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272948" data-ipsquote-contentid="24489" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534871917" data-ipsquote-userid="10612" data-ipsquote-username="Hamilcar">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		5 hours ago, Hamilcar said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Why doesn't it have infinite amounts of itself?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It does.
</p>

<p>
	One vs two is a distinction, a duality. Nonduality is both one and two. All distinctions are embraced at once, creating one unified field containing an infinite number of distinctions.
</p>

<p>
	Oneness and many-ness are in fact identical.
</p>

<p>
	Notice that a carton of eggs is both one and many at the same time. There is no contradiction because number is a relative projection of your mind. You're the one deciding whether you see the carton as 1 carton or a dozen eggs.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 23:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273146</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lesser Jihads vs Being a Carpet</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24482-lesser-jihads-vs-being-a-carpet/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273140</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	The Lesser Jihad isn't to be demonized, it's just a distraction, a red herring. In the same way that having a giant porn poster hanging on the wall in your office would be a distraction from getting any work done. It would be foolish to hang such a poster up in the office. This doesn't mean porn or sex is bad, it just means you have to be careful with not letting it distract you from the bigger picture.
</p>

<p>
	What you are complaining about is survival. If you feel other people are threatening you, or dehumanizing you, that's a survival issue. For example, someone might complain, "But Leo, I can't do enlightened work because I live in war zone. What am I supposed to do? Meditate while people are shooting bombs around my house?"
</p>

<p>
	The answer is: you must engineer your environment to minimize threats to your survival so that you can focus on what's really important: truth-realization. Yes, it's very hard to focus on truth-realization when you can't feed yourself, can't pay your bills, get into fights with people, have family breathing down your neck, have toxic friends who want you to do drugs and watch TV, etc.
</p>

<p>
	You must strategically extricate yourself from all of that so that you can focus on the real work. It might take you several years just to fix that part of your life so that you are in a stable place where you can focus on the real work.
</p>

<p>
	For someone living in a war-torn hell-hole, there is no self-actualization, and awakening. For them, just getting safe shelter and food is #1 priority. You cannot meditate if your life is being actively threatened.
</p>

<p>
	Then again, most threats to your survival in 1st world countries are purely conceptual and self-created. You could be a billionaire living in Hollywood and still feel like your survival is threatened every day, and so you distract yourself from ever doing truth-seeking. Survival is the whole game of life, and it feels very real at all times, and it's very addictive. Your mind's whole job is to only focus on survival at all times. Truth-seeking is all about overriding this primordial drive. Which is why it's so counter-intuitive, challenging, and rarely done.
</p>

<p>
	This is really a question about Maslow's Hierarchy of Needs. Those who are very low on the pyramid will find self-actualization and self-transcendence extremely difficult.
</p>

<p>
	Do other people's ideologies REALLY dehumanize you? Why do you care what other people think at all? Why not focus instead on what you have control over, like meditation, self-inquiry, yoga, psychedelics, etc? Unless Nazi's are physically threatening your life, then you are probably blowing this ideology thing way out of proportion.
</p>

<p>
	Conflicts over what other people think of you are some of the biggest time-wasters. They are almost totally unnecessary and self-created, unless your physical life is seriously in danger (in which case, fix that situation ASAP and get back to inner work).
</p>

<p>
	Fighting ideology with counter-ideology is the Lesser Jihad. It is a trap, a distraction.
</p>

<p>
	You don't need to be a carpet. By engaging the Greater Jihad you put yourself in the strongest possible position. In doing that, you gain all the power. Those who get far enough along on the Greater Jihad become invincible to outside forces.
</p>

<p>
	Going out into the woods and mediating for 30 days straight is the very opposite of being a carpet. And almost anyone can find a way to do it. The problem is, no one wants to because they have a bunch of excuses. And it's not fun. It will the be the most challenging thing you've ever done in your life.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 23:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273140</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trouble with self-inquiry..</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24480-trouble-with-self-inquiry/?do=findComment&amp;comment=273129</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12464-cody_atzori/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12464" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12464-cody_atzori/" rel="">@Cody_Atzori</a> What if the mind is deceiving itself that it is the body, in the same way that a religious fanatic deceives himself?
</p>

<p>
	How do you know what you are supposed to be?
</p>

<p>
	Where is it written that you are supposed to be a body? Why can't you be omnipresent consciousness, and the body is just another object like all other objects?
</p>

<p>
	Does the body really have any special boundary around it? Is it really any different than a coffee table? If the body is really you, how is it possible that you can perceive the coffee table? After all, the coffee table ceases to exist if you close your eyes. So clear the coffee table is a creation of your mind. As is your body.
</p>

<p>
	Why are you trusting those bodily sensations as evidence of your identification with the body? After all, you have sensation of the coffee table (you see it), but you do not identify with it. Who says that bodily feeling is more real or determinative of your identity than colors? Why are feeling superior to colors? Who said so? Why are you blindly trusting your feelings? Who said feelings have any meaning whatsoever?
</p>

<p>
	Who said the feeling of a body = you? How arbitrary is that?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 22:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">273129</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>got a glimpse of non dual experience</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24470-got-a-glimpse-of-non-dual-experience/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272717</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9725-nevon/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9725" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9725-nevon/" rel="">@Nevon</a> Good work.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 08:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272717</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24198-jordan-peterson/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272714</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	You can split hairs over all sorts of nuances of JP's work, but in the end, it's still thoroughly grounded in the classic dualistic Christian paradigm of meaning, morality, order, right vs wrong, good vs evil, etc.
</p>

<p>
	Which is, ironically, the opposite of what Christ realized.
</p>

<p>
	You are not going to realize Christ through studying myth. You will realize it through hardcore spiritual practice and deconstruction of all belief systems, morality, value, and meaning.
</p>

<p>
	The paradox is, you will find Christ at the very bottom end of nihilism.
</p>

<p>
	And the distinction JP draws between the individual self and collectivism is a duality which did not exist for Christ.
</p>

<p>
	The individual self and the collective self are in fact one and the same.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 08:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272714</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24198-jordan-peterson/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272710</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272613" data-ipsquote-contentid="24198" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534822547" data-ipsquote-userid="11668" data-ipsquote-username="Brittany">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 hours ago, Brittany said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Jordan is a Bodhisattva.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	A Bodhisattva is someone who has awakened.
</p>

<p>
	That ain't JP.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 08:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272710</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Words don’t help</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24466-words-don%E2%80%99t-help/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272701</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<ul>
	<li>
		Kirya yoga
	</li>
	<li>
		Psychedelics
	</li>
	<li>
		Solo retreats
	</li>
</ul>

<p>
	That is the killer combo right there.
</p>

<p>
	Getting magically enlightened at the hands of some guru is extremely rare and it's a super disempowering attitude to have. You might as well be hoping to win the lottery.
</p>

<p>
	Take your awakening into your own hands. No one will do it for you.
</p>

<p>
	If you are feeling stuck, go do a Bufo 5-MeO retreat with Octavio. You'll experience infinity in 5 minutes. It's worth the travel.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 07:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272701</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>S. Harris &amp; J. Peterson duo-mental-masturbation (funny)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24447-s-harris-j-peterson-duo-mental-masturbation-funny/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272615</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I expect better of you guys.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 03:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272615</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>golden teacher mushroom</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24453-golden-teacher-mushroom/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272612</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272556" data-ipsquote-contentid="24453" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534812526" data-ipsquote-userid="11429" data-ipsquote-username="Laymen">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Laymen said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Can I use psychedelics everyday?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Do your research.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 03:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272612</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dangers of psychedelics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24424-dangers-of-psychedelics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272611</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272609" data-ipsquote-contentid="24424" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534821766" data-ipsquote-userid="1356" data-ipsquote-username="cirkussmile">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		10 minutes ago, cirkussmile said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Leo, Do Sadhguru have to take psychedelics at least 50 times before you can discuss with him about psychedelics?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	He'd have to do at least a dozen trips, yes.
</p>

<p>
	Otherwise what would we be talking about?
</p>

<p>
	Just because a person is enlightened does not mean he knows psychedelics.
</p>

<p>
	It would be pointless discussing pizza with Sadhguru unless he ate some pizza first.
</p>

<p>
	This is really just common sense. People who talk of things which they have zero experience with end up saying stupid things. I know cause I've done it. I am now much more careful about what I choose to speak about so that I don't over-step my experience too much. It's a constant problem. The mind loves to speak of things which it has not experienced as though it has.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 03:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272611</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dangers of psychedelics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24424-dangers-of-psychedelics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272596</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/343-key-elements/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="343" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/343-key-elements/" rel="">@Key Elements</a> That's right, you must explore and discover the truth for yourself.
</p>

<p>
	All else is hearsay.
</p>

<p>
	Which is why I do BOTH: psychedelics and lots of non-psychedelic methods.
</p>

<p>
	I was only arguing against those who oppose psychedelics on dogmatic grounds. This anti-psychedelic dogma is almost always rooted in lack of experience with psychedelics.
</p>

<p>
	People do not fully appreciate just how badly our culture stigmatizes psychedelics. They take on this stigma and argue from this stigma unwittingly. Psychedelics have not become mainstream yet, so you will often find people criticizing them simply based on that.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 02:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272596</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dangers of psychedelics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24424-dangers-of-psychedelics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272579</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272000" data-ipsquote-contentid="24424" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534739043" data-ipsquote-userid="10892" data-ipsquote-username="SaWaSaurus">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		21 hours ago, SaWaSaurus said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			For example Leo made a video saying all enlightenment were practically the same. It is untrue Zen satori is just a brief awakening experience. It is not equal to the Samadhi sadhguru had. Awakening out of the mind is not the same as a flow state. A flow state is not the same as unity consciousness. That isn't the same as ego death a temporary loss of the i. That isn't the same as a NDE which apparently is permanent. Leo has some decent stuff but pretends to know more than he does.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I repeatedly stated that there are many facets and levels of depth to nonduality, and also all kinds of mystical and non-ordinary states of consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	But this is actually a case for using more psychedelics, not less. It's precisely because there are so many facets and various kinds of states and levels of depth that without psychedelics you will almost never explore even a small percentage of them.
</p>

<p>
	There is also a confusion happening here between stages of development vs states of consciousness. They not the same thing.
</p>

<p>
	Also, NDEs are not permanent. By definition, an NDE is a near death EXPERIENCE. And I've never conflated NDEs with awakening. They are very different things.
</p>

<p>
	I have repeatedly told you guys that this entire field is much more nuanced and complex than most people assume.
</p>

<p>
	And therefore, psychedelics are a great tool to explore this vast landscape and see what's up.
</p>

<p>
	The only problem is that people don't want to do it. They want one simple solution rather than doing 100s of trips and dealing with all the questions they will raise in your mind.
</p>

<p>
	No one is suggesting that you trip once and close your mind down. Just the opposite. You trip more and more, with each trip your mind opens more and more.
</p>

<p>
	It's sort of like you're being told, "Hey, go travel to Africa, there's cool stuff to see there." and you say, "No way, it's too dangerous!" or you say, "I've been to Africa once and seen everything there is to see."
</p>

<p>
	Both attitudes are deeply misguided.
</p>

<p>
	You could trip 100 times and still not see everything there is to see. People who have tripped less than 50 times, I can't even take them seriously. They have a massive lack of experience.
</p>

<p>
	So before you ask people for advice on psychedelics, first ask them, how many times have you tripped, and on how many different substances and at which dosages and under which conditions? That will shut most people up as it would be embarrassing for them to admit their lack of experience.
</p>

<p>
	Before you even think of hanging up the phone, answer it 100 times. You never know who's calling.
</p>

<p>
	Whatever excuses you have for not doing psychedelics, that's just what they are, excuses.
</p>

<p>
	Are there dangers? Of course! Exploration of any kind is dangerous. If you want to be safe, stay in the middle of mindless herd. Exploration is for daring souls. The mindless herd will always whine and complain about why exploration is evil. Don't ask a sheep for advice on how to be a lion.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 01:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272579</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What happens after we die?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24402-what-happens-after-we-die/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272553</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272262" data-ipsquote-contentid="24402" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534779955" data-ipsquote-userid="11707" data-ipsquote-username="SoonHei">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		10 hours ago, SoonHei said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>
		</p>

		<p>
			so when this idea is seen to be an illusion or when the idea die
		</p>

		<p>
			is there a new idea formed once this one falls away?
		</p>

		<p>
			and to that one, who sees the idea of a person for the illusion it is before physical death of the body (dies before dies) 
		</p>

		<p>
			does that "one" form another NEW idea <em><strong>after</strong></em> the death of the physical body she/he once thought they were?
		</p>

		<p>
			cuz while enlightened, that "person" still communicates via the body until that body dies..
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You could form another idea, but that would be just another false identification.
</p>

<p>
	You could believe you are a unicorn, but so what?
</p>

<p>
	After all ideas are extinguished, what remains is Nothing. And Nothing is not an idea.
</p>

<p>
	Try to imagine life, but without you. Like, there is still a body, but no you inside it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272553</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272458</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272455" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534797023" data-ipsquote-userid="11707" data-ipsquote-username="SoonHei">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		5 minutes ago, SoonHei said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			but that would eff me up no?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, it will shock the shit out of you.
</p>

<p>
	That's the point: enlightenment shock treatment <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	You will integrate afterwards.
</p>

<p>
	After just one 5-MeO breakthrough, you will never look at reality the same way again. Even though you will fall back into duality and ego. You will still have a memory of awakening. And that memory will serve as a roadmap for pursing awakening.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 20:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272458</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272453</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272127" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534766910" data-ipsquote-userid="11325" data-ipsquote-username="Enlightenment">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		8 hours ago, Enlightenment said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Are you claiming that 5-MeO is beyond Nirvana/Brahman/Pure Consciousness Experience that is possible to experience via meditation?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No, it is not beyond. It is just that.
</p>

<p>
	But there are many facets to that insight and many degrees of depth to it.
</p>

<p>
	I merely said that enlightenment teachers do not understand that 5-MeO can go there as directly as it does.
</p>

<p>
	If there was a pill you could take which would give you the level of consciousness of a Zen master with 40 years of daily practice, 5-MeO would take you there in 15 minutes and possibly even give you a deeper insight into that than that Zen master has had.
</p>

<p>
	Of course, the difference is, after 60 minutes, you'd be back to normal. Whereas the Zen master is stabilized in his insight.
</p>

<p>
	The purpose of 5-MeO is to give you a very deep glimpse of total nonduality. To show you how little you know and how worthwhile it is to pursue.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 20:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272453</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Enlightenment/psychadelics...a question</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24454-enlightenmentpsychadelicsa-question/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272445</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	You didn't get it. You got a tiny glimpse of the Truth perhaps and it freaked the ego out.
</p>

<p>
	Yeah, Truth is scary to the unprepared mind.
</p>

<p>
	Enlightenment is the most wonderful thing. But you gotta prepare your mind for it with spiritual practices.
</p>

<p>
	Be careful judging enlightenment by one psychedelic trip. That would be a big mistake. Psychedelic trips can be weird and freaky. That's not enlightenment per se.
</p>

<p>
	Do 20 trips, then see where things are at. One trip means almost nothing.
</p>

<p>
	Truth is an acquired taste.
</p>

<p>
	You will appreciate Truth more and more as you complete healing your past trauma. More trips should help you heal.
</p>

<p>
	Just be open to what the trips are showing you. Sometimes they show you harsh truths. This is in fact great! You just gotta be open to it. Be curious about reality rather than trying to defend yourself.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 20:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272445</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>golden teacher mushroom</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24453-golden-teacher-mushroom/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272443</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Probably try to figure out the mushrooms first.
</p>

<p>
	It's important to find your right dose to determine how high your natural tolerance is so then you can properly dose other psychedelics.
</p>

<p>
	2g dried should be a fairly strong trip. 4g dried is a very intense trip. But individuals can have different tolerances. And mushrooms can have different potencies. It's easier to dose LSD.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 20:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272443</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mastering the Core Teachings of the Buddah. Book.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24395-mastering-the-core-teachings-of-the-buddah-book/?do=findComment&amp;comment=272062</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="272027" data-ipsquote-contentid="24395" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534744971" data-ipsquote-userid="12542" data-ipsquote-username="Christer">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Christer said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			He explains that the noting should be on cutting edge, constantly pushing it faster and more precise. He continues to emphasize that to "see" reality you have to be able to ping-pong this insanely fast, like a rainshower. Cause the true Truth flickers, in and out of existence, from sensation, consciousness, noting, mental image. And this happens at a machinegun`s speed, and this is what we are training our minds to acually percieve. Can you please give me some thoughts on this?  And the three "notes" you use?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	There are many ways to skin the same cat.
</p>

<p>
	Going so fast is not necessary. I actually find a lot of value in slowing down the labeling, so you can really feel into every sensation fully.
</p>

<p>
	The labels I use are: see, hear, feel.
</p>

<p>
	Although I don't do this practice much any more. These days I focus on yoga.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 07:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">272062</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271991</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	None of them have ever taken 5-MeO.
</p>

<p>
	And 5-MeO should not even be in the same category as other psychedelics. It is its own thing.
</p>

<p>
	No one who hasn't taken it has any idea such things are possible. Even if they are enlightened, they still don't understand what 5-MeO can do.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 03:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271991</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I am so tired</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24418-i-am-so-tired/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271990</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10773-onecirrus/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10773" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10773-onecirrus/" rel="">@Onecirrus</a> Convert that energy into a concrete spiritual practice, like yoga or meditation or self-inquiry.
</p>

<p>
	It does no good whining aimlessly about one's suffering. You must use it to mobilize yourself into serious practice. As you start taking action your suffering will diminish.
</p>

<p>
	There can be no awakening without hardcore practice.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 03:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271990</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is there a place for self-development where you are going for enlightment?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24380-is-there-a-place-for-self-development-where-you-are-going-for-enlightment/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271989</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Not necessarily. Both can be done at once. Or you can focus one or the other strategically.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 03:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271989</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo put on the brakes and back up a bit</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24414-leo-put-on-the-brakes-and-back-up-a-bit/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271986</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="271914" data-ipsquote-contentid="24414" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534719856" data-ipsquote-userid="7356" data-ipsquote-username="Revolutionary Think">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 hours ago, Revolutionary Think said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I'm just wondering though eventually in the future when all of your work dissipate do you think that the tides will eventually turn and the world will become more self-actualized and go higher up the spiral dynamics or enlightenment stages or is the pendulum swinging the other way towards hatred, ignorance, corruption, and ideology? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The world is constantly evolving. People are more openminded every decade, every century, every millennium.
</p>

<p>
	It is a good time to be alive.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 03:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271986</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question about consciousness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24216-question-about-consciousness/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271984</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	The world is not made out of energy because energy is a concept.
</p>

<p>
	The world is made out of what you see before your eyes right now. This substance has no name. It is empty and ungraspable.
</p>

<p>
	Consciousness, emptiness, being, or distinction would be the best way to describe it. Although none of those words are the territory itself.
</p>

<p>
	It's critical to realize that the substance of reality cannot be defined. That's its very essence: undefinablity.
</p>

<p>
	It's critical to understand why it must be this way. Why it must be Nothing. Otherwise you will key painting it as something, some quality, thereby limiting it. But it is in fact unlimited! So no limited description can ever be it.
</p>

<p>
	In the very act of trying to grasp it, you destroy it. In the very act of trying to see it, you hide it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 03:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271984</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo put on the brakes and back up a bit</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24414-leo-put-on-the-brakes-and-back-up-a-bit/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271899</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7356-revolutionary-think/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7356" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7356-revolutionary-think/" rel="">@Revolutionary Think</a> Obviously, since you're here, you have avoided some nasty ideologies in life. Otherwise you could not be openminded enough to watch my videos. So you did something right. More than most people.
</p>

<p>
	Probably 90%+ of the world cannot watch my videos. Because they are simply too attached to some ideology.
</p>

<p>
	A lot of openminded people find it hard to understand that most of the world is closedminded, and that if not but for a bit of luck, you would have been one of the closedminded ones.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 22:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271899</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How exactly does 5-MEO contradict the Materialist Pradigm?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24119-how-exactly-does-5-meo-contradict-the-materialist-pradigm/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271887</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="271514" data-ipsquote-contentid="24119" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534637908" data-ipsquote-userid="11882" data-ipsquote-username="fluidmonolith">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		22 hours ago, fluidmonolith said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			That's the difficulty in using direct experience to derive truth, right? That experience can't be shared or even really agreed upon by others.
		</p>

		<p>
			In this example, we have two possibilities:
		</p>

		<p>
			1) Taking 5-MEO causes people to exit the dream and see true reality
		</p>

		<p>
			2) Taking 5-MEO causes people to <em>think</em> they have exited the dream and seen true reality.
		</p>

		<p>
			If one hasn't taken 5-MEO, it makes sense that they would expect case (2) above. I have not used psychedelics, so I cannot personally validate or invalidate them at this time. The best I can do at this time is to admit that both (1) and (2) are possible. I suspect if I did try psychedelics, I might draw similar conclusions (that I am have seen reality outside of the dream).
		</p>

		<p>
			But I still have a problem with this conclusion. Even if future me takes 5-MEO and decides that case (1) above is correct ... that doesn't mean it's actually true! All it really means is that I think it's true. Even if I trust my experience completely, that doesn't mean that I'm right. Right? In other words, even if someone takes 5-MEO and then agrees with you, that just indicates agreement, not truth. I'm not saying that case (1) is wrong. I'm just trying to figure out how direct experience alone is sufficient to make it true. What am I missing here?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, from your current POV and level of consciousness. that's how it appears.
</p>

<p>
	But what you're missing is the Absolute.
</p>

<p>
	You are assuming the Absolute will just be another relative phenomenon. Except the Absolute is not that. It's Absolute!
</p>

<p>
	"Direct experience" of the Absolute is not like a regular experience. That word "experience" is misleading here. We use that word because you do not have direct consciousness of the Absolute and so it cannot be communicated to you in any other way than to call it "an experience". But it's not really an experience, or a perception, or a thought, or a belief, or knowledge. It's something entirely new which you've never encountered before. And yet it's right there under your nose right this second.
</p>

<p>
	What you're missing is that you have 100% raw direct unmediated access to Absolute Truth, prior to perception or experience.
</p>

<p>
	Because you believe that you exist, this sense of self which you think is real has co-opted the Absolute and recontextualized it as "my experience". Such that the Absolute is right there, but you cannot see it because the ego has managed to convince itself that "this is MY experience". Once the ego is realized to be an illusion, "experience" will be recontextualized into the Absolute.
</p>

<p>
	There actually never was such a thing as "experience" or "perception" or "a human looking at the world". That was the Absolute the whole time, but you didn't realized it because you were so self-absorbed that you mistook the Absolute for "my life, my experience, my perception."
</p>

<p>
	If you could understand what I am saying here, you'd already be enlightened and there would be no need to have this conversation as it would be perfectly obvious to you already.
</p>

<p>
	Can you notice that you are not a human being, but that you are God? It's right there! Look! You're God!
</p>

<p>
	See it?
</p>

<p>
	The thing looking through your skull, your eyes, is God. Seriously. Stop fucking around and notice it. Realize what you are.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 22:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271887</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo put on the brakes and back up a bit</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24414-leo-put-on-the-brakes-and-back-up-a-bit/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271881</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7356-revolutionary-think/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7356" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7356-revolutionary-think/" rel="">@Revolutionary Think</a> You still accepted a lot of beliefs which you're yet unconscious of.
</p>

<p>
	Rebels are not as rebellious as they like to think. You still have a lot in common with your culture and parenting.
</p>

<p>
	And reacting against a teaching often just creates an ideology of the opposite kind, which is no better.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 22:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271881</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Life Coach Program Reviews/Thoughts</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24284-life-coach-program-reviewsthoughts/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271877</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11125-kev014/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11125" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11125-kev014/" rel="">@kev014</a> It doesn't really matter what I think. Get clear about your life purpose and then follow it every day. It basically just boils down to that. Trust in the over-arching strategy and principles of LP to carry you if you work it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 22:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271877</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What happens after we die?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24402-what-happens-after-we-die/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271843</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/4932-mrdmitriiv/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="4932" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/4932-mrdmitriiv/" rel="">@MrDmitriiV</a> You're assuming there is a you who can die.
</p>

<p>
	There isn't.
</p>

<p>
	You are an idea.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 21:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271843</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mastering the Core Teachings of the Buddah. Book.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24395-mastering-the-core-teachings-of-the-buddah-book/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271835</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	You should distinguish between noting and labeling.
</p>

<ul>
	<li>
		Noting: noticing a sensation with your awareness.
	</li>
	<li>
		Labeling: giving the sensation a name like "see", "hear", "feel".
	</li>
</ul>

<p>
	Noting must always happen in this practice. Labeling is optional but highly recommended.
</p>

<p>
	Keep your labeling simple! Don't go creating 10 different labels. 3 is sufficient.
</p>

<p>
	You do NOT note/label EVERY arising sensation. That is impossible. There are dozens of sensations arising each second. Rather, you select just ONE and note/label it.
</p>

<p>
	It's not a lot. It's 1 note/label every 2 to 10 seconds. You can linger your awareness on a sensation for as long as 10 seconds if you want. Try various speeds until you find one which you like.
</p>

<p>
	Keep this whole practice very simple. Don't over-complicate it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 20:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271835</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ideology Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24381-ideology-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271646</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10087-markussweden/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10087" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10087-markussweden/" rel="">@MarkusSweden</a> There are many subtle forms of ideology. It's not as easy to avoid as you might think. It would be a dangerous mistake to think of ideology as simply being a Neo-Nazi.
</p>

<p>
	Many stage Green ideologies are "love"-based.
</p>

<p>
	And virtually all the highest consciousness teachings are turned into ideology by the mind.
</p>

<p>
	I've been studying this topic for over a decade and I still don't have a solid handle on it.
</p>

<p>
	This is a very slippery topic.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 10:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271646</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ideology Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24381-ideology-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271605</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
	<div>
		<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NYXZQ9BRiGw?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
	</div>
</div>

<p>
	 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 07:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271605</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ideology Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24381-ideology-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271603</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
	<div>
		<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mwmr2QMLuWY?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
	</div>
</div>

<p>
	 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 07:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271603</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ideology Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24381-ideology-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271602</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
	<div>
		<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HjLMAoejW-A?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
	</div>
</div>

<p>
	 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 07:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271602</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ideology Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24381-ideology-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271600</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I need your help gathering video examples of ideology in action in the real world. I'd like to gather a diverse catalogue of various kinds of ideologies, from various cultures, in both gross and subtle degrees.
</p>

<p>
	Please avoid posting long videos. Try to find videos which are short and to-the-point, so the ideology in on full display.
</p>

<p>
	Try to find diverse examples.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 07:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271600</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, has your advice to young people changed?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24251-leo-has-your-advice-to-young-people-changed/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271439</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9098-jacko/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9098" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9098-jacko/" rel="">@Jacko</a> I would imagine you could accomplish more on your own and enjoy it more.
</p>

<p>
	Learning is so much more enjoyable solo, without all the stupid tests and class schedules.
</p>

<p>
	As long as you have the motivation for it.
</p>

<p>
	College curriculums are so lame. They don't cover the most important and juicy topics.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 20:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271439</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kriya Yoga Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/19678-kriya-yoga-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271435</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270807" data-ipsquote-contentid="19678" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534493029" data-ipsquote-userid="2450" data-ipsquote-username="see_on_see">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 8/17/2018 at 1:03 AM, see_on_see said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> do you do Talabya Kriya / Khechari Mudra at all? For example Gamana's Kriya Supreme Fire says to do it as first step, altho I can barely move the tongue upwards while I'm doing all the other locks (primarily because the throat lock means I have my head tilted downwards). 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Not yet. I've held off on that technique to focus on mastering the other ones. I might add it in in the future.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 20:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271435</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dark night of the soul &amp; kundalini syndrome?!?!</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24345-dark-night-of-the-soul-kundalini-syndrome/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271281</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12429-tony-845/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12429" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12429-tony-845/" rel="">@Tony 845</a> It's mostly just a phase. You pass through it. It's not solid enlightenment yet. And it doesn't happen to everyone.
</p>

<p>
	I have a vid called: The Dark Side Of Meditation, which covers this to some extent.
</p>

<p>
	Solid awakening is the most awesome thing. Assuming you're the metaphysical sort of person. If you're attached to being an ego, then it could be a problem.
</p>

<p>
	I've never experienced anything as good in life as awakening. But that's me.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 09:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271281</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Looking for ICF-certified life coaching programs w/ a spiritual focus</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24322-looking-for-icf-certified-life-coaching-programs-w-a-spiritual-focus/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271277</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="271178" data-ipsquote-contentid="24322" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534553933" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			So, what do you think about doing a cheaper program first, and establishing a coaching business? I've seen a couple that looked decent for around $2000. And they were about six month long courses. Then, with the money from that coaching business, going and completing the IPEC program? I know it's not ideal, but that's really the only way I can slice it that it seems actionable.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I can't speak to those cheap programs. $2000 sounds very cheap. Most decent coaching programs cost significantly more.
</p>

<p>
	But I guess you gotta do what you gotta do. Something's better than nothing.
</p>

<p>
	Some coaching programs might even have payment plans. Check with IPEC. You can call them and do a free consultation and ask all your questions. They are pretty honest and straightforward.
</p>

<p>
	Some programs can definitely be scammy, so watch out. Especially with the really cheap ones. In the case of coaching programs I tend to believe that you generally get what you pay for.
</p>

<p>
	P.S. Sounds like you need to be more strategic with making income. $10,000 should be something you can easily afford if you live in Murica. Don't work in low-paying jobs, think bigger.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 08:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271277</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Looking for ICF-certified life coaching programs w/ a spiritual focus</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24322-looking-for-icf-certified-life-coaching-programs-w-a-spiritual-focus/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271276</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="271178" data-ipsquote-contentid="24322" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534553933" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Are any of those books on your book list?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, there is a small coaching book section.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="271178" data-ipsquote-contentid="24322" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534553933" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I purchased it a couple years ago, and I haven't looked at it in a while.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You've missed out on a ton of amazing new books I've added in those couple of years (not coaching related).
</p>

<p>
	 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 08:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271276</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Highly detailed biographies of rising men</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24358-highly-detailed-biographies-of-rising-men/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271275</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I got a lot of great biographies in my book list.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 08:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271275</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>ayahuasca trip report - reborn</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24338-ayahuasca-trip-report-reborn/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271224</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Sounds like some nice breakthrough-level trippin' <img alt=":D" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin@2x.png 2x" title=":D" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 05:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271224</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Law of One</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24352-the-law-of-one/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271222</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	We had a long thread about it here a long time ago, which I started.
</p>

<p>
	It's pretty controversial.
</p>

<p>
	The biggest problem with it is, to you, it's just hearsay.
</p>

<p>
	You must seek direct experience rather than building up spiritual beliefs about extraordinary things.
</p>

<p>
	The reason I personally found it interesting is because it independently corroborated my direct experience of Absolute Infinity. Can't speak to the rest of it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 05:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271222</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271148</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="271120" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534540894" data-ipsquote-userid="9004" data-ipsquote-username="DnoReally">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, DnoReally said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Slightly off-topic but I didn't want to make a separate thread for this. In your 2C-B video you said you plugged it <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?page=39#comment-198116" rel="">much like you do with 5-MeO</a>. My question is how much water did you use to dissolve ~10mg of 2C-B. There's not much information on stuff like this out there.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	As little water as you can get away with.
</p>

<p>
	Like 0.5ml
</p>

<p>
	20-30mg of 5-MeO can be dissolved in as little as 0.1-0.2ml. Literally a few drops.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 22:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271148</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Looking for ICF-certified life coaching programs w/ a spiritual focus</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24322-looking-for-icf-certified-life-coaching-programs-w-a-spiritual-focus/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271141</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/826-emerald/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="826" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/826-emerald/" rel="">@Emerald</a> There do exist books on how to coach. At the very least read up on them.
</p>

<p>
	It can also be very eye-opening to get coached yourself. So you can see how it feels.
</p>

<p>
	But doing an in-person coaching programming is really the key. You will learn so much.
</p>

<p>
	For you, since you already have an audience, it might make sense to take out a loan/credit to do the coaching program since you are basically guaranteed to make the money back (because you have an audience).
</p>

<p>
	You can probably make $10,000 back within 6 months of finishing the program. Program takes about 1 year to finish.
</p>

<p>
	You're actually losing money every day by not taking the program. But this is unique to you, because you already have the hardest part done: building an audience. This is not the case for most new coaches.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 22:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271141</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who is deciding?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24287-who-is-deciding/?do=findComment&amp;comment=271075</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12190-sashaj/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12190" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12190-sashaj/" rel="">@Sashaj</a> Start doing inquiry or yoga or whichever practice you like most.
</p>

<p>
	There's little point in talking about it. The answers are in the doing of it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 19:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">271075</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, has your advice to young people changed?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24251-leo-has-your-advice-to-young-people-changed/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270836</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/4740-michael569/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="4740" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/4740-michael569/" rel="">@Michael569</a> No other way than the LP Course. That course is my life's work, struggling to figure it out for myself. It is no small thing. The course is really just the tip of an iceberg. If a person is unwilling to do the course, they are not remotely serious about this issue and will never resolve it anyways. Life purpose is not something for lazy slobs.
</p>

<p>
	I invested about 10 years figuring it out until I finally did. The principles are all there. But it takes serious work to actualize it.
</p>

<p>
	It's worth the work in the end. Unfortunately so few people will ever see that. Just like enlightenment. It's so amazing, but who will ever get it? Almost no one. Almost no one will realize what life can be.
</p>

<p>
	There is no cure for too little vision.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 09:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270836</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is my understanding of the Spiral Dynamics stages accurate?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24320-is-my-understanding-of-the-spiral-dynamics-stages-accurate/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270805</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270745" data-ipsquote-contentid="24320" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534484467" data-ipsquote-userid="12145" data-ipsquote-username="Feel Good">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Feel Good said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			The problem green has is people taking orange to unhealthy extremes. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	But that too is part of Orange.
</p>

<p>
	You can't have Orange without excesses any more than you can have a baby who doesn't poo.
</p>

<p>
	Every stage will have its excesses, and that is part of the package of growing up. People do stupid and selfish things out of ignorance and lack of development.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 07:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270805</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Looking for ICF-certified life coaching programs w/ a spiritual focus</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24322-looking-for-icf-certified-life-coaching-programs-w-a-spiritual-focus/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270801</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	IPEC is a really good program (which I did).
</p>

<p>
	Yes, they teach some business stuff, but the real value of it is they train you how to properly coach, which is quite difficult to learn on your own. You will meet lots of people there who you can practice-coach with to build up your skills. They will also teach you lots of great techniques.
</p>

<p>
	Coaching is not what most people think it is. Coaching is NOT about giving people advice. Coaching is about asking powerful questions which facilitate the client to contemplate. Coaching is actually more powerful than giving people advice. Any fool can give advice, but very few people can coach. Coaching requires humility.
</p>

<p>
	Coaching skills are very versatile. They are not limited to business or spirituality or life purpose. You can use those skills to coach in whichever sub-specialty you want. You can definitely become a spirituality coach, if that's your passion.
</p>

<p>
	I might have 6-8 clients at my peak. But I was never a full-time coach. That was never my desire. Turned down many clients. Most of my time went into shooting videos. I have probably coached over 100 people in total.
</p>

<p>
	From what I can see you would make a great coach. The only question is, do you really want to be a coach? To be a good coach you gotta want to work with people one-on-one and deal with their "stuff". It can be very rewarding, but it's not for everyone.
</p>

<p>
	For example, I prefer mouthing off in videos rather than coaching people. But coaching can also be fun. A different kind of fun.
</p>

<p>
	P.S. I doubt you'll find a coaching program with a spiritual focus. That is unnecessary anyhow.
</p>

<p>
	And IPEC is all about consciousness, consciousness, consciousness. That's all they talk about. Just not in a woo-woo way. It's toned down to appeal to ordinary folk. You can teach and coach spirituality without ever telling a person it is spirituality or "God", and they will eat it up. They'll think it's the most amazing and powerful thing. But you can phrase it very plainly and pragmatically.
</p>

<p>
	Or... you can go all fucking woo-woo and pull out the crystals and group chanting <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" /> Same thing, different window-dressing.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 07:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270801</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, has your advice to young people changed?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24251-leo-has-your-advice-to-young-people-changed/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270800</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10914-thj50/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10914" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10914-thj50/" rel="">@THJ50</a> For business, I much prefer hands-on, do-it-yourself-entrepreneurship rather than learning theory. Business is all about practice.
</p>

<p>
	But that's my take on it. You could have different plans.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 07:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270800</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How can space and time be inside consciousness?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24205-how-can-space-and-time-be-inside-consciousness/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270796</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11312" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/" rel="">@CreamCat</a> Can't say for sure, but seems that way.
</p>

<p>
	Evolution seems like it will lead to an ultimate unity, which will then subdivide itself from scratch.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 07:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270796</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Where is the world heading? :(</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24294-where-is-the-world-heading/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270794</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270791" data-ipsquote-contentid="24294" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534490034" data-ipsquote-userid="12145" data-ipsquote-username="Feel Good">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		5 minutes ago, Feel Good said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			It's not that healthy.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's as healthy as you make it.
</p>

<p>
	Health is never in the thing, but in how you use it.
</p>

<p>
	Sex can be unhealthy too. Anything in the hands of a fool can become unhealthy.
</p>

<p>
	Practice masturbating consciously, like a sage <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 07:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270794</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Where is the world heading? :(</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24294-where-is-the-world-heading/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270789</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270787" data-ipsquote-contentid="24294" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534489739" data-ipsquote-userid="12145" data-ipsquote-username="Feel Good">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 minutes ago, Feel Good said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> I thought masturbation WAS repression?
		</p>

		<p>
			It certainly seems like it to me.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	What??
</p>

<p>
	Lol
</p>

<p>
	You guys have become too brainwashed by the no-fap people.
</p>

<p>
	Proper masturbation is an artform! <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	All sex is masturbation, BTW. No matter what, you're always having sex with none other than yourself.
</p>

<p>
	Life is just God's masturbatorium.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 07:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270789</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Where is the world heading? :(</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24294-where-is-the-world-heading/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270784</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270463" data-ipsquote-contentid="24294" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534434207" data-ipsquote-userid="8644" data-ipsquote-username="Florian">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		15 hours ago, Florian said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> So do you think NoFap is a bad idea?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I have never been a fan of the whole no-fap movement.
</p>

<p>
	Fap serves a useful function when used properly. Running around like a horny dog is problematic.
</p>

<p>
	If you do no-fap, it has to be done in a non-repressive way and for some good reasons, like maybe if you're getting into serious pickup or yoga.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 07:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270784</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who is deciding?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24287-who-is-deciding/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270773</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270753" data-ipsquote-contentid="24287" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534486450" data-ipsquote-userid="12190" data-ipsquote-username="Sashaj">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		30 minutes ago, Sashaj said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			“I” know all of this already. So what now
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's not enough to "know" it. If you're still using the word "I" you don't get it yet.
</p>

<p>
	This is the crux of self-inquiry and it requires thousands of hours of inquiry on this very point.
</p>

<p>
	Don't go looking for "new stuff". You must go deeply on this one thing until your realize you never existed. This is no small thing.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 06:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270773</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo stresses college so much?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24296-why-leo-stresses-college-so-much/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270769</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270757" data-ipsquote-contentid="24296" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534486985" data-ipsquote-userid="10023" data-ipsquote-username="RendHeaven">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		19 minutes ago, RendHeaven said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Alright, so are all of these courses equally valid? Can I take one of them and say: "Aha! Now I know marketing."
		</p>

		<p>
			Thanks for the reply Leo <img alt="^_^" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/happy.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/happy@2x.png 2x" title="^_^" width="20" />
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Of course not.
</p>

<p>
	That's like saying every book in the book store is equally valid and if I just read one book I will understand the world.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 06:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270769</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is my understanding of the Spiral Dynamics stages accurate?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24320-is-my-understanding-of-the-spiral-dynamics-stages-accurate/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270732</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11312" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/" rel="">@CreamCat</a> Equality means: those who are part of a historically, systemically oppressed group, should no longer be oppressed.
</p>

<p>
	Like, gay people should stop being demonized and denied jobs.
</p>

<p>
	Or black people should not get shot by police for sneezing.
</p>

<p>
	There is obvious discrimination which needs to be addressed.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 05:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270732</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo stresses college so much?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24296-why-leo-stresses-college-so-much/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270731</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270724" data-ipsquote-contentid="24296" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534479220" data-ipsquote-userid="10023" data-ipsquote-username="RendHeaven">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		42 minutes ago, RendHeaven said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			"learn marketing" is something I hear ALL the time.
		</p>

		<p>
			Pretty misleading advice, if you ask me. Maybe if I had a comprehensive library of knowledge to fall back on, I could easily expand that library on my own time. But I've got nothing right now, and I don't even know where to start <img alt=":(" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/sad.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/sad@2x.png 2x" title=":(" width="20" />
		</p>

		<p>
			All the gurus have different opinions. Does "learn marketing" really mean to check out what each and every person has to say personally? Or is there any place with most of this info assembled and organised? Is that too much to ask <img alt=":P" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue@2x.png 2x" title=":P" width="20" />
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	There exist literally thousands of video courses, seminars, and workshops which teach marketing in painful detail, for virtually every industry.
</p>

<p>
	There are courses for how to market carpet cleaning, dentistry, weight loss, surgery, information products, websites, vitamins, self help, life coaching, consulting, whatever.
</p>

<p>
	And there are courses which just teach general marketing principles.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 04:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270731</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is my understanding of the Spiral Dynamics stages accurate?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24320-is-my-understanding-of-the-spiral-dynamics-stages-accurate/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270728</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	The biggest difference between Green and Yellow is that Green believes its value system of equality for all should be universal, but Yellow understands it is just another perspective. Also, Yellow is self-aware of the stages whereas Green is not. Green believes it must conquer all the lower stages whereas Yellow understands that all stages have their place and that the entire Spiral has a purpose. Green tends to demonize lower stages whereas Yellow is above that.
</p>

<p>
	Yellow tries to guide people up the Spiral whereas Green tries to get everyone to become Green. Green does not understand that a Blue person cannot become Green without first living through Orange.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 04:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270728</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo stresses college so much?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24296-why-leo-stresses-college-so-much/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270722</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7356-revolutionary-think/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7356" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7356-revolutionary-think/" rel="">@Revolutionary Think</a> Ha! That's the problem EVERYONE has. That's a business problem.
</p>

<p>
	Learn business and marketing to solve that problem.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270722</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo stresses college so much?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24296-why-leo-stresses-college-so-much/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270715</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7356-revolutionary-think/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7356" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7356-revolutionary-think/" rel="">@Revolutionary Think</a> Something like that is a good idea. There are many possible alternative models. It's a great field to research with lots of pioneers starting to blaze some trails.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270715</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24198-jordan-peterson/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270710</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270553" data-ipsquote-contentid="24198" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534449390" data-ipsquote-userid="6183" data-ipsquote-username="hundreth">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		9 hours ago, hundreth said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			He actually acknowledges post modernism and that ultimately it's all relative. Where his ideas differ is that he believes there are infinite interpretations, but there's only a small finite set of interpretations that lead to a positive and meaningful life.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	This is a clever egoic trick. There are in fact far more viable and healthy interpretations than Peterson would lead you to believe.
</p>

<p>
	He makes it sound like his Christian-based solutions are the only ones that would work. Which is far from the case.
</p>

<p>
	The whole point of cultural relativism is to acknowledge all the weird and diverse solutions that cultures have come up with. Peterson just glosses over this part.
</p>

<p>
	One of the serious downsides of the stage Blue traditionalist worldview is that it is incapable of learning from other cultures because it holds itself as the one superior culture.
</p>

<p>
	For example, why is Peterson not talking about Hinduism? Yoga? Advaita? Buddhism? Sikhism? Paganism? Jainism? Concepts from Islam? etc. Some of these cultures have far superior spiritual teachings to Christianity, which is extremely corrupt and degraded.
</p>

<p>
	And, the most positive and meaningful life comes from dropping all interpretations as much as possible. You see how JP is avoiding infinity? Trying to make it finite?
</p>

<p>
	It's not just that JP rails against the radical left. I would criticize the radical left too. The much bigger problem is that he paints most of the left as radical left. Which is utterly absurd. Obnoxious college feminists in their early 20's do NOT represent the mainstream left almost at all. That's like 1% of the left. The most immature version of the left. It would be like representing all conservatives as KKK.
</p>

<p>
	He is making a mountain out of a molehill. As if a handful of obnoxious college feminists are about to take over the world. Please!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:33:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270710</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo stresses college so much?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24296-why-leo-stresses-college-so-much/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270709</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270703" data-ipsquote-contentid="24296" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534476077" data-ipsquote-userid="7356" data-ipsquote-username="Revolutionary Think">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		9 minutes ago, Revolutionary Think said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Changing this system is what I'm making my life purpose about
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's a very worthy cause.
</p>

<p>
	But also be mindful of the complexities of this system. Be careful that you don't inadvertently design a system which is even worse. Complex systems which handle tens of millions of people are notoriously difficult to design.
</p>

<p>
	A study of system theory would be a must.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270709</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Strong anger towards meat-eaters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24250-strong-anger-towards-meat-eaters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270706</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5473-sgn/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5473" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5473-sgn/" rel="">@sgn</a> It's got nothing to do with reality or facts.
</p>

<p>
	If you get triggered, that's ALL you! It's all about how your mind is failing to understanding the complexities of reality, denying reality.
</p>

<p>
	The reality is, people eat animals and you don't like it. That's not the world's problem, that's your problem. Don't project it on them. Own it.
</p>

<p>
	Triggering is never in the situation, it's in YOUR interpretation of the situation. If you were fully awakened, Hitler himself torturing kittens would not trigger you.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270706</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo stresses college so much?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24296-why-leo-stresses-college-so-much/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270701</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270699" data-ipsquote-contentid="24296" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534475884" data-ipsquote-userid="7356" data-ipsquote-username="Revolutionary Think">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 minute ago, Revolutionary Think said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			from time to time you have a situation where school (and sometimes family) not only doesn't help a person reach their potential but, actively diminishes their potential as well as pushes them away from what they want to do in life.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	In this case you follow your own heart and do whatever you feel is best.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270701</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo stresses college so much?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24296-why-leo-stresses-college-so-much/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270700</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270694" data-ipsquote-contentid="24296" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534475424" data-ipsquote-userid="7356" data-ipsquote-username="Revolutionary Think">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		11 minutes ago, Revolutionary Think said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Also doesn't it depend on the school? What if the teachers poison your mind with rhetoric like you'll never amount to anything etc.?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Of course it depends on the school. I am assuming you'd go to a good school, not a madrasa.
</p>

<p>
	If your school is a toxic hellhole, then yeah, maybe you're best off with no school at all.
</p>

<p>
	It's hard for me to say cause I only went to great schools. I don't really know what a bad school feels like.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270700</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo stresses college so much?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24296-why-leo-stresses-college-so-much/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270698</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270695" data-ipsquote-contentid="24296" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534475605" data-ipsquote-userid="7356" data-ipsquote-username="Revolutionary Think">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 minutes ago, Revolutionary Think said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Radical open mindedness no? Why is the word must even in your vocabulary? <img alt="9_9" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/rolleyes.gif" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/rolleyes@2x.png 2x" title="9_9" width="20" /> <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/wildly-successful-people-who-dropped-out-of-high-school-2015-9" rel="external nofollow">https://www.businessinsider.com/wildly-successful-people-who-dropped-out-of-high-school-2015-9</a>  
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Of course you can always find exceptions.
</p>

<p>
	We are talking about general guidelines for people, not what works for 1 in 1000.
</p>

<p>
	A solid education is very important.
</p>

<p>
	And don't confuse success with personal development and consciousness. Just because someone drops out of school and earns millions of dollars doesn't mean much. He could be selling tobacco to children or a used car salesmen.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270698</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo stresses college so much?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24296-why-leo-stresses-college-so-much/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270697</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="270670" data-ipsquote-contentid="24296" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1534468043" data-ipsquote-userid="11312" data-ipsquote-username="CreamCat">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, CreamCat said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			There was a lot of bullying from students and teachers. I didn't learn much from schools. A lot of downside with little benefits.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Bullying is a separate issue. Of course if there is lots of bullying in your school that will sour your whole education experience.
</p>

<p>
	Bullying varies a lot from school to school and by geographic location.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270697</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Strong anger towards meat-eaters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24250-strong-anger-towards-meat-eaters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270692</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10664-stardewvalley/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10664" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10664-stardewvalley/" rel="">@StardewValley</a> Sounds like a shadow issue.
</p>

<p>
	In other words, the reason you are angry at them is because you have actually disowned this meat-eater part of yourself. You've told yourself it it wrong, but this was really a denial rather than a genuine transcendence.
</p>

<p>
	Contemplate with a journal how you have disowned this part of yourself and created an identity around being a moralistic non-meat-eater.
</p>

<p>
	What is your ego getting out of hating meat-eaters? It's getting something! There's some secret payoff.
</p>

<p>
	Meditation actually tends to not resolve shadow issues. You need to contemplate, not meditate this issue.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270692</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I have a crippling fear of failure that ironically leads me to fail</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24318-i-have-a-crippling-fear-of-failure-that-ironically-leads-me-to-fail/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270690</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Sit down with a journal and dig into why you procrastinate. What is really going on there?
</p>

<p>
	Don't speculate. Sit down and contemplate it seriously. You might be surprised what you discover. The root causes are not always what they first appear.
</p>

<p>
	Keep probing this question day after day for at least a week. Get deep with it. Explore your true psyche. Ask yourself why you are doing all this. If it's fear, what do you really fear and why is it so bad?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270690</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who is deciding?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24287-who-is-deciding/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270688</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12190-sashaj/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12190" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12190-sashaj/" rel="">@Sashaj</a> Notice how often your posts contain the words "I", "me", "my".
</p>

<p>
	You keep saying "I", "I", "I"... but notice, there isn't one. Stop screwing around and try to pinpoint what this "I" is that you claim you are.
</p>

<p>
	If the "I" cannot be pinpointed, then why are you so sure you exist? Why keep saying "I"?
</p>

<p>
	What if "I" is just a word which points to nothing? Like Santa Claus or unicorn.
</p>

<p>
	What if you are just an idea?
</p>

<p>
	What if you cannot die because in fact you never existed?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 02:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270688</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, has your advice to young people changed?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24251-leo-has-your-advice-to-young-people-changed/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270675</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8351-cepzeu/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8351" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8351-cepzeu/" rel="">@Cepzeu</a> It hasn't changed that much. The fundamentals are still the same.
</p>

<p>
	The one thing I would change is, if you have a clear sense of direction, college is not necessarily the way to go. I now feel that college is only right for certain types of people and certain types of majors.
</p>

<p>
	If you're self-driven, you can out-perform college by your own.
</p>

<p>
	Of course it all depends on what you want to do with your life. If you want to be a doctor or engineer, college is basically a must.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 01:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270675</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Life Coach Program Reviews/Thoughts</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24284-life-coach-program-reviewsthoughts/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270674</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Most coaches cannot sustain a living doing coaching because they are just bad at marketing themselves and getting clients. It has little to do with your coaching skills and more to do with your business and networking skills. Coaching is traditionally a very network-oriented business. You need to be a good networker, or a good online marketer.
</p>

<p>
	I am a bad example of a coach because I don't really coach people and I don't network. I sort of created my own category of online philosopher because I never really cared to be a traditional coach.
</p>

<p>
	If you are a great networker and really hustle, you can certainly make low six figures. But this is highly usual for coaches. Most coaches can't make $20k/year because they don't realize that coaching isn't about coaching, it requires business savvy.
</p>

<p>
	Honestly, it's gonna be tough to be a coach at your age. You're just a bit too young and immature still and people will not take you seriously (and they aren't wrong). You need more life experience and more theoretical foundation. But don't let that discourage you. You can still lay the groundwork now for a coaching career in your late 20's and early 30's.
</p>

<p>
	Don't expect any cookie-cutter formula or coaching programming to land you a 6 figure income. A 6 figure income is only possible through creative, original thinking and lots of hustle, above and beyond what most coaches do.
</p>

<p>
	In the meantime, you can try to find a career which will get you more experience, like counseling students in college or working with substance abuse victims or tutoring teens or some kind of community organizer jobs. Jobs like that can be a good segue into coaching later on, as they allow you to develop people skills and start practicing mentoring.
</p>

<p>
	To be a good coach you have to enjoy working with and mentoring people. You also need to know how to sell people on the value of coaching. People are generally very hesitant to pay hard money for soft advice. You gotta find ways to make coaching very tangible and practice for people. Like, "I can help you save your marriage" or "I can help you double your salary".
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 01:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270674</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Shamanic / Holotropic Breathing Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/20161-shamanic-holotropic-breathing-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270672</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/3166-herghly/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="3166" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/3166-herghly/" rel="">@herghly</a> That sounds like a neat innovation. I can def see it being very powerful.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 01:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270672</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why do so many famous people do suicid?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/24222-why-do-so-many-famous-people-do-suicid/?do=findComment&amp;comment=270671</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Fame is like pouring gasoline onto an already toxic and deluded ego-mind. It makes the ego drunk with power.
</p>

<p>
	And the day after you get everything you ever wanted will be the most depressing day of your life. People overlook this point in our materialistic culture.
</p>

<p>
	Unsuccessful people cannot appreciate how hollow success is. Successful people can.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 01:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">270671</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>