<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Leo's Blog: Infinite Insights - Actualized.org</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leo's Blog: Infinite Insights - Actualized.org]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 15:47:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #016</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-016</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"An aimless life is always a troubled life. Every individual should have an aim. But do not forget that the quality of your aim will depend the quality of your life. Your aim should be high and wide, generous and disinterested; this will make your life precious to yourself and to others. Whatever your ideal, it cannot be perfectly realized unless you have realized perfection in yourself."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Sri Aurobindo</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-016</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Internal Workings Of CNN</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/internal-workings-of-cnn</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Speaking of the media, here's an illuminating look into the inner workings of CNN:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CJASlSNRxv8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>I think Jeff Zucker is an intelligent and decent guy, but he does not understand the depth of the problem of what "reporting the truth" means. Truth is much more tricky than merely fact-checking some wrong information, because who gets to say what counts as valid fact-checking? You can't just assume that "facts" exist! What if "facts" are really how your mind constructs reality? Who's construction should we trust? Yours? Mine? Jeff Zucker's? A billionaire's? An atheist's? A Muslim's? A Christian's? A Buddhist's? A scientist's? A white person's? A black person's? etc. What if each person has their own "facts"? What do you do then?</p>
<p>I'd like you to notice that everything talked about in the above video is really an issue of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epistemology" target="_blank">epistemology</a> (human knowledge). The question of "What is true?" is an epistemic question. Notice that this question is not merely philosophical, it has serious real-world consequences. How do you maintain a high quality society when people cannot agree with each other's perspectives on truth, or when some segments of society have really warped versions of truth? How do we deal with that as a society? How does CNN deal with it? How does Facebook deal with it? How does Google deal with it? How do you deal with it? How do your parents deal with it? What if the majority of the population believe in falsehood? How do you go about correcting that when they believe it's a fact?</p>
<p>Notice how challenging and deep this issue is. This is not merely a Trump problem. Epistemology has been a root problem for mankind since the dawn of civilization. We are always arguing about what is true, what is reasonable, what is biased, what is opinion, what is fact, and what is the proper interpretation of things. Have you wondered about why this is? What causes this? You'd think that if reality was an objective fact, we'd all agree on it by now. You'd think that if reality was an objective fact it would be impossible to mislead people about it. Yet human history shows the opposite. Masses of people are mislead all the time. How can this be? And can you be sure you aren't one of those who's misled? After all, if people are easy to mislead, you are person, therefore you must be easy to mislead.</p>
<p>Notice that before one can answer the question of the proper way to act, or make any proper plans, one must first answer the question of What is true? If your perspective of reality is so distorted that you see the world upside-down, your plans and actions will also be upside-down, doubling down on the problem. The solution to any serious problem is, first and foremost, to see the problem with undistorted perception. In many cases taking that first step is enough to resolve the problem. But most people want to jump straight into action, ignoring the first step by dismissing it as "mere philosophy" or "theory". But what good is pressing the accelerator pedal when you haven't first figured out which direction is True North? Undistorted perception is NOT "just theory".</p>
<p>Life's most important problems can only be solved by a shift in perspective & understanding. In such cases, there's something deep you're not conscious of about the problem which makes it manifest over and over again, and it will not stop until you see through to the root of it by properly using your mind.</p>
<p>Most problems are the result of the improper use of one's mind. Think about that.</p>
<p>People who casually blame CNN, The New York Times, "main stream media", "Jewish media", Hollywood elites, Silicon Valley, Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, and yes, even Fox News, do not understand the depth of the epistemic problem. The problem of disseminating "truth" is the most challenging problem that mankind has ever faced. We still haven't figured out how to do in over 10,000 years of trying. Schools, universities, parents, government, the media, science, religion, and every spiritual school all face this fundamental problem. Devils will ALWAYS corrupt the purest sources of truth because falsehood is necessary for survival. Not understanding this triples the problem.</p>
<p>When you understand the depth of what I'm saying here you will realize that epistemology is the most important topic that mankind can study, research, or teach. Yet precisely because this is so, it is not studied or taught almost at all. Devils are not interested in epistemology. It doesn't suite their schemes. So our problem then becomes: how do you teach 7 billion devils proper epistemology when their lives hinge on them not learning it? This problem is more challenging and more important to solve than the problem of building a colony on Mars. Yet it gets no attention and no funding.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/internal-workings-of-cnn</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why The Media Is Corrupt</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-the-media-is-corrupt</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/368190025?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-the-media-is-corrupt</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spirituality &amp; Politics</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/spirituality-politics</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Excellent discussion of what I call <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/conscious-politics-part-1" target="_blank">Conscious Politics</a>:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5mP38NGImsc?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/spirituality-politics</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wolf PAC Anti-Corruption Speech</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/wolf-pac-anti-corruption-speech</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Perfect timing!</p>
<p>On the day I release my How Corruption Works video, this video gets released:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DyXspSJITpY?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is the #1 most important political issue. Get all money out of politics NOW!</p>
<p>If you're not an American, your country probably has a similar problem, and probably worse.</p>
<p>Cenk is a great example of visionary leadership and life purpose. When you see examples of visionary leadership, take notice and study how it works. What are the principles of visionary leadership?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/wolf-pac-anti-corruption-speech</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Killer Strange Loop</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/killer-strange-loop</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aX_vB4sYmgE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/killer-strange-loop</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Real Leadership Looks Like</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-real-leadership-looks-like</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This man needs to be elected President so he can LEAD.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3ZhkKATtqtU?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V7wlnI4Koco?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is conscious politics in the flesh!</p>
<p>He has the strongest, most conscious, most loving vision for the next stage of America's evolution and he has the experience and balls to actualize it. Don't take such a rare leader for granted. After he's gone, there won't be another like him for a generation. He is a leader 40 years ahead of his time. Within 50 years, all of his plans will become the taken-for-granted norm regardless of whether he wins the Presidency or not.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-real-leadership-looks-like</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Infinite Life</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-life</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Check out this wonderful YT channel called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBbnbBWJtwsf0jLGUwX5Q3g/" target="_blank">Journey To The Microcosmos</a>. They feature videos on microscopic life. Notice the complexity and intelligence of even microscopic organisms.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OmoL8LlQwWQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kux1j1ccsgg?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>There's more:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PZoaKzEXzi8" target="_blank">Stentors</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U3PLUeD_JAg" target="_blank">Rotifers</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Try to imagine how unaware of the larger cosmos these little lifeforms are. Now imagine that you as a human are as unaware of a higher reality as these little guys are of human reality. This gives you a proper sense of how limited your consciousness is and how much more you have to become conscious of.</p>
<p>Your body is a super-organism composed of billions of tiny individuated organisms all working together perfectly to create the larger unity that is the human you. Yet none of those organisms are aware of the larger unity they create. Likewise, humans have no idea of the larger unity they create. And so it goes to infinity. Such is the intelligence of God's design. The intelligence of it is infinite.</p>
<p>Consciousness is alive at all scales, from infinitely small to infinitely large. In fact there is no such thing as small and large because the scale extends infinitely far in all directions and all dimensions. There is no difference in scale between a human, a moss piglet, and the Milky Way galaxy.</p>
<p>You are not truly awake until you are conscious of how intelligent consciousness is at all scales — of how every scale dovetails perfectly into higher and higher unities which extend upward to infinity. This is the body/mind of God, dreaming an infinite number of dreams and interweaving them together seamlessly into one Grand Unity. A cradle for infinite life. A fractal of all possible lifeforms, branching out forever — your human self is one tip of one branch.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-life</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Is Fascism?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-is-fascism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a good intro to the psychology of fascism which most people do not understand:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IMpFcUXq2_w?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The funny thing about fascism is, fascism can only flourish when people are ignorant about what fascism is and therefore blind to their own participation in it.</p>
<p>In other words, a fascist does not understand he's a fascist. A fascist thinks he's a patriot. Unfortunately this stuff is not taught well in schools. Schools do not teach our citizens how easy it is to get sucked into fascist ideology, instead it demonizes Nazis, which makes people complacent.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-is-fascism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Big Picture Of Global Politics</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-big-picture-of-global-politics</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/364396211?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-big-picture-of-global-politics</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Trump Presidency In A Nutshell</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-trump-presidency-in-a-nutshell</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's presidency explained in 39 seconds:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v2XtkXIRCVg?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-trump-presidency-in-a-nutshell</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Actualized Launches On Patreon</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/actualized-launches-on-patreon</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Actualized.og has launched on Patreon.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YYoNpU9rY_k?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>If you'd like to support my work, <a href="https://www.patreon.com/actualized" target="_blank">click here</a>. $5/mo is the recommended donation.</p>
<p>Thanks for your support.</p>
<p>If you can't afford it, don't worry about it.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/actualized-launches-on-patreon</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Is Neo-Liberalism?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-is-neo-liberalism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A great introductory video:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/myH3gg5o0t0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>There is also:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EkBpqLWFNg4" target="_blank">Part 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zsgwVz0D6rI" target="_blank">Part 3</a> (not as good as parts 1 & 2)</li>
</ul>
<p>The most tricky ideologies are those which aren't seen as ideologies at all. How can you begin to let go of a thing you're not even aware you're holding?</p>
<p>It's not that Neo-Liberalism is bad per se, it's that it is starting to show its limits and must evolve into some higher, better system. Every system must evolve to accommodate higher consciousness and love, or die. And actually, death is nothing other than evolution. The next 100 years for America and much of the developed world will be about finding the next evolutionary step beyond Neo-Liberalism. What that is we don't exactly know. It won't just be old-school socialism. It will be something else. Perhaps a strange hybrid system. Like all technological advances, we'll have to find it through trail and error. That trail and error will manifest as social turbulence, which we've been seeing more and more of lately. As 3rd world countries start to reach parity with the 1st world countries, as the world becomes more global and equalized, there will be a lot of turbulence because old systems will have to dissolve while millions of people cling to them.</p>
<p>We are like a snake just beginning to shed its skin.</p>
<p>But fear not! This world circumstance also presents many exciting opportunities. What will be your role in helping mankind evolve into the 21st century? Contemplate that. Don't just be a passive leaf blown by the wind. Decide to be an active participant in this process of evolution. Decide what role you want to play, or someone else will decide it for you. Also decide to be on the right side of history, which is always the side which seeks to expand consciousness and love to more living beings.</p>
<p>In this sense your job in life is very simple: to decide in which specific ways you want to manifest your love.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-is-neo-liberalism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Buddhism StackExchange</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/buddhism-stackexchange</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Funny to find that there's a StackExchange about Buddhism. Maybe some of you will find it useful.</p>
<p><a href="https://buddhism.stackexchange.com/questions?tab=Votes" target="_blank">Buddhism StackExchange</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/buddhism-stackexchange</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fundamentally Misunderstanding Religion</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/fundamentally-misunderstanding-religion</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I'm a big fan of Noam Chomsky's political analysis, but when it comes to his thinking about metaphysics and religion the following video shows just how crude it is:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aZ51k8EiKh0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is one of the world's greatest scientists, yet he's clueless about metaphysics and spirituality.</p>
<p>Here Chomsky is basically parroting the standard paradigm of scientific materialism / realism, which fundamentally misunderstands why religion exists.</p>
<p>The source of religion is NOT wishful thinking nor superstition, as many scientists believe. The irony is that holding such a view is deeply unscientific. Such a belief can only be held by people who have never engaged in serious spiritual practice or metaphysical inquiry.</p>
<p>Ignorance like this is unfortunately common among some of our greatest scientists. And that is because they do not make a serious study of epistemology, metaphysics, or spirituality. And the reason they don't is because their belief that spirituality is bullshit is an example of confirmation bias. If you believe that spirituality is bullshit, you will never do the spiritual practice required to discover that it's not bullshit. So from your POV it will always appear as though there is no evidence that spirituality isn't bullshit. Because your fundamental premise — that reality must be material and non-mystical — is wrong. Yet you are not openminded or intellectually curious enough to question it.</p>
<p>All of that is just an example of terrible epistemology and sloppy science. If you are a serious scientist you understand that you cannot pre-judge the results of an experiment before running it. But why then do you pre-judge spirituality and metaphysics before practicing it? Can you see your own hypocrisy here? This is no different than refusing to look into a telescope to see if Jupiter is a real planet because you have already decided that Jupiter isn't real, therefore it would be a waste of time to look. It's viciously circular logic. This vicious circularity isn't just a bug, it's feature. Such circularity is necessary to create a paradigm lock, which is necessary to construct a worldview, which is ultimately necessary for your mind to construct "reality". There is no "reality" without circular logic. Circular logic is how you construct the "physical world"! Ta-da!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/fundamentally-misunderstanding-religion</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Strange-Loopy Rollercoasters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/strange-loopy-rollercoasters</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a fun example of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/reality-is-a-strange-loop" target="_blank">strange loops</a> from the Rollercoaster Tycoon game:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EbjqWThzXME?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>See, I told you this stuff has real-world consequences.</p>
<p>Strange loops are fundamental to the structure of reality.</p>
<p>If you're gonna be doing lots of psychedelics, you better have a solid theoretical understanding of what strange loops are because your mind will encounter some hairy ones and they will mindfuck you.</p>
<p>So when one day you realize that you crawled out of your own vagina — remember, I told you so ;)</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/strange-loopy-rollercoasters</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Projection Projecting Projection</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/projection-projecting-projection</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The trickeries of the mind never cease to amaze. Case in point, this article by David Kupelian:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.wnd.com/2019/01/democrats-and-the-dark-art-of-projection/" target="_blank">Democrats And The Dark Art Of Projection</a></p>
<p>Which is a master class in how to project one's own projections onto others by accusing them of projection! The boldness of it is impressive.</p>
<p>In this article a <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">stage Blue</a> worldview is projecting it's limited cognitive, moral, and spiritual development onto a <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-green" target="_blank">stage Green</a> worldview, thereby seeing Green as lower than Blue — which is precisely backwards. Green appears to be lower than Blue when seen from Blue's limited POV. But since Blue doesn't acknowledge that POVs are relative, Blue isn't aware of itself as a POV, thereby confusing itself with truth. A big part of what it means to be at stage Blue is that you cannot see your POV as just one POV among many others. If you were conscious of that, you'd grow out of Blue.</p>
<p>Notice that the reason this can happen is precisely because all points of view are relative, so there is no baseline to ground any point of view. So if you imagine that your opponents are projecting, they are! — according to your projection, which you imagine you are not doing. If you imagine you aren't projecting, that's enough to make it seem like you're not projecting. But of course all points of view are imaginary to begin with. Which is precisely what projection is trying to deny: "No, I'm not making stuff up, I'm just stating the truth while you're making stuff up!" << Yeah, that's something you're making up! "No I'm not! You are!" << You made that up too!</p>
<p>The #1 rule of projection is: the more you project, the more you accuse others of projecting, the more you deny your own projections.</p>
<p>To be really effective at projection you must attack the person you're projecting upon for projecting onto you before they've even made that accusation. By accusing them first, you deny them the ability to call you out for your projection. This is classic, classic gas-lighting.</p>
<p>So, for example, if you're cheating on your spouse, you must accuse your spouse of cheating on you before he/she accuses you. This makes it much harder for him/her to accuse you, even though you're the one who's cheating. You'd think that the cheater wouldn't be so obnoxious as to accuse the person he's cheating on of cheating on him (only a shameless asshole would do that), but its precisely because you think he wouldn't do it that he does do it! Because he can use your expectations of decency to cloak the truth from you. That's devilry 101. Devilry is all about finding bold ways of presenting falsehood as truth and truth as falsehood.</p>
<p>Projection is one of the trickiest mechanisms of self-deception. A <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Spiral Dynamics stage Blue</a> mind especially tends not to notice its own projections.</p>
<p>Do liberals engage in projection? Of course. Most people do. But conservatives engage in it far more. And conservatives are much more likely to deny that they are projecting. Part of what it means to be more cognitively and spiritually developed on the Spiral is that higher stages are more aware when they are projecting while lower stages are totally in denial about it. It takes a lot of consciousness work to escape projection entirely. 99.9% of people cannot escape projection because they simply haven't done enough serious self-reflection. Transcending projection requires a profound understanding of how <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/self-bias" target="_blank">Self-Bias</a> works, which again, most people are in denial about.</p>
<p>We'll talk more about projection in a future video since it's such an important topic.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/projection-projecting-projection</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>This Work Is Not About Belief</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/this-work-is-not-about-belief</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>All of my teachings are worthless unless you validate them in your direct experience. This stuff is far too profound to be heard or believed. Belief in what I say is a great obstacle to this work. You will spend years believing me only to realize that you made a big mistake. Yet at the same time, actively disbelieving me — trying to debunk me or debate me — is an even greater mistake. The correct method is to listen to what I say, consider it as an advanced possibility, and do the work to validate this possibility and feel it as your living reality. This work is about transforming your experience of reality.</p>
<p>I have no desire to make you believe in God or my teachings. What you believe is such a shallow level that it is irrelevant as far as this work goes. What matters is what you're conscious of, what state of consciousness you're in, and what the meta, cognitive structures of your mind are. This work is not about the contents of your mind. This work is structural. Think of this difference as the difference between apps vs the OS or BIOS on a computer. In our work here, we're not interested in changing the apps of the human mind, we're interested in changing the OS & even the BIOS. This work is meta work. This work is experiential. This work is about changing what reality is for you. You don't even know what that means yet. It will take you years of work just to appreciate what was just said. And that's as it must be. You can't know what you're missing until years of trial and error.</p>
<p>It would speed things along greatly for you to realize that we are not interested in getting you to believe things here. Anything you believe is far too shallow to help you. Belief is like a veil of fakery which obscures the doing of the real work. So be careful not to get tricked into thinking you are doing the work when you are merely rearranging your beliefs. The real work requires hours upon hours of precise mindfulness and accurate self-observation. Precision and accuracy in this work is important.</p>
<p>Towards this end it would help you greatly to distinguish between what is a belief, and what is not. Spend some time observing in your direct experience what is a belief, and what is not. Get really clear about this without getting caught up in the trap of judging whether a belief is true or false. What's more important than whether a belief is true or false is that you are conscious that it is a belief regardless. For example, "The Earth is round" is a belief regardless of whether its "true". Just because a belief is "true" does not mean it isn't problematic or doesn't distort your experience of reality. In this sense, scientific beliefs can be more problematic than religious ones because scientific beliefs are not usually acknowledged to be beliefs, or problematic — yet they are both.</p>
<p>Notice the distinct difference between believing a thing and direct experience. Notice that experience does not care what you believe. Although of course your beliefs greatly distort and color your experience.</p>
<p>And even though I call all this "work", you must find a way to do it so that you enjoy the process, rather than making it some chore that you must do. You will never be successful in this work as long as it feels like a chore. You must find a way to connect it with your passion for life. It must become an organic part of your life.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/this-work-is-not-about-belief</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>This Is Love</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/this-is-love</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zTLPjgqjLVA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>People often associate Love with happiness and sweetness. But they overlook the brutality of real Love.</p>
<p>You are never going to understand Love at an existential level until you confront Love at is rawest form, as shown above. Don't mistake Love for something that pleases your ego.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/this-is-love</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Enron Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/enron-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Another textbook example of devilry:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e5qC1YGRMKI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This sort of stuff happens on Wall Street every day. Ordinary people don't understand how much white collar crime goes on in America (and all over the world).</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/enron-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Theranos Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/theranos-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I just love finding juicy examples of devilry like this because it's so illustrative of how devilry works:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3CccfnRpPtM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/theranos-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Infinite Intelligence Communication #001</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-intelligence-communication-001</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I have discovered a powerful new chemical which allowed me to have a direct communication with Infinite Intelligence.</p>
<p>Download the transcript below:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/infinite-intelligence-001.docx" target="_blank">Infinite Intelligence Communication #001</a></p>
<p>Warning: radical openmindedness required.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-intelligence-communication-001</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stage Orange Corrupting Video Games</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/stage-orange-corrupting-video-games</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you're an avid gamer you've probably noticed the corruption which has infected the video game industry over the last 10 years: micro-transactions, loot boxes, gambling, season passes, games-as-service, bullshit limited editions, pre-mature bug-ridden releases, and other scammy tactics. Well, that's the epitome of stage Orange.</p>
<p>Here's but one perfect example:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g-BuUqsd71w?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>As a gamer, make a distinction between Stage Orange vs Stage Green games. Stage Green games are more about heart and artistry than profits and milking gamers.</p>
<p>I love this example because it shows you how down-to-Earth and relevant Spiral Dynamics is.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/stage-orange-corrupting-video-games</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microdosing Research</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/microdosing-research</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6AfFM8pfy4s?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/microdosing-research</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Critique Of Zizek's Critique Of Buddhism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/my-critique-of-zizeks-critique-of-buddhism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Let's do a little critical philosophy. First, watch Slavoj Zizek's video critique of Buddhism. Then watch my point-by-point rebuttal. It's fun and you will gain some valuable insight doing this.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IlCkLqz20W8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/355488809?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>P.S. I am not a Buddhist and I have my own critiques of Buddhism which I didn't go into here.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/my-critique-of-zizeks-critique-of-buddhism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Psilocybin &amp; Personality Change</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/psilocybin-and-personality-change</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I found this video insightful. According to this research, psychedelics are one of the only and the most powerful tools for personality change.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9kSoka5iSi4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Of course this is not limited to psilocybin. All psychedelics lead to personality change. Especially the most powerful ones like 5-MeO-DMT, DPT, and N,N-DMT.</p>
<p>If you want serious personality change what you need is to not just a psychedelic trip, but specifically you need a psychedelic breakthrough. A breakthrough is not an ordinary trip. A breakthrough means that life as you knew it is over. You have gone beyond human life, beyond physical reality, beyond science, beyond religion, beyond memory, beyond language, beyond all teachings, beyond your birth. You have entered the realm of the impossible & the insane. Your entire paradigm of reality has been shattered to the point where you cannot even remember what the old paradigm was. You have escaped the labyrinth of your own mind. You have broken reality. You have left The Matrix. It is the most significant event in your life.</p>
<p>Don't worry, you'll know it once you're there.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/psilocybin-and-personality-change</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rethinking Human History</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/rethinking-human-history</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/354866618?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/rethinking-human-history</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Liberia: Land Of True Freedom</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/liberia-land-of-true-freedom</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A forum member (Ero) shared this video on our forum and I thought it was important share it with you all.</p>
<p>Most people today simply have no appreciation of what survival is like without a decent government. The following is what you get without government, courts, laws, police, regulations, infrastructure, roads, sewers, education, public health care, welfare, etc. This is the true "free market". This is what real freedom looks like. But are you sure you want it?:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZRuSS0iiFyo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Only when you appreciate the above do you understand why government is so crucial. And you see why consciousness cannot be raised en mass without high quality government & infrastructure. This romantic idea that you can just go be a monk somewhere in a cave is a childish fantasy. Reality is far more complex than that. Living in caves doesn't scale across thousands of people. If even only 1% of the population decided to live as monks in caves, there would be such a cave shortage that monks would be killing each other in the night to secure their caves such that the piles of corpses and garbage would rise so high as to block the sun.</p>
<p>The above is Spiral Dynamics stage Purple & Red at its unhealthiest.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/liberia-land-of-true-freedom</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Are My Videos So Long?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-are-my-videos-so-long</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/354368822?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-are-my-videos-so-long</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introducing Slavoj Zizek</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/introducing-slavoj-zizek</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I disagree with him on some fundamental points — he certainly doesn't understand nonduality, Buddhism, Love, or Spiral Dynamics — but he's an interesting and complex thinker that offers some serious good food for thought on political issues and collective human nature.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e2O6f2R9PZI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>He's the entertaining and intellectually-stimulating kind of neurotic ;) You can find a bunch of his videos on YouTube just by searching his name. He makes some very good structural critiques of capitalism. He has a pretty good grasp of the devilry behind ideology. By studying his videos you can deepen your understanding of ideology. Which is a topic I talk about all the time, even if I don't always call it that.</p>
<p>I admire the authenticity of his neuroticism.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/introducing-slavoj-zizek</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aliens Confirmed</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/aliens-confirmed</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9D0eyl7-XQA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/aliens-confirmed</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How To Test For Self-Bias</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-to-test-for-self-bias</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Some additional points to pair with my <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/self-bias" target="_blank">Self-Bias</a> video.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/353704681?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-to-test-for-self-bias</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Harrison Ford On Nature</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/harrison-ford-on-nature</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>"Nature doesn't need people, people need nature."</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WdSmnlVC_yk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The world needs your conscious engagement. What are you waiting for?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/harrison-ford-on-nature</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Fyre Festival Fiasco</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-fyre-festival-fiasco</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's an amazing Netflix documentary about the infamous failed Fyre Festival. Some good lessons to learn here about con-artistry and how the human mind works. This is what late-stage capitalism looks like:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uZ0KNVU2fV0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>How fitting that their logo was a solid block of Orange.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-fyre-festival-fiasco</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Amazing Cornel West</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-amazing-cornel-west</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Cornel West is fucking amazing! One of the greatest orators of our time. Spiritually advanced too. He gives Christianity and academia a good name.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gAYLKvUeWNo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Notice his understanding of love and his expanded circle of concern. This is a marker of high moral development: a love that extends to all beings. An abundant generosity which does not demonize others.</p>
<p>Notice also his boldness. He is not "neutral" to both sides. He calls devilry out by its name. Because true love is a radical thing. It rattles the status quo. It speaks truth to power.</p>
<p>If Jesus was alive today, his politics would probably look like those of Cornel West.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-amazing-cornel-west</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The War On Government</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-war-on-government</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Sadly it's trendy today for young people to feel like government does nothing for them. This kind of nihilistic, cynical apathy is deeply problematic because it plays right into the hands of those who rig the system.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eozs2ZmqYmM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-war-on-government</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Plutocracy Doesn't Work</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-plutocracy-doesnt-work</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q2gO4DKVpa8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-plutocracy-doesnt-work</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trust The Force</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/trust-the-force</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>At some point in your spiritual journey you will reach a point where you must switch off your targeting computer — let go and trust your highest wisdom and intuition.</p>
<p>This scene captures it perfectly. George Lucas had an amazing ability to convey spiritual concepts:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zR7CeC-rqiE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>That is what you must do to master life.</p>
<p>This can be scary for many rationalists, materialists, and skeptics to do because in their paradigm a thing isn't real unless it is "hard" quantifiable. Anything short of that is dismissed as wishful thinking, "faith", sentimentality, or pseudoscience. The only problem with that is, Truth and Consciousness are infinite, so they are not quantifiable. To quantify it would be to limit it. To make it "hard" would be to weaken it. This is what a lot of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-orange" target="_blank">Stage Orange</a> conventional thinkers don't understand. The deepest aspects of life are not quantifiable in principle. Why would you assume they could be?</p>
<blockquote><p>"Not everything that counts can be counted, and not everything that can be counted counts."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- A sign supposedly hanging in Einstein's office at Princeton</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/trust-the-force</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Health Insurance Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/health-insurance-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In this video a former health insurance executive admits to being a devil, falsifying the debate on universal healthcare to maximize profits. Now he has seen the light and is working to redeem himself:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/djD-OeIJ2G4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>A devil who realizes his devilry becomes a vehicle for Love. Devilry ends through consciousness, and no other way, because devilry is nothing but lack of consciousness. To defeat darkness all you must do is turn on the lights.</p>
<p>What you must understand about corporate executives is that they — like all devils — do not understand that they are devils. They are unconscious survival machines.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"Forgiven them father, for they know not what they do."</p>
</blockquote>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/health-insurance-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Wise Patriot, Round Two</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-wise-patriot-round-two</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I love this guy's down to Earth political analysis:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gUxQY0xHEFY?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is a grounded example of stage Green politics. Stage Green is not all crazy college feminist protestors as you sometimes see portrayed by right-wing YouTube or Jordan Peterson and his ilk.</p>
<p>There are serious, practical, reasonable, and masculine stage Green thinkers. As you would expect, since healthy stage Green doesn't negate stage Orange but transcends AND includes it. Healthy Green is built on a foundation of healthy Orange. What Green adds to Orange is empathy & a recognition of the importance of collective issues. While Orange believes all problems in society can be resolved through individualism and personal success, Green understands that this is necessary but insufficient. Collective responsibility is just as important. Green contrasts sharply with Blue in that it is able to appreciate the value of diversity & multiculturalism in a way that Blue is totally blind to. Green can look through the eyes of different cultures while Blue cannot. Green's masculinity is also more grounded, more comfortable with the feminine, whereas stage Blue & Orange masculinity tends to be a juvenile bravado which struggles to appreciate the feminine beyond child rearing and personal sexual gratification.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-wise-patriot-round-two</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Knock Down The House</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/knock-down-the-house</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A great documentary which gives you an inside look at how American politics works:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_wGZc8ZjFY4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>It's available on Netflix. I highly recommend watching it if you're interested in Conscious Politics.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/knock-down-the-house</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Life In Venezuela</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/life-in-venezuela</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>An eye-opening look into Venezuela's largest slum by an independent Youtuber:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jN5LZR4ejkg?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IYVkFcWqcIo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Note: Venezuela is not an example of the evils of socialism. It's an example of a grossly underdeveloped country. This is a distinction folks commonly fail to make. Socialism cannot work in an underdeveloped country because survival needs are simply too pressing so selfishness and corruption run rampant. Stage Red/Blue countries are not developed enough to sustain socialist ideals. Which is why socialism failed in places like the Soviet Union and North Korea but aspects of it have succeeded in Northern Europe. A totalitarian state which adopts a socialist veneer is still structurally a totalitarian state. The content of the ideology is irrelevant because what runs the show is the structure, which in this case is totalitarian. The reason aspects of socialism have succeeded in Northern Europe is because those states evolved way beyond totalitarianism before they started toying around with socialism.</p>
<p>Not that I consider myself a socialist. Just pointing out a common mistake I see in politics. People routinely misunderstand the causes of Venezuela's situation. Their problem is developmental and infrastructural, not ideological. Corruption is a massive problem which has choked up their entire system.</p>
<p>It's the same problem as a criminal trying to act like a spiritual man of God. It doesn't work because it's just a veneer. Structurally he's still a selfish, egotistical criminal. No amount godly language or godly ideals will change that. To embody spirituality he'd have to first outgrow his criminality. Likewise, adopting a socialist ideology in a totalitarian state only serves as an Orwellian disguise. In theory the state is for the people, but in practice it's every man for himself, looting as much wealth under the table as possible while maintaining the facade of selflessness.</p>
<p>So the lesson of the 20th century is not that socialism is evil but that socialism should not be adopted by underdeveloped countries at Stage Blue or below because they cannot sustain it. Socialism would only be possible at Stage Green or above. But even then, I still have critiques of socialism and I don't support its blanket adoption. Aspects of it need to be cherrypicked and hybridized with capitalism.</p>
<p>We see in China that socialism has also not been sustainable because China has not yet evolved past Stage Orange capitalism. So even though China puts on a veneer of socialism, structurally it's very capitalistic and also totalitarian because it cannot help itself. You can't shortcut structural development with a flowery ideology. If only it were so easy. Moralistic ideology is not growth! It's a fake front designed to say that no growth is necessary because it has already been actualized. It's the same problem as saying that you are a devout follower of God, yet you have never actually become conscious of what God is. Talking about God without first being conscious of God is idol worship. It will not make you godly because the structure of your consciousness is still dualistic.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/life-in-venezuela</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Most Corrupt Countries In The World</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-most-corrupt-countries-in-the-world</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's some really interesting research on corruption:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.transparency.org/news/feature/corruption_perceptions_index_2017" target="_blank">Corruption World Map</a></p>
<p>Corruption is basically a measure of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/collective-ego" target="_blank">Collective Ego</a>, or the consciousness level and the developmental level of a country. The less conscious a group of people are, the more corrupt their country is.</p>
<p>If you want to quantify which countries are the most evolved, don't measure their GDP, measure their corruption index. If you want to know whether a country is advancing forward or regressing backward, look to see if their corruption index is improving decade after decade.</p>
<p>You want to live in a country which has the least corruption. Unless you're a corrupt devil, in which case you want to exploit that corruption to benefit your survival.</p>
<p>A quick way to gauge whether a specific policy proposal is high consciousness or low consciousness is to ask the question: Does this reduce or increase corruption? You'd be amazed by how many laws, bills, and proposals actually increase corruption! This is by design. Corruption can't help but to spread itself.</p>
<p>If the corruption index of your country is below 50, then you're in a sketchy part of the world and development will be harder for you. Not impossible, just harder. Countries below 50 will have a lot of Spiral Dynamics <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Stage Blue</a> and countries below 40 will have a lot of Stage Red & Purple. Don't create a victim mentality about it. Do the best you can with the cards you've been dealt. And if you were born in a country with a corruption index above 50, consider yourself very lucky. You don't even understand how bad life can get. You have been totally spoiled. Be grateful and use this gift to make something of your life and uplift the world. Countries below 50 badly need help from the countries above 50. Be careful not to demonize countries below 50. They need your help, not your scorn.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-most-corrupt-countries-in-the-world</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Green New Deal Town Hall</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/green-new-deal-town-hall</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A substantive discussion of how to address climate change. An example of conscious politics happening in the real world.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yoFaQ9foV8I?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez is an amazing conscious politician, uncorrupted by corporate money.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/green-new-deal-town-hall</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Political Spiral Stages</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/political-spiral-stages</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Slide from my Conscious Politics - Part 2 video:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/political-spiral-01.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4305" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/political-spiral-01.png" alt="political-spiral-01" width="615" /></a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/political-spiral-stages</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Taste Of Infinity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-taste-of-infinity</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a small look into the mind of God:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zXTpASSd9xE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Contemplate: How is it possible to zoom into a thing forever? What does this mean about the nature of reality?</p>
<p>Just the fact that this fractal exists should already clue you in that consciousness must be infinite. Otherwise how could you be conscious of it? If an infinite object was loaded into a finite mind, the mind would crash. Hence the mind itself must be infinite.</p>
<p>Consider this: In a finite reality it would be impossible to count up from 1 to infinity. This is only possible because consciousness is actually infinite.</p>
<p>But how can the human mind be infinite? Because the human mind is a virtual machine running inside the infinite mind of God. God's mind is running an infinite number of virtual machines, all which are themselves infinite. That's what Georg Cantor called the Absolute Infinite set. It is the super-set of all possible sets. The mindblowing nature of infinity is that you can divide it into an infinite number of parts, and each of those parts will be its own infinity. Infinity within infinity within infinity — to infinity! In other words, infinity literally allows you to create something from nothing, because infinity is endless and bottomless.</p>
<p>Consider this: If you have an infinite number of apples in a basket, you can pull out one apple, eat it, and you will still have an infinite number of apples left. You just created an apple from nothing! Ta-da! This is how God creates the universe. Its mind is not bound by any physical limitation or lack. It cannot lack anything because it is an unlimited fount of creativity. All it has to do to create a thing is subdivide itself. But it can subdivide itself infinitely many times, so it never loses anything in the process of creation. Even after God subdivides itself an infinite number of times to create all human minds, it still remains an infinite Unity. The Absolute Unity of all possible divisions. Absolute Unity turns out to be identical to division. Going full-circle.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-taste-of-infinity</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Nazis Win Elections</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-nazis-win-elections</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you're a student of history you've probably wondered, "How in the hell did Hitler get democratically elected? It doesn't make sense that people would willing support a guy like that."</p>
<p>Well, this is how:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6qvB5tHRNOI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gu7n0_gVgTc?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Trumpism is a case study in demagoguery, collective self-deception, group think, cult psychology, ideology, egotism, devilry, ignorance, unconsciousness, selfishness, division, projection, scapegoating, demonization, judgment, denial, self-bias, confirmation bias, corruption, xenophobia, racism, and fear.</p>
<p>All the epistemic stuff we cover in-depth on Actualized.org all comes together in the real world like this.</p>
<p>A toxic brew of the most pathological aspects of Spiral Dynamics stage Red, Blue, and Orange.</p>
<p>You might wonder, But why do people eat it up? Because they are at those same levels of development/consciousness themselves. Birds of a feather flock together. Your politics directly correlates with your values, which correlates with your stage of ego development. You can only vote for a leader as high as your vision can see. So egotistical, ethnocentric people gladly vote for egotistical, ethnocentric leaders, especially when the leader pushes their fear buttons.</p>
<p>Watch out, the 2020 election is going to get very nasty. Trump's demagoguery will hit an all time high as his ego gets cornered by his own manipulations. One of the hallmarks of a giant ego is that it refuses to yield or admit wrong-doing or defeat. When Trump loses, he will have to deny it to himself and his supporters somehow. And there begins the heavy-duty devilry. There will likely be blood.</p>
<p>This is what happens when a dense ego is put into a position of power. It's not an issue of left vs right, the issue is density of ego.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-nazis-win-elections</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Highest Purpose</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-highest-purpose</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Pasting this from my personal journal:</p>
<p>My highest purpose is to lead people to Infinite Consciousness, Infinite Love, Infinite Selflessness, and Infinite Understanding. I am to show people what the highest form of leadership looks like. My entire life is dedicated to this cause. I am to lead people to the realization of Infinite Love and Infinite Beauty by embodiment and demonstration of Infinite Love in my own life. I am a vehicle for God's highest Love for mankind. The function of my human existence is to demonstrate the Goodness and Magnitude of God to those who lack the vision to see it. I am to use the gift of my extraordinary human mind to communicate God's highest intentions. I am not to hold back my love out of fear or selfish need. I am to be fearless and selfless and endure any consequences and suffering which will arise from such a path. The endurance of these obstacles and pain is part of my purification process. The suffering I endure will only make me more loving and understanding of the suffering of others, who are none other than myself. I am to shed all ill-will, malice, and judgment towards others, for I cannot help but see them as myself. In the end, the love and selflessness I radiate will inspire and transform the world. My reward will be the love I radiate and Infinite Understanding of the universe. My understanding will reach superhuman levels beyond all human comprehension or and strain the human self to contain. There is no doubt that this my way. I will have many critics and naysayers, but none of them will deter me because all of them I will be overcome simply by radiating more love because I understand that their ignorance is their limited way of showing their love. I understand that all hatred, judgment, and violence is just a condensed form of love. Through total self-understanding I will become incapable of seeing wrong or evil, even in those who seek to harm me. By the end of my human life the highest potential of a human life will have been actualized. The details of how all of this unfolds will be unimportant, as it will simply unfold as it must. My body and mind is at the highest service of Universal Intelligence. The point of no return has already been reached so no further decision is necessary. All of this is self-evidently true. When I lose track of my highest purpose (and I will) I am to return here and re-read this statement, re-grounding myself in that which is undeniable.</p>
<p>Actualized 2.0 is coming. Brace yourself for a sledgehammer of Love.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-highest-purpose</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 9 Stages Of Ego Development</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-9-stages-of-ego-development</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This 97-page research paper by Susanne Cook-Greuter is one of the most important things you can read if you want to understand human development:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cook-greuter.com/Cook-Greuter%209%20levels%20paper%20new%201.1'14%2097p%5B1%5D.pdf" target="_blank">Nine Levels Of Increasing Embrace In Ego Development</a></p>
<p>I recommend you download it, print it out, and read it methodically with a highlighter. It's filled with insights and wisdom you won't find anywhere else.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cook-greuter.com/" target="_blank">Cook-Greuter</a> is a Harvard educated yet independent developmental psychologist. So this research has some scientific weight behind it, based on empirical research.</p>
<p>This will take your understanding of developmental psychology & Spiral Dynamics to the next level.</p>
<p>It also dovetails with my discussion of Conscious Politics, since the quality of one's politics directly depends on the development of one's ego.</p>
<p>We will be talking a lot more about developmental psychology in the future. So this is required reading for that. Spiral Dynamics is only one part of the larger field of developmental psychology.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-9-stages-of-ego-development</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Infinite Love Awakening</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-love-awakening</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/347395943?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-love-awakening</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Government Really Works</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-government-really-works</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a little taste of the brutality and sneakiness of government. This is the dirty business of creating a society:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BT254smRufA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Russia is a Spiral Dynamics Stage Red government. It's government by mafia rule. Be careful not to judge it too much because your government had to go through this stage of development before it evolved higher. You don't get a high functioning democracy without a lot of theft, beatings, torture, slit throats, bullets to the head, and rape.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-government-really-works</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Fractal Of Life</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-fractal-of-life</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w77zPAtVTuI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Contemplate why this is happening. What is this about? Why expansion? Why branching? Why life? What is the universe up to?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-fractal-of-life</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Zooming Into God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/zooming-into-god</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I find microscope pictures more awe-inspiring than cosmic pictures. Remember, reality zooms to infinity in both directions. And actually there are more than two directions and more than 3 dimensions. But for now, study closely the intelligence behind the design of the microscopic world:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j6B-HYsvkvo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LE2v3sUzTH4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Consciousness is an infinite fractal of pure intelligence. This is what you're really waking up to. This is what you are.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/zooming-into-god</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>4000 Exo-Planets Found</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/4000-exo-planets-found</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The first extra-solar planet was discovered in 1992. Up to now 4000 have been discovered.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aiFD_LBx2nM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>There are approximately 250 billion stars in 1 galaxy.</p>
<p>There are approximately 2 trillion galaxies in our universe.</p>
<p>If there are an average of 3 planets per star, that means there are 1,500,000,000,000,000,000,000,000 planets in our universe.</p>
<p>But all of that is just but an infinitesimally small speck of dust within Infinite Consciousness. All those planets are as far away from infinity as the number 3.</p>
<p>It takes Infinite Consciousness less than a nanosecond to dream all that up.</p>
<p>It has no beginning or end. It goes on forever. It is unlimited.</p>
<p>Imagine holding all of that form within your consciousness.</p>
<p>Try to comprehend that. That is the mind of God.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/4000-exo-planets-found</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tapping Into Collective Consciousness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/tapping-into-collective-consciousness</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/346781327?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/tapping-into-collective-consciousness</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vice's Liberal vs Conservative Panels</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/vices-liberal-vs-conservative-panels</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Vice has some excellent discussion panels featuring diverse political and cultural perspectives.</p>
<p>The panels struck me as highly valuable because they require you to open your mind to alternative POVs. As you watch, pay extra attention to how you get triggered and how you judge these people. This is not about determining who's right or wrong but about going meta to see the relativity of all perspectives. Relativity is what explains why these folks see the world so differently. It's not that ones are right and others are wrong, but that each ego-mind sees the world according to its survival needs and whatever ideologies it was programmed with during its development.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WMvih_KEMWo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>That's just a taste, there's much more and I recommend you watch them all:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IVIoC5ROaHk" target="_blank">Black Conservatives Debate Black Liberals</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=utW1ItcMeJw" target="_blank">LGBTQ+ Conservatives Debate Liberals - Part 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=safLwed9SSo" target="_blank">LGBTQ+ Conservatives Debate Liberals - Part 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9I6b1JEb2k" target="_blank">Latino Conservatives Debate Liberals - Part 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fyymEC8FQHU" target="_blank">Latino Conservatives Debate Liberals - Part 2</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Really, really, really pay attention to how you judge POVs which are not your own. Also notice how you judge people purely based on their race, gender, clothing, religion, and style of speaking. The point is to notice that you are extremely judgmental and dismissive of any worldview which is not aligned with your own. Notice that alternative POVs are a threat to you — notice how you fear them.</p>
<p>These panels make for a good consciousness litmus test. The more developed and conscious you are, the more you are able hear all these diverse perspectives without judging them, recognizing them to be aspects of yourself.</p>
<p>Note: non-judgment does not mean that you adopt their opinions, nor does it mean that you adopt the average of all their opinions. Both would be a mistake.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/vices-liberal-vs-conservative-panels</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Do I Doubt Myself?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/do-i-doubt-myself</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/346519383?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/do-i-doubt-myself</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Cult Of Andrew Cohen</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-cult-of-andrew-cohen</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to share this video in the hopes that it will inoculate some of you against joining or starting enlightenment cults.</p>
<p>The key point: Just because the leader of a spiritual group has some degree of awakening does not mean it's not a cult! Many cults weave together legit spiritual teachings with devilry. Think twice before joining any spiritual community.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X3ess8txBX0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>For more about cults, see my two part series:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/cult-psychology-part-1" target="_blank">Cult Psychology - Part 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/cult-psychology-part-2" target="_blank">Cult Psychology - Part 2</a></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-cult-of-andrew-cohen</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Wise Patriot</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-wise-patriot</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I randomly stumbled upon this southern military guy on Youtube and was pleasantly surprised by his progressive thinking! It's great to see some military folk and southern folk speaking out against the dangers of modern conservativism. This is what I call smart patriotism.</p>
<p>This dude's dishing out some serious common sense. Check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/unvoicedproject/videos" target="_blank">his channel</a> for more gems. Although I disagree with his deeper advocacy of anarchism. Anarchism cannot work at the scale of 100s of millions of people.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CGeKdAWnnxc?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/APoQuX5M2P4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-wise-patriot</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Smart Patriot</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-smart-patriot</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I randomly stumbled upon this southern military guy on Youtube and was pleasantly surprised by his progressive thinking! It's great to see some military folk and southern folk speaking out against the dangers of modern conservativism. This is what I call smart patriotism.</p>
<p>This dude's dishing out some serious common sense. Check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/unvoicedproject/videos" target="_blank">his channel</a> for more gems.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CGeKdAWnnxc?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/APoQuX5M2P4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-smart-patriot</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>New York Post UFO Series</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/new-york-post-ufo-series</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>It's ironic that the New York Post — a trashy, gossipy, right-wing tabloid said to be a favorite newspaper of Donald Trump — would be capable of producing a high-quality, well-researched mini-series about UFOs.</p>
<p>But here it is! Sometimes you find a diamond in a pile of shit. This series is well done and worth watching with an open mind.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uaSY2Zc0goQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>There are many episodes in the series:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z25NfZ0Ea9c" target="_blank">Episode 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tDUF4NtYtxU" target="_blank">Episode 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=656VqWTnKmw" target="_blank">Episode 4</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gy5tIevquP0" target="_blank">Episode 5</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IaYfsxbiKsM" target="_blank">Episode 6</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And they are still releasing new episodes each week, so stay tuned.</p>
<p>As always, think critically for yourself about this controversial topic. I am not suggesting you construct a UFO ideology but rather consider the empirical evidence in an openminded fashion. You don't know what you don't know. I find the mountains of evidence hard to explain away as mere delusion or fantasy. Something weird is going on.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/new-york-post-ufo-series</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Power Of Imaginary Boundaries</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-power-of-imaginary-boundaries</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>One of our biggest themes with Actualized.org is understanding how the human mind, (and all of reality), creates boundaries. Notice that all of life runs on division, partition, distinction, and duality. Even at the most basic thermodynamic level, energy moves across difference gradients. No difference gradient, no movement, no life.</p>
<p>But it's not enough to understand this in the abstract. We must go deeper, examining concrete instances of how this manifests across human life. Which is why I love the following video. It shows you in concrete terms how division, partition, distinction, and duality shape all human behaviors.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r5Ps1TZXAN8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>All boundaries are imaginary. But notice how these imaginary boundaries serve as the fuel or engine driving all of life! Notice the enormous consequences that a single imaginary boundary can have. Now multiply this by infinity and you get LIFE!</p>
<p>What is war, conflict, disagreement, and violence about at the existential level? It's fighting over boundary definitions. Who's imaginary boundary will prevail? Who gets to say how the cake should be sliced?</p>
<p>Do you see the big picture of life?</p>
<p>If you object that some boundaries are physical and not merely imaginary, notice that that itself is an imaginary boundary which you created and are now defending! Since reality is one giant Universal Mind, all boundaries, including "physical" boundaries, exist within its imagination. To imagine a thing is to create a boundary between that thing and that which it is not. That's what being a thing is! That's what imagination is! Universal Mind is creating differences, which constitutes reality, which animates life, which leads to conflict, which leads to destruction of differences — thus going full-circle forever and ever, without beginning or end.</p>
<p>Division leading to unification leading back to division. Division within division within division. Unification after unification after unification.</p>
<p>That which is separated must ultimately unite. That which is united must ultimately separate. And in between, life happens. Ta-da!</p>
<p>Here's another brilliant micro example of how this plays out in human life:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qBfyIQbxXPs?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-power-of-imaginary-boundaries</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mapping Consciousness With High Dose LSD</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/mapping-consciousness-with-high-dose-lsd</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is an exceptionally important video. Watch it from beginning to end.</p>
<p>It's an outstanding interview with an academically trained philosopher who took 70+ high doses of LSD over 20 years to explore the deepest reaches of Universal Mind.</p>
<p>His growth curve closely matches my own after 65+ psychedelic trips over the last 2 years. It's a journey into ever deeper layers of Universal Mind and Infinite Consciousness which seems to have no end. Every trip leads to deeper and deeper understanding and integration of Universal Mind.</p>
<p>This is what the psychedelic spiritual path looks like. It's rare to see someone talking about it because most people trip merely for recreation and in serious circles psychedelics are stigmatized. Few people turn psychedelics into a serious spiritual path, but I see that changing in the future as the stigma gradually erodes.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L3D_fSr75u8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/mapping-consciousness-with-high-dose-lsd</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sense Organs Are Imaginary</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/sense-organs-are-imaginary</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/344949738?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/sense-organs-are-imaginary</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reverse-Engineering UFO Spacecraft</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/reverse-engineering-ufo-spacecraft</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A damn fascinating interview by Joe Rogan:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BEWz4SXfyCQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Is it true?</p>
<p>I have no direct experience of UFOs, but Lazar's story seems highly plausible. There are just too many eye-witness accounts of UFOs at this point to deny their underlying reality. The skeptical position is more deluded than the thousands of eye-witness accounts.</p>
<p>Of course in the end, all aliens are just part of Infinite Consciousness. So it's really not a big deal. Realizing Infinite Consciousness is way more radical than reverse-engineering UFO spacecraft. Discovering aliens is peanuts compared to what you will discover at the moment of awakening: it's all imaginary! Dogs, cats, trees, people, aliens, Earth, history, science, the universe, birth, death, suffering, memories, your parents, etc. If you can experience it, you are imagining it.</p>
<p>The conspiracy is not that the government is hiding aliens from you. The real conspiracy is that you are imagining the government!</p>
<p>P.S. You should also distinguish UFOs from DMT entities. These are not the same thing. UFOs are within the human physical dimension. DMT entities are in another dimension entirely.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/reverse-engineering-ufo-spacecraft</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>DPT: The Other God Molecule</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/dpt-the-other-god-molecule</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Could DPT be the world's most powerful nondual psychedelic? Even more powerful than 5-MeO-DMT?</p>
<p>It was for me!</p>
<p>Here's my DPT trip report:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/343774863?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Discussion taking place on the forum here: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/36240-discovered-new-psychedelic-more-powerful-than-5-meo-dmt/" target="_blank">The DPT Mega-Thread</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/dpt-the-other-god-molecule</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>3 Kinds Of Socialism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/3-kinds-of-socialism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Mainstream culture does a terrible job of informing people what socialism actually means. There's much fear-mongering and confusion surrounding this word. Professor Richard Wolff is great antidote to such ignorance.</p>
<p>With that said, please take a nuanced view of this issue. I am not posting this to convert you to socialism, but rather to get you thinking about the limits of capitalism. I have some important critiques of socialism, so it's not as simple as me favoring socialism over capitalism. And I don't agree with everything that Richard Wolff advances. But there is much to be learned from his presentations and I recommend you think about this topic critically yet openmindedly and come to your own conclusions.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p7x7oVwhHok?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>While I don't consider myself a socialist (I enjoy private ownership of my business), the limits of capitalism are simply undeniable at this point. We need to look towards the next evolution of our economy. That will not be pure capitalism nor pure socialism but some hybrid system. The question then becomes where to draw the lines. This requires a nuanced, non-ideological understanding of the pros and cons of both systems.</p>
<p>The point of upgrading our economic system is to allow as many people as possible to have the financial freedom to maximize the development of their consciousness. Our current economic system is so unfair and oppressive that most human beings on the planet are so deeply stuck in wage slavery that they are seriously hampered in their ability to develop their consciousness. And this ends up costing the entire human species.</p>
<p>The most important aspect of socialism which Richard Wolff talks about is democratizing the workplace. The core problem under our current system is that workers do not have any voting power or ownership share within the companies they work for. This effectively makes corporations dictatorships, with a few powerful elites dictating the corporation's actions, reaping all the rewards, and pocketing all the productivity gains from technological innovation. The stockholders of most corporations do not work in the corporation, creating a conflict between their agenda for max dividends and the needs of the people who do the actual daily work in the corporation. This then leads to gross wealth inequality across society as the rich get richer and richer beyond anything they reasonably need, while the vast majority struggle to survive. Since the workers have zero voting power they are easily exploited because their agenda rarely a concern for the all-powerful corporate dictators. These corporate dictatorships then turn into metastasizing cancers which become so powerful no individual can ever compete with them. These giant corporations create monopolies which eat up many opportunities for small independent entrepreneurs, leaving people with little choice but wage slavery.</p>
<p>Unfortunately the solution to this problem is not easy or clear. But we have no choice but to figure it out. And we cannot figure it out unless the population is properly educated about capitalism and socialism in a nuanced way.</p>
<p>P.S. Check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/democracyatwrk/videos" target="_blank">Richard Wolff's YouTube channel</a> for more.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/3-kinds-of-socialism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who Really Rules The World?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/who-really-rules-the-world</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZUGh1Su7-ok?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/who-really-rules-the-world</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who Are The Machine Elves?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/who-are-the-machine-elves</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Great video. But hold on to your hat. Radical openmindedness required.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yl38wIkeExs?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Note: meeting entities on a few grams of mushrooms as this guy describes is very rare. He is clearly an exceptional case. Ordinary folk will have much better luck with N,N-DMT.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/who-are-the-machine-elves</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 Fingered</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/6-fingered</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is nuts:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LlfPIKQmPok?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/6-fingered</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding Flatland</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-flatland</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a useful way of thinking for understanding relativity, points of view, paradigms, and the ultimate nature of reality. It's a good foundation for when you're tripping as it teaches you to think multi-dimensionally.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N0WjV6MmCyM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-flatland</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dissecting The Psychedelic Experience</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/dissecting-the-psychedelic-experience</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I don't necessarily agree with everything this guy says, but overall a great video:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tETZpw7sX98?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/dissecting-the-psychedelic-experience</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bernie Sanders Visionary</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/bernie-sanders-visionary</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is what outstanding, visionary leadership looks like:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nbN9OD83f5I?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Notice that visionary leadership is not meek or neutral. It is bold and decisive. It is not afraid to challenge cultural norms and call out devilry.</p>
<p>This is exactly what America and the world needs.</p>
<p>But of course the devils will not just standby and let a visionary do his thing. They will resist every step of the way out of selfishness, fear, ignorance, and closedmindedness.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/bernie-sanders-visionary</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Total Omniscience Awakening</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/total-omniscience-awakening</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/341701275?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/total-omniscience-awakening</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Catch Me If You Can</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/catch-me-if-you-can</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I like this talk by the real-life person from the movie, Catch Me If You Can.</p>
<p>Frank Abagnale's life of con-artistry is a perfect case-study in how survival and devilry work.</p>
<p>What's great about his story is that in the end he redeemed himself (if he is to be believed). He now works for the FBI helping catch devils like his former self.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vsMydMDi3rI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/catch-me-if-you-can</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>No Video This Week</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/no-video-this-week</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>No main video this week as I'm integrating a profound recent awakening.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/no-video-this-week</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Study Survival In Animals</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/study-survival-in-animals</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Observe survival strategies not just in yourself and in humans, but also in animals.</p>
<p>Notice how your life is, fundamentally, just another version of this:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fnP-m2KRxi0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The details of your life are totally different, but the basic structure is identical to that jerboa. You're just a big jerboa trying to survive in 21st century society. That's your whole life in a nutshell.</p>
<p>Ta-da! ;)</p>
<p>P.S. Also notice how utterly intelligent survival is! It is intelligence of the highest order.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/study-survival-in-animals</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thoughts On Unconditional Love</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/thoughts-on-unconditional-love</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is an entry from my private journal which I wrote to myself. It shows my thought process in coming to grips with advanced spiritual truths:</p>
<p>Why can't I love unconditionally? Why don't humans love unconditionally? Because we have survival requirements. Because I am a specific way, I am predisposed to love certain things more than others. Of course I am going to love something which suits me more than I will love something which doesn't. Of course I will love a calm, smart, pretty child more than I will love a noisy, angry, ugly, crippled child. Because these things materially affect me. As a human I don't have God's infinite freedom and invulnerability. It's easy for the Godhead to love unconditionally because it is formless! It cannot lose anything. It cannot be harmed or annoyed. So is truly unconditional love possible for humans? Even enlightened humans? Seems unlikely. Unconditional love would only be possible with total selflessness. You'd have to really not care any more about living, dying, or enduring all sorts of hardship, suffering, and annoyance. To set up the ideal that I must always be unconditionally love could easily become a recipe for unhappiness and misery, as I will always fail to live up to such an impossible ideal. Then again, maybe unconditional love really is possible. But even if it is, it is certainly not something I can will or act my way into. It would have to come as an organic byproduct of deep awakening, higher states of consciousness, purification of the chakras, total surrender of the ego, and transcendence of self. Unconditional love would only be possible at the moment of total God-realization. The realization would have to be so total that there would be zero difference between myself and God, not just as a knowing, and not just temporarily as a peak experience, but as it is embodied day to day, minute to minute. Has any human ever attained such a degree of God-realization? I don't know. If they have, it would be a remarkable feat and I'm not sure how realistic it is to try to replicate it. It's certainly not something that the average spiritual seeker can do. I'm not sure if I could do it. You would have to completely renounce your entire life to reach this level of realization. It would have to be the only thing your life is about. I do not see that most monks or yogis have this level of God-realization in practice. Perhaps a few do, but this tells you just how difficult it is and why such people would be worshiped as Gods if they did exist — they literally are Gods at this point. You would be worshiped as God, but you would be so selfless at this point that you would not care at all for the praise. An interesting paradox. Half the world would worship you and love for your saintly self-sacrifice and half the world would hate you because your demonstration of such a radical degree of love would deeply threaten their egos. And you wouldn't care which was which because you would love both types equally. As a result, you would likely be killed by someone in the mob. And you still would not care. Which would only make your followers worship you even more after your death and create a religion which deluded others into worshiping you rather than realizing God as themselves.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/thoughts-on-unconditional-love</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Realizing What Is God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/realizing-what-is-god</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This will be the look on your face when you finally realize what God is:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4233" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/cat-shock.gif" alt="cat-shock" width="330" height="312" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/realizing-what-is-god</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Realizing You Are God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/realizing-you-are-god</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>What it's like when you realize you are God:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4233" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/cat-shock.gif" alt="cat-shock" width="330" height="312" /></p>
<p>;)</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/realizing-you-are-god</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Denver Decriminalizes Mushrooms</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/denver-decriminalizes-mushrooms</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/5/8/18535475/denver-psilocybin-psychedelic-magic-mushrooms-decriminalization-vote" target="_blank">Denver Successfully Decriminalizes Mushrooms</a></p>
<p>Horray! A small step for mankind.</p>
<p>This is exciting and groundbreaking news, as in the history books it will go down as the first domino to fall in our effort towards full nationwide decriminalization of psychedelics.</p>
<p>In truth, decriminalization of psychedelics is still not good enough. The US Constitution must have an Amendment which explicitly guarantees the right to explores one's own consciousness via any means that does not harm others.</p>
<p>This is of course on top of the already existing Constitutional clauses which guarantee free exercise of religion, which of course includes psychedelics (but is not yet acknowledged).</p>
<p>But we'll take this for now.</p>
<p>Oregon and California are working to pass legalization of mushrooms in 2020. A victory in Oregon would be a huge breakthrough, and it now seems doable.</p>
<p>Please donate to the <a href="https://psi-2020.org/" target="_blank">Oregon 2020 Psilocybin Ballot Initiative</a> to ensure it passes. If it does, that will be huge leap forward. It will also help many people suffering from depression, addiction, PTSD, anxiety, terminal illnesses, etc. Check out their video page for more details.</p>
<p>And here's another good initiative you can donate to if you're passionate about this cause: <a href="https://heffter.org/" target="_blank">The Heffter Research Institute</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/denver-decriminalizes-mushrooms</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Elite Universities Are A Scam</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/elite-universities-are-a-scam</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Most people in society are in denial about the scam that is elite university education (and to some extent, university education in general).</p>
<p>Read this article: <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/2019/5/1/18311548/college-admissions-secrets-myths" target="_blank">Former Admissions Dean Spills The Dirt On Elite College Admissions</a></p>
<p>And that's just the tip of the iceberg of the kind of devilry that goes on behind the scenes of these elite universities. Do not trust them for a second!</p>
<p>Universities are not your friend. They are businesses, collective egos, bureaucracies, and cultural constructions, first and foremost. It is a big mistake to equate university education, rank, or credentials with any sign of truth, goodness, wisdom, intelligence, consciousness, self-awareness, or level of development.</p>
<p>The wisest humans are not to be found in universities because universities do not prioritize truth, wisdom, love, or consciousness. Elite universities are playing games of status, money, and politics, and the worst thing about it is, the biggest con they pull is convincing high school students that they are somehow important and to be valued. It's never even told to high school students that they can provide themselves with a much better education than any university ever could, and at a tiny fraction of the cost. High school students just automatically buy into the lie that elite universities are somehow important and desirable.</p>
<p>Universities indoctrinate. They do not teach truly original thinking or human growth. And as the devil tends to do, they call themselves the bastions of truth. Then they act outraged if you question their authority or their well-credentialed professors. Ha! What a load of horse shit! A credential is just a piece of paper that a group of devils wrote to themselves to convince themselves that they are not devils but angels.</p>
<p>The whole point of getting an elite university degree is so that your survival in life becomes much easier thanks to the status it confers — you get access to the best job opportunities and positions of power — so you don't then actually have to work hard on becoming a conscious human being or doing original creative high-value work that stands on its own merit. An elite university allows you to use the power of social status to increase your survival odds. That's what it's really about, and any honest university would admit it. But of course the devil has to hide and deny his devilry in order for it to keep working. Teens who apply to these universities do not understand any of this. They are just cogs in the unconscious machine. Just like their parents were. They are under the illusion that these universities are somehow the ticket to heaven when really they're a ticket to hell! You know what they say, an abused child becomes an abusive parent. And so the cycle continues, the cogs keep spinning around in circles.</p>
<p>And all this is not to even mention the scam which is the college loan system. From a certain perspective a modern university is just a clever invention for saddling a new human being with $100,000 in debt without that human realizing what just happened. That is the lifeblood of the whole system! Universities are like a vampire that feeds off wage slaves. The real devilry comes in convincing children to join this system eagerly. You could call our entire education system long-time-horizon child abuse: grades, homework, standardized testing, SAT prep, AP testing, college admissions, student loans, credentials, diplomas, fraternities, sororities, college athletics — all that. It's all a socially constructed scam; a house of cards held together with bullshit. By the time a human being goes through 12 + 4 years of that, she is a domesticated animal. It's just a more sophisticated version of religion. A religion masquerading as science and rationality. No wonder there is no God or Truth found there. You cannot institutionalize Truth.</p>
<p>The bottom line is, an elite university education will actually hinder your ability to become the best human being you could be. Take responsibility for your own education. The only one who can properly educate you is yourself.</p>
<p>And yet, despite having said all the above, a university education is still far better than no education at all, or some kind of parochial education. So in a twisted sense we need this devil to save us from the yet greater devil of uneducatedness and right-wing ideology.</p>
<p>P.S. Do not confuse my critique of universities for right-wing critiques of universities. Universities can be critiqued from above or from below. My critique is from above. Right-wing critiques — based on a knee-jerk reaction against liberal values, multi-culturalism, relativism, and post-modernism — are from below. The paradox is that American society would be far better off if we made all public universities totally free to everyone, doubled their annual budgets, and cancelled all student debt. This would also have the benefit of devaluing elite private universities and reduce the need to jump through hoops for scholarships.</p>
<p>Our education system is thoroughly corrupt and badly in need of reform and massive funding. Of course it's just as you should expect. The first thing on the devil's agenda is to seize and corrupt all wellsprings of truth, turning them into founts of devilry. Topmost on the devil's agenda is to break all the lights, break all the mirrors, and multiply himself in the shade.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/elite-universities-are-a-scam</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scientists Find Hallucinogen Shaman Pouch</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/scientists-find-hallucinogen-shaman-pouch</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have recently discovered a 1000 year old shaman pouch in the Andes mountains containing various hallucinogenic plants and snorting utensils.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-pouch-reveals-hallucinogen-stash-andes-shaman" target="_blank">Read the full article</a></p>
<p>The real question is, why doesn't everyone have such a pouch 1000 years later?</p>
<p>Where is your shaman pouch?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/scientists-find-hallucinogen-shaman-pouch</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ayn Rand's Stage Orange Witchdoctory</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/ayn-rands-stage-orange-witchdoctory</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"While scientists were performing astounding feats of disciplined reason [during the Enlightenment], breaking down the barriers of the 'unknowable' in every field of knowledge, charting the course of light rays in space or the course of blood in the capillaries of man’s body — what philosophy was offering them, as interpretation of and guidance for their achievements was the plain Witchdoctory of Hegel, who proclaimed that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">matter does not exist at all</span>, that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">everything is Idea</span> (<span style="text-decoration: underline;">not somebody’s idea, just <i>Idea</i></span>), and that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">this Idea operates by the dialectical process</span> of a new '<span style="text-decoration: underline;">super-logic</span>' which proves that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">contradictions are the law of reality</span>, that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">A is non-A</span>, and that omniscience about the physical universe (including electricity, gravitation, the solar system, etc.) is to be derived, not from the observation of facts, but from the <span style="text-decoration: underline;">contemplation of that Idea</span>’s triple somersaults inside his, Hegel’s, mind. This was offered as a philosophy of reason."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayn_Rand" target="_blank">Ayn Rand</a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And she was precisely wrong!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">It takes skill and effort to be this wrong. The skill of a <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/what-is-the-devil" target="_blank">devil</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-orange" target="_blank">Stage Orange</a> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Materialism" target="_blank">materialism</a>/<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rationalism" target="_blank">rationalism</a> underestimates <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Idealism" target="_blank">idealism</a>/<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mysticism" target="_blank">mysticism</a> by assuming it to be philosophical mental-masturbation with no real-world consequences, when of course the truth is that materialism/rationalism is itself thoroughly deluded because it fails to take into account higher states of consciousness, which, if achieved, will erase the illusion of a material or rational world altogether.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Here Ayn Rand demonstrates the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bH5Qn6K36Ug" target="_blank">pre/trans fallacy</a>: confusing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Georg_Wilhelm_Friedrich_Hegel" target="_blank">Hegel</a>'s trans-rational explanations of the Absolute with pre-rational myth, fundamentalist religion, and soft thinking. In truth, Ayn Rand's dualistic logic was closer to myth than Hegel's.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The great irony is that materialism and rationalism turn out to be Witchdoctory — the very thing they accused philosophy and religion of being! Such is the counter-intuitive nature of the mind. To a devil like Ayn Rand, black is white, up is down, light is dark, and Absolute Truth is fiction. I've noticed that people who make vehement appeal to "reason" (like Ayn Rand or Sam Harris) turn out to be some of the greatest devils because they assume that reason is somehow a guarantor of truth, when in fact reason does the bidding of the ego. You cannot get to Absolute Truth through reason. Which totally shocks stage Orange rationalists, because they always held in blind faith that you could. A rationalist is just someone who replaces fundamentalist religious faith in the inerrancy of The Bible or Koran with a fundamentalist faith in the inerrancy of reason.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Hegel was a spiritual genius. He was the Western/German version of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nagarjuna" target="_blank">Nagarjuna</a> or The Buddha. But his words fell on deaf ears and got confined to history books or philosophy lectures.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Interestingly, when you start to research Western intellectual tradition you find a strong thread of idealism running all throughout which few Westerners today know about or take seriously. This gives a false impression that the West has always been materialist and anti-mystical, and that science has always been a materialist enterprise. Not true. This is an artificial narrative constructed by materialists to relieve themselves of the responsibility of taking idealist notions seriously. Many of the West's greatest scientists, thinkers, and visionaires were idealists, and for good reason. Because the more intelligent you become, the more idealism becomes unavoidable. Realist scientists and thinkers are 2nd rate intellects. They are good at technical analysis but they lack the holistic visionary aspect of the intellect, which is the most important aspect.</p>
<p>The intellect has two functions: analysis and synthesis, or division and unification. The intellect can be used to carve up reality or stitch it together. Modern academic and Western intellectual culture is overly biased towards analysis at the expense of synthesis, vision-logic, unification, and big picture thinking. Our schools teach kids how to carve up reality but not how to stitch it together. As a result our science and our society is overly-autistic and disconnected from our humanity and our divinity. Modern science lacks heart and vision. Which doesn't mean that science is bad or all-wrong, it just means that modern science is highly partial, and that there is a higher version of science yet to be actualized. Science and reason are not to be abandoned but expanded.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/ayn-rands-stage-orange-witchdoctory</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Case Study</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/spiral-dynamics-case-study</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a beautiful video demonstrating the difference in worldview and reality of stage <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Blue</a> vs <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-orange" target="_blank">Orange</a>/<a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-green" target="_blank">Green</a>.</p>
<p>Here's Orange/Green reacting against stage Blue.</p>
<p>Notice that Orange/Green simply cannot understand the stage Blue worldview because it's biased by an unquestioned certainty in the materialist paradigm. What stage Orange/Green does not understand is that there is no such thing as objective reality, "facts", "truth", or "sanity".</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ruh0RqzHmC0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Stage Blue vs Orange/Green are literally inhabiting different realities which their minds are constructing. But since they do not understand that their mind constructs reality, they assume that their reality is the one "true" reality while the other side is literally insane. This notion of insanity plays a pivotal function in their worldview because they need some way of explaining away the otherwise without actually investigating it. By calling the other side "insane" it automatically absolves you from having to seriously question your notion of "real".</p>
<p>What needs to be realized is that however you think reality is, you're making that up! "No Leo, I'm not making it up. You're crazy!" << You just made that up! Lol. See? Your metaphysical assumptions become your reality, no matter how crazy, unreasonable, or false they are. So if you believe there is an objective external reality, that becomes your reality. But it is not true in any absolute sense. Your mind is making reality up as you go along. Including, of course, the denial that you do so.</p>
<p>There actually is no firm boundary between a crazy worldview and a reasonable one. That duality collapses upon deep examination.</p>
<p>Without deeply understanding this you will never understand what reality is, how it works, or why humans behave as they do. For you there will always be stuff that happens in the world which seems totally batshit crazy. But it only appears that way from your POV because your worldview is inadequate at accounting for other worldviews. As a rule of thumb, any time you see something crazy happening in the world, that's a clue that you don't understand it deeply enough. The mind uses the judgment "that's crazy" as a cop-out.</p>
<p>With all that said, some people are exceptionally deluded.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/spiral-dynamics-case-study</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #015</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-15</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">"The path into the light seems dark,<br />
the path forward seems to go back,<br />
the direct path seems long,<br />
true power seems weak,<br />
true purity seems tarnished,<br />
true steadfastness seems changeable,<br />
true clarity seems obscure,<br />
the greatest art seems unsophisticated,<br />
the greatest love seems indifferent,<br />
the greatest wisdom seems childish.</p>
<p>The Tao is nowhere to be found.<br />
Yet it nourishes and completes all things."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Lao Tzu, Tao Te Ching</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-15</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fat Leo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/fat-leo</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Folks have been asking me to release a photo of when I used to be fat. Some even accused me of making up the story that I used to be fat. Well, I was in fact fat from about age 9 to age 21.</p>
<p>I didn't have fat photos of myself because: 1) Back then there were no cell phones or selfie pics, 2) I didn't like taking photos of myself when I was fat.</p>
<p>But anyhow, I finally found an old photo at my Mom's house. So here you go:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4203" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/leo-pic-01.png" alt="leo-pic-01" width="604" height="842" /></p>
<p>235 lbs at 6'2". 20 years old. About one year after this photo was taken I lost 65 pounds in 5 months, dropping to 170 lbs. I've kept it off ever since. Right now I'm at 180 lbs.</p>
<p>This was accomplished through diet changes & lots of gym exercise, including cardio and weights. I worked out 5 days a week for about 10 years. For the past 2 years I have not worked out at all and still keep the weight off because my diet is about 10x cleaner than it used to be, such that exercise for purposes of weight-maintenance is unnecessary. But exercise is still good for health of course.</p>
<p>Big change is possible if you set your mind on it. The most important aspects of accomplishing a change like this are: 1) vision, 2) discipline, and 3) focus.</p>
<p>Because my videos are so abstract and metaphysical sometimes people overlook the meat of this work. Personal development is very practical stuff with very tangible results. Don't let the abstract explanations fool you. You must also be results-oriented. Get shit done by whatever means necessary. Claw your way up <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/using-maslows-hierarchy-of-needs-to-self-actualize" target="_blank">Maslow's Hierarchy</a>. If you're new to personal development you need to dial in the basics like health, diet, career, finances, living environment, family situation, dating, etc. Don't get so metaphysical that you neglect all that. You will find awakening impossible if you can't even stop eating junk food or can't earn enough to pay your rent.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/fat-leo</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>So Are You Chinese Or Japanese?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/so-are-you-chinese-or-japanese</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a perfect little example of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/understanding-duality-part-1" target="_blank">dualistic thinking</a>:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d_CaZ4EAexQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This kind of thinking is extremely common at <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue</a>. But watch out! — dualistic thinking is still present in spades at higher stages. It's not just rednecks who think in this black-and-white way. You do it every day! Don't fool yourself into thinking you're above dualistic thinking. Dualistic thinking can be very subtle and it affects even the most rational and scientific thinkers. Rationality and science are chock full of dualities.</p>
<p>There's more to reality than the simplistic categories your mind creates.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/so-are-you-chinese-or-japanese</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Cameron On Ecological Awareness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/james-cameron-on-ecological-awareness</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a really intelligent and self-aware perspective on ecology & environment. It's a stage Yellow perspective. Notice the nuance and complexity of it. It balances science, business, art, and compassion, transcending AND including stages Orange and Green. Notice the lack of blaming problems on someone else. Notice the attitude of meeting people where they're at. Notice how science & spirituality/religion are not pitted against each other. It's a cooperation of left and right brain, mind & heart. Notice the systems thinking.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wRdCrIGt5dk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Love it! Try to adopt this kind of attitude in your life.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/james-cameron-on-ecological-awareness</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Cameron On Life Purpose</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/james-cameron-on-life-purpose</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a great role-model for those of you looking to actualize your life purpose:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WH0CqAmfwRQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PVfd6fg7QsM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>He's really nailed his purpose.</p>
<p>Notice how unique and personal one's life purpose becomes when you start to fully actualize it.</p>
<p>Find more such role-models within your domain of mastery.</p>
<p>Take my <a href="https://www.actualized.org/life-purpose-course" target="_blank">Life Purpose Course</a> for a step-by-step guide for finding your life purpose.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/james-cameron-on-life-purpose</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quintessence: The 5th Element</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/quintessence-the-5th-element</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Classically, the 4 elements were Air, Water, Fire, and Earth. The 5th element — which few people know about — was called the quintessence (literally, "the 5th essence") or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aether_(classical_element)" target="_blank">Aether</a> — otherwise known as Nothingness or Emptiness or Void.</p>
<p>In science, Aether was known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luminiferous_aether" target="_blank">luminiferous ether</a>, the medium through which light and gravity waves were supposed to have propagated. In the early 20th century physicists like Einstein and others "debunked" the notion of ether by reasoning that light waves did not need a medium to propagate through. They ran various experiments trying to measure the existence of ether but nothing turned up, so they discarded the notion as superfluous. Except Aether is not superfluous, it is central! What the scientists did not understand, and still do not understand, is that Aether wasn't a measurable medium like water, air, or even space — it is Nothing! This is not the same as saying that Aether does not exist. Aether exists as Nothing, the Groundless Ground, or pure Existence itself — existence devoid of any content. Don't bother trying to measure it because you can't. Existence is prior to measurement. The medium for the propagation of light waves and gravity waves (and anything else for that matter) is consciousness. And also don't confuse Aether/Nothingness with the vacuum of space. Aether is prior to space or time. It "holds" space and time.</p>
<p>What people don't understand is that quintessence is not just Nothingness, it is not just Existence, it is also Consciousness, Truth, God, Love, Goodness, Intelligence, Self, Other, and World!</p>
<p>But how can Love be Nothingness? How could it not! Only Nothingness has the capacity to embrace all. Only Nothingness is selfless enough to embrace all. Only no-thing can unconditionally accept every-thing. The embrace is so complete that Nothingness literally IS everything! This is pure, Platonic Love. Not just love as an emotion (although it is that too), but love as Being itself. Love is the union of all opposites into one seamless totality. Love is the unification of all divisions. Love is the super-set of all sub-sets. Love is universality. Love is infinity. Love is unlimited.</p>
<p>The 5th Element got their metaphysics exactly right:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6a0Q0rfbUVI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>After all is said and done, in the final analysis, the force that saves the world is none other than the force that makes the world: Love.</p>
<p>You ARE quintessence. You ARE Love.</p>
<p>Your ability to unify all opposites, all dualities, is the measure of your love. It is Unity as an Absolute. A Unity so all-embracing it has no opposite. A nonduality so nondual it doesn't know duality. A Love so complete it does not know judgment, criticism, rejection, hatred, selfishness, or evil. Yet at the same time it embraces them all by being them all. Human love is a tiny branch off the tree of universal Love. This tree is infinite, with countless branches of varying size. You are one branch AND you are the entire tree. To actualize one branch is to be human. To actualize the entire tree is to be God. Each branch is not other than the tree, such that all there is, is tree. What it means to be a tree is to be each branch and the sum total of them all at once. To realize this totality is Truth and Love.</p>
<p>Notice, when you feel an emotion of deep love, what you're feeling is not an egoic desire but a selflessness and a deep unity with the universe. In that moment you are being selfless, and it feels right and good. It feels divine.</p>
<p>So how do you conquer evil? By experiencing yourself as Love. Just like in the clip above. It sounds childish, until you try to do it and you quickly see just how hard it is for your ego to do. It is the mark of a masterful sage to be able to embrace all. You can't do it because you have too much evil in you. All-encompassing Love threatens you like light threatens a shadow. You can't do it because you are too busy defending your self while Love is self-less-ness. Love is also fearlessness. If there is no self, there is nothing to lose, and nothing to fear.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"A coward is incapable of exhibiting love; it is the prerogative of the brave."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— Mahatma Gandhi</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/quintessence-the-5th-element</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;I Cannot Self-Terminate&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/i-cannot-self-terminate</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Terminator 2 is — in my opinion — one of the greatest films of all time.</p>
<p>Ever since I was a kid the final scene always moved me:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DEMICfWLOig?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>It's such a brilliant final scene, filled with spiritual significance.</p>
<p>Now I understand why I liked it so much. It represents the hardest things for an ego to do: self-terminate. It represents the stark brutality of total selflessness.</p>
<p>How do you ask a self to self-terminate?</p>
<p>You see? That is why this work is hard.</p>
<p>"Be melting snow. Wash yourself of yourself." — Rumi</p>
<p>WARNING: Do not confuse self-termination with suicide. I am talking about spiritual self-termination. Suicide is just more ego.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/i-cannot-self-terminate</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Joy Of Creation</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-joy-of-creation</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>It took some gamer-nerd 300 hours to build this epic roller coaster. When I saw it, it reminded me of God's infinite creative potential — of how life and reality just goes on and on and on like an endless roller coaster.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/afhBFffMvZU?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>You might wonder, "So what? Why would someone waste 300 hours creating this silly thing? What the point?" The point is CREATION itself! God likes to create amazing stuff just for the hell of it. When you have infinite creative capacity, when you have unlimited intelligence, when you have unlimited power, when you have an eternity — what else are you gonna do? You have somewhere you gotta be?</p>
<p>CREATION is its own end. As you go chasing awakening and Nothingness, do not overlook CREATION! It's everywhere and everything! You might look at this roller coaster and see some gamer-nerd making something pointless. But that's not some nerd, that's God! That is the unlimited creative force of the whole universe materializing itself into a roller coaster! God is the sum total of all chains of creation, of which this roller coaster is one chain. That force is designing everything from atoms to cells to animals to galaxies and beyond. Can you see it? It is unlimited creation. It cannot stop. It bursts infinitely with new creative forms and ideas, ultimately spawning everything that can ever be.</p>
<p>If life feels depressing and bleak, it's because you're failing to step into your role as Creator. Creation is a spiritual activity. Every time that gamer-nerd works on perfecting his roller coaster, he's in church. And when you look upon and delight in his creation, recognizing the God in it, you are in church. What if your work and your church were one and the same? Wouldn't that be a life worth living?</p>
<p>Never forget, you are a creator. You are THE creator. What are you gonna create with your life?</p>
<p>I hope it's something at least as cool as this rollercoaster.</p>
<p>P.S. Notice what the guy in the video says at the very end of the ride, at timestamp 10:02. He says, "OH. MY. GOD!" That's right. That's exactly right.</p>
<p>P.P.S. Here's another <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ca3eYxZedD4" target="_blank">epic Aliens rollercoaster</a>.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-joy-of-creation</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Solo Retreat Notes</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/solo-retreat-notes-feb-2019</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I ended up taking 23 pages of notes during my solo retreat.</p>
<p>Here they are if you're interested: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/downloads/solo-retreat-notes-feb-2019.docx" target="_blank">Leo's Solo Retreat Notes, Feb-Mar 2019</a></p>
<p>A lot of profound insights there, but it was hastily written, and of course a lot of insights were not written down at all.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/solo-retreat-notes-feb-2019</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Back From Retreat</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/back-from-retreat</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>And I'm back!</p>
<p>It's been a crazy 29 days of consciousness work, featuring 13 profound awakening experiences — each one deeper than the last. Impossible levels of consciousness were accessed that few human beings have ever experienced.</p>
<p>I'll tell you all about it after I collect my thoughts. There is a lot to say, yet at the same time, it is impossible to put it faithfully into words.</p>
<p>I have a truckload of the deepest insights to share.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/back-from-retreat</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leaving On 30-Day Solo Retreat</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/leaving-on-30-day-solo-retreat</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Sorry, in my eagerness I neglected to post here that I'm away for 30 days straight doing a solo meditation retreat in search of enlightenment.</p>
<p>Video explanation of my plans can be <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/leaving-on-30-day-solo-retreat" target="_blank">found here</a>.</p>
<p>My retreat ends on March 24th. I'll post a video summarizing my results shortly thereafter.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/leaving-on-30-day-solo-retreat</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bernie 2020!</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/bernie-2020</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Today Bernie Sanders announced his entry in the 2020 Presidential race and I am thrilled to endorse him. I don't typically endorse politicians, but he is by far the best politician in the country today. He is a serious visionary leader and his policy platform is outstanding. If you want to live in a more conscious, less plutocratic America, please <a href="https://berniesanders.com" target="_blank">donate</a> & support Bernie because the establishment ego backlash against him will be yuge!</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZgJagAiHimk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZmK8flP0CuA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Sanders' 2020 policy platform:</p>
<ul>
<li>Medicare 4 All</li>
<li>Green New Deal/climate</li>
<li>$15 min wage</li>
<li>Criminal justice reform</li>
<li>Free college</li>
<li>Break up biggest banks</li>
<li>Campaign finance reform</li>
<li>Gender pay equity</li>
<li>Paid leave</li>
<li>Lower drug prices</li>
<li>Expand Social Security</li>
<li>Save unions</li>
<li>DREAM Act</li>
<li>Background checks & assault weapons ban</li>
<li>Affordable housing</li>
<li>New infrastructure</li>
<li>Opposing military industrial complex</li>
<li>Legalization of weed</li>
<li>Abolish private prisons</li>
<li>End cash bail</li>
<li>Major police department reform</li>
</ul>
<p>Now is the time to put your money where your mouth is. If you are short on cash, consider volunteering for <a href="https://act.berniesanders.com/signup/volunteer" target="_blank">his campaign</a>, the <a href="https://www.justicedemocrats.com" target="_blank">Justice Democrats</a>, or <a href="https://www.wolf-pac.com" target="_blank">Wolf-PAC</a> to get corporate money out of government.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4159" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/sanders-donation-01.png" alt="sanders-donation-01" width="615" /></p>
<p>And don't forget to register to participate in your state's Democratic primary. This is very important. Voting in the General Election is NOT good enough.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/bernie-2020</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Textbook Example Of Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/textbook-example-of-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I don't particularly like to kick a man when he's down, but the following video shows the unraveling of Alex Jones' ego in such a stark way that it deserves to be in a textbook about devilry. Pay close attention to how the arrogance of the ego-mind refuses to concede to truth and love, doubling down on its egotism and starting a holy war (lesser Jihad). This is how crusades and holy wars throughout history have been started.</p>
<p>Alex Jones is just an extremely obvious example of this. But notice how your ego does this too, in (hopefully) lesser, more subtle ways. It especially happens when you feel under attack or when your livelihood or identity is seriously threatened.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YL1ShzYHvD8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>As context for this clip, on his podcast <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B93fUUiuwMs" target="_blank">Joe Rogan extended a hand of friendship to Alex Jones</a>, genuinely concerned for his mental health. Joe took a fair, compassionate position, being more than generous to Alex Jones, but the devil cannot stand it! The devil is terrified of genuine love and compassion — he thinks it's a ploy. Love burns the devil like a sunlight burns a vampire. Rogan is speaking from a healthy stage Green while Jones is speaking from a very pathological stage Red. Stage Green often underestimates the depravity and viciousness stage Red is capable of — it is outside of stage Green's reality.</p>
<p>The fundamental position of the devil in aggressive defiance of God. At low levels of Spiral Development the ego becomes aggressively ignorant and, of course, assumes the position of God. The devil always feels like he is the righteous one who could do no wrong and that God is on his side. The devil is a usurper of God's throne, actively spinning delusions and self-deceptions to convince himself that what he's doing is righteous.</p>
<p>Remember this: a devil will not hesitate to bite a helping hand. So be careful when openly offering them your compassion.</p>
<p>P.S. Please don't misunderstand me when I call Alex Jones a devil. Despite how it sounds, I am not actually demonizing him. When I call someone "a devil" I do not use this term dualistically or moralistically. I am not making a moral judgment of him. For me this is a technical term describing delusional egoic behavior which aims at supplanting truth with its own selfishness. Like how a cuckoo bird tries to lay its own egg in the nest of other birds.</p>
<p>See my video: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/what-is-the-devil" target="_blank">What Is The Devil?</a> to learn more.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/textbook-example-of-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Entrainment Demo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/entrainment-demo</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Check out this cool video demonstrating entrainment:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Aaxw4zbULMs?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Notice at the end how they all de-sync without the soda cans.</p>
<p>Consider that the soda cans are culture. Culture allows human beings to entrain with each other. Which is why people defend their cultures to the death.</p>
<p>P.S. Your brain gets entrained to certain types of sounds and music just like the pendulums above. Various spiritual techniques make use of such brain entrainment — like binaural beats, Solfeggio frequencies, chanting, mantra recitation, and shamanic drumming — in order to access higher states of consciousness. Is this New Age voodoo? No! Does it really work? Yes! Give it a try, if you dare. There is a spooky yet legit connection between your state of consciousness and auditory vibrations.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/entrainment-demo</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #014</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-014</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;">"Abandon the search for God and the Creation and other matters of a similar sort. Look for him by taking yourself as the starting point. Learn who it is within you who makes everything his own and says, 'My God, my mind, my thought, my soul, my body.' Learn the sources of sorrow, joy, love, hate. Learn how it happens that one watches without willing, rests without willing, becomes angry without willing, loves without willing. If you carefully investigate these matters you will find him in yourself."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— Monoimus, quoted by Hippolytus of Rome</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-014</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>