<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=content&amp;type=forums_topic_post</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 18:31:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Psychedelics vs Consciousness practices</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33024-psychedelics-vs-consciousness-practices/?do=findComment&amp;comment=392230</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="392228" data-ipsquote-contentid="33024" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553861894" data-ipsquote-userid="14274" data-ipsquote-username="noselfnofun">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		8 minutes ago, noselfnofun said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			The only drawback I've seen from psychedelics is its hard to integrate the insights you get on them into your everyday life.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I haven't found it any harder than integrating insights from a 10 day Vipassana retreat.
</p>

<p>
	Integration is core to all spiritual practice. Do not assume you will just awaken and become an angel without a TON of integration work.
</p>

<p>
	There is more work in integration than there is in having the awakening.
</p>

<p>
	Try doing 30 days of Vipassana and then go spend a week living with your mother and see how that goes. See if you can keep your Vipassana insights while living with your mother.
</p>

<p>
	It's easy to keep your Vipassana insights when you meditate for 8 hours a day in a cave non-stop while someone else prepares your food for you. It's much harder when you have to run a business, raise a family, attract a mate, cook your own food, do your own taxes, etc.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 12:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">392230</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Psychedelics vs Consciousness practices</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33024-psychedelics-vs-consciousness-practices/?do=findComment&amp;comment=392224</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13993-arhattobe/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="13993" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13993-arhattobe/" rel="">@Arhattobe</a> The psychedelic is a transformative tool. You are judging is improperly when you judged it like so: If it fully enlightens me in one go, then it's good. If it doesn't, then it's bad and useless.
</p>

<p>
	If you're gonna use that criterion, then you should apply it equally to meditation. Like so: if I sit down and meditate for 30 minutes and it fully enlightens me, then I will do it and it's good. But if doesn't, then it's bad and I'm never going to meditate again.
</p>

<p>
	How many meditation sits does it take to become stably awakened? 1000? 5000? 10,000?
</p>

<p>
	Now apply those numbers to psychedelics. So your comparison is fair.
</p>

<p>
	What would happen if you did 1000 trips? Would you become stably awake? If so, you'd beat mediation by 10x.
</p>

<p>
	Why do I have a deeper understanding of metaphysical reality than Shinzen Young, who has 40 years of professional practice while I have less than 5 years of amateur practice? How do you explain that? There's some facts and statistics for ya.
</p>

<p>
	You see, there's more to this than just awakening. You must look at psychedelics as a holistic tool for self-awareness, personal development, and mental health.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 12:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">392224</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Psychedelics vs Consciousness practices</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33024-psychedelics-vs-consciousness-practices/?do=findComment&amp;comment=392220</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="392218" data-ipsquote-contentid="33024" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553860941" data-ipsquote-userid="5757" data-ipsquote-username="Scholar">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		5 minutes ago, Scholar said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I am just asking who would eventually reach the greatest depth, a yogi who is talented and does consciousness work all day long or someone who took lots of psychedelics and had a amateur-esk consciousness practice? I have no idea, I just want to propose that it might be possible that the one who did the consciousness work all his life might get into the greater depth eventually.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's hard to say. You can only know by doing both and seeing which one gets you higher.
</p>

<p>
	5-MeO is gonna be hard to beat. You could only beat it if you devoted your entire life to full-time practice. You basically would have no life but meditation.
</p>

<p>
	The real answer is to do both. They complement each other perfectly. Nothing I realize on 5-MeO-DMT really contradicts what the most advanced yogis say. The alignment is uncanny.
</p>

<p>
	If 5-MeO somehow revealed truths which were the opposite of what the most advanced yogis say, then we would have a serious problem, as you would not know which to trust. But if they are 90% aligned, then there's no problem.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 12:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">392220</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Psychedelics vs Consciousness practices</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33024-psychedelics-vs-consciousness-practices/?do=findComment&amp;comment=392216</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="392201" data-ipsquote-contentid="33024" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553859006" data-ipsquote-userid="5757" data-ipsquote-username="Scholar">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		57 minutes ago, Scholar said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Is it not possible that by doing consciousness practices for years and years, one actually creates a process for becoming more conscious which exponentially increases consciousness so that it seems like, for someone who has not practice long enough, it would be impossible to reach consciousness levels as high as one does with psychedelics?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Of course, that's exactly what it takes, decades of industrial-grade practice which virtually no one is ready to do.
</p>

<p>
	You have to understand that most people are not full-time yogis. So what good is it to tell people: become a full-time yogi, otherwise you will not understand anything I teach?
</p>

<p>
	What we need are efficient ways of communicating these powerful insights. 10 to 20 years of practice is not within the realm of reality for most people. So we need something more effective. Someone who is going to do these practices hardcore for 20 years is already fully-bought in. You are preaching to the choir when teaching him. The real issue is, how do you teach to new people? People who are not part of the choir.
</p>

<p>
	That's where psychedelics come in.
</p>

<p>
	And also don't forget, there are many Zen masters and teachers who still have never accessed levels of consciousness as high as 5-MeO-DMT can deliver within 15 minutes. So 20 years of practice is no guarantee whatsoever that you will beat out 5-MeO-DMT. Can someone like Sadhguru beat out 5-MeO? Probably, but that's totally irrelevant because that helps no one. That is like saying that Arnold can lift 500 pounds. Yes, he can, but your sister can't. She needs to use a forklift.
</p>

<p>
	The point of technology is to make things which almost no one can do accessible to everyone easily.
</p>

<p>
	Could you imagine how backwards it would be if everyone had to be computer programmer in order to use a computer or smart phone? Or a pilot in order to use an airplane? Think about it.
</p>

<p>
	Think about how backwards it is that a person must spend 20 years of his life chasing an enlightenment experience.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">392216</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Last Stage</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33022-the-last-stage/?do=findComment&amp;comment=392197</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6805-principium-nexus/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6805" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6805-principium-nexus/" rel="">@Principium Nexus</a> Well, if you want to be precise, tranquility underlies everything, emptiness underlies every emotion. So it's not about not being excited, it's about realizing that excitement is happening within the emptiness that is your true nature. Trying to achieve some monotone state is not the goal, nor will you ever succeed in that. You can have emotional ups and downs while being conscious and detached from them.
</p>

<p>
	Emotional range is good and healthy. Don't try to be monotone. Laugh & cry.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 11:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">392197</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Emotional Problems Sub-Forum</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33008-emotional-problems-sub-forum/?do=findComment&amp;comment=392106</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Also understand that a significant percentage of the general population has serious emotional issues to work through. So banning such talk is not going to eliminate the problem. It will only make it worse. At least here people can vent and get some decent pointers/resources. By eliminating this sub-forum people would have to keep all that pent up inside them with no one to talk to. And of course it would inevitably spill over into the other sub-forums.
</p>

<p>
	It's not self-actualization or this forum which is causing these serious emotional problems. They are pre-existing conditions. A psychologically healthy person is not going to come to this forum and leave sick or suicidal. So don't blame the existence of this forum for these issues. This is just a place for people to express themselves. Expect to see a lot of ego expressed here.
</p>

<p>
	I have noticed that when someone here is truly feeling suicidal, people on this forum try to do what they can to help them. But even so, some people are in such bad shape psychologically that forum talk is not going to heal them. How else could it be? With thousands of people visiting this forum, we are gonna some really dysfunctional cases which might even be beyond help (at least help via online).
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 03:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">392106</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Emotional Problems Sub-Forum</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33008-emotional-problems-sub-forum/?do=findComment&amp;comment=392091</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	User <span><a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14940-sharp/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14940" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14940-sharp/" rel="">@Sharp</a> </span>has been banned form this forum.
</p>

<p>
	He was a devil trying to manipulate this forum:
</p>

<p>
	<a class="ipsAttachLink ipsAttachLink_image" data-fileid="15226" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/monthly_2019_03/2019-03-28_2018.png.077f25d34695ad79622acd31664d6923.png" rel=""><img alt="2019-03-28_2018.png" class="ipsImage ipsImage_thumbnailed" data-fileid="15226" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/monthly_2019_03/2019-03-28_2018.thumb.png.24d2f525044efd49505cceae70eddba8.png" /></a>
</p>

<p>
	 
</p>

<p>
	Like I have said to the devils that lurk here, don't think for a minute that I don't see through your games.
</p>

<p>
	As far as seriously suicidal people, those we should treat with compassion and try to help them, but only if they ask for our help. If a person does not want any help (even if they are suicidal) then that is their choice and we are not to impose our will and our desires on them. Keep in mind that people have a right to commit suicide and you should not judge them for it if that is what they really want.
</p>

<p>
	If a person truly wants help with a serious emotional issue, they will ask for help. And they will receive it.
</p>

<p>
	But keep in mind that the ego-mind loves to use threats of suicide to play games, get sympathy, get attention, etc. So do take such threats with a grain of salt. If someone really wanted to commit suicide they would just do it. They would not brag about it on a forum, trying to fish for attention -- that is all ego.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 03:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">392091</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question about Life Purpose course</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32908-question-about-life-purpose-course/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391712</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15294-sleyker/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15294" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15294-sleyker/" rel="">@Sleyker</a> If you can watch the samples, you can watch the full course.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391712</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trying to find a book from the 1920s about man being the &quot;time-fixing animal&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32997-trying-to-find-a-book-from-the-1920s-about-man-being-the-time-fixing-animal/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391702</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Sounds like Alfred Korzybski.
</p>

<p>
	<a href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Alfred_Korzybski" rel="external nofollow">https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Alfred_Korzybski</a>
</p>

<p>
	Manhood of Humanity
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391702</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using the force of God as an excuse to have sex your son's wife?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32919-using-the-force-of-god-as-an-excuse-to-have-sex-your-sons-wife/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391615</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="391611" data-ipsquote-contentid="32919" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553748357" data-ipsquote-userid="5818" data-ipsquote-username="Gabriel Antonio">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		21 minutes ago, Gabriel Antonio said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			You sound like a religious fanatic.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Sure sounds like it the inexperienced.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 05:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391615</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>To take medication or not to</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32581-to-take-medication-or-not-to/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391613</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5344-jcent/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5344" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5344-jcent/" rel="">@Jcent</a> Keep in mind that not everyone is like you. Just because something works for you doesn't mean it will work for everyone. So stay humble with your advice. Health issues can be very complex, multi-factorial, and personal.
</p>

<p>
	Your fantasies about my right knee are purely your own projections.
</p>

<p>
	Do not stick your nose in other people's health issues as if you know them.
</p>

<p>
	The point of the money is to afford the medical treatments (which tend to be expensive). If <a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9989-fountainbleu/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9989" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9989-fountainbleu/" rel="">@Fountainbleu</a> didn't have a money shortage, then this situation would be much easier to handle. Not everyone can just take months off from work to heal. That is a luxury which assumes you've got money to burn through.
</p>

<p>
	Generally-speaking I am very against anti-depressants. But if there is no other way, then you must do what you must do to survive.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 05:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391613</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using the force of God as an excuse to have sex your son's wife?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32919-using-the-force-of-god-as-an-excuse-to-have-sex-your-sons-wife/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391592</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="391227" data-ipsquote-contentid="32919" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553692240" data-ipsquote-userid="5761" data-ipsquote-username="ajasatya">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		13 hours ago, ajasatya said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			has it? <img alt="xD" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/laugh.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/laugh@2x.png 2x" title="xD" width="20" />
		</p>

		<p>
			we do see patterns on higher levels. is logic innate of the fabric of Reality or a tool for survival and contemplation on the level of the mind?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It has.
</p>

<p>
	The most amazing thing about reality is that it is intelligible. Nothing is arbitrary.
</p>

<p>
	Human logic is a tiny splinter off God's logic.
</p>

<p>
	It's not just patterns and survival. I'm talking about understanding the metaphysical structure of reality and why it is the way it is. There is no accident or randomness to it. It has a Logos.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 02:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391592</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391580</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Anyone try the oxalate version? How does it compare? Same potency as HCl?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 02:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391580</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>To take medication or not to</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32581-to-take-medication-or-not-to/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391534</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9989-fountainbleu/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9989" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9989-fountainbleu/" rel="">@Fountainbleu</a> It's hard to say. Are you saying that all of these social anxiety issues started after your car crash?? You didn't have them before?
</p>

<p>
	Brain trauma is a serious thing and requires serious treatment, not merely spiritual techniques. There are supplements and various EEG brain training methods which might help you a lot. Research neurofeedback brain training.
</p>

<p>
	You can also contact the Dr Amen brain clinic in California. I know they do great work when it comes to assessing and healing brain injury. Or find another similar provider.
</p>

<p>
	I would focus on doing whatever it takes to heal your brain injury because you are gonna have to live with it for life and it will seriously affect your earning potential.
</p>

<p>
	If you need to take some meds to start a biz to earn the money to heal your brain, that is a good plan if you cannot afford to heal yourself immediately.
</p>

<p>
	Here's a link to Dr Amen's clinic:
</p>

<p>
	<a href="https://www.amenclinics.com" rel="external nofollow">https://www.amenclinics.com</a>
</p>

<p>
	You should also do research into brain injury recovery. Many books have been written on the subject. Educate yourself on the best ways to heal.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 23:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391534</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using the force of God as an excuse to have sex your son's wife?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32919-using-the-force-of-god-as-an-excuse-to-have-sex-your-sons-wife/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391222</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="391199" data-ipsquote-contentid="32919" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553688113" data-ipsquote-userid="9705" data-ipsquote-username="lmfao">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		57 minutes ago, lmfao said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			How could there be some sort of "why" reason. Things are just what they are. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Things are not just as they are. They are a very specific way, a very deliberate and intelligent way. Everything is intelligible. It is possible to become conscious of why every hair on your arm exists exactly as it does and not otherwise.
</p>

<p>
	It is possible to understand why the whole universe exists. Profound awakening required of course. This is no ordinary reason. You must penetrate the very structure of God. It has a logic to it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 12:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391222</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>5g Silent Darkness Mushroom Trip Report</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32950-5g-silent-darkness-mushroom-trip-report/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391220</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6002-adam-m/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6002" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6002-adam-m/" rel="">@Adam M</a> Motel room works just as well. On LSD, even a dirty bathroom will be so interesting and profound you will never be bored. You can easily spend 5 hours tripping in a bathroom and have the time of your life.
</p>

<p>
	The kingdom of heaven is within <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 12:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391220</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Are kids more conscious than adults?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32959-are-kids-more-conscious-than-adults/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391187</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5864-nahm/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5864" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5864-nahm/" rel="">@Nahm</a> Little devils they are.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 11:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391187</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Can you possibly Love Everything?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32960-how-can-you-possibly-love-everything/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391182</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14120-sqaad/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14120" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14120-sqaad/" rel="">@SQAAD</a> You (ego) cannot.
</p>

<p>
	Egolessness is required. Surrender is required. Deep, profound surrender.
</p>

<p>
	Consciousness is required. Profound consciousness. A blinding radiance that bleaches out all shadows.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 11:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391182</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using the force of God as an excuse to have sex your son's wife?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32919-using-the-force-of-god-as-an-excuse-to-have-sex-your-sons-wife/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391180</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	There is nothing wrong with Zen teachings per se, I was just saying that they are minimalist. Minimalism does not make people aware of what they are missing.
</p>

<p>
	How many Zen students really understand the depth of Zen? Virtually none. It requires super-human levels of consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	The Buddha said: no one will understand. And so it is. It's too much.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 11:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391180</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using the force of God as an excuse to have sex your son's wife?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32919-using-the-force-of-god-as-an-excuse-to-have-sex-your-sons-wife/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391178</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="391135" data-ipsquote-contentid="32919" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553682675" data-ipsquote-userid="10252" data-ipsquote-username="tsuki">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		57 minutes ago, tsuki said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Do you believe that the 'point' is to get as many people as enlightened as possible?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The point is EVERYTHING.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 11:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391178</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using the force of God as an excuse to have sex your son's wife?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32919-using-the-force-of-god-as-an-excuse-to-have-sex-your-sons-wife/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391130</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10252-tsuki/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10252" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10252-tsuki/" rel="">@tsuki</a> The Zen approach suffers from the problem that it undersells God. It plays coy.
</p>

<p>
	Virtually no one who practices Zen understands how deep consciousness goes or what God is. Only a few of the highest Zen masters do.
</p>

<p>
	For example, Shinzen Young does not understand why reality exists. He's not fully woke and he does not know it. That's with 40 years of professional Zen practice.
</p>

<p>
	BTW, nothing at all against his teachings. I'm just saying there are levels which virtually no one has accessed. I am just using this example to point out how tricky this work is. No one is safe. Proceed with extreme care.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 10:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391130</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Are kids more conscious than adults?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32959-are-kids-more-conscious-than-adults/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391128</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	No they aren't.
</p>

<p>
	They are just less corrupted by beliefs and less rigid.
</p>

<p>
	Kids are very selfish and nowhere close to woke. They are like animals. They have no clue they are God.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 10:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391128</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question about contemplation</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32912-question-about-contemplation/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391097</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="391096" data-ipsquote-contentid="32912" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553673767" data-ipsquote-userid="343" data-ipsquote-username="Key Elements">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 minutes ago, Key Elements said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Because sometimes when it happens, the person just passes that off as a fantastic dream instead of it being the Truth and just settles for the maya without realizing what happened, unfortunately.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Well, there's no cure for ignorance.
</p>

<p>
	Try, try again until awakening is undeniable.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 08:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391097</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question about contemplation</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32912-question-about-contemplation/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391094</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/343-key-elements/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="343" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/343-key-elements/" rel="">@Key Elements</a> The Absolute Truth is totally self-evident and self-validating. It is prior to doubt or question.
</p>

<p>
	Infinity answers all whys. But not logically or verbally. It's just Infinity. The end. What else could anything be?
</p>

<p>
	You ARE the Absolute Truth. Look at your body -- there it is. You're BEING it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 07:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391094</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>If God is all Loving, how can it Experience Hatred?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32936-if-god-is-all-loving-how-can-it-experience-hatred/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391093</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12556-wisebaxter/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12556" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12556-wisebaxter/" rel="">@Wisebaxter</a> You should distinguish God in its pure form vs God as the devil. In it's disguise as the devil God does all sorts of evils. In its pure undisguised from God is pure love and goodness. For God to hate it must incarnate itself as an ego and delude itself into believing it is not God. So when God forgets who it is, it does evil. When God is forced to play the game of survival, it does evil in order to survive.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 07:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391093</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How I became conscious of God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32942-how-i-became-conscious-of-god/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391073</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8928-highest/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8928" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8928-highest/" rel="">@Highest</a> You exist, as God, which is nothing. Non-existence is not a thing. Non-existence does not exist.
</p>

<p>
	But there is more. Have you become conscious that God is infinity? And what infinity means?
</p>

<p>
	Have you become conscious of Infinite Intelligence? Infinite Love? Infinite Goodness? Eternity?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 06:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391073</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Am Immortal</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32946-i-am-immortal/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391072</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9252-wasem/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9252" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9252-wasem/" rel="">@Wasem</a> Very good.
</p>

<p>
	The thing that is immortal IS God.
</p>

<p>
	Look into it. What is your true nature? What is the true nature of pure consciousness? What is that thing sitting inside your skull?
</p>

<p>
	Hint: it's God!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 06:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391072</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question about contemplation</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32912-question-about-contemplation/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391069</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="390491" data-ipsquote-contentid="32912" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553579855" data-ipsquote-userid="10506" data-ipsquote-username="Tearos">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 3/25/2019 at 10:57 PM, Tearos said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			If both my friend and I contemplate on the same topic, will we both naturally at some point go to the same conclusions which would be the Truth?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	If you mean Absolute Truth then your contemplations should eventually converge. But even so, there are many facets to Absolute Truth such that even the same person will not reach the same point twice in a row, never mind other people. The trick is that the Absolute is singular, but it can be seen in various light, so to speak, and it will be interpreted very differently by different minds. It's sort of like looking at an object with very little light in the room. The object itself is always the same, but the lighting conditions plus your perspective on that object plus your distance from that object determine what you will see. Someone from 100ft away at night will see something very different than someone 2 inches away in full daylight. And then there's your reactions, opinions, feelings, and judgments about the object. All of that makes it very unlikely that two people understand/see anything the same way, even the Absolute.
</p>

<p>
	But even so, there should be some rough broad consensus.
</p>

<p>
	As far as relative truths are concerned, the situation there is even worse. The mind will color everything in such a way that your understanding of relative truths will tend to be very different from other people. Because how you see the world is a direct reflection of how you must see it in order to survive. Survival distorts perception enormously. What you see, what you know, and how you understand things is almost totally dominated by your survival needs. Truth is hardly anything your mind cares about. Your mind is 99.9% preoccupied with survival. Which is why there is so much disagreement between people.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 06:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391069</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using the force of God as an excuse to have sex your son's wife?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32919-using-the-force-of-god-as-an-excuse-to-have-sex-your-sons-wife/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391064</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11463-pouya/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11463" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11463-pouya/" rel="">@Pouya</a> Well, that is true, but it's much misunderstood by common folk who merely believe it but have no direct experience of what those words mean.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 05:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391064</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>5g Silent Darkness Mushroom Trip Report</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32950-5g-silent-darkness-mushroom-trip-report/?do=findComment&amp;comment=391041</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	That's how growin is done!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 04:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">391041</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trying to understand the concept of consciousness better</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32921-trying-to-understand-the-concept-of-consciousness-better/?do=findComment&amp;comment=390987</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15299-seththomas/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15299" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15299-seththomas/" rel="">@Seththomas</a> What is consciousness? is the most profound question in the universe. To fully grasp what consciousness is so astounding that it ends you entire old way of life.
</p>

<p>
	When you ask What is consciousness? you are really asking What is the substance of all of existence? That's a monster of a question. It may take you 10-20 years of work to get the answer.
</p>

<p>
	I have a video: What Is Consciousness? Maybe check that out.
</p>

<p>
	In short: consciousness is nothing, consciousness is everything, consciousness is God. But just hearing that as words does very little for you. You must undertake a journey to personally realize what consciousness is. This requires multiple deep enlightenment experiences.
</p>

<p>
	Very simply, to ground your inquiry, pull out your hand right now and hold it close to your face. Look at it closely. Your hand is consciousness. Realize that. And then begin to wonder: What is consciousness? What is it's very essence? Here it is, but WHAT is it?
</p>

<p>
	HINT: Any object you look at is consciousness. There is nothing but consciousness. Consciousness is not a thing, it is a sort of ever-present, self-aware, space.
</p>

<p>
	VERY IMPORTANT: Stop thinking of consciousness is a secretion of the brain or somehow arising out of matter. The brain and matter are both made out of consciousness. Consciousness is prior to physics or physical reality. It is impossible to understand consciousness from within the materialist paradigm.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 01:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">390987</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using the force of God as an excuse to have sex your son's wife?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32919-using-the-force-of-god-as-an-excuse-to-have-sex-your-sons-wife/?do=findComment&amp;comment=390985</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="390639" data-ipsquote-contentid="32919" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553606534" data-ipsquote-userid="5757" data-ipsquote-username="Scholar">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		11 hours ago, Scholar said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> I have a question about something that is not directly related to this topic, I see it happening quite a bit with you and many other higher evolved individuals. I am currently making myself familiar with Ken Wilber's model of cognitive/consciousness development/evolution.
		</p>

		<p>
			When making statements like "Things only happen by God's will." are we not running into the risk of confusing and deluding people due to the stark difference in interpretation between gross, casual, subtle and non-dual state of consciousness, and also due to a difference in cognition from different cognitive stages? 
		</p>

		<p>
			It seems to me like a person only capable of, for example, formal operational thought is actually incapable of correctly interpreting your statement, due to the inherent limitations of his cognition. Statements coming from vision logic or beyond will actually cease to be the same statements when viewed from formal operational cognition. When they read it and they are at that stage, and they agree with you, they are actually wrong about what they agree with you about. And if they do not agree, they are wrong too because they do not even comprehend the true meaning of the statement. Either way they will come out confused, whether they believe you or not.
		</p>

		<p>
			And to me this is a real problem in the spiritual community, especially with non-dual "truths" that are being thrown around like candy, necessarily misinterpreted by those who hear them, as they themselves cannot truly understand the meaning of those truths if they have not reached any non-dual states.
		</p>

		<p>
			In this forum alone I see countless of people who are adopting non-dual, casual, subtle or psychic intellectual positions without having even experienced these states. And furthermore it seems like these statements only make sense while being in the particular state they originated from, which further complicates everything as it can easily lead to self-delusion by the person who has temporarily experienced one of these states.
		</p>

		<p>
			What do we do about this problem? I know your style is not conducive to the zen-master riddle approach, but are you not worried about leading people on the wrong path if you give them higher truths that they are bound to be deluded and misinterpreted? Wouldn't a spiral wizard be a little more sophisticated, by for example luring a person to the next stage instead of going full non-dual on them if they are far removed from that realm?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, that's basically right. Higher truths/wisdom requires a certain wisdom to understand and interpret properly. Ignorant devils will misinterpret the hell out of all the highest teachings because that's what devils do. Devils turn truth into falsehood. That's the entire function of a devil.
</p>

<p>
	We are sort of damned if we do, and damned if we don't. If we don't talk about God, we are not being honest and people are being mislead. If we do talk about God, we are creating representations of God, all of which are not the actual thing, and people will be mislead. That's the tragedy of our collective situation.
</p>

<p>
	When I speak of God's will, I speak from direct experience. Of course most people have no experience of what God or God's will mean. And any ideas you have about it are wrong. So what are we to do? Direct experience is required to understand the highest teachings.
</p>

<p>
	One of the reasons I'm big on psychedelics is that they give ordinary people such direct experiences very quickly, without decades of grueling practice. So then they can understand me a lot better. You can take a psychedelic and ask it the question, "What is God's will?" or "What is God?" and it will show you the answer very clearly, as long as you are truly open to it and willing to surrender yourself and your beliefs. It might take you a few trips, but you'll get it.
</p>

<p>
	But yes, talking about God to uninformed people is very misleading to them. Because their ideas of God are so confused and backwards. You can really only talk about God to people who have experienced that they are God. Which sort of defeats the point of talking at all. And yet without talking about God how are people gonna find God? Only by accident. Which is not a good solution.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 01:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">390985</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Will there ever be an end to the Human understanding and Research?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32937-will-there-ever-be-an-end-to-the-human-understanding-and-research/?do=findComment&amp;comment=390983</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	The world of form is infinite in all directions. You can study it forever and you will be no closer to the end than when you began.
</p>

<p>
	But as far as understanding the Absolute, you can make some really headway there. You can grasp the nature of reality in one shot, although there are many facets and degrees of depth to it. So even there you can spend a lot of time understanding it deeper and deeper.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">390983</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Using the force of God as an excuse to have sex your son's wife?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32919-using-the-force-of-god-as-an-excuse-to-have-sex-your-sons-wife/?do=findComment&amp;comment=390583</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5722-alwaysbenice/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5722" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5722-alwaysbenice/" rel="">@AlwaysBeNice</a> Don't you dare question God's will!
</p>

<p>
	<img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	The irony is that if it actually happened, it was God's will. Lol. Things only happen by God's will.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 11:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">390583</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I am scared of women</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32521-i-am-scared-of-women/?do=findComment&amp;comment=390494</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6475-anirban657/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6475" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6475-anirban657/" rel="">@Anirban657</a> You just need more practice and experience with them, that is all. As with all things, practice makes perfect.
</p>

<p>
	At 19 you basically have zero experience. So of course you feel that way.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 06:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">390494</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lack love for my domain of mastery</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32907-lack-love-for-my-domain-of-mastery/?do=findComment&amp;comment=390423</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Sometimes you grow out of your passion onto something new. And sometimes you just need to rekindle your passion because you are doing it too mechanically, too much for external rather than internal reasons.
</p>

<p>
	Taking time to contemplate your life in solititude helps enormously to figure what the problem is.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 01:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">390423</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>2g Magic Mushrooms First Trip Raport</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32852-2g-magic-mushrooms-first-trip-raport/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389960</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="389955" data-ipsquote-contentid="32852" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553517092" data-ipsquote-userid="15214" data-ipsquote-username="KP_Spirituality27">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		21 minutes ago, KP_Spirituality27 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I think that soon the time will come for my spiritual death.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Try not to make a big spectacle of it. Then it won't be so dramatic and scary. With spiritual death you discover that you've jumped off a cliff only to land on the fluffiest feather mattress, so you're not really losing anything. Don't let the ego create a big story about how it's losing so much. You're mostly losing bullshit delusions and gaining peace and authenticity. So it's a good trade.
</p>

<p>
	I've made the mistake in the past of over-dramatizing the ego-death part. Yes it happens but facing death is also not as hard or bad as it sounds. After a couple dozen ego-deaths it becomes natural and not a big deal.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 12:47:02 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389960</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do we know anything?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32770-how-do-we-know-anything/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389898</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8214-andyjohnsonman/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8214" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8214-andyjohnsonman/" rel="">@andyjohnsonman</a> There is an Absolute Truth. In fact, Absolute Truth is all there ever is. That's what truth is: that which is the case. It's actually very simple: whatever is must be true. And that which is untrue does not exist at all.
</p>

<p>
	The being of this very moment is none other than Absolute Truth, but you are not yet conscious enough to see it as such. Concepts are getting in the way of direct consciousness of being.
</p>

<p>
	Once you find the Absolute Truth you will discover that it is so grand, astounding, epic, and good that it will kill you. "Death by Truth" I call this <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" /> And you will realize that no one can know it but you. It cannot be shared with anyone else, since in truth, there is only YOU! It's ALL you! <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" /> It will break your heart that something this good cannot be shared with anyone but yourself, so learn to enjoy your own magnificence in solitude.
</p>

<p>
	Ta-da!
</p>

<p>
	But this will take you some years of hard work to fully realize. So get to work. It's worth it.
</p>

<p>
	Or maybe everything I said above is false? You don't know. This requires exploration.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 09:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389898</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do we know anything?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32770-how-do-we-know-anything/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389892</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8214-andyjohnsonman/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8214" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8214-andyjohnsonman/" rel="">@andyjohnsonman</a> That is one way out of dozens.
</p>

<p>
	You could eat some magic mushrooms and know things which would otherwise be impossible for a human to know. That would be another way.
</p>

<p>
	You don't even know if Kriya yoga will work. Maybe it's a scam as far as you know. See how tricky knowledge is? What do you trust? What is true?
</p>

<p>
	Truth is a highly non-trivial matter. How do you even know what criterion you'll use to determine if a thing is true? What if your criterion is false?
</p>

<p>
	And yet at the same time you also cannot say that all knowledge is false or impossible since that itself would be true knowledge, and you don't actually know that for sure. Such a claim would require that you test every piece of knowledge in the universe to make sure they are all false. You are nowhere close to doing that.
</p>

<p>
	So the bottom line is: keep a very open mind, don't dismiss anything, and run some experiments. Kriya yoga is one such experiment out of hundreds that you will have to run in order to come to know what knowledge is and is not.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 09:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389892</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>does absolute ethics exist?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32877-does-absolute-ethics-exist/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389884</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13670-foxfoxfox/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="13670" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13670-foxfoxfox/" rel="">@FoxFoxFox</a> Sorta. Although violence and disturbance is also an aspect of consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	There is no "best" really. It depends on your goals. Some people love their suffering and fantasies. Very few people are really ready and willing to awaken from Maya.
</p>

<p>
	Harmony is a tricky thing. Being a total pacificist for example when all your neighbors are wolves will not lead to harmony but your extinction or enslavement.
</p>

<p>
	Violence and peace are both necessary, which is why they co-exist. Violence begets peace, and peace begets violence. It's dialectical.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389884</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>All teachings and beliefs are false.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32862-all-teachings-and-beliefs-are-false/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389880</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11463-pouya/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11463" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11463-pouya/" rel="">@Pouya</a> Again, don't be so blunt. This kind of thinking is itself delusion.
</p>

<p>
	Be nuanced. Not all beliefs and teachings are wrong or false. You must evaluate them within a certain limited relative context. Stop trying to make everything be absolute.
</p>

<p>
	Teachings have certain pragmatic purposes and also limits. Teachings are partial relative truths. How else could it be?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 09:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389880</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>does absolute ethics exist?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32877-does-absolute-ethics-exist/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389877</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="389871" data-ipsquote-contentid="32877" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553503499" data-ipsquote-userid="13670" data-ipsquote-username="FoxFoxFox">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		15 minutes ago, FoxFoxFox said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10252-tsuki/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10252" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10252-tsuki/" rel="">@tsuki</a> I want to know how Leo has come to the conclusion that the connection to the self can be cut in the first place. In other words, how does the illusion of ignorance comes about?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It is not cut in actually, it is cut as an illusion.
</p>

<p>
	If an actor on stage got so wrapped up in playing his character that he forgot for a moment that he was just acting, that's how ignorance comes about.
</p>

<p>
	It is the nature of consciousness to be very hypnotic. It hypnotizes itself into dreamlike states which it then cannot resist.
</p>

<p>
	Ever play a video game and get so immersed in the world that you forget about the "real" world? Well, that's precisely how consciousness works. Appearance becomes reality. For a while. Always only for a while.
</p>

<p>
	Ever jerk off to porn? What is that? You are literally jerking off to an LCD screen! There's your illusion.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389877</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do we know anything?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32770-how-do-we-know-anything/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389872</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8214-andyjohnsonman/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8214" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8214-andyjohnsonman/" rel="">@andyjohnsonman</a> The question of how we know anything and what can and cannot be known is a very deep one. I have been studying this question for over 15 years. I have literally poured thousands of hours contemplating this one question because it is so important. On it hinges everything else. If you get this question wrong, you're basically fucked in life.
</p>

<p>
	From your current POV the truth is you don't know what can or cannot be known. You do not even know what knowing is!
</p>

<p>
	This is a great place to start. From this place you can do some serious inquiry. This question is not to be guessed or answered by looking up an answer in a book. You must really go on a journey and explore what knowledge is and how it works.
</p>

<p>
	Also keep in mind that there are different kinds of knowing. Verbal or rational knowing is only one kind. The most advanced things I speak of are knowable, but not from your current state of consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	For example, it is possible to know what God is or why existence exists or what consciousness is. But not through coventional logical verbal knowledge. There is knowing and understanding beyond the human mind.
</p>

<p>
	The deepest insights I share are not just stories or beliefs -- they are transrational understandings.
</p>

<p>
	Consider that there is a very profound connection between knowing and being. Some things can only be known by being them. This is the domain of mysticism and samadhi.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389872</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>4g Magic Mushroom Trip Report - Desintegration and Insight</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32834-4g-magic-mushroom-trip-report-desintegration-and-insight/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389870</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/3288-cle103/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="3288" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/3288-cle103/" rel="">@cle103</a> Great work!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:37:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389870</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>does absolute ethics exist?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32877-does-absolute-ethics-exist/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389869</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8090-joseph-maynor/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8090" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8090-joseph-maynor/" rel="">@Joseph Maynor</a> Think of ethics/morality as a matter of balance/harmony.
</p>

<p>
	Being too much out of balance becomes pathological relative to one's own well-being. In short, extreme selfishness or devilry backfires.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389869</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Knowledge does not exist. Understanding is an illusion.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32488-knowledge-does-not-exist-understanding-is-an-illusion/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389861</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13817-ivankiss/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="13817" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13817-ivankiss/" rel="">@ivankiss</a> Don't be so quick to trash all knowledge.
</p>

<p>
	Knowledge as a relative thing is good and legit.
</p>

<p>
	Understanding is real and not to be trashed. Without understanding you could not even understand this sentence or awakening.
</p>

<p>
	Be careful not to throw the baby out with the bathwater. Be more nuanced. The Absolute and understanding and knowledge can all co-exist. Each has its proper place and role to play. The mistake is to confuse them. The mistake is to not realize their limits. Knowledge simply has limits.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389861</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>2g Magic Mushrooms First Trip Raport</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32852-2g-magic-mushrooms-first-trip-raport/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389859</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15214-kp_spirituality27/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15214" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15214-kp_spirituality27/" rel="">@KP_Spirituality27</a> Excellent!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389859</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>i dont know what i am</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32871-i-dont-know-what-i-am/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389856</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10809-applejuice/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10809" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10809-applejuice/" rel="">@Applejuice</a> That's good. You must exhaust the mind's answers. Purge them. It would be very helpful for you to write down all your theories about what you are, no matter how ridiculous, just to purge them. Write them out, then cross them out and throw them in the trash.
</p>

<p>
	Not knowing is exactly the place you want to get to. The problem is that you still have many ideas and theories about what you are. You haven't purged enough yet to truly not know.
</p>

<p>
	The mind will never grasp it. It must be silenced through this purging method. Then just sit and bask in the silence, and that will be your best chance of enlightenment. It will not happen via your mind. The mind is the only obstacle to enlightenment.
</p>

<p>
	A LOT of purging must happen. Way more than you'll be comfortable with. You must even purge things like your childhood memories of yourself, since they are not the True Self.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389856</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>does absolute ethics exist?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32877-does-absolute-ethics-exist/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389852</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="389851" data-ipsquote-contentid="32877" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1553501481" data-ipsquote-userid="14523" data-ipsquote-username="Jkris">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 minute ago, Jkris said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> beautiful 😊. Welcome back to the forum after your retreat. 
		</p>

		<p>
			How was your retreat? 🙏
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Very amazing. Thanks!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389852</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>does absolute ethics exist?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/32877-does-absolute-ethics-exist/?do=findComment&amp;comment=389849</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Since God is Absolute Truth, even a hint of lying, dishonesty, falsehood, or inathenticity automatically severes your connection to God. That is okay. It is not "bad" to be seperated from God, but it painful since you become lost in your own falsehood. That is the definition of devilry.
</p>

<p>
	Lying is only "bad" relative to if you want to be happy. If you are okay with being unhappy, then lie a lot. If you want to be happy, lie as little as possible. If you want to realize God, lie as little as possible.
</p>

<p>
	There is only one reason you lie: fear. If you were immortal, untouchable, and fearless you would never lie. In other words if you were God, you'd never lie. Really think about that. That's deep.
</p>

<p>
	Absolute ethics is Truth/Love. It is Goodness without an opposite. It is God.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 08:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">389849</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>5-Meo Trip Report - 6mg + MDMA minidose</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31980-5-meo-trip-report-6mg-mdma-minidose/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374776</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14466-tkp/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14466" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14466-tkp/" rel="">@TKP</a> If you have 5-MeO-DMT, you don't need MDMA. Let go of the MDMA and go for a 5-MeO breakthrough. That is the Full Monty. It should occur in the 25-30 mg range.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 06:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374776</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I let myself pursue sex again after Leo's recent posts</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31953-i-let-myself-pursue-sex-again-after-leos-recent-posts/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374757</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8950-waves/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8950" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8950-waves/" rel="">@Waves</a> There is no way to formulate that balance. It will be unique for each person, and it will even change for the same person over time.
</p>

<p>
	You must experiment and see what works best for you.
</p>

<p>
	You can certainly maintain a 1hr daily meditation practice or Kriya yoga practice while you do pickup or dating. That's the minimum I'd recommend.
</p>

<p>
	Generally speaking you should set an overarching goal/plan for your year. What is the biggest thing you'll be focusing on this year? Attraction? Enlightenment? Business? Improving self esteem? Better nutrition? etc.
</p>

<p>
	Don't try to do it all at once. Space things out. You'll be amazed how much stuff you can do in 5-10 years if you focus.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 03:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374757</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Does It Mean To Question Existence Itself?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31975-what-does-it-mean-to-question-existence-itself/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374754</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="374728" data-ipsquote-contentid="31975" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550885482" data-ipsquote-userid="582" data-ipsquote-username="PetarKa">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, PetarKa said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			But that doesn't change things. Experience is still there.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's a belief you should question.
</p>

<p>
	It seems nothing will change, but the whole point of this work is that appearances are very deceptive.
</p>

<p>
	Basically, just take a psychedelic. Otherwise you will waste 10 years and still not realize what you're missing. I am not kidding about psychedelics. They will change your life forever. There is no more powerful tool for understanding reality.
</p>

<p>
	You absolutely need to hit entirely new states of consciousness to understand the power and depth of this work.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 03:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374754</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I know what I am. Ask me anything.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31951-i-know-what-i-am-ask-me-anything/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374722</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="374718" data-ipsquote-contentid="31951" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550883952" data-ipsquote-userid="10250" data-ipsquote-username="KMB4222">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, KMB4222 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I don’t see how anything anybody says can be of any use.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Right. So now sit down and actually do the work of directly experiencing what you are.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			But how is it possible to experience my true nature if I have been told what I am?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Let go of what you've been told and sit with an empty mind. You must enter a deep state of not-knowing. The simple truth is, you do not know what you are.
</p>

<p>
	Make a clear distinction between talking about, reading about, listening to, or thinking about what you are, versus actually sitting and silently observing what you are. These are totally different activities.
</p>

<p>
	See my video: What Is Actuality? to help ground yourself in the actual work.
</p>

<p>
	Or, just take a psychedelic.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 01:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374722</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>All theory is trap</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31957-all-theory-is-trap/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374702</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
	<div>
		<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tOIf3pY9LqE?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
	</div>
</div>

<p>
	One of my most important videos.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374702</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Night out report</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31747-night-out-report/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374697</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="374080" data-ipsquote-contentid="31747" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550767724" data-ipsquote-userid="13173" data-ipsquote-username="Dorotheus">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 2/21/2019 at 8:48 AM, Dorotheus said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I am studying the pickup material, and stumbled on this:
		</p>

		<p>
			<a href="https://goo.gl/images/MMtmHt" rel="external nofollow">https://goo.gl/images/MMtmHt</a>
		</p>

		<p>
			This is just toxic to be honest.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I don't know where you found that nonsense. That is not what I consider proper pickup. Why are you even looking at that when there is so much good material out there?
</p>

<p>
	You don't have to be an abusive juvenile jerk to attract women.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="374274" data-ipsquote-contentid="31747" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550792021" data-ipsquote-userid="14948" data-ipsquote-username="Elia">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 2/21/2019 at 3:33 PM, Elia said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> do you think women can be proactive in pickup as well? And in what way as opposed to men? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Pickup theory does not apply to women trying to find men. Women need a whole different set of advice and techniques. You can find tons of material specifically tailored to women. Dating advice for women. It is not going to involve cold approaching men on the street asking for phone numbers.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374697</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I let myself pursue sex again after Leo's recent posts</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31953-i-let-myself-pursue-sex-again-after-leos-recent-posts/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374692</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6511-amadeusz/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6511" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6511-amadeusz/" rel="">@Amadeusz</a> You young people who follow me have to understand that I talk about extremely advanced stuff (nowadays). Really, really, really advanced stuff! It took me tens of years of earthly development before I got to the lofty topics I'm now covering. There are many earthly materialistic development topics which I hardly cover at all even though they are very important for the average viewer.
</p>

<p>
	It's sort of like I'm teaching a college calculus class but you walk in by accident as a 5th grader. You need to handle the basics first.
</p>

<p>
	What most of you guys need is some basic Tony Robbins shit. Do some of that before you try to get all spiritual. Be mindful of getting ahead of your skiis.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374692</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Infinite Not Knowing Finite</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31954-infinite-not-knowing-finite/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374687</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="374548" data-ipsquote-contentid="31954" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550856119" data-ipsquote-userid="11314" data-ipsquote-username="Jonty">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		6 hours ago, Jonty said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I have heard him say over and over again that the infinite can never know the finite and vice versa.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I'm not sure what this means.
</p>

<p>
	The finite can know the infinite. And the infinite can know the finite. The infinite is not other than the finite.
</p>

<p>
	You have to understand spiritual phrasing in their proper contexts.
</p>

<p>
	What Spria might be talking about is the the Absolute formless Godhead which you can think of as sort of disconnected from the formed realm. You could say that it does not know the finite formed realm. But at the same it is also identical with the finite formed realm.
</p>

<p>
	In this context, you have to understand that the word "know" is virtually identical with "be". We are not talking about linguistic knowledge. We are talking about being.
</p>

<p>
	But all of this talk will only confuse you more. You must let all this go and just do the practices. Take a psychedelic to easily see what Spira is pointing to.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374687</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>God is existence</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31956-god-is-existence/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374683</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	It's not the weed, it's one's existential questioning that does the work. The weed is just a lubricant. A lubricant does not do the work by itself, it needs a running engine.
</p>

<p>
	Which explains why most people who smoke weed never realize God. Because their engine isn't running to begin with. They are not existentially questioning reality.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 23:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374683</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I know what I am. Ask me anything.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31951-i-know-what-i-am-ask-me-anything/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374681</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10250-kmb4222/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10250" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10250-kmb4222/" rel="">@KMB4222</a> Does not sound like you know what you are.
</p>

<p>
	The whole point of enlightenment is to reach your Absolute Nature and to be sure about it.
</p>

<p>
	If you feel like you can die, you're not there yet. Keep going until you're 100% sure you're immortal.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 23:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374681</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can low self-esteem make you selfish?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31938-can-low-self-esteem-make-you-selfish/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374678</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Low self esteem people tend to be very insecure, helpless, and needy. They love to play victim.
</p>

<p>
	When you are incapable of meeting your basic needs your entire life becomes dysfunctional and backwards. You are forced to resort to outrageous degrees of selfishness just to maintain your basic existence.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 23:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374678</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I am enlightened, ask me some, but definitely not any, thing</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31899-i-am-enlightened-ask-me-some-but-definitely-not-any-thing/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374675</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="374396" data-ipsquote-contentid="31899" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550826341" data-ipsquote-userid="9578" data-ipsquote-username="Sven">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		14 hours ago, Sven said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			There's always more to learn and more to be conscious of for the hippocampus. But "enlightenment" is before all that. You already are it all, there's no need to huff and puff to try to reach for something other just seeing that you are the one reaching. I mean look. It would be fun to know but there's nothing that will fill up the illusionary empty hole you keep thinking up when pretending you're somethin else than that which you are..!
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You misunderstood what I asked you. I was not talking about learning more stuff for the hippocampus. I was talking about being conscious of things which you're still not conscious of.
</p>

<p>
	A little bit of enlightenment is a dangerous thing indeed. Makes for a flippant smartass.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 23:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374675</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>God is existence</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31956-god-is-existence/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374674</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8928-highest/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8928" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8928-highest/" rel="">@Highest</a> Good work. Now be that conscious 24/7 <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 23:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374674</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aztec Human Sacrifices</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31812-aztec-human-sacrifices/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374666</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/2835-anton-rogachevski/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="2835" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/2835-anton-rogachevski/" rel="">@Anton Rogachevski</a> All 3 of them were killed so that they would not be in charge any more!
</p>

<p>
	The most ruthless Aztecs probably ate the wisest ones.
</p>

<p>
	P.S. And JFK, Gandhi, and MKL were not the wisest people in our culture. Not even close. They were just relatively wise compared to average political leaders. Which is not a high bar. None of them were enlightened. The wisest people in the culture are so wise hardly anyone knows about them.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 22:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374666</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>All life purposes are materialistic</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31966-all-life-purposes-are-materialistic/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374665</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6564-winter/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6564" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6564-winter/" rel="">@Winter</a>
</p>

<p>
	A) Material = spirit. A truly spiritual person understands this. Notice the duality you are creating.
</p>

<p>
	B) Karma yoga
</p>

<p>
	The whole point of being spiritual is to infuse your everyday life and "material" actions with spirit. Life purpose is nothing else but working from your heart and higher self -- letting Teotl work through you on account having enough wisdom to see through Teotl's many disguises.
</p>

<p>
	What you call "material" is just you admitting, "I can't see Teotl. I am fooled by Teotl." Material is how Teotl appears to those who are not wise enough to see Teotl's pure form.
</p>

<p>
	Go re-watch my Aztec episode. You still have much to learn from it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 22:46:47 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374665</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Counterintuitiveness of Money and Selfishness?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31961-the-counterintuitiveness-of-money-and-selfishness/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374648</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	As with all things, it requires a delicate balance.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 21:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374648</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>All theory is trap</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31957-all-theory-is-trap/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374647</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Lack of theory is also a trap.
</p>

<p>
	The opposite of a trap, is another trap.
</p>

<p>
	I see so many Zen devils around due to poor or insufficient theory. And of course the first thing those devils do is dismiss the value of reading or theory. How convenient for a devil to not have to read about his own devilry on the pretense that he is "too woke" to read books.
</p>

<p>
	Lol! It's absurd!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 21:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374647</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stage orange values</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31949-stage-orange-values/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374645</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9584-noselfself/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9584" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9584-noselfself/" rel="">@NoSelfSelf</a> You are getting ahead of your skiis.
</p>

<p>
	You must be honest about where you actually ARE, not some fantasy about the future.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 21:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374645</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why is there a need for survival to begin with?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31931-why-is-there-a-need-for-survival-to-begin-with/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374408</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5317-how-to-be-wise/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5317" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5317-how-to-be-wise/" rel="">@How to be wise</a> Contemplate: What is survival?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 09:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374408</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why is there a need for survival to begin with?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31931-why-is-there-a-need-for-survival-to-begin-with/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374382</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	There can be no stable forms without survival. Survival IS nothing other than the stabilization of forms within Teotl.
</p>

<p>
	Without survival you could not ask any questions.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 08:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374382</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How do you know the truth is the truth?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31939-how-do-you-know-the-truth-is-the-truth/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374380</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14954-aespinosa/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14954" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14954-aespinosa/" rel="">@aespinosa</a> Western philosophy has been trying to solve the problem of truth for over 2000 years. And they still haven't got it.
</p>

<p>
	You must appreciate how deep this problem goes.
</p>

<p>
	Nevertheless, Absolute Truth exists and it can be directly comprehended. But not in the way you're trying to do. Not by sitting there and theorizing about it. Truth is precisely not theory.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 08:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374380</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I am enlightened, ask me some, but definitely not any, thing</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31899-i-am-enlightened-ask-me-some-but-definitely-not-any-thing/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374224</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9578-sven/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9578" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9578-sven/" rel="">@Sven</a> What is it exactly that you became conscious of?
</p>

<p>
	Are you conscious of what reality is?
</p>

<p>
	Are you conscious of what other is?
</p>

<p>
	Are you conscious of why everything exists?
</p>

<p>
	Are you conscious of what God is?
</p>

<p>
	Keep in mind, there may be more to become conscious of.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 21:34:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374224</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What made the “legends of enlightenment” different?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31893-what-made-the-%E2%80%9Clegends-of-enlightenment%E2%80%9D-different/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374219</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11021-tetcher/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11021" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11021-tetcher/" rel="">@Tetcher</a> Even if there are souls and all that, genetics is still a big factor. A great soul in a crippled body will not go very far.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="374008" data-ipsquote-contentid="31893" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550756620" data-ipsquote-userid="9534" data-ipsquote-username="Rinne">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, Rinne said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Could a concentration practice solve a ADD problem? Or would one need to do brain training etc?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Such conditions often have multiple causes. You must experiment to find what the root cause is for you. Not everyone gets ADD for the same reasons.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 21:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374219</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Food Addiction - Basic Devil’s tool</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31910-food-addiction-basic-devil%E2%80%99s-tool/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374214</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11910-ar_senses/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11910" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11910-ar_senses/" rel="">@Ar_Senses</a> Great self-reflection here.
</p>

<p>
	Yeah, food is tricky because grabage food is EVERYWHERE and healthy food nowhere.
</p>

<p>
	You must basically cook all your own food if you want to eat clean.
</p>

<p>
	Diet is super important. It's really the foundation. You will not get far with self-actualization without proper diet.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 21:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374214</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is my Girlfriend Really an Illusion?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31890-is-my-girlfriend-really-an-illusion/?do=findComment&amp;comment=374000</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12556-wisebaxter/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12556" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12556-wisebaxter/" rel="">@Wisebaxter</a> No, what she's saying it not dictated by your ego.
</p>

<p>
	You and I are identical, nothing.
</p>

<p>
	The mistake you're making is you're getting too attached to perceptions and forms.
</p>

<p>
	Consider: you could have perceptions of there while I have perceptions over here, yet we are still one. I am still you. In the same way that the entire universe is one thing.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 12:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">374000</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is my Girlfriend Really an Illusion?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31890-is-my-girlfriend-really-an-illusion/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373983</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12556-wisebaxter/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12556" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12556-wisebaxter/" rel="">@Wisebaxter</a> She is YOU!
</p>

<p>
	Lol
</p>

<p>
	You're just talking to yourself in this thread. There's no one here but you.
</p>

<p>
	Do not mistake what I am saying for solipsism. As I have said before, nonduality is not solipsism. It's not that you gf or the demon is unreal. It's that they are facets of universal mind (YOU).
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 12:14:24 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373983</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What made the “legends of enlightenment” different?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31893-what-made-the-%E2%80%9Clegends-of-enlightenment%E2%80%9D-different/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373950</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11021-tetcher/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11021" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11021-tetcher/" rel="">@Tetcher</a> To me there is little difference between genetics and past lives.
</p>

<p>
	Genetics is just universal memory.
</p>

<p>
	The genetics of a donkey do not allow it to have sufficient consciousness to learn mathematics.
</p>

<p>
	Humans brains have enormous variety. We do not all have one type of brain. Each brain has unique pros and cons. Some are good at linear thinking, others at meditation, others at emotions, others at art, others a language, others at psychic powers, etc.
</p>

<p>
	No one brain does it all equally well. There are real tradeoffs.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 10:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373950</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo where do I start if everything seems fucked up?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31887-leo-where-do-i-start-if-everything-seems-fucked-up/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373947</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14836-ravlondon/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14836" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14836-ravlondon/" rel="">@ravlondon</a> I haven't watched RSD for about 3 years so I don't know what they are teaching now.
</p>

<p>
	I was assuming it would get better, not worse. But there's definitely a lot of devilry in that community. Owen has not purified himself of his own devilry last time I checked. He's taking his sweet time. His ambition is his greatest strength and weakness.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 10:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373947</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What made the “legends of enlightenment” different?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31893-what-made-the-%E2%80%9Clegends-of-enlightenment%E2%80%9D-different/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373945</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="373816" data-ipsquote-contentid="31893" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550719330" data-ipsquote-userid="9566" data-ipsquote-username="tecladocasio">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, tecladocasio said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Enlightenment has nothing to do with genetics ... 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	How much consciousness one can muster definitely depends on genetics and physiology.
</p>

<p>
	The Absolute is of course prior to genetics. But this means jack if your brain is fucked up.
</p>

<p>
	This is simply not recognized by most spiritual traditons because they are 1000 years older than genetics or neuroscience.
</p>

<p>
	If your brain is filled with lead and mercury, good luck getting enlightened. You'll have ADD so bad you will barely be able to read a book.
</p>

<p>
	The deep problem here is that genetically gifted spiritual people take their own abilities totally for granted, as if everyone has them. No they don't.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 10:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373945</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Night out report</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31747-night-out-report/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373896</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	The upside of rolling solo is that you grow very fast, as long as you're able to do approaches. If you're going out solo and you're so scared that you don't even approach, then you're not ready for that yet. You need a wingman/friend.
</p>

<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14201-brenzo2/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14201" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14201-brenzo2/" rel="">@Brenzo2</a> You mean you're in a relationship but you want to build your pickup skills at the same time? That's hard. In practice, once you get in a comfortable relationship your pickup skills will suffer. There's a trade-off.
</p>

<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/4468-joel3102/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="4468" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/4468-joel3102/" rel="">@Joel3102</a> Yes, it certainly is, but it's going to take much more work than you imagine at the outset. But the upside is that it will also be much more rewarding (in terms of growth) than you imagine. To really get good at pickup you need to hit it hardcore for a couple of years, approaching 5000+ people. You need to take it very seriously. A half-assed attitude will not work here. You basically need to rewire and retrain much of your mind. Attraction is extremely counter-intuitive. It will shock you. You'll be in for some rude awakening. It will be emotionally difficult. But it will grow you like crazy. If you do it, don't do it for the sex, do it for the stronger man it makes you. It can also be very fun and exciting compared to sitting at home and playing Fortnite. Doing pickup hardcore makes you feel ALIVE! It makes you feel like a hero on his journey towards manhood.
</p>

<p>
	I highly recommend handling this part of your life. Just don't be a douche, don't hurt women, and don't develop an ideology or identity around it.
</p>

<p>
	If you want to get serious about learning this skill set, you must bite the bullet and move to a large city with great nightlife and lots of hot girls. LA, NYC, Chicago, Miami, Austin, Vegas, London, etc. It's very worth it. Don't be trying to learn pickup in some redneck part of the world. You need volume to practice on. If you're not willing to relocate, you're not very serious about it.
</p>

<p>
	But at the same time, don't make excuses if you can't relocate immediately. Begin wherever you're at and make plan to upgrade your situation.
</p>

<p>
	Pickup is not just about attracting girls. Pickup is about upgrading your entire lifestyle. It's about better nutrition, better fitness, better apartment, better decor, better cloths, better haircut, better friends, better car, better everything. Transform yourself into an attractive fucking man with an awesome life such that a woman would be itching to be around you. Shed your old childish ways. Become awesome. When you become a truly awesome, valuable man, guys and girls will flock to be around you. This is not some gimmick. You are actually becoming awesome. It's a total makeover.
</p>

<p>
	But also don't get lost in it. Return to spirituality once you've completed that phase of your life.
</p>

<p>
	P.S. There are always limits to everything a human does. Don't let that stop you from being awesome. You don't need to sleep with 100 girls. You don't need to become the Michael Jordan of pickup. You just need to become decent and score a few girlfriends. Which basically any guy can do.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 08:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373896</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why No Actualized Events?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31896-why-no-actualized-events/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373894</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I hope to do a Tour in the future. We have a thread about it. But the Tour has been delayed as I work on myself.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 07:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373894</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Funny opinion from Neil Degrasse Tyson about Perception</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31855-funny-opinion-from-neil-degrasse-tyson-about-perception/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373892</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I'm just looking out for Tyson's job. He's got to eat too <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 07:51:53 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373892</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Self-Inquiry/Meditation tips</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31898-self-inquirymeditation-tips/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373891</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14618-alexander-goffrier/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14618" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14618-alexander-goffrier/" rel="">@Alexander Goffrier</a> The biggest challenge with spiritual work is that the mind refuses to do it. And the closer you get the Truth, the more the mind resists.
</p>

<p>
	There cannot be spirituality without self-discipline and training.
</p>

<p>
	There is no magic trick for avoiding this. It must be faced. Which grows you in and of itself.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 07:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373891</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Combining Spiral Dynamics with my geography class</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31866-combining-spiral-dynamics-with-my-geography-class/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373890</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12889-ampresus/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12889" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12889-ampresus/" rel="">@Ampresus</a> Do you care more about pleasing your teacher, or speaking truth with people?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 07:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373890</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo where do I start if everything seems fucked up?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31887-leo-where-do-i-start-if-everything-seems-fucked-up/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373815</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/742-carlos/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="742" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/742-carlos/" rel="">@Carlos</a> At your age all of that is totally normal. The good news is you're actually way ahead of the curve because you've already found the most important thing: the field of personal development and spirituality. Most people won't find these fields until they are 30, 40, or 50 years old.
</p>

<p>
	Since you're only 17 you've got many many years to resolve all those issues.
</p>

<p>
	I have made multiple videos where I give a blueprint of how to begin doing personal development and I give long lists of techniques.
</p>

<p>
	Just pick a thing and start working on it. Focus on whatever your heart wants most. If it's girls, then go chat up girls. A very simple exercise is to go to the local mall on the weekends and start trying to have conversations with shop clerks. Try to chat them up. Don't even hit on them, just chat with them. Try to make the conversation last for 5, 10, 15 minutes. Try to make them laugh.
</p>

<p>
	After practicing that for a few months, then start applying those exact same skills at school by approaching random girls at lunch. Girls you don't know. Just teach yourself how to socialize. You don't even need pickup skills at this point. Learn to have conversations with strangers. Learn small talk. Learn eye contact. Learn how to talk about yourself. Learn how to tell interesting stories. Learn how to smile. Learn how to project your voice. Learn how to be friendly.
</p>

<p>
	All of this stuff has been written about in books and talked about in videos ad nauseam. Just go apply it. Break it down into small actionable steps.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 03:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373815</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Family Question for Leo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31801-family-question-for-leo/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373813</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="373390" data-ipsquote-contentid="31801" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550654106" data-ipsquote-userid="13884" data-ipsquote-username="ActualizedDavid">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		22 hours ago, ActualizedDavid said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			don't you think you have a tendency to prove something to your parents?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I'm not trying to prove anything to my parents. After all the talking I do via my videos, I'm good.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 03:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373813</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Love &amp; Belonging need</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31894-love-belonging-need/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373812</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6867-tashawoodfall/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6867" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6867-tashawoodfall/" rel="">@tashawoodfall</a> The issue is, someone who hasn't satisfied the Love & Belonging need will not be capable of self-love. Or at least they will not believe that self-love can help because they think they need other-love.
</p>

<p>
	So can you? Yes.
</p>

<p>
	Will you? I wouldn't bet on it.
</p>

<p>
	Learn to crawl before you fly. Self-love is much harder than finding someone else to love you. Self-love requires a lot of maturity and consciousness to execute.
</p>

<p>
	Isn't it true that you hate yourself? Think about what it would take to never hate yourself again.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 03:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373812</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>LEO- Spirituality vs Relationships, Advice.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31878-leo-spirituality-vs-relationships-advice/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373810</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6180-kalki-avatar/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6180" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6180-kalki-avatar/" rel="">@Kalki Avatar</a> Notice how in your relationships, you never actually relate to the actual person. You're always just relating to your own needs, the way that person fits into your life. The relationship is always about you relating not who she is, but to your fantasies of what you want and need her to be. But the actual her never lives up to your fantasies so you try to change her over and over again, which still doesn't work, until eventually you give up and leave.
</p>

<p>
	YOU ARE ALWAYS RELATING TO YOUR OWN EGO! Not to what is actual. You don't give a rats ass about what is actual. You want to live in a fantasy. But you want it to feel like its real. So you just call your fantasy reality.
</p>

<p>
	EVERYTHING YOU DO IS YOU MAINTAINING YOUR OWN FANTASY. Every thought you have and every emotion you feel is part of this effort. Notice this. Then maybe you can learn how to relate to things actually.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 02:56:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373810</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is my Girlfriend Really an Illusion?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31890-is-my-girlfriend-really-an-illusion/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373807</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="373742" data-ipsquote-contentid="31890" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550709939" data-ipsquote-userid="12556" data-ipsquote-username="Wisebaxter">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, Wisebaxter said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I brought up the idea that I don't actually know if she exists. She assured me she does and sounded convincing, so what's going on here?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Lol
</p>

<p>
	Your logic is like this:
</p>

<p>
	Doctor: "Bob, you've got psychosis. You are hallucinating demons."
</p>

<p>
	Bob: "But doctor! How could that be so? Hold on doc, let me check. Hey, demon! Come here. Now answer me truthfully demon: You really exist right? I can trust you right?"
</p>

<p>
	Demon: "Yes, of course you can trust me Bob. I'm totally real. I would never lie to you."
</p>

<p>
	Bob: "Ah good. I knew I wasn't crazy. See doctor! I'm not crazy. I asked the demon and it assured me that it's real and it sounded convincing. So what's going on here doctor? How do you explain it?"
</p>

<p>
	Demon: "Don't trust anything the doctor says Bob. Better yet, maybe you should just kill him. After all, he's clearly a bad doctor if he thinks you're crazy. If you don't kill him, this doctor might harm many innocent patients like yourself over his long career. So yeah, it's best if you kill him and make a soup out of his remains. There's good nutrition in those bones. Would be a shame to let those juicy bones go to waste. Quickly now! Just bonk him over the head with this hammer."
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 02:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373807</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What made the “legends of enlightenment” different?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31893-what-made-the-%E2%80%9Clegends-of-enlightenment%E2%80%9D-different/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373796</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Contemplate how many thousands of people even greater than Jesus, Buddha, and Mahavira lived and died, but you never knew about them due to lack of marketing.
</p>

<p>
	The things you know about you only know about for one reason: someone marketed the shit out of them. Not because they are the best.
</p>

<p>
	What made them different was that they were genetically predisposed to it. They are freaks of nature, like someone who is 7 ft tall. Good luck beating him at basketball. Mental capacities are correlated to the brain. You are never going to get a donkey to understand trigonometry.
</p>

<p>
	And now, for those of you who are eager to turn what I said into a victim mindset about how you can't achieve enlightenment. We'll that's nonsense. You can. You're just making excuses. It would be like arguing that you can't play basketball since you're not 7 ft tall. You don't need to be 7 ft tall to play basketball. Will you be the best basketball player in the world at 5ft tall? No. But being the the best in the world is an ego trip. Let it go. Just be the best that YOU can be.
</p>

<p>
	Don't try to be Sadhguru or Buddha or Christ. Be you.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 02:18:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373796</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Combining Spiral Dynamics with my geography class</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31866-combining-spiral-dynamics-with-my-geography-class/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373735</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Spiral Dynamics is not a good model for explaining in 15 minutes. You're gonna feel very rushed and people will not really understand it in that short a time. It's likely to confuse them or misinform them.
</p>

<p>
	For example, calling the USA Blue is far too simplistic and will lead to incorrect conclusions. Spiral Dynamics needs to be complex because it's describing very complex phenomena.
</p>

<p>
	Perhaps choose a different topic.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373735</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bernie Sanders</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31846-bernie-sanders/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373732</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9705-lmfao/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9705" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9705-lmfao/" rel="">@lmfao</a> That all sounds fine. My only issue is that I don't see him having a chance in hell of winning the Democrat primaries. He won't even be in the top 5.
</p>

<p>
	Besides being good on policies a politician needs to be charismatic, able to rally people behind him, and excite his base.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373732</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bernie Sanders</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31846-bernie-sanders/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373710</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="373708" data-ipsquote-contentid="31846" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550704455" data-ipsquote-userid="5317" data-ipsquote-username="How to be wise">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		5 minutes ago, How to be wise said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			After you see the world as an illusion, doing ceases. Decisions and actions are made spontaneously. I’m only following whatever arises to me.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	And what's rising in you now is foolishness.
</p>

<p>
	Let's see what tune you sing when someone takes a dump in your soup.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 23:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373710</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bernie Sanders</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31846-bernie-sanders/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373707</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9705-lmfao/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9705" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9705-lmfao/" rel="">@lmfao</a> Again, you also have to be realistic. Does the person you're voting for really have a chance of winning? Will your donation go to waste?
</p>

<p>
	Simple-mindedly voting for the highest stage candidate is not good enough. Because society might not be ready for stage Yellow yet, or because stage Yellow might not be the right counter-balance to stage Blue & Orange in the way that stage Green might be. You have to consider all these nuances. There are many stage Yellow people in the world who would not make for effective politicians or who might not introduce significant enough policy proposals. Dealing with the hardcore right in this country is not easy. You have to know how to drive a hard bargain. Meeting them half-way often doesn't work so well (as we saw with Obama). Sometimes a good battle is necessary to bring the losing position into collective awareness.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 23:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373707</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bernie Sanders</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31846-bernie-sanders/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373701</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="373695" data-ipsquote-contentid="31846" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550703282" data-ipsquote-userid="5317" data-ipsquote-username="How to be wise">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		10 minutes ago, How to be wise said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Materialist paradigm much? 
		</p>

		<p>
			The world exists only as thoughts and beliefs; it is not real. So voting really does not matter. The future is an illusion; only beliefs and thoughts. Same with the past.
		</p>

		<p>
			As for whether or not I vote, I really don’t bother with that. Doership is an illusion. Whether or not you vote will be decided by the body after you clear it of all its shadow/fears. It will think and move on its own.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Read what I wrote again. I was specifically talking about this very trap you just fell into. It's the trap of absolutism.
</p>

<p>
	When all you have is hammer, everything looks like a nail. << That's you
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 23:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373701</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bernie Sanders</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31846-bernie-sanders/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373671</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Spiral stages are equal in the absolute sense but are inferior/superior in the relative sense.
</p>

<p>
	Just like drinking pure spring water is relatively better for a human being than drinking water from a public toilet. But in the absolute sense, the toilet water is no worse than spring water.
</p>

<p>
	The value of water is RELATIVE to the health of a human being. So it is important IF you care about human health. It is not important in the absolute sense.
</p>

<p>
	When it comes to politics and issues of governance be careful not to adopt too much of an absolute perspective, since politics is a question of pragmatic solutions for issues of survival. Poliltics requires a pragmatic eye. What will actually improve peoples lives? What will put mankind in harmony with our environment? Taking an absolute stance on such questions is a mistake.
</p>

<p>
	For example, naive people pursuing nonduality might wrongly conclude that after enlightenment voting no longer matters because they are now so above politics. So they stop voting. But then that action might lead to a facist getting elected and starting WWIII or outlawing spirituality. There cannot be a decent society without voting. Good luck getting enlightened in North Korea. It is not enough to just get enlightened, you must also help to create a society where other people can get enlightened like you did. It is not right to say, "Well, I'm enlightened now, so fuck ya'll." Because you would have never gotten enlightened if all enlightened people took that attitude. The path to your awakening was laid by millions of people working for thousands of years to create a society which would allow it. So it would be kind of you to return the favor.
</p>

<p>
	Remember the important role that balance plays in earthly life. The point of politics is to get our collective balance right, so we don't fall into collective disease.
</p>

<p>
	No one is above politics. Not as long as you care about living. By not voting, you've cast your vote for the status quo.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 22:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373671</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What actually changes when your consciousness increases?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31815-what-actually-changes-when-your-consciousness-increases/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373668</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="373622" data-ipsquote-contentid="31815" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550693597" data-ipsquote-userid="12740" data-ipsquote-username="FredFred">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, FredFred said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> On one end some people say that everything there is is consciousness, on the other end some say the only thing there is is Nothingness. I'm a bit confused here, can you give a quick explanation?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Consciousness = Nothingness = Everything
</p>

<p>
	But the question is, how conscious are you?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 21:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373668</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>LEO- Spirituality vs Relationships, Advice.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31878-leo-spirituality-vs-relationships-advice/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373667</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6180-kalki-avatar/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6180" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6180-kalki-avatar/" rel="">@Kalki Avatar</a> Sounds like the typical relationship.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 21:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373667</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What actually changes when your consciousness increases?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31815-what-actually-changes-when-your-consciousness-increases/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373609</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Consciousness is irreducible -- since it is the only thing there is. What changes is your degree of consciousness. You need to get an experiential hit on what degrees of consciousness are. Psychedelics are the easiest way to do that.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 19:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373609</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Funny opinion from Neil Degrasse Tyson about Perception</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/31855-funny-opinion-from-neil-degrasse-tyson-about-perception/?do=findComment&amp;comment=373606</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="373427" data-ipsquote-contentid="31855" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1550663237" data-ipsquote-userid="7997" data-ipsquote-username="MM1988">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, MM1988 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			"just get the human out of it"
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	In that case there is no science.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 19:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">373606</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>