<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Leo's Blog: Infinite Insights - Actualized.org</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leo's Blog: Infinite Insights - Actualized.org]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 06:42:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Green New Deal Town Hall</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/green-new-deal-town-hall</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A substantive discussion of how to address climate change. An example of conscious politics happening in the real world.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yoFaQ9foV8I?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez is an amazing conscious politician, uncorrupted by corporate money.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/green-new-deal-town-hall</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Political Spiral Stages</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/political-spiral-stages</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Slide from my Conscious Politics - Part 2 video:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/political-spiral-01.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4305" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/political-spiral-01.png" alt="political-spiral-01" width="615" /></a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/political-spiral-stages</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Taste Of Infinity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-taste-of-infinity</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a small look into the mind of God:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zXTpASSd9xE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Contemplate: How is it possible to zoom into a thing forever? What does this mean about the nature of reality?</p>
<p>Just the fact that this fractal exists should already clue you in that consciousness must be infinite. Otherwise how could you be conscious of it? If an infinite object was loaded into a finite mind, the mind would crash. Hence the mind itself must be infinite.</p>
<p>Consider this: In a finite reality it would be impossible to count up from 1 to infinity. This is only possible because consciousness is actually infinite.</p>
<p>But how can the human mind be infinite? Because the human mind is a virtual machine running inside the infinite mind of God. God's mind is running an infinite number of virtual machines, all which are themselves infinite. That's what Georg Cantor called the Absolute Infinite set. It is the super-set of all possible sets. The mindblowing nature of infinity is that you can divide it into an infinite number of parts, and each of those parts will be its own infinity. Infinity within infinity within infinity — to infinity! In other words, infinity literally allows you to create something from nothing, because infinity is endless and bottomless.</p>
<p>Consider this: If you have an infinite number of apples in a basket, you can pull out one apple, eat it, and you will still have an infinite number of apples left. You just created an apple from nothing! Ta-da! This is how God creates the universe. It's mind is not bound by any physical limitation or lack. It cannot lack anything because it is an unlimited fount of creativity. All it has to do to create a thing is subdivide itself. But it can subdivide itself infinitely many times, so it never loses anything in the process of creation. Even after God subdivides itself an infinite number of time to create all human minds, it still remains an infinite Unity. The Absolute Unity of all possible divisions. Absolute Unity turns out to be identical to division. Going full-circle.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-taste-of-infinity</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Nazis Win Elections</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-nazis-win-elections</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you're a student of history you've probably wondered, "How in the hell did Hitler get democratically elected? It doesn't make sense that people would willing support a guy like that."</p>
<p>Well, this is how:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6qvB5tHRNOI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gu7n0_gVgTc?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Trumpism is a case study in demagoguery, collective self-deception, group think, cult psychology, ideology, egotism, devilry, ignorance, unconsciousness, selfishness, division, projection, scapegoating, demonization, judgment, denial, self-bias, confirmation bias, corruption, xenophobia, racism, and fear.</p>
<p>All the epistemic stuff we cover in-depth on Actualized.org all comes together in the real world like this.</p>
<p>A toxic brew of the most pathological aspects of Spiral Dynamics stage Red, Blue, and Orange.</p>
<p>You might wonder, But why do people eat it up? Because they are at those same levels of development/consciousness themselves. Birds of a feather flock together. Your politics directly correlates with your values, which correlates with your stage of ego development. You can only vote for a leader as high as your vision can see. So egotistical, ethnocentric people gladly vote for egotistical, ethnocentric leaders, especially when the leader pushes their fear buttons.</p>
<p>Watch out, the 2020 election is going to get very nasty. Trump's demagoguery will hit an all time high as his ego gets cornered by his own manipulations. One of the hallmarks of a giant ego is that it refuses to yield or admit wrong-doing or defeat. When Trump loses, he will have to deny it to himself and his supporters somehow. And there begins the heavy-duty devilry. There will likely be blood.</p>
<p>This is what happens when a dense ego is put into a position of power. It's not an issue of left vs right, the issue is density of ego.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-nazis-win-elections</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Highest Purpose</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-highest-purpose</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Pasting this from my personal journal:</p>
<p>My highest purpose is to lead people to Infinite Consciousness, Infinite Love, Infinite Selflessness, and Infinite Understanding. I am to show people what the highest form of leadership looks like. My entire life is dedicated to this cause. I am to lead people to the realization of Infinite Love and Infinite Beauty by embodiment and demonstration of Infinite Love in my own life. I am a vehicle for God's highest Love for mankind. The function of my human existence is to demonstrate the Goodness and Magnitude of God to those who lack the vision to see it. I am to use the gift of my extraordinary human mind to communicate God's highest intentions. I am not to hold back my love out of fear or selfish need. I am to be fearless and selfless and endure any consequences and suffering which will arise from such a path. The endurance of these obstacles and pain is part of my purification process. The suffering I endure will only make me more loving and understanding of the suffering of others, who are none other than myself. I am to shed all ill-will, malice, and judgment towards others, for I cannot help but see them as myself. In the end, the love and selflessness I radiate will inspire and transform the world. My reward will be the love I radiate and Infinite Understanding of the universe. My understanding will reach superhuman levels beyond all human comprehension or and strain the human self to contain. There is no doubt that this my way. I will have many critics and naysayers, but none of them will deter me because all of them I will be overcome simply by radiating more love because I understand that their ignorance is their limited way of showing their love. I understand that all hatred, judgment, and violence is just a condensed form of love. Through total self-understanding I will become incapable of seeing wrong or evil, even in those who seek to harm me. By the end of my human life the highest potential of a human life will have been actualized. The details of how all of this unfolds will be unimportant, as it will simply unfold as it must. My body and mind is at the highest service of Universal Intelligence. The point of no return has already been reached so no further decision is necessary. All of this is self-evidently true. When I lose track of my highest purpose (and I will) I am to return here and re-read this statement, re-grounding myself in that which is undeniable.</p>
<p>Actualized 2.0 is coming. Brace yourself for a sledgehammer of Love.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-highest-purpose</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 9 Stages Of Ego Development</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-9-stages-of-ego-development</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This 97-page research paper by Susanne Cook-Greuter is one of the most important things you can read if you want to understand human development:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cook-greuter.com/Cook-Greuter%209%20levels%20paper%20new%201.1'14%2097p%5B1%5D.pdf" target="_blank">Nine Levels Of Increasing Embrace In Ego Development</a></p>
<p>I recommend you download it, print it out, and read it methodically with a highlighter. It's filled with insights and wisdom you won't find anywhere else.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cook-greuter.com/" target="_blank">Cook-Greuter</a> is a Harvard educated yet independent developmental psychologist. So this research has some scientific weight behind it, based on empirical research.</p>
<p>This will take your understanding of developmental psychology & Spiral Dynamics to the next level.</p>
<p>It also dovetails with my discussion of Conscious Politics, since the quality of one's politics directly depends on the development of one's ego.</p>
<p>We will be talking a lot more about developmental psychology in the future. So this is required reading for that. Spiral Dynamics is only one part of the larger field of developmental psychology.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-9-stages-of-ego-development</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Infinite Love Awakening</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-love-awakening</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/347395943?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-love-awakening</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Government Really Works</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-government-really-works</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a little taste of the brutality and sneakiness of government. This is the dirty business of creating a society:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BT254smRufA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Russia is a Spiral Dynamics Stage Red government. It's government by mafia rule. Be careful not to judge it too much because your government had to go through this stage of development before it evolved higher. You don't get a high functioning democracy without a lot of theft, beatings, torture, slit throats, bullets to the head, and rape.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-government-really-works</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Fractal Of Life</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-fractal-of-life</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w77zPAtVTuI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Contemplate why this is happening. What is this about? Why expansion? Why branching? Why life? What is the universe up to?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-fractal-of-life</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Zooming Into God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/zooming-into-god</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I find microscope pictures more awe-inspiring than cosmic pictures. Remember, reality zooms to infinity in both directions. And actually there are more than two directions and more than 3 dimensions. But for now, study closely the intelligence behind the design of the microscopic world:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j6B-HYsvkvo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LE2v3sUzTH4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Consciousness is an infinite fractal of pure intelligence. This is what you're really waking up to. This is what you are.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/zooming-into-god</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>4000 Exo-Planets Found</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/4000-exo-planets-found</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The first extra-solar planet was discovered in 1992. Up to now 4000 have been discovered.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aiFD_LBx2nM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>There are approximately 250 billion stars in 1 galaxy.</p>
<p>There are approximately 2 trillion galaxies in our universe.</p>
<p>If there are an average of 3 planets per star, that means there are 1,500,000,000,000,000,000,000,000 planets in our universe.</p>
<p>But all of that is just but an infinitesimally small speck of dust within Infinite Consciousness. All those planets are as far away from infinity as the number 3.</p>
<p>It takes Infinite Consciousness less than a nanosecond to dream all that up.</p>
<p>It has no beginning or end. It goes on forever. It is unlimited.</p>
<p>Imagine holding all of that form within your consciousness.</p>
<p>Try to comprehend that. That is the mind of God.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/4000-exo-planets-found</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tapping Into Collective Consciousness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/tapping-into-collective-consciousness</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/346781327?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/tapping-into-collective-consciousness</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vice's Liberal vs Conservative Panels</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/vices-liberal-vs-conservative-panels</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Vice has some excellent discussion panels featuring diverse political and cultural perspectives.</p>
<p>The panels struck me as highly valuable because they require you to open your mind to alternative POVs. As you watch, pay extra attention to how you get triggered and how you judge these people. This is not about determining who's right or wrong but about going meta to see the relativity of all perspectives. Relativity is what explains why these folks see the world so differently. It's not that ones are right and others are wrong, but that each ego-mind sees the world according to its survival needs and whatever ideologies it was programmed with during its development.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WMvih_KEMWo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>That's just a taste, there's much more and I recommend you watch them all:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IVIoC5ROaHk" target="_blank">Black Conservatives Debate Black Liberals</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=utW1ItcMeJw" target="_blank">LGBTQ+ Conservatives Debate Liberals - Part 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=safLwed9SSo" target="_blank">LGBTQ+ Conservatives Debate Liberals - Part 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I9I6b1JEb2k" target="_blank">Latino Conservatives Debate Liberals - Part 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fyymEC8FQHU" target="_blank">Latino Conservatives Debate Liberals - Part 2</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Really, really, really pay attention to how you judge POVs which are not your own. Also notice how you judge people purely based on their race, gender, clothing, religion, and style of speaking. The point is to notice that you are extremely judgmental and dismissive of any worldview which is not aligned with your own. Notice that alternative POVs are a threat to you — notice how you fear them.</p>
<p>These panels make for a good consciousness litmus test. The more developed and conscious you are, the more you are able hear all these diverse perspectives without judging them, recognizing them to be aspects of yourself.</p>
<p>Note: non-judgment does not mean that you adopt their opinions, nor does it mean that you adopt the average of all their opinions. Both would be a mistake.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/vices-liberal-vs-conservative-panels</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Do I Doubt Myself?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/do-i-doubt-myself</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/346519383?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/do-i-doubt-myself</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Cult Of Andrew Cohen</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-cult-of-andrew-cohen</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to share this video in the hopes that it will inoculate some of you against joining or starting enlightenment cults.</p>
<p>The key point: Just because the leader of a spiritual group has some degree of awakening does not mean it's not a cult! Many cults weave together legit spiritual teachings with devilry. Think twice before joining any spiritual community.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X3ess8txBX0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>For more about cults, see my two part series:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/cult-psychology-part-1" target="_blank">Cult Psychology - Part 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/cult-psychology-part-2" target="_blank">Cult Psychology - Part 2</a></li>
</ul>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-cult-of-andrew-cohen</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Wise Patriot</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-wise-patriot</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I randomly stumbled upon this southern military guy on Youtube and was pleasantly surprised by his progressive thinking! It's great to see some military folk and southern folk speaking out against the dangers of modern conservativism. This is what I call smart patriotism.</p>
<p>This dude's dishing out some serious common sense. Check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/unvoicedproject/videos" target="_blank">his channel</a> for more gems. Although I disagree with his deeper advocacy of anarchism. Anarchism cannot work at the scale of 100s of millions of people.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CGeKdAWnnxc?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/APoQuX5M2P4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-wise-patriot</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Smart Patriot</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-smart-patriot</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I randomly stumbled upon this southern military guy on Youtube and was pleasantly surprised by his progressive thinking! It's great to see some military folk and southern folk speaking out against the dangers of modern conservativism. This is what I call smart patriotism.</p>
<p>This dude's dishing out some serious common sense. Check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/unvoicedproject/videos" target="_blank">his channel</a> for more gems.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CGeKdAWnnxc?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/APoQuX5M2P4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-smart-patriot</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>New York Post UFO Series</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/new-york-post-ufo-series</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>It's ironic that the New York Post — a trashy, gossipy, right-wing tabloid said to be a favorite newspaper of Donald Trump — would be capable of producing a high-quality, well-researched mini-series about UFOs.</p>
<p>But here it is! Sometimes you find a diamond in a pile of shit. This series is well done and worth watching with an open mind.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uaSY2Zc0goQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>There are many episodes in the series:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z25NfZ0Ea9c" target="_blank">Episode 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tDUF4NtYtxU" target="_blank">Episode 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=656VqWTnKmw" target="_blank">Episode 4</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gy5tIevquP0" target="_blank">Episode 5</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IaYfsxbiKsM" target="_blank">Episode 6</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And they are still releasing new episodes each week, so stay tuned.</p>
<p>As always, think critically for yourself about this controversial topic. I am not suggesting you construct a UFO ideology but rather consider the empirical evidence in an openminded fashion. You don't know what you don't know. I find the mountains of evidence hard to explain away as mere delusion or fantasy. Something weird is going on.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/new-york-post-ufo-series</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Power Of Imaginary Boundaries</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-power-of-imaginary-boundaries</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>One of our biggest themes with Actualized.org is understanding how the human mind, (and all of reality), creates boundaries. Notice that all of life runs on division, partition, distinction, and duality. Even at the most basic thermodynamic level, energy moves across difference gradients. No difference gradient, no movement, no life.</p>
<p>But it's not enough to understand this in the abstract. We must go deeper, examining concrete instances of how this manifests across human life. Which is why I love the following video. It shows you in concrete terms how division, partition, distinction, and duality shape all human behaviors.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r5Ps1TZXAN8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>All boundaries are imaginary. But notice how these imaginary boundaries serve as the fuel or engine driving all of life! Notice the enormous consequences that a single imaginary boundary can have. Now multiply this by infinity and you get LIFE!</p>
<p>What is war, conflict, disagreement, and violence about at the existential level? It's fighting over boundary definitions. Who's imaginary boundary will prevail? Who gets to say how the cake should be sliced?</p>
<p>Do you see the big picture of life?</p>
<p>If you object that some boundaries are physical and not merely imaginary, notice that that itself is an imaginary boundary which you created and are now defending! Since reality is one giant Universal Mind, all boundaries, including "physical" boundaries, exist within its imagination. To imagine a thing is to create a boundary between that thing and that which it is not. That's what being a thing is! That's what imagination is! Universal Mind is creating differences, which constitutes reality, which animates life, which leads to conflict, which leads to destruction of differences — thus going full-circle forever and ever, without beginning or end.</p>
<p>Division leading to unification leading back to division. Division within division within division. Unification after unification after unification.</p>
<p>That which is separated must ultimately unite. That which is united must ultimately separate. And in between, life happens. Ta-da!</p>
<p>Here's another brilliant micro example of how this plays out in human life:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qBfyIQbxXPs?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-power-of-imaginary-boundaries</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mapping Consciousness With High Dose LSD</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/mapping-consciousness-with-high-dose-lsd</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is an exceptionally important video. Watch it from beginning to end.</p>
<p>It's an outstanding interview with an academically trained philosopher who took 70+ high doses of LSD over 20 years to explore the deepest reaches of Universal Mind.</p>
<p>His growth curve closely matches my own after 65+ psychedelic trips over the last 2 years. It's a journey into ever deeper layers of Universal Mind and Infinite Consciousness which seems to have no end. Every trip leads to deeper and deeper understanding and integration of Universal Mind.</p>
<p>This is what the psychedelic spiritual path looks like. It's rare to see someone talking about it because most people trip merely for recreation and in serious circles psychedelics are stigmatized. Few people turn psychedelics into a serious spiritual path, but I see that changing in the future as the stigma gradually erodes.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L3D_fSr75u8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/mapping-consciousness-with-high-dose-lsd</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sense Organs Are Imaginary</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/sense-organs-are-imaginary</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/344949738?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/sense-organs-are-imaginary</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reverse-Engineering UFO Spacecraft</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/reverse-engineering-ufo-spacecraft</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A damn fascinating interview by Joe Rogan:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BEWz4SXfyCQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Is it true?</p>
<p>I have no direct experience of UFOs, but Lazar's story seems highly plausible. There are just too many eye-witness accounts of UFOs at this point to deny their underlying reality. The skeptical position is more deluded than the thousands of eye-witness accounts.</p>
<p>Of course in the end, all aliens are just part of Infinite Consciousness. So it's really not a big deal. Realizing Infinite Consciousness is way more radical than reverse-engineering UFO spacecraft. Discovering aliens is peanuts compared to what you will discover at the moment of awakening: it's all imaginary! Dogs, cats, trees, people, aliens, Earth, history, science, the universe, birth, death, suffering, memories, your parents, etc. If you can experience it, you are imagining it.</p>
<p>The conspiracy is not that the government is hiding aliens from you. The real conspiracy is that you are imagining the government!</p>
<p>P.S. You should also distinguish UFOs from DMT entities. These are not the same thing. UFOs are within the human physical dimension. DMT entities are in another dimension entirely.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/reverse-engineering-ufo-spacecraft</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>DPT: The Other God Molecule</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/dpt-the-other-god-molecule</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Could DPT be the world's most powerful nondual psychedelic? Even more powerful than 5-MeO-DMT?</p>
<p>It was for me!</p>
<p>Here's my DPT trip report:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/343774863?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Discussion taking place on the forum here: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/36240-discovered-new-psychedelic-more-powerful-than-5-meo-dmt/" target="_blank">The DPT Mega-Thread</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/dpt-the-other-god-molecule</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>3 Kinds Of Socialism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/3-kinds-of-socialism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Mainstream culture does a terrible job of informing people what socialism actually means. There's much fear-mongering and confusion surrounding this word. Professor Richard Wolff is great antidote to such ignorance.</p>
<p>With that said, please take a nuanced view of this issue. I am not posting this to convert you to socialism, but rather to get you thinking about the limits of capitalism. I have some important critiques of socialism, so it's not as simple as me favoring socialism over capitalism. And I don't agree with everything that Richard Wolff advances. But there is much to be learned from his presentations and I recommend you think about this topic critically yet openmindedly and come to your own conclusions.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p7x7oVwhHok?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>While I don't consider myself a socialist (I enjoy private ownership of my business), the limits of capitalism are simply undeniable at this point. We need to look towards the next evolution of our economy. That will not be pure capitalism nor pure socialism but some hybrid system. The question then becomes where to draw the lines. This requires a nuanced, non-ideological understanding of the pros and cons of both systems.</p>
<p>The point of upgrading our economic system is to allow as many people as possible to have the financial freedom to maximize the development of their consciousness. Our current economic system is so unfair and oppressive that most human beings on the planet are so deeply stuck in wage slavery that they are seriously hampered in their ability to develop their consciousness. And this ends up costing the entire human species.</p>
<p>The most important aspect of socialism which Richard Wolff talks about is democratizing the workplace. The core problem under our current system is that workers do not have any voting power or ownership share within the companies they work for. This effectively makes corporations dictatorships, with a few powerful elites dictating the corporation's actions, reaping all the rewards, and pocketing all the productivity gains from technological innovation. The stockholders of most corporations do not work in the corporation, creating a conflict between their agenda for max dividends and the needs of the people who do the actual daily work in the corporation. This then leads to gross wealth inequality across society as the rich get richer and richer beyond anything they reasonably need, while the vast majority struggle to survive. Since the workers have zero voting power they are easily exploited because their agenda rarely a concern for the all-powerful corporate dictators. These corporate dictatorships then turn into metastasizing cancers which become so powerful no individual can ever compete with them. These giant corporations create monopolies which eat up many opportunities for small independent entrepreneurs, leaving people with little choice but wage slavery.</p>
<p>Unfortunately the solution to this problem is not easy or clear. But we have no choice but to figure it out. And we cannot figure it out unless the population is properly educated about capitalism and socialism in a nuanced way.</p>
<p>P.S. Check out <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/democracyatwrk/videos" target="_blank">Richard Wolff's YouTube channel</a> for more.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/3-kinds-of-socialism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who Really Rules The World?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/who-really-rules-the-world</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZUGh1Su7-ok?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/who-really-rules-the-world</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who Are The Machine Elves?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/who-are-the-machine-elves</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Great video. But hold on to your hat. Radical openmindedness required.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yl38wIkeExs?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Note: meeting entities on a few grams of mushrooms as this guy describes is very rare. He is clearly an exceptional case. Ordinary folk will have much better luck with N,N-DMT.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/who-are-the-machine-elves</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>6 Fingered</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/6-fingered</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is nuts:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LlfPIKQmPok?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/6-fingered</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding Flatland</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-flatland</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a useful way of thinking for understanding relativity, points of view, paradigms, and the ultimate nature of reality. It's a good foundation for when you're tripping as it teaches you to think multi-dimensionally.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N0WjV6MmCyM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-flatland</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dissecting The Psychedelic Experience</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/dissecting-the-psychedelic-experience</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I don't necessarily agree with everything this guy says, but overall a great video:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tETZpw7sX98?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/dissecting-the-psychedelic-experience</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bernie Sanders Visionary</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/bernie-sanders-visionary</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is what outstanding, visionary leadership looks like:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nbN9OD83f5I?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Notice that visionary leadership is not meek or neutral. It is bold and decisive. It is not afraid to challenge cultural norms and call out devilry.</p>
<p>This is exactly what America and the world needs.</p>
<p>But of course the devils will not just standby and let a visionary do his thing. They will resist every step of the way out of selfishness, fear, ignorance, and closedmindedness.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/bernie-sanders-visionary</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Total Omniscience Awakening</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/total-omniscience-awakening</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/341701275?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/total-omniscience-awakening</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Catch Me If You Can</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/catch-me-if-you-can</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I like this talk by the real-life person from the movie, Catch Me If You Can.</p>
<p>Frank Abagnale's life of con-artistry is a perfect case-study in how survival and devilry work.</p>
<p>What's great about his story is that in the end he redeemed himself (if he is to be believed). He now works for the FBI helping catch devils like his former self.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vsMydMDi3rI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/catch-me-if-you-can</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>No Video This Week</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/no-video-this-week</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>No main video this week as I'm integrating a profound recent awakening.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/no-video-this-week</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Study Survival In Animals</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/study-survival-in-animals</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Observe survival strategies not just in yourself and in humans, but also in animals.</p>
<p>Notice how your life is, fundamentally, just another version of this:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fnP-m2KRxi0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The details of your life are totally different, but the basic structure is identical to that jerboa. You're just a big jerboa trying to survive in 21st century society. That's your whole life in a nutshell.</p>
<p>Ta-da! ;)</p>
<p>P.S. Also notice how utterly intelligent survival is! It is intelligence of the highest order.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/study-survival-in-animals</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thoughts On Unconditional Love</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/thoughts-on-unconditional-love</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is an entry from my private journal which I wrote to myself. It shows my thought process in coming to grips with advanced spiritual truths:</p>
<p>Why can't I love unconditionally? Why don't humans love unconditionally? Because we have survival requirements. Because I am a specific way, I am predisposed to love certain things more than others. Of course I am going to love something which suits me more than I will love something which doesn't. Of course I will love a calm, smart, pretty child more than I will love a noisy, angry, ugly, crippled child. Because these things materially affect me. As a human I don't have God's infinite freedom and invulnerability. It's easy for the Godhead to love unconditionally because it is formless! It cannot lose anything. It cannot be harmed or annoyed. So is truly unconditional love possible for humans? Even enlightened humans? Seems unlikely. Unconditional love would only be possible with total selflessness. You'd have to really not care any more about living, dying, or enduring all sorts of hardship, suffering, and annoyance. To set up the ideal that I must always be unconditionally love could easily become a recipe for unhappiness and misery, as I will always fail to live up to such an impossible ideal. Then again, maybe unconditional love really is possible. But even if it is, it is certainly not something I can will or act my way into. It would have to come as an organic byproduct of deep awakening, higher states of consciousness, purification of the chakras, total surrender of the ego, and transcendence of self. Unconditional love would only be possible at the moment of total God-realization. The realization would have to be so total that there would be zero difference between myself and God, not just as a knowing, and not just temporarily as a peak experience, but as it is embodied day to day, minute to minute. Has any human ever attained such a degree of God-realization? I don't know. If they have, it would be a remarkable feat and I'm not sure how realistic it is to try to replicate it. It's certainly not something that the average spiritual seeker can do. I'm not sure if I could do it. You would have to completely renounce your entire life to reach this level of realization. It would have to be the only thing your life is about. I do not see that most monks or yogis have this level of God-realization in practice. Perhaps a few do, but this tells you just how difficult it is and why such people would be worshiped as Gods if they did exist — they literally are Gods at this point. You would be worshiped as God, but you would be so selfless at this point that you would not care at all for the praise. An interesting paradox. Half the world would worship you and love for your saintly self-sacrifice and half the world would hate you because your demonstration of such a radical degree of love would deeply threaten their egos. And you wouldn't care which was which because you would love both types equally. As a result, you would likely be killed by someone in the mob. And you still would not care. Which would only make your followers worship you even more after your death and create a religion which deluded others into worshiping you rather than realizing God as themselves.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/thoughts-on-unconditional-love</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Realizing What Is God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/realizing-what-is-god</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This will be the look on your face when you finally realize what God is:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4233" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/cat-shock.gif" alt="cat-shock" width="330" height="312" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/realizing-what-is-god</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Realizing You Are God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/realizing-you-are-god</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>What it's like when you realize you are God:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4233" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/cat-shock.gif" alt="cat-shock" width="330" height="312" /></p>
<p>;)</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/realizing-you-are-god</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Denver Decriminalizes Mushrooms</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/denver-decriminalizes-mushrooms</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/5/8/18535475/denver-psilocybin-psychedelic-magic-mushrooms-decriminalization-vote" target="_blank">Denver Successfully Decriminalizes Mushrooms</a></p>
<p>Horray! A small step for mankind.</p>
<p>This is exciting and groundbreaking news, as in the history books it will go down as the first domino to fall in our effort towards full nationwide decriminalization of psychedelics.</p>
<p>In truth, decriminalization of psychedelics is still not good enough. The US Constitution must have an Amendment which explicitly guarantees the right to explores one's own consciousness via any means that does not harm others.</p>
<p>This is of course on top of the already existing Constitutional clauses which guarantee free exercise of religion, which of course includes psychedelics (but is not yet acknowledged).</p>
<p>But we'll take this for now.</p>
<p>Oregon and California are working to pass legalization of mushrooms in 2020. A victory in Oregon would be a huge breakthrough, and it now seems doable.</p>
<p>Please donate to the <a href="https://psi-2020.org/" target="_blank">Oregon 2020 Psilocybin Ballot Initiative</a> to ensure it passes. If it does, that will be huge leap forward. It will also help many people suffering from depression, addiction, PTSD, anxiety, terminal illnesses, etc. Check out their video page for more details.</p>
<p>And here's another good initiative you can donate to if you're passionate about this cause: <a href="https://heffter.org/" target="_blank">The Heffter Research Institute</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/denver-decriminalizes-mushrooms</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Elite Universities Are A Scam</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/elite-universities-are-a-scam</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Most people in society are in denial about the scam that is elite university education (and to some extent, university education in general).</p>
<p>Read this article: <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/2019/5/1/18311548/college-admissions-secrets-myths" target="_blank">Former Admissions Dean Spills The Dirt On Elite College Admissions</a></p>
<p>And that's just the tip of the iceberg of the kind of devilry that goes on behind the scenes of these elite universities. Do not trust them for a second!</p>
<p>Universities are not your friend. They are businesses, collective egos, bureaucracies, and cultural constructions, first and foremost. It is a big mistake to equate university education, rank, or credentials with any sign of truth, goodness, wisdom, intelligence, consciousness, self-awareness, or level of development.</p>
<p>The wisest humans are not to be found in universities because universities do not prioritize truth, wisdom, love, or consciousness. Elite universities are playing games of status, money, and politics, and the worst thing about it is, the biggest con they pull is convincing high school students that they are somehow important and to be valued. It's never even told to high school students that they can provide themselves with a much better education than any university ever could, and at a tiny fraction of the cost. High school students just automatically buy into the lie that elite universities are somehow important and desirable.</p>
<p>Universities indoctrinate. They do not teach truly original thinking or human growth. And as the devil tends to do, they call themselves the bastions of truth. Then they act outraged if you question their authority or their well-credentialed professors. Ha! What a load of horse shit! A credential is just a piece of paper that a group of devils wrote to themselves to convince themselves that they are not devils but angels.</p>
<p>The whole point of getting an elite university degree is so that your survival in life becomes much easier thanks to the status it confers — you get access to the best job opportunities and positions of power — so you don't then actually have to work hard on becoming a conscious human being or doing original creative high-value work that stands on its own merit. An elite university allows you to use the power of social status to increase your survival odds. That's what it's really about, and any honest university would admit it. But of course the devil has to hide and deny his devilry in order for it to keep working. Teens who apply to these universities do not understand any of this. They are just cogs in the unconscious machine. Just like their parents were. They are under the illusion that these universities are somehow the ticket to heaven when really they're a ticket to hell! You know what they say, an abused child becomes an abusive parent. And so the cycle continues, the cogs keep spinning around in circles.</p>
<p>And all this is not to even mention the scam which is the college loan system. From a certain perspective a modern university is just a clever invention for saddling a new human being with $100,000 in debt without that human realizing what just happened. That is the lifeblood of the whole system! Universities are like a vampire that feeds off wage slaves. The real devilry comes in convincing children to join this system eagerly. You could call our entire education system long-time-horizon child abuse: grades, homework, standardized testing, SAT prep, AP testing, college admissions, student loans, credentials, diplomas, fraternities, sororities, college athletics — all that. It's all a socially constructed scam; a house of cards held together with bullshit. By the time a human being goes through 12 + 4 years of that, she is a domesticated animal. It's just a more sophisticated version of religion. A religion masquerading as science and rationality. No wonder there is no God or Truth found there. You cannot institutionalize Truth.</p>
<p>The bottom line is, an elite university education will actually hinder your ability to become the best human being you could be. Take responsibility for your own education. The only one who can properly educate you is yourself.</p>
<p>And yet, despite having said all the above, a university education is still far better than no education at all, or some kind of parochial education. So in a twisted sense we need this devil to save us from the yet greater devil of uneducatedness and right-wing ideology.</p>
<p>P.S. Do not confuse my critique of universities for right-wing critiques of universities. Universities can be critiqued from above or from below. My critique is from above. Right-wing critiques — based on a knee-jerk reaction against liberal values, multi-culturalism, relativism, and post-modernism — are from below. The paradox is that American society would be far better off if we made all public universities totally free to everyone, doubled their annual budgets, and cancelled all student debt. This would also have the benefit of devaluing elite private universities and reduce the need to jump through hoops for scholarships.</p>
<p>Our education system is thoroughly corrupt and badly in need of reform and massive funding. Of course it's just as you should expect. The first thing on the devil's agenda is to seize and corrupt all wellsprings of truth, turning them into founts of devilry. Topmost on the devil's agenda is to break all the lights, break all the mirrors, and multiply himself in the shade.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/elite-universities-are-a-scam</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scientists Find Hallucinogen Shaman Pouch</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/scientists-find-hallucinogen-shaman-pouch</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have recently discovered a 1000 year old shaman pouch in the Andes mountains containing various hallucinogenic plants and snorting utensils.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/ancient-pouch-reveals-hallucinogen-stash-andes-shaman" target="_blank">Read the full article</a></p>
<p>The real question is, why doesn't everyone have such a pouch 1000 years later?</p>
<p>Where is your shaman pouch?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/scientists-find-hallucinogen-shaman-pouch</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ayn Rand's Stage Orange Witchdoctory</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/ayn-rands-stage-orange-witchdoctory</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"While scientists were performing astounding feats of disciplined reason [during the Enlightenment], breaking down the barriers of the 'unknowable' in every field of knowledge, charting the course of light rays in space or the course of blood in the capillaries of man’s body — what philosophy was offering them, as interpretation of and guidance for their achievements was the plain Witchdoctory of Hegel, who proclaimed that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">matter does not exist at all</span>, that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">everything is Idea</span> (<span style="text-decoration: underline;">not somebody’s idea, just <i>Idea</i></span>), and that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">this Idea operates by the dialectical process</span> of a new '<span style="text-decoration: underline;">super-logic</span>' which proves that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">contradictions are the law of reality</span>, that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">A is non-A</span>, and that omniscience about the physical universe (including electricity, gravitation, the solar system, etc.) is to be derived, not from the observation of facts, but from the <span style="text-decoration: underline;">contemplation of that Idea</span>’s triple somersaults inside his, Hegel’s, mind. This was offered as a philosophy of reason."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ayn_Rand" target="_blank">Ayn Rand</a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">And she was precisely wrong!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">It takes skill and effort to be this wrong. The skill of a <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/what-is-the-devil" target="_blank">devil</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-orange" target="_blank">Stage Orange</a> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Materialism" target="_blank">materialism</a>/<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rationalism" target="_blank">rationalism</a> underestimates <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Idealism" target="_blank">idealism</a>/<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mysticism" target="_blank">mysticism</a> by assuming it to be philosophical mental-masturbation with no real-world consequences, when of course the truth is that materialism/rationalism is itself thoroughly deluded because it fails to take into account higher states of consciousness, which, if achieved, will erase the illusion of a material or rational world altogether.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Here Ayn Rand demonstrates the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bH5Qn6K36Ug" target="_blank">pre/trans fallacy</a>: confusing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Georg_Wilhelm_Friedrich_Hegel" target="_blank">Hegel</a>'s trans-rational explanations of the Absolute with pre-rational myth, fundamentalist religion, and soft thinking. In truth, Ayn Rand's dualistic logic was closer to myth than Hegel's.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The great irony is that materialism and rationalism turn out to be Witchdoctory — the very thing they accused philosophy and religion of being! Such is the counter-intuitive nature of the mind. To a devil like Ayn Rand, black is white, up is down, light is dark, and Absolute Truth is fiction. I've noticed that people who make vehement appeal to "reason" (like Ayn Rand or Sam Harris) turn out to be some of the greatest devils because they assume that reason is somehow a guarantor of truth, when in fact reason does the bidding of the ego. You cannot get to Absolute Truth through reason. Which totally shocks stage Orange rationalists, because they always held in blind faith that you could. A rationalist is just someone who replaces fundamentalist religious faith in the inerrancy of The Bible or Koran with a fundamentalist faith in the inerrancy of reason.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Hegel was a spiritual genius. He was the Western/German version of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nagarjuna" target="_blank">Nagarjuna</a> or The Buddha. But his words fell on deaf ears and got confined to history books or philosophy lectures.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Interestingly, when you start to research Western intellectual tradition you find a strong thread of idealism running all throughout which few Westerners today know about or take seriously. This gives a false impression that the West has always been materialist and anti-mystical, and that science has always been a materialist enterprise. Not true. This is an artificial narrative constructed by materialists to relieve themselves of the responsibility of taking idealist notions seriously. Many of the West's greatest scientists, thinkers, and visionaires were idealists, and for good reason. Because the more intelligent you become, the more idealism becomes unavoidable. Realist scientists and thinkers are 2nd rate intellects. They are good at technical analysis but they lack the holistic visionary aspect of the intellect, which is the most important aspect.</p>
<p>The intellect has two functions: analysis and synthesis, or division and unification. The intellect can be used to carve up reality or stitch it together. Modern academic and Western intellectual culture is overly biased towards analysis at the expense of synthesis, vision-logic, unification, and big picture thinking. Our schools teach kids how to carve up reality but not how to stitch it together. As a result our science and our society is overly-autistic and disconnected from our humanity and our divinity. Modern science lacks heart and vision. Which doesn't mean that science is bad or all-wrong, it just means that modern science is highly partial, and that there is a higher version of science yet to be actualized. Science and reason are not to be abandoned but expanded.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/ayn-rands-stage-orange-witchdoctory</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Case Study</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/spiral-dynamics-case-study</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a beautiful video demonstrating the difference in worldview and reality of stage <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Blue</a> vs <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-orange" target="_blank">Orange</a>/<a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-green" target="_blank">Green</a>.</p>
<p>Here's Orange/Green reacting against stage Blue.</p>
<p>Notice that Orange/Green simply cannot understand the stage Blue worldview because it's biased by an unquestioned certainty in the materialist paradigm. What stage Orange/Green does not understand is that there is no such thing as objective reality, "facts", "truth", or "sanity".</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ruh0RqzHmC0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Stage Blue vs Orange/Green are literally inhabiting different realities which their minds are constructing. But since they do not understand that their mind constructs reality, they assume that their reality is the one "true" reality while the other side is literally insane. This notion of insanity plays a pivotal function in their worldview because they need some way of explaining away the otherwise without actually investigating it. By calling the other side "insane" it automatically absolves you from having to seriously question your notion of "real".</p>
<p>What needs to be realized is that however you think reality is, you're making that up! "No Leo, I'm not making it up. You're crazy!" << You just made that up! Lol. See? Your metaphysical assumptions become your reality, no matter how crazy, unreasonable, or false they are. So if you believe there is an objective external reality, that becomes your reality. But it is not true in any absolute sense. Your mind is making reality up as you go along. Including, of course, the denial that you do so.</p>
<p>There actually is no firm boundary between a crazy worldview and a reasonable one. That duality collapses upon deep examination.</p>
<p>Without deeply understanding this you will never understand what reality is, how it works, or why humans behave as they do. For you there will always be stuff that happens in the world which seems totally batshit crazy. But it only appears that way from your POV because your worldview is inadequate at accounting for other worldviews. As a rule of thumb, any time you see something crazy happening in the world, that's a clue that you don't understand it deeply enough. The mind uses the judgment "that's crazy" as a cop-out.</p>
<p>With all that said, some people are exceptionally deluded.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/spiral-dynamics-case-study</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #015</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-15</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">"The path into the light seems dark,<br />
the path forward seems to go back,<br />
the direct path seems long,<br />
true power seems weak,<br />
true purity seems tarnished,<br />
true steadfastness seems changeable,<br />
true clarity seems obscure,<br />
the greatest art seems unsophisticated,<br />
the greatest love seems indifferent,<br />
the greatest wisdom seems childish.</p>
<p>The Tao is nowhere to be found.<br />
Yet it nourishes and completes all things."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Lao Tzu, Tao Te Ching</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-15</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fat Leo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/fat-leo</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Folks have been asking me to release a photo of when I used to be fat. Some even accused me of making up the story that I used to be fat. Well, I was in fact fat from about age 9 to age 21.</p>
<p>I didn't have fat photos of myself because: 1) Back then there were no cell phones or selfie pics, 2) I didn't like taking photos of myself when I was fat.</p>
<p>But anyhow, I finally found an old photo at my Mom's house. So here you go:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4203" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/leo-pic-01.png" alt="leo-pic-01" width="604" height="842" /></p>
<p>235 lbs at 6'2". 20 years old. About one year after this photo was taken I lost 65 pounds in 5 months, dropping to 170 lbs. I've kept it off ever since. Right now I'm at 180 lbs.</p>
<p>This was accomplished through diet changes & lots of gym exercise, including cardio and weights. I worked out 5 days a week for about 10 years. For the past 2 years I have not worked out at all and still keep the weight off because my diet is about 10x cleaner than it used to be, such that exercise for purposes of weight-maintenance is unnecessary. But exercise is still good for health of course.</p>
<p>Big change is possible if you set your mind on it. The most important aspects of accomplishing a change like this are: 1) vision, 2) discipline, and 3) focus.</p>
<p>Because my videos are so abstract and metaphysical sometimes people overlook the meat of this work. Personal development is very practical stuff with very tangible results. Don't let the abstract explanations fool you. You must also be results-oriented. Get shit done by whatever means necessary. Claw your way up <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/using-maslows-hierarchy-of-needs-to-self-actualize" target="_blank">Maslow's Hierarchy</a>. If you're new to personal development you need to dial in the basics like health, diet, career, finances, living environment, family situation, dating, etc. Don't get so metaphysical that you neglect all that. You will find awakening impossible if you can't even stop eating junk food or can't earn enough to pay your rent.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/fat-leo</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>So Are You Chinese Or Japanese?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/so-are-you-chinese-or-japanese</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a perfect little example of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/understanding-duality-part-1" target="_blank">dualistic thinking</a>:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d_CaZ4EAexQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This kind of thinking is extremely common at <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue</a>. But watch out! — dualistic thinking is still present in spades at higher stages. It's not just rednecks who think in this black-and-white way. You do it every day! Don't fool yourself into thinking you're above dualistic thinking. Dualistic thinking can be very subtle and it affects even the most rational and scientific thinkers. Rationality and science are chock full of dualities.</p>
<p>There's more to reality than the simplistic categories your mind creates.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/so-are-you-chinese-or-japanese</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Cameron On Ecological Awareness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/james-cameron-on-ecological-awareness</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a really intelligent and self-aware perspective on ecology & environment. It's a stage Yellow perspective. Notice the nuance and complexity of it. It balances science, business, art, and compassion, transcending AND including stages Orange and Green. Notice the lack of blaming problems on someone else. Notice the attitude of meeting people where they're at. Notice how science & spirituality/religion are not pitted against each other. It's a cooperation of left and right brain, mind & heart. Notice the systems thinking.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wRdCrIGt5dk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Love it! Try to adopt this kind of attitude in your life.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/james-cameron-on-ecological-awareness</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Cameron On Life Purpose</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/james-cameron-on-life-purpose</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a great role-model for those of you looking to actualize your life purpose:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WH0CqAmfwRQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PVfd6fg7QsM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>He's really nailed his purpose.</p>
<p>Notice how unique and personal one's life purpose becomes when you start to fully actualize it.</p>
<p>Find more such role-models within your domain of mastery.</p>
<p>Take my <a href="https://www.actualized.org/life-purpose-course" target="_blank">Life Purpose Course</a> for a step-by-step guide for finding your life purpose.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/james-cameron-on-life-purpose</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Quintessence: The 5th Element</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/quintessence-the-5th-element</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Classically, the 4 elements were Air, Water, Fire, and Earth. The 5th element — which few people know about — was called the quintessence (literally, "the 5th essence") or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aether_(classical_element)" target="_blank">Aether</a> — otherwise known as Nothingness or Emptiness or Void.</p>
<p>In science, Aether was known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luminiferous_aether" target="_blank">luminiferous ether</a>, the medium through which light and gravity waves were supposed to have propagated. In the early 20th century physicists like Einstein and others "debunked" the notion of ether by reasoning that light waves did not need a medium to propagate through. They ran various experiments trying to measure the existence of ether but nothing turned up, so they discarded the notion as superfluous. Except Aether is not superfluous, it is central! What the scientists did not understand, and still do not understand, is that Aether wasn't a measurable medium like water, air, or even space — it is Nothing! This is not the same as saying that Aether does not exist. Aether exists as Nothing, the Groundless Ground, or pure Existence itself — existence devoid of any content. Don't bother trying to measure it because you can't. Existence is prior to measurement. The medium for the propagation of light waves and gravity waves (and anything else for that matter) is consciousness. And also don't confuse Aether/Nothingness with the vacuum of space. Aether is prior to space or time. It "holds" space and time.</p>
<p>What people don't understand is that quintessence is not just Nothingness, it is not just Existence, it is also Consciousness, Truth, God, Love, Goodness, Intelligence, Self, Other, and World!</p>
<p>But how can Love be Nothingness? How could it not! Only Nothingness has the capacity to embrace all. Only Nothingness is selfless enough to embrace all. Only no-thing can unconditionally accept every-thing. The embrace is so complete that Nothingness literally IS everything! This is pure, Platonic Love. Not just love as an emotion (although it is that too), but love as Being itself. Love is the union of all opposites into one seamless totality. Love is the unification of all divisions. Love is the super-set of all sub-sets. Love is universality. Love is infinity. Love is unlimited.</p>
<p>The 5th Element got their metaphysics exactly right:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6a0Q0rfbUVI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>After all is said and done, in the final analysis, the force that saves the world is none other than the force that makes the world: Love.</p>
<p>You ARE quintessence. You ARE Love.</p>
<p>Your ability to unify all opposites, all dualities, is the measure of your love. It is Unity as an Absolute. A Unity so all-embracing it has no opposite. A nonduality so nondual it doesn't know duality. A Love so complete it does not know judgment, criticism, rejection, hatred, selfishness, or evil. Yet at the same time it embraces them all by being them all. Human love is a tiny branch off the tree of universal Love. This tree is infinite, with countless branches of varying size. You are one branch AND you are the entire tree. To actualize one branch is to be human. To actualize the entire tree is to be God. Each branch is not other than the tree, such that all there is, is tree. What it means to be a tree is to be each branch and the sum total of them all at once. To realize this totality is Truth and Love.</p>
<p>Notice, when you feel an emotion of deep love, what you're feeling is not an egoic desire but a selflessness and a deep unity with the universe. In that moment you are being selfless, and it feels right and good. It feels divine.</p>
<p>So how do you conquer evil? By experiencing yourself as Love. Just like in the clip above. It sounds childish, until you try to do it and you quickly see just how hard it is for your ego to do. It is the mark of a masterful sage to be able to embrace all. You can't do it because you have too much evil in you. All-encompassing Love threatens you like light threatens a shadow. You can't do it because you are too busy defending your self while Love is self-less-ness. Love is also fearlessness. If there is no self, there is nothing to lose, and nothing to fear.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"A coward is incapable of exhibiting love; it is the prerogative of the brave."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— Mahatma Gandhi</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/quintessence-the-5th-element</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;I Cannot Self-Terminate&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/i-cannot-self-terminate</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Terminator 2 is — in my opinion — one of the greatest films of all time.</p>
<p>Ever since I was a kid the final scene always moved me:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DEMICfWLOig?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>It's such a brilliant final scene, filled with spiritual significance.</p>
<p>Now I understand why I liked it so much. It represents the hardest things for an ego to do: self-terminate. It represents the stark brutality of total selflessness.</p>
<p>How do you ask a self to self-terminate?</p>
<p>You see? That is why this work is hard.</p>
<p>"Be melting snow. Wash yourself of yourself." — Rumi</p>
<p>WARNING: Do not confuse self-termination with suicide. I am talking about spiritual self-termination. Suicide is just more ego.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/i-cannot-self-terminate</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Joy Of Creation</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-joy-of-creation</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>It took some gamer-nerd 300 hours to build this epic roller coaster. When I saw it, it reminded me of God's infinite creative potential — of how life and reality just goes on and on and on like an endless roller coaster.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/afhBFffMvZU?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>You might wonder, "So what? Why would someone waste 300 hours creating this silly thing? What the point?" The point is CREATION itself! God likes to create amazing stuff just for the hell of it. When you have infinite creative capacity, when you have unlimited intelligence, when you have unlimited power, when you have an eternity — what else are you gonna do? You have somewhere you gotta be?</p>
<p>CREATION is its own end. As you go chasing awakening and Nothingness, do not overlook CREATION! It's everywhere and everything! You might look at this roller coaster and see some gamer-nerd making something pointless. But that's not some nerd, that's God! That is the unlimited creative force of the whole universe materializing itself into a roller coaster! God is the sum total of all chains of creation, of which this roller coaster is one chain. That force is designing everything from atoms to cells to animals to galaxies and beyond. Can you see it? It is unlimited creation. It cannot stop. It bursts infinitely with new creative forms and ideas, ultimately spawning everything that can ever be.</p>
<p>If life feels depressing and bleak, it's because you're failing to step into your role as Creator. Creation is a spiritual activity. Every time that gamer-nerd works on perfecting his roller coaster, he's in church. And when you look upon and delight in his creation, recognizing the God in it, you are in church. What if your work and your church were one and the same? Wouldn't that be a life worth living?</p>
<p>Never forget, you are a creator. You are THE creator. What are you gonna create with your life?</p>
<p>I hope it's something at least as cool as this rollercoaster.</p>
<p>P.S. Notice what the guy in the video says at the very end of the ride, at timestamp 10:02. He says, "OH. MY. GOD!" That's right. That's exactly right.</p>
<p>P.P.S. Here's another <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ca3eYxZedD4" target="_blank">epic Aliens rollercoaster</a>.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-joy-of-creation</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Solo Retreat Notes</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/solo-retreat-notes-feb-2019</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I ended up taking 23 pages of notes during my solo retreat.</p>
<p>Here they are if you're interested: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/downloads/solo-retreat-notes-feb-2019.docx" target="_blank">Leo's Solo Retreat Notes, Feb-Mar 2019</a></p>
<p>A lot of profound insights there, but it was hastily written, and of course a lot of insights were not written down at all.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/solo-retreat-notes-feb-2019</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Back From Retreat</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/back-from-retreat</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>And I'm back!</p>
<p>It's been a crazy 29 days of consciousness work, featuring 13 profound awakening experiences — each one deeper than the last. Impossible levels of consciousness were accessed that few human beings have ever experienced.</p>
<p>I'll tell you all about it after I collect my thoughts. There is a lot to say, yet at the same time, it is impossible to put it faithfully into words.</p>
<p>I have a truckload of the deepest insights to share.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/back-from-retreat</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leaving On 30-Day Solo Retreat</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/leaving-on-30-day-solo-retreat</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Sorry, in my eagerness I neglected to post here that I'm away for 30 days straight doing a solo meditation retreat in search of enlightenment.</p>
<p>Video explanation of my plans can be <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/leaving-on-30-day-solo-retreat" target="_blank">found here</a>.</p>
<p>My retreat ends on March 24th. I'll post a video summarizing my results shortly thereafter.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/leaving-on-30-day-solo-retreat</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bernie 2020!</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/bernie-2020</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Today Bernie Sanders announced his entry in the 2020 Presidential race and I am thrilled to endorse him. I don't typically endorse politicians, but he is by far the best politician in the country today. He is a serious visionary leader and his policy platform is outstanding. If you want to live in a more conscious, less plutocratic America, please <a href="https://berniesanders.com" target="_blank">donate</a> & support Bernie because the establishment ego backlash against him will be yuge!</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZgJagAiHimk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZmK8flP0CuA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Sanders' 2020 policy platform:</p>
<ul>
<li>Medicare 4 All</li>
<li>Green New Deal/climate</li>
<li>$15 min wage</li>
<li>Criminal justice reform</li>
<li>Free college</li>
<li>Break up biggest banks</li>
<li>Campaign finance reform</li>
<li>Gender pay equity</li>
<li>Paid leave</li>
<li>Lower drug prices</li>
<li>Expand Social Security</li>
<li>Save unions</li>
<li>DREAM Act</li>
<li>Background checks & assault weapons ban</li>
<li>Affordable housing</li>
<li>New infrastructure</li>
<li>Opposing military industrial complex</li>
<li>Legalization of weed</li>
<li>Abolish private prisons</li>
<li>End cash bail</li>
<li>Major police department reform</li>
</ul>
<p>Now is the time to put your money where your mouth is. If you are short on cash, consider volunteering for <a href="https://act.berniesanders.com/signup/volunteer" target="_blank">his campaign</a>, the <a href="https://www.justicedemocrats.com" target="_blank">Justice Democrats</a>, or <a href="https://www.wolf-pac.com" target="_blank">Wolf-PAC</a> to get corporate money out of government.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4159" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/sanders-donation-01.png" alt="sanders-donation-01" width="615" /></p>
<p>And don't forget to register to participate in your state's Democratic primary. This is very important. Voting in the General Election is NOT good enough.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/bernie-2020</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Textbook Example Of Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/textbook-example-of-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I don't particularly like to kick a man when he's down, but the following video shows the unraveling of Alex Jones' ego in such a stark way that it deserves to be in a textbook about devilry. Pay close attention to how the arrogance of the ego-mind refuses to concede to truth and love, doubling down on its egotism and starting a holy war (lesser Jihad). This is how crusades and holy wars throughout history have been started.</p>
<p>Alex Jones is just an extremely obvious example of this. But notice how your ego does this too, in (hopefully) lesser, more subtle ways. It especially happens when you feel under attack or when your livelihood or identity is seriously threatened.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YL1ShzYHvD8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>As context for this clip, on his podcast <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B93fUUiuwMs" target="_blank">Joe Rogan extended a hand of friendship to Alex Jones</a>, genuinely concerned for his mental health. Joe took a fair, compassionate position, being more than generous to Alex Jones, but the devil cannot stand it! The devil is terrified of genuine love and compassion — he thinks it's a ploy. Love burns the devil like a sunlight burns a vampire. Rogan is speaking from a healthy stage Green while Jones is speaking from a very pathological stage Red. Stage Green often underestimates the depravity and viciousness stage Red is capable of — it is outside of stage Green's reality.</p>
<p>The fundamental position of the devil in aggressive defiance of God. At low levels of Spiral Development the ego becomes aggressively ignorant and, of course, assumes the position of God. The devil always feels like he is the righteous one who could do no wrong and that God is on his side. The devil is a usurper of God's throne, actively spinning delusions and self-deceptions to convince himself that what he's doing is righteous.</p>
<p>Remember this: a devil will not hesitate to bite a helping hand. So be careful when openly offering them your compassion.</p>
<p>P.S. Please don't misunderstand me when I call Alex Jones a devil. Despite how it sounds, I am not actually demonizing him. When I call someone "a devil" I do not use this term dualistically or moralistically. I am not making a moral judgment of him. For me this is a technical term describing delusional egoic behavior which aims at supplanting truth with its own selfishness. Like how a cuckoo bird tries to lay its own egg in the nest of other birds.</p>
<p>See my video: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/what-is-the-devil" target="_blank">What Is The Devil?</a> to learn more.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/textbook-example-of-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Entrainment Demo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/entrainment-demo</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Check out this cool video demonstrating entrainment:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Aaxw4zbULMs?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Notice at the end how they all de-sync without the soda cans.</p>
<p>Consider that the soda cans are culture. Culture allows human beings to entrain with each other. Which is why people defend their cultures to the death.</p>
<p>P.S. Your brain gets entrained to certain types of sounds and music just like the pendulums above. Various spiritual techniques make use of such brain entrainment — like binaural beats, Solfeggio frequencies, chanting, mantra recitation, and shamanic drumming — in order to access higher states of consciousness. Is this New Age voodoo? No! Does it really work? Yes! Give it a try, if you dare. There is a spooky yet legit connection between your state of consciousness and auditory vibrations.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/entrainment-demo</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #014</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-014</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;">"Abandon the search for God and the Creation and other matters of a similar sort. Look for him by taking yourself as the starting point. Learn who it is within you who makes everything his own and says, 'My God, my mind, my thought, my soul, my body.' Learn the sources of sorrow, joy, love, hate. Learn how it happens that one watches without willing, rests without willing, becomes angry without willing, loves without willing. If you carefully investigate these matters you will find him in yourself."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— Monoimus, quoted by Hippolytus of Rome</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-014</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Neoclassical Economics Is A Cult</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/neoclassical-economics-is-a-cult</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Free-market capitalism (especially the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chicago_school_of_economics" target="_blank">Chicago School</a>) is a dangerous cult ideology. Similar to positivism, behaviorism, and materialism. A lot of otherwise intelligent people get sucked into them because the group-think and status quo is so strong it goes completely unquestioned, masquerading as "science" or "fact". The devil loves to lie using mathematics because it gives him the perfect cover of "objectivity".</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JeplRmADW3E?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Of course Marxism also tends to be cult-like. But right now America has a serious addiction to capitalism, to the point of being in denial about it.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/neoclassical-economics-is-a-cult</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Strange Loop Universe</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-strange-loop-universe</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Consider the following intriguing possibility:</p>
<p>According to modern cosmology, our universe started as an infinite singularity which spontaneously blew up and started expanding at an accelerating rate, which it is still doing today. There has been some speculation that in the future it might start to decelerate and eventually crash in on itself in a Big Crunch, back to where it began. An elegant solution, but our universe currently shows no sign of deceleration so I wouldn't hold my breath. So let's assume it just keeps accelerating outwardly forever. What then? How do we end it in an elegant way?</p>
<p>Thermodynamics tells us that ultimately the universe will end in entropic heat death, where all the atoms dissipate their kinetic energy until the entire universe is one energetically uniform, lukewarm field. This is the universe's most boring state. Nothing interesting to see or do because everything is so uniform that everywhere is the same. There's nowhere to go and you don't have enough of an energy gradient to power anything (no cars, no power plants, no life). Everything is one uniform temperature and eventually even all the atoms decompose into a perfectly uniform soup.</p>
<p>But at precisely this point our perfectly uniform universe also becomes indistinguishable from a singularity! Now, you might think, "But wait a minute, this new singularity is a billion times larger than the old one, due to billions of years of expansion." Except size, distance, and time are all relative notions. In a totally uniform universe it is impossible to distinguish distance or time and hence impossible to distinguish the old singularity from the new singularity, making them literally identical!</p>
<p>After all, who is to say there is difference between beginning and end?</p>
<p>And suddenly the whole thing explodes again.</p>
<p>Ta-da! We've come full-circle!</p>
<p>But wait, it gets even stranger! If reality is nothing but distinction, could it be possible to eliminate the distinction between something and nothing, reality and unreality? After all, who is to say that the universe is real or has ever even happened?!</p>
<p>This very moment you are sitting here reading this sentence thinking you are inside an actual universe which has happened. But perhaps if you realized that "actual" is a distinction that you are creating, you could also collapse it, thus making it literally impossible to distinguish an "actual" universe from its opposite, a "potential" universe, thus nullifying this very moment, as though it never actually happened, all at the same time as it appears to be happening!</p>
<p>After all, who is to say there is a difference between happening and non-happening?</p>
<p>So, was there an actual Big Bang or not? Adapting, a bit, the famous words of Henry Ford, "Whether you think there was, or think there wasn't, you're right!"</p>
<p>How does God create something out of nothing? By imagining a difference between the two.</p>
<p>Ta-da!</p>
<p>So while everyone else is running around taking life seriously, you might be able to realize that life isn't happening at all. Perhaps existence is only possible as an idea.</p>
<p>Sounds insane? Who is to say there is a difference between sane and insane? ;)</p>
<p>Here's an interesting video long these lines, although not quite as radical. Modern cosmology is still not addressing the elephant in the room: the relativity of existence itself.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FVDJJVoTx7s?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-strange-loop-universe</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Strange Loop Cosmology</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/strange-loop-cosmology</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Consider the following intriguing possibility:</p>
<p>According to modern cosmology, our universe started as an infinite singularity which spontaneously blew up and started expanding at an accelerating rate — which is continuing today. There has been some speculation that in the future it might start to decelerate and eventually crash in on itself in a Big Crunch, back to where it began. An elegant solution, but our universe currently shows no sign of deceleration so I wouldn't hold my breath. So let's assume it just keeps accelerating outwardly forever. What then? How do we end it in an elegant way?</p>
<p>Thermodynamics tells us that ultimately the universe will end in entropic heat death, where all the atoms dissipate their kinetic energy until the entire universe is one energetically uniform, frozen field. This is the universe's most boring state. Nothing interesting to see or do because everything is so uniform that everywhere is the same. There's nowhere to go and you don't have enough of an energy gradient to power anything (no cars, no power plants, no life). Everything is one uniform temperature and eventually even all the atoms decompose into a perfectly uniform soup.</p>
<p>But at precisely this point our perfectly uniform universe also becomes indistinguishable from a singularity! Now, you might think, "But wait a minute, this new singularity is a billion times larger than the old one, due to billions of years of expansion." Except size, distance, time, and temperature are all relative notions. In a totally uniform universe it is impossible to distinguish here from there, big from small, past from future, or hot from cold, and hence impossible to distinguish the old singularity from the new singularity, making them literally identical!</p>
<p>After all, who is to say there is difference between beginning and end?</p>
<p>And suddenly the whole thing explodes again.</p>
<p>Ta-da! We've come full-circle! The perfect <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/reality-is-a-strange-loop" target="_blank">strange loop</a>.</p>
<p>But wait, it gets even stranger! If reality is nothing but distinction, could it be possible to eliminate the distinction between something and nothing, reality and unreality? After all, who is to say that the universe is real or has ever even happened?!</p>
<p>This very moment you are sitting here reading this sentence thinking you are inside an actual universe which has happened. But perhaps if you realized that "actual" is a distinction that you are creating, you could also collapse it, thus making it literally impossible to distinguish an "actual" universe from its opposite, a "potential" universe, thus nullifying this very moment, as though it never actually happened, all at the same time as it appears to be happening!</p>
<p>After all, who is to say there is a difference between happening and non-happening?</p>
<p>So, was there an actual Big Bang or not? Adapting, a bit, the famous words of Henry Ford, "Whether you think there was, or think there wasn't, you're right!"</p>
<p>How does God create something out of nothing? By imagining a difference between the two.</p>
<p>Ta-da!</p>
<p>So while everyone else is running around taking life seriously, you might be able to realize that life isn't happening at all. Perhaps existence is only possible as an idea.</p>
<p>Sounds impossible? Who is to say there is a difference between possible and impossible?</p>
<p>Sounds insane? Who is to say there is a difference between sane and insane? ;)</p>
<p>Here's an interesting video long these lines, although not quite as radical. Modern cosmology is still not addressing the elephant in the room: the relativity of existence itself.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FVDJJVoTx7s?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/strange-loop-cosmology</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Galaxy In A Rock</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-galaxy-in-a-rock</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Opals are the coolest rocks. It's like God photographed deep space using a rock.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4131" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/opal-rock.jpg" alt="opal-rock" width="615" /></p>
<p>Above: Oregon Contra Luz Opal with botryoidal Jasper inclusions, from Oregon</p>
<p>Below: the Carina Nebula as photographed by the Hubble Space Telescope with its newest Wide Field Camera 3.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4133" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/eagle-nebula-hubble.jpg" alt="eagle-nebula-hubble" width="615" /></p>
<p>Behold the beauty of the infinite cosmic fractal that is you!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-galaxy-in-a-rock</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Capitalist Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/capitalist-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I love Anand's analysis of the current state of American society. Everything he's talking about is the limits of Spiral Dynamics <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-orange" target="_blank">stage Orange</a> which I have explained in my video.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fdt5a6CJ3HY?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d_zt3kGW1NM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is the kind of political analysis I'm into. Notice how different it is from the commonplace partisan bickering, namecalling, and conventional thinking.</p>
<p>Notice also how the themes he talks about are part of the much broader dynamic of devilry (see video <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/what-is-the-devil" target="_blank">What Is The Devil?</a>). Devilry is nothing other than the force of blind self-survival. This force is so strong because it needed to be that strong in order to get you to where you are right now. But then survival goes overboard, becoming counter-productive. As is always the case with duality, too much of a good thing becomes a bad thing.</p>
<blockquote><p>"It is difficult to get a man to understand something when his salary depends upon his not understanding it."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Upton Sinclair</p>
<p>Of course rich people are not going to understand how they create global suffering and inequality because it is against their self-interest to understand. That would be too much consciousness, too much responsibility. Then they could not pursue wealth as ruthlessly as they do. The devil is always going to resist seeing that he is the devil. This is true not just of rich people, but EVERYONE! Religious people, military people, Big Oil, Big Pharma, criminals, children — and YOU! I want you to notice that you are not conscious of the collateral damage that your own survival produces because it doesn't help your survival to be conscious of it. So you are in deep denial about it. Notice the stories and justifications you create for how you are not a devil but an angel. It is precisely these stories which make you a devil! Ta-da! Self-deception at its finest.</p>
<p>What's that you say? "But Leo! I need money, I need sex, I need medicine, I need a house, I need a good school for my kids, I need X, I need Y, I need Z. If I stop pursuing my survival needs, I will die!"</p>
<p>Exactly! Exactly...</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/capitalist-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Political Awakening</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/my-political-awakening</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/312856887?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>While we're on the topic of politics, here are my favorite political channels on YouTube:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/SamSeder/videos" target="_blank">The Majority Report</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCo9oQdIk1MfcnzypG3UnURA/videos" target="_blank">The Rational National</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/SecularTalk/videos" target="_blank">Secular Talk</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/MidweekPolitics/videos" target="_blank">The David Pakman Show</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/TheYoungTurks/videos" target="_blank">TYT</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/MikeAnthonyTV/videos" target="_blank">The Humanist Report</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/democracynow/videos" target="_blank">Democracy Now!</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Please keep in mind that I do not necessarily agree with all of the ideas & opinions these channels espouse. These are <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-green" target="_blank">stage Green</a> channels. They are definitely biased and ideological. My view of politics is at least <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-yellow" target="_blank">stage Yellow</a>, so I have some important criticisms of these Green channels, but in an environment where stage Yellow political analysis is virtually non-existent, this is as good as you're likely to find, for now. We have a lot of growing to do just to get society to Green, nevermind Yellow. There will definitely be some excessive and unhealthy manifestations of Green from time to time, but right now I'm not too concerned about it.</p>
<p>Rather than adopting my personal political beliefs, what I suggest you do with this domain of life is to study it (if you want). Become serious about understanding how government & society works in a systemic, non-partisan, non-culture-war way. Set aside your political prejudices and educate yourself. Be careful not to get radicalized and not to build a political ego. Be careful about confirmation bias. Diversify your news sources and seriously investigate the positions of your political opponents. But also don't fall into the trap of false equivalency, splitting issues evenly down the middle, or automatically accepting the status quo. By not making a choice, you've made a choice in favor of the status quo. By not taking action, you've taken action in defense of the status quo.</p>
<p>When it comes to politics, you're damned if you do, but you're even more damned if you don't.</p>
<p>If you are seriously working on enlightenment you might want to stay away from politics for a while so it doesn't turn into a distraction. But overall, you should be well-informed about various political trends and what makes for good governance. You might want to subscribe to a serious journalistic new outlet like the New York Times or Washington Post and actually read their articles. Also, read books on politics and governance. You cannot understand this domain of life without some in-depth reading and a sense of history.</p>
<p>Above all, remember, proper politics and governance is not about what YOU need. It's about what helps elevate the majority of mankind. Often times what's good for the greater system may not be what's personally good for you, your family, your ethnicity, your gender, or your company. Be very careful not to make politics just another survival game that your ego plays.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/my-political-awakening</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Cult Of Capitalism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-cult-of-capitalism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Excellent analysis of the current state of America:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n-2TEwdRnX0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Notice how Spiral Dynamics explains all this, and foreshadows the next inevitable development step. We are beginning to reach the limits of unbridled stage Orange.</p>
<p>Be careful not to turn the current state of society into a victim mindset or an excuse for why you can't create a great life. Never let aggregate macro trends dictate your personal effort and results. It doesn't really matter what others are failing to do, what matters is that you do what you need to do. Conscious capitalism is possible, and you can lead the way in that.</p>
<p>For more on that see my video: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/how-to-escape-wage-slavery" target="_blank">How To Escape Wage Slavery</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-cult-of-capitalism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inside The Cult Of Scientology</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/inside-the-cult-of-scientology</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's an eye-opening interview of Ron Miscavige, father of David Miscavige, the current leader of the cult of Scientology. Compare Ron's story with the cult check list I gave in my video on <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/cult-psychology-part-1" target="_blank">Cult Psychology</a>.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FVVdCikBDQk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/inside-the-cult-of-scientology</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inside The Alex Jones Cult</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/inside-the-alex-jones-cult</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's an outstanding interview by David Pakman with the wife of Alex Jones, offering a rare glimpse into the self-delusion and narcissism fueling the Alex Jone phenomenon.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ebByb9JJgJg?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is very typical of unhealthy Spiral Dynamics stage Red. Alex Jones is basically an online cult leader.</p>
<p>Watch out! The 21st century will see many more cults forming online. The online medium is ripe for exploitation and weaponization by devils proclaiming themselves to be angels. YouTube, Facebook, Google, Twitter, iTunes, Instagram, etc will all be hijacked by devils to some degree, in the same way that TV, radio, and newspapers were. The devil always thrives in newly developing media because they lack legal regulations and ethical norms. The devil thrives in the wild west, which is one of the fundamental flaws of anarchism and libertarianism. In a wild west environment the biggest devils will rule.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/inside-the-alex-jones-cult</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inside The R. Kelly Sex Cult</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/inside-the-r-kelly-sex-cult</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the things I hope you get from watching my videos is just how timely, relevant, and practical all of the stuff we talk about is. Philosophy, epistemology, metaphysics, psychology, and spirituality are not just some wooly academic pursuit, their effects are felt throughout culture every day. You can see it in the news every day if you know what to look for because the principles we discuss on Actualized.org are so fundamental they shape all human action across all geographical locations across all time.</p>
<p>Here's but one example:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/m2muGNE9t_s?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oP5uVD82gO8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is a good example of a secular cult.</p>
<p>R. Kelly seems to exhibit quite a bit of unhealthy Spiral Dynamics stage Red, which is quite common for rappers and cult leaders.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/inside-the-r-kelly-sex-cult</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aztec Nonduality</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/aztec-nonduality</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Should it be any surprise at this point that the Aztecs were nondualists?</p>
<p>Here's a summary of Aztec metaphysics from the <a href="https://www.iep.utm.edu/aztec/" target="_blank">Internet Encyclopedia of Philosophy</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;">"At the heart of Nahua (Meso-American) philosophy stands the thesis that there exists a single, dynamic, vivifying, eternally self-generating and self-regenerating sacred power, energy or force: what the Nahuas called teotl (God)<em>. </em>Elizabeth Boone writes, 'The real meaning of teotl is spirit — a concentration of power as a sacred and impersonal force'. According to Jorge Klor de Alva, 'Teotl implies something more than the idea of the divine manifested in the form of a god or gods; instead it signifies the sacred in more general terms'. The multiplicity of gods in official, state sanctioned Aztec religion does not gainsay this claim, for this multiplicity was merely the sacred, merely teotl, 'separated, as it were by the prism of human sight, into its many attributes'.<em><br />
</em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Teotl continually generates and regenerates as well as permeates, encompasses, and shapes the cosmos as part of its endless process of self-generation and regeneration. That which humans commonly understand as nature — e.g. heavens, earth, rain, humans, trees, rocks, animals, etc. — is generated by teotl, from teotl as one aspect, facet, or moment of its endless process of self-generation-and-regeneration. Yet teotl is more than the unified totality of things; <strong>teotl is identical with everything and everything is identical with teotl</strong>. Since identical with teotl, the cosmos and its contents ultimately transcend such dichotomies as personal vs. impersonal, animate vs. inanimate, etc. As the single, all-encompassing life force of the universe, teotl vivifies the cosmos and its contents. Lastly, <strong>teotl is both metaphysically immanent and transcendent</strong>. It is immanent in that it penetrates deeply into every detail of the universe and exists within the myriad of created things; it is transcendent in that it is not exhausted by any single, existing thing.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Nahua metaphysics is processive. Process, movement, becoming and transmutation are essential attributes of teotl. Teotl is properly understood as ever-flowing and ever-changing energy-in-motion — not as a discrete, static entity.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Although essentially processive and devoid of any permanent order, the ceaseless becoming of the cosmos is nevertheless characterized by an overarching balance, rhythm, and regularity: one provided by and constituted by teotl... Dialectical polar monism holds that: (1) the cosmos and its contents are substantively and formally identical with teotl; and (2) teotl presents itself primarily as the ceaseless, cyclical oscillation of polar yet complementary opposites.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Teotl's process presents itself in multiple aspects, preeminent among which is duality. This duality takes the form of the endless opposition of contrary yet mutually interdependent and mutually complementary polarities that divide, alternately dominate, and explain the diversity, movement, and momentary arrangement of the universe. These include: being and not-being, order and disorder, life and death, light and darkness, masculine and feminine, dry and wet, hot and cold, and active and passive. Life and death, for example, are mutually arising, interdependent, and complementary aspects of one and the same process.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The created cosmos consists of the unending, cyclical tug-of-war or dialectical oscillation of these polarities — all of which are the manifold manifestations of teotl. Because of this, <strong>the created cosmos is characterized as unstable, transitory, and devoid of any lasting being, order or structure</strong>. Yet teotl is nevertheless characterized by enduring pattern or regularity. How is this so? Teotl is the dynamic, sacred energy shaping as well as constituting these endless oscillations; it is the immanent balance of the endless, dialectical alternation of the created universe's interdependent polarities.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Because essentially processive and dynamic, teotl is properly characterized neither by being nor not-being but by becoming. Being and not-being are simply two dialectically interrelated presentations or facets of teotl, and as such inapplicable to teotl itself. Similarly, teotl is properly understood as neither ordered (law-governed) nor disordered (anarchic) but as unordered. Indeed, this point is fully general: life/death, active/passive, male/female, etc. are strictly speaking not predicable of teotl. Teotl captures a tertium quid transcending these dichotomies by being simultaneously neither-alive-nor-dead-yet-both-alive-and-dead, simultaneously neither-orderly-nor-disorderly-yet-both-orderly-and-disorderly, etc.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In the end, teotl is essentially an unstructured and unordered, seamless totality. Differentiation, regularity, order, etc. are simultaneously fictions of human unknowing and artistic-shamanic presentations of teotl. In Western philosophical terminology, one perhaps best characterizes the radical ontological indeterminacy of Nahua metaphysics as an extreme nominalist anti-realism, and teotl, as a Kantian-like noumenon.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Nahuas philosophers also conceived teotl pantheistically: (a) everything that exists constitutes an all-inclusive and interrelated unity; (b) this unity is sacred; (c) everything that exists is substantively identical and hence one with the sacred; (d) the sacred is teotl. <strong>There is only one thing, teotl, and all other forms or aspects of reality and existence are identical with teotl</strong>; (e) teotl is not a minded being or person.</p>
<p>Teotl is a sacred artist who endlessly fashions and refashions itself into and as the cosmos. The cosmos is teotl's grand, ongoing artistic-cum-metaphorical self-presentation; teotl's ongoing work of performance art or 'metaphor in motion'.</p>
<p>Teotl artistically-cum-shamanically presents and masks itself to humans in a variety of ways: (1) the apparent thingness of existents, i.e. the appearance of static entities such as humans, mountains, trees, insects, etc. <strong>This is illusory, since one and all are merely facets of teotl's sacred motion;</strong> (2) the apparent multiplicity of existents, i.e. the appearance of discrete, independently existing entities such as individual humans, plants, mountains, etc. <strong>This is illusory since there is only one thing: teotl;</strong> and (3) the apparent exclusivity, independence, and irreconcilable oppositionality of dualities such as order and disorder, life and death, etc. <strong>This is illusory since they are interrelated, complementary facets of teotl.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As an epistemological consequence of teotl's self-disguising, when humans customarily gaze upon the world, what they see is teotl as a human, as a tree, as female, etc. — i.e. teotl self-disguised — rather than teotl as teotl. <strong>Wisdom enables humans to discern the sacred presence of teotl in its myriad disguises.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is humans' misperceiving and misunderstanding teotl as its disguise which prevents them from seeing teotl (reality) as it really is. The only way humans experience teotl knowingly is to experience teotl sans description (non-symbolically). Humans experience teotl knowingly via a process of mystical-style union between their hearts and teotl that enables them to experience teotl directly i.e. without mediation by language, concepts, or categories. One comes to know teotl through teotl."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In other words:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4106" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yin_yang.gif" alt="yin_yang" width="615" /></p>
<p>You are Teotl!</p>
<p>This is one of the most beautiful & complete articulations of nonduality that I've ever come across.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/aztec-nonduality</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inside The Moonies Cult</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/inside-the-moonies-cult</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the world's most powerful cults is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unification_movement" target="_blank">Unification Church</a>, otherwise known as The Moonies. It was founded by Korean business tycoon, prophet, and convicted felon, Sun Myung Moon.</p>
<p>Here's an eye-opening documentary about it:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u1KruPlKi68?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>*Remember to take Wikipedia pages about major cults with a grain of salt. Cults have no qualms about falsifying their own Wikipedia pages to make themselves look better.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/inside-the-moonies-cult</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>An Inside Look At The Moonies Cult</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/an-inside-look-at-the-moonies-cult</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the world's most powerful cults is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unification_movement" target="_blank">Unification Church</a>, otherwise known as The Moonies. It was founded by Korean business tycoon, prophet, and convicted felon, Sun Myung Moon.</p>
<p>Here's an eye-opening documentary about it:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/u1KruPlKi68?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>*Remember to take Wikipedia pages about major cults with a grain of salt. Cults have no qualms about falsifying their own Wikipedia pages to make themselves look better.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/an-inside-look-at-the-moonies-cult</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Truth &amp; Silence</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/truth-and-silence</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you become so conscious of the truth of a matter that you just go silent.</p>
<p>Truth and silence work both ways: deep truth results in long silence, long silence results in deep truth.</p>
<p>Train yourself to bask in silence, like a cat basking in the rays of the sun.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/truth-and-silence</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Philosopher's Lamp</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/philosophers-lamp</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I love this example of a <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/reality-is-a-strange-loop" target="_blank">strange loop</a> by Belgian surrealist artist, Rene Magritte.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4088" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/rene-magritte-philosophers-lamp.jpg" alt="rene-magritte-philosophers-lamp" width="615" /></p>
<p>Here's how <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ren%C3%A9_Magritte" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a> describes Magritte's style: "He became well known for creating a number of witty and thought-provoking images. Often depicting ordinary objects in an unusual context, his work is known for challenging observers' preconditioned perceptions of reality. Magritte's constant play with reality and illusion has been attributed to the early death of his mother."</p>
<p>René Magritte described his paintings as "visible images which conceal nothing; they evoke mystery and, indeed, when one sees one of my pictures, one asks oneself this simple question, 'What does that mean?'. It does not mean anything, because mystery means nothing either, it is unknowable."</p>
<p>Just like nonduality. God is a strange loop. You try to know yourself, but you cannot.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/philosophers-lamp</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Recontexualized Porn Meme</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/recontexualized-porn-meme</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Just saw this amazing example of recontextualization, as discussed in my <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/understanding-recontextualization" target="_blank">Understanding Recontextualization</a> video.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BrLHHkSDJpV/" target="_blank">Recontextualized Porn Meme</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/recontexualized-porn-meme</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Weird Life Purpose = Win!</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/weird-life-purpose-equals-win</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>People sometimes think, "But Leo, how am I going to make a career out of my passion? What if my passion is something weird that cannot earn money?"</p>
<p>What people don't understand is, virtually any passion can be turned into a profitable life purpose and a career. Especially now in a globalized internet economy. Look at how this guy is following his passion:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8JWmLw5DR2Y?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>That could be you — metaphorically ;)</p>
<p>Don't be afraid to be weird. Own your passion, whatever it is. You can be weird as long as you are also strategic and following the principles laid out in my Life Purpose Course.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/weird-life-purpose-equals-win</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stage Green Epitome</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/stage-green-epitome</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Life doesn't get much Greener than this:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2bs24nK5er8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Pay close attention if watching this video triggers judgment in you. That's the Green value system rubbing up against your Orange & Blue ego.</p>
<p>How deeply have you integrated Green? How comfortable are you with Green? If this kind of value system disturbs you, you're not as developed as you like to think.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/stage-green-epitome</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Conscious Capitalism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/conscious-capitalism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.consciouscapitalism.org" target="_blank">Conscious Capitalism, Inc</a> is a non-profit organization started by the founder of Whole Foods, John Mackey, whose mission is to integrate consciousness with business. They take a Spiral Dynamics stage Green/Yellow approach to business.</p>
<p>Pretty cool!</p>
<p>If you are running a stage Orange business and you do not evolve your business into Green or above in the next 50 years, your business will be crushed by Green/Yellow corporations. So stop chasing max profits and start thinking strategically about how your business fits within human society at large. Your business must serve a super-ordinate purpose beyond lining your wallet.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/conscious-capitalism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Monism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/monism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4069" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/monism_01.png" alt="monism_01" width="292" height="292" /></p>
<p>Monism is simply the idea that "strictly speaking, there exists only a single thing, the Universe, which can only be artificially and arbitrarily divided into many things" and that "only one kind of stuff exists, although many things may be made up of this stuff."</p>
<p>This "stuff" is consciousness, or "mind", out of which EVERYTHING is made. So... An atom is consciousness; a tree is consciousness; a car is consciousness; a rock is consciousness; the sun is consciousness; a mathematics equation is consciousness; a political party is consciousness; the Big Bang is consciousness; your skull is consciousness; the pixels on this screen are consciousness; and so on until every last object in the universe is accounted for. Reality is one unified field of consciousness which subdivides itself in infinite variations.</p>
<p>This is a very elegant and powerful explanation of reality. It also happens to be Absolutely True. It is so true that its truth is prior to any religion, philosophical system, scientific theory, or physical law. It is more true than 1 = 1.</p>
<p>I recommend you thoroughly read this Wikipedia entry on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monism" target="_blank">Monism</a>. It's a great encapsulation of metaphysics, religion, and God across history. Monism is just another word for nonduality, and every culture around the world has a storied history of it because it turns out to be the ultimate truth. The only problem is that ultimate truth turns out to be a tricky thing for the mind to grasp, leading to much confusion and controversy.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/monism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Strange Loop Game</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-strange-loop-game</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>You can only appreciate this game after you understand <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/reality-is-a-strange-loop" target="_blank">what strange loops are</a>, and that YOU are a strange loop.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wC1jHHF_Wjo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>These are the kind of games I was interested in making when I was a game designer. It took me several decades to realize that my love of game design was really just my interest in showing off the beauty of God. That's really what all art is about.</p>
<p>Sometimes we don't realize how deep our motivations run until we're years into our spiritual journey. Most artists do not understand why they are artists. It's a form of pseudo-spirituality.</p>
<p>This game goes well with my other video: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/life-is-a-maze" target="_blank">Life Is A Maze</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-strange-loop-game</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Spiral View Of Terrorism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-spiral-view-of-terrorism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a great article by Dr. Don Beck (developer of Spiral Dynamics) on the nuances of terrorism. Terrorism is a lot more complex than you've been led to believe in the mainstream media:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.spiraldynamics.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/spiral-view-of-terrorism.pdf" target="_blank">Spiral View Of Terrorism PDF</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-spiral-view-of-terrorism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #013</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-013</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's the full quote from this week's video on <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/the-counter-intuitive-nature-of-life" target="_blank">The Counter-Intuitive Nature Of Life</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: justify;">"Sometimes when you win, you really lose, and sometimes when you lose, you really win, and sometimes when you win or lose, you actually tie, and sometimes when you tie, you actually win or lose. Winning or losing is all one organic mechanism, from which one extracts what one needs."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— White Men Can't Jump</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-013</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mystical Cat</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/mystical-cat</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Pure awesome!</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4wWvv6R-ZqQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/mystical-cat</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Zen Master Yamada Mumon</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/zen-master-yamada-mumon</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a rare look at Zen Master Yamada Mumon, as quoted in my video <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/the-ten-ox-herding-pictures" target="_blank">The Ten Ox-Herding Pictures</a>.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VYyPDwT1c2c?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>At the very end of the video, notice Mumon's instruction in response to the monk's attempt to answer his koan. The monk's answer came from the ego-mind, not the enlightened mind. Hence he failed the koan.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/zen-master-yamada-mumon</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How To Plug Psychedelics</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-to-plug-psychedelics</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/302242033?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Very important: Make sure you empty your bowels right before doing this, otherwise the substance will fail to properly absorb and your trip will be very weak. Treat this as an unbreakable rule: must go to the toilet before plugging.</p>
<p>Also, always trip on an empty stomach. Especially with 5-MeO-DMT, you want a TOTALLY empty stomach for at least 4 hours prior to the trip. This will make the difference between a great trip and a horrific trip. Do not violate this rule unless you like to suffer.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-to-plug-psychedelics</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Ideological Mind</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-ideological-mind</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's an eye-opening look inside the mind of conspiracy theorists. Not exactly a self-reflective bunch.</p>
<p>Here's how the trickeries of epistemology plays out in real life:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/To91BJGKr5I?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-ideological-mind</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Chart</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/spiral-dynamics-chart</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's the chart from this week's <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-important-insights" target="_blank">Spiral Dynamics - Important Insights</a> video:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/spiral-dynamics-chart-01.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4028" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/spiral-dynamics-chart-01.png" alt="spiral-dynamics-chart-01" width="615" /></a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/spiral-dynamics-chart</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding Fascism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-fascism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Fascism has recently been on the rise in the US and Europe.</p>
<p>Here's a really good interview. I also highly recommend you read the author's book.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ViPtWRJKu-Q?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The only thing missing from this discussion is an understanding of Spiral Dynamics.</p>
<p>Notice how both the interviewer and the author still don't have a deep grasp of where fascism sits along the spectrum of human development and what lies beyond stage Green progressive politics (of which TYT is a solid example).</p>
<p>Imagine how much better TYT would be if they understood Spiral Dynamics! Their analysis would be on another level entirely.</p>
<p>If you're looking for a life purpose and biz opportunity, start a news network like TYT but which covers politics from a stage Yellow integral perspective. That is the wave of the future. We have a severe lack of stage Yellow news networks and political commentary.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-fascism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Whirling Your Way To Enlightenment</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/whirling-your-way-to-enlightenment</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>There are more techniques to get enlightened than most people imagine. Case in point: Turkey's traditional Whirling Dervishes. Many Western tourists know of this odd-looking ritual, but how many of them know that this is a legit enlightenment technique? Developed by none other than the great Persian mystic Rumi.</p>
<p>Whirling is not just a hokey ritual but a form of active meditation. The spinning is designed to shut off the egoic monkey mind and produce states of ecstatic trance.</p>
<p>Read more about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sufi_whirling" target="_blank">Sufi Whirling Dervishes on Wikipedia</a>.</p>
<p>The symbolism of the ritual is pretty interesting too. The dancer wears a tall thick camel hair hat which represents the tombstone of the ego. The dancer's white skirt represents the shroud of the ego which must be cast off (sound familiar?). The taking off of the black cloak prior to whirling represents spiritual rebirth into the Truth. The crossing of the arms represents the number one, for the nondual unity of God. The whirling is done around the center of the heart, which represents unconditional love for reality. And mantras are mentally recited while whirling to further still the monkey mind.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fHjFgOfoZ7M?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>If you decide to give whirling a try at home, watch out that you don't hit anything, or fall down, or faint from dizziness. This can be a physically dangerous technique. You can easily crack your head open. Best to do it out on a grassy field.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/whirling-your-way-to-enlightenment</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Futurama's Bender Encounters God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/futuramas-bender-encounters-god</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Great scene:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_nwvCGLmFEA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/futuramas-bender-encounters-god</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Enlightenment Retreat Fail</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/enlightenment-retreat-fail</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>When your solo enlightenment retreat fails:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4011" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/enlightenment-retreat-fail-01.gif" alt="enlightenment-retreat-fail-01" width="420" height="316" /></p>
<p>P.S. This is also what it looks like when your first business fails and your first attempt to pick up a girl fails ;)</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/enlightenment-retreat-fail</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding Psychosis</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-psychosis</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a really good video explaining how psychosis intersects with spirituality.</p>
<p>Very few Western scientists, academics, doctors, or mental health professionals understand what psychosis is and how to properly handle it — because they are spiritually ignorant, operating from the materialist paradigm. This is not a clinical problem so much as a cultural problem. Doctors will often just think of you as crazy and load you up on drugs, making the situation much worse. If you know anyone who has suffered from symptoms of psychosis, show them this video. It could be a life-changer.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CFtsHf1lVI4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-psychosis</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dumbo Gets Trippy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/dumbo-gets-trippy</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Something about this animation rings so true of how universal mind works. Universal mind has this sort of whimsical intelligence, which makes it so creative.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jcZUPDMXzJ8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Notice how much intelligence is displayed here. This is a tiny glimpse of infinite intelligence. Notice how it is non-rational. It's not less than rational, it's more than.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/dumbo-gets-trippy</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Remember To Vote 2018</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/remember-to-vote-2018</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3999" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/leo_vote_01.jpg" alt="leo_vote_01" width="400" height="533" /></p>
<p>If you're in the US, it's time to vote. Early voting has started in many states.</p>
<p>2018 is an important election cycle.</p>
<p>Who should you vote for? Vote for the most conscious, the most Spirally developed candidates who have a reasonable chance of winning. Do not fall into the trap of voting on single issues. Vote on the overall level of development of the candidate. The more conscious the leader, the better they will lead, the less corruption and egotism they will enable.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/remember-to-vote-2018</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nootropics Forum</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/nootropics-forum</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>As promised in the Nootropics video, here's a nootropics forum I like:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.longecity.org/forum/forum/169-brain-health/" target="_blank">LongeCity Brain Health Forum</a></p>
<p>It's a great resource if you're trying to optimize your brain health.</p>
<p>P.S. The <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Nootropics/" target="_blank">Nootropics subReddit</a> is also great.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/nootropics-forum</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Magic Of Consciousness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-magic-of-consciousness</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>It can be easier to recognize what consciousness is when it changes rapidly and fluidly right before your eyes. Can you see that the image below is pure consciousness? Look at what consciousness can do! Try staring at it as though you were meditating on it. Become aware that it is you. This is NOT pixels on a screen! This is CONSCIOUSNESS!</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3973" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/consciousness.gif" alt="consciousness" width="500" /></p>
<p>Marvel at your own beauty.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-magic-of-consciousness</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Dunning-Kruger Effect</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-dunning-kruger-effect</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect" target="_blank">Dunning-Kruger Effect</a> explains why, when people are ignorant, they tend to be aggressively ignorant.</p>
<p>"If you're incompetent, you can't know you're incompetent... The skills you need to produce a right answer are exactly the skills you need to recognize what a right answer is." — David Dunning</p>
<p>Basically, the more of a fool you are, the less capacity you have to recognize that you are being a fool. Have you noticed? — when dealing with a fool, how difficult it can be to convince him that he's a fool? That's precisely what makes him a fool!</p>
<p>Arrogance & intransigence are the hallmark of fools.</p>
<p>Humility is the hallmark of sages.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-dunning-kruger-effect</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Skepticism &amp; Nonduality</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/skepticism-and-nonduality</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/293223395?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/skepticism-and-nonduality</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Shugendo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/shugendo</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Shugendo is a 7th century Japanese form of spirituality:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8Cl3MCzB_WM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Shugendo was banned by the Japanese government in 1872 until the end of WWII, when religious freedom was restored.</p>
<p>This is how self-actualization was done 1000 years ago. And it's still done this way in many places around the world today.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/shugendo</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Yugen</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/yugen</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yugen_02.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3976" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yugen_02.png" alt="yugen_02" width="615" /></a></p>
<p>This is what I was talking about in the <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/what-is-spirituality" target="_blank">What Is Spirituality? video</a> where I said that spirituality is "developing a deep metaphysical connection with reality."</p>
<p>Yugen! — that's what you're really looking for.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/yugen</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How I Started My First Business</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-i-started-my-first-business</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/293100442?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-i-started-my-first-business</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hate or Love?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/hate-or-love</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a really interesting look into a heavy version of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Spiral Dynamics stage Blue</a> ethnocentrism.</p>
<p>Ethnocentrism means: "I love my family, people, my race, my religion, my country, my culture, my traditions We are the best!" The world is divided into us vs them. What happens to "them" — other peoples, races, nations, religions, countries, cultures — does not matter. They are basically dispensable. They can be hated, excluded, demonized, slandered, raped, killed, tortured, etc. That doesn't matter because "they" are not "us".</p>
<p>One of the astounding features of the ethnocentric mindset is that it lacks the self-awareness to realize that it is ethnocentric. It literally cannot see outside its own perspective. You must understand: just because you have the capacity to look at the world through different perspectives does not mean that everyone else does! Most people do not have this capacity! This capacity is not a given.</p>
<p>Very few people understand the ethnocentric mindset. Those who have developed beyond it cannot understand it because it looks like delusion of the highest order. To whose who are immersed in it, it looks totally natural, normal, and could not be otherwise. So neither side really understands.</p>
<p>I challenge you here not to judge, not to gawk, but to really seek to understand the mindset and worldview of an ethnocentric person. Get inside their mind. Look at the world as they see it.</p>
<p>Remember, about 70-80% of the world population is at ethnocentric stage Blue. It would be wise of you to develop a deep understanding of how they think.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HFwOF9VTvhA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Important Note: Ethnocentrism comes in many degrees. The example above is a fairly heavy degree. Not all stage Blue people are this heavy. Although, many of them are! — just in more socially acceptable ways.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/hate-or-love</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>