<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Leo's Blog: Infinite Insights - Actualized.org</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leo's Blog: Infinite Insights - Actualized.org]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 11:07:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>How Capitalism Is Corrupting Science</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-capitalism-is-corrupting-science</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A very interesting discussion about the dirty realities of how science works:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1on3njRwdA0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Over the next 50 years, I foresee science becoming more and more biased by capitalistic forces, skewing our overall worldview to one which favors the corporate collective ego.</p>
<p>The materialist metaphysics that's prevalent in science doesn't just exist because it's reasonable, but because a mystical worldview is fundamentally threatening to business as usual ($$$). The materialist metaphysics helps business earn lots of money, and business re-invests this money back into more materialistic forms of research, creating a vicious circle of materialism, blind to higher consciousness truths.</p>
<p>So on the surface those people who trust in science (including the scientists themselves) end up thinking that materialism is getting more and more validated when in fact that's only happening because non-materialistic findings are being ignored because they don't feed the capitalist agenda. To put it simply, truth is bad for business.</p>
<p>Almost everyone knows that religion gets corrupted by ego because that's old news. What's new news is that science gets corrupted by ego in just the same way. The problem with atheists railing against religion is that it makes them blind to parallel dynamics occurring within science. The devil (ego) doesn't care whether your favorite ideology is religion or science. He will find a way to delude you with it all the same.</p>
<p>Always be skeptical when you hear an ego quoting scientific research as if it were objective fact. People like Sam Harris, Richard Dawkins, Jordan Peterson come to mind here. People like that love to weaponize science to advance their own agendas.</p>
<p>P.S. Don't make the mistake that I am an enemy of science. Just the opposite. Every time I speak against science it's because I want science to be pure and unbiased. I speak against its corruptions and lack of self-awareness in the same way that Martin Luther spoke against the Catholic Church. But as always, the problem with calling out corruption inside any institution is that one gets seen as an enemy of that institution. Every institution has a collective ego which stubbornly defends itself — warts, corruption, and all.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-capitalism-is-corrupting-science</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Capitalism Corrupts Science</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-capitalism-corrupts-science</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A very interesting discussion about the dirty realities of how science works:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1on3njRwdA0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Over the next 50 years, I foresee science becoming more and more biased by capitalistic forces, skewing our overall worldview to one which favors the corporate collective ego.</p>
<p>The materialist metaphysics that's prevalent in science doesn't just exist because it's reasonable, but because a mystical worldview is fundamentally threatening to business as usual ($$$). The materialist metaphysics helps business earn lots of money, and business re-invests this money back into more materialistic forms of research, creating a vicious circle of materialism, blind to higher consciousness truths.</p>
<p>So on the surface those people who trust in science (including the scientists themselves) end up thinking that materialism is getting more and more validated when in fact that's only happening because non-materialistic findings are being ignored because they don't feed the capitalist agenda. To put it simply, truth is bad for business.</p>
<p>Almost everyone knows that religion gets corrupted by ego because that's old news. What's new news is that science gets corrupted by ego in just the same way. The problem with atheists railing against religion is that it makes them blind to parallel dynamics occurring within science. The devil (ego) doesn't care whether your favorite ideology is religion or science. He will find a way to delude you with it all the same.</p>
<p>Always be skeptical when you hear an ego quoting scientific research as if it were objective fact. People like Sam Harris, Richard Dawkins, Jordan Peterson come to mind here. People like that love to weaponize science to advance their own agendas.</p>
<p>P.S. Don't make the mistake that I am an enemy of science. Just the opposite. Every time I speak against science it's because I want science to be pure and unbiased. I speak against its corruptions and lack of self-awareness in the same way that Martin Luther spoke against the Catholic Church. But as always, the problem with calling out corruption inside any institution is that one gets seen as an enemy of that institution. Every institution has a collective ego which stubbornly defends itself — warts, corruption, and all.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-capitalism-corrupts-science</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ken Wilber Explains Integral Spirituality</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/ken-wilber-explains-integral-spirituality</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a fantastic high level overview of spirituality & human cultural evolution:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H4jcxxJ_0ok?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/ken-wilber-explains-integral-spirituality</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Super Mario Edition</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/spiral-dynamics-super-mario-edition</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This one is for all you video game fans in the audience. Have you noticed how video games have evolved over the last 40 years?</p>
<p>See any parallels to how human culture evolved over the last 2000 years?</p>
<p>Here's a little something I put together:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/spiral-dynamics-super-mario-edition-01.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3808" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/spiral-dynamics-super-mario-edition-01.png" alt="spiral-dynamics-super-mario-edition-01" width="615" /></a></p>
<p>(click to enlarge image)</p>
<p>Everything is evolving!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/spiral-dynamics-super-mario-edition</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Strange Loop Meme</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/strange-loop-meme</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The structure of reality in a nutshell:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3798" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/asian-mind-fuck.jpg" alt="asian-mind-fuck" width="480" height="440" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/strange-loop-meme</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Exodus 3:13-14</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/exodus-313-14</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"Then Moses said to God, 'If I come to the people of Israel and say to them, 'The God of your fathers has sent me to you,' and they ask me, 'What is his name?' what shall I say to them? God said to Moses, "I AM WHO I AM.' And he said, 'Say this to the people of Israel, 'I AM has sent me to you.'"</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— Exodus 3:13-14</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/exodus-313-14</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoda #010</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-010</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3789" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-feminism-02.png" alt="yoda-feminism-02" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-010</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Growing Earth?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-growing-earth</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Dragonflies have puzzled me for a long time. You see, they used to have a 2 foot wingspan! (<em>Meganeuradae</em>)</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3738" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/meganeura_01.jpg" alt="meganeura_01" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3739" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/meganeura_02.jpg" alt="meganeura_02" width="615" /></p>
<p>So have pterodactyls. Can you imagine one of these beasts (<em>Quetzalcoatlus</em>) — the size of a giraffe — flying through the air?</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3741" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/dactyl_02.jpg" alt="dactyl_02" width="237" height="269" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3740" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/dactyl_01.jpg" alt="dactyl_01" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3742" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/quetzalcoatlu_01.jpg" alt="quetzalcoatlu_01" width="614" height="390" /></p>
<p>And finally we have the walking giants, like the <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2017/08/is-this-really-the-biggest-dinosaur-ever-discovered/536187/" target="_blank"><em>Patagotitan</em></a>, larger than a blue whale.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3743" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/dino_scale_01.jpg" alt="dino_scale_01" width="615" /></p>
<p>How could such large creatures exist given Earth's gravity? And why are there no such large animals at all any more? No mammal, no reptile, no bird, no insect even comes close.</p>
<p>So with that in the back of your mind, now consider this unorthodox idea:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oJfBSc6e7QQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>A few more detailed videos if you want to go down the rabbit hole:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=swCnPOi5qOU" target="_blank">Explaining the Expanding Earth - With Peter Woodhead</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WARitSJub40" target="_blank">Earth Expansion Tectonics Lecture by Dr James Maxlow</a></li>
</ul>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3754" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/expansion-tectonics-01.png" alt="expansion-tectonics-01" width="615" /></p>
<p>Evidence in favor of a growing Earth:</p>
<ul>
<li>Continent borders seem to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7018h1a6o_0" target="_blank">line up perfectly</a> at an Earth radius of ~50%.</li>
<li>Fossil record of monstrously-sized dinosaurs and insects which seem anatomically impossible given Earth current gravity. Why are all of today's creatures far smaller than those of the past? This trend is very noticeable with no good explanation. This is easily accounted for by reducing Earth size by ~50% (not just radius but mass too).</li>
<li>Why aren't giant dragonflies still a thing? We still have dragonflies today. What is stopping them from growing 2 foot long? Other animals which used to be giant-sized, like giant sharks and giant crocodiles, are also now small. Why?</li>
<li>It seems that ancient fossils are only found on land. No ancient fossils are found in the oceans.</li>
<li><a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/08/Age_oceanic_lithosphere%2C_Muller_et_al.%2C_2008.jpg" target="_blank">Dating of the sea floor</a> shows it to be extremely young. The oldest sea floor is only 180 million years old and much of it is newer. There is no billion year old sea floor rock.</li>
<li>Stretch marks seem to radiate outward as if the Earth was a slowly inflating balloon.</li>
<li>The theory of plate tectonics is less than 100 years old. It was extremely controversial when first proposed, and rejected by most geologists. It only became accepted by scientific consensus in the 1960's. And to this day the theory contains inconsistencies.</li>
<li>Plate tectonics and continental drift theory would have us believe that continents slide and rotate around almost randomly, which looks absurd and nonsensical. Why would continents float around and rotate?</li>
<li>It makes little sense why Pangaea would form on the early Earth. Why would the Earth be so lopsided, with 1/3rd solid continents and the other 2/3rds solid ocean? It makes more sense that the distribution of land and water on the early Earth was uniform.</li>
<li>There is no strong empirical evidence of subduction (land sliding back inside the Earth's core). No good theory as to why subduction would happen given the density of the underlying rock.</li>
<li>Evidence for spreading ocean floor is much more significant than evidence for subducting ocean floor. The notion of subduction could easily just be a cop-out hypothesis designed to save the otherwise nonsensical theory of plate tectonics.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/rare-diamond-confirms-that-earths-mantle-holds-an-oceans-worth-of-water/" target="_blank">Newly discovered ringwoodite</a> in the Earth's core contains more locked-in water than the entire surface of the Earth! There is literally enough water in the Earth's core to refill all the Earth's oceans several times over. Think about that. This makes it much more plausible that the oceans leaked out from inside the core over millions of years. Like slowly squeezing a lemon.</li>
<li>The <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tBT8KyWVxj8" target="_blank">moon</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d44Jj_3gp-M" target="_blank">Mars</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zy3_sWF7tv4" target="_blank">Europa</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Fsg1XJTbKA" target="_blank">Ganymede</a> show similar kinds of stretch marks and signs of growth.</li>
<li>There is zero direct empirical evidence of what's inside the Earth's core, only vague guesses. Scientists assume they know, but that is merely inference, which can easily turn out wrong. Since scientists have never directly observed the deep inner core of any planet, their models of what's really going on inside are mostly just speculation, which could turn out to be wildly inaccurate. It's conceivable that even if the core was hollow, it would be very difficult for scientists to discover that without actually going there.</li>
<li>There is zero direct empirical evidence of Pangaea, or how the continents moved, or how they were arranged hundreds of millions of years ago. There are just vague extrapolations based on prevailing continental drift theory, which is precisely the thing being called into question.</li>
<li>If the Earth used to be smaller, as it grows bigger, its rotation speed will have to slow down to conserve angular momentum. It is well known that the rotation of the Earth has been slowing down, with days getting longer.</li>
</ul>
<p>Crazy? True?</p>
<p>I can't say for sure, but it is an intriguing idea that's just unorthodox enough to slip under the radar of the mainstream scientific establishment. It's just the kind of idea that a closedminded academic would dismiss as "pseudoscience" due to lack of understanding of epistemology and how paradigms work.</p>
<p>The reason I'm presenting this idea isn't to get you to buy into a conspiracy theory, but to jostle your worldview and get you to really question what you think you know about reality. What do you really know for sure? I want you to start to notice how giant discoveries can lurk right under your nose, hidden in plain sight. Even if this theory turns out to be false, others like it may not. Most people assume that modern science is so advanced that there's just no room for massive blindspots. This is not the case. It's important to start to see that science is much more messy and complex than people are taught. The cutting edge of science is always wrestling with questions of how to properly interpret the data, which anomalies are worth taking seriously and which are not.</p>
<p>Of course the whole trick here is how do you distinguish between science vs pseudoscience? How do you distinguish between a promising new theory vs a crackpot conspiracy theory? Well... the key point is that it's not as easy as you've been led to believe. All knowledge is nontrivial. There never was a clear demarcation between truth and falsehood, fact and fiction, data and theory. You only assumed there was.</p>
<p>So for all you Jurassic Park fans, consider the possibility that if dinosaurs were genetically birthed in a lab today, they would fall dead under their own weight.</p>
<p>My goal here is not to make you feel convinced, but you make you feel doubtful about what you know.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-growing-earth</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wendover Productions</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/wendover-productions</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>You can find some really good educational channels on Youtube. Here's one that I found recently which I really liked. It covers interesting topics, like this:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQ2jmrz_xgU?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Check out their other interesting videos: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/Wendoverproductions/videos" target="_blank">Wendover Productions</a></p>
<p>The geography ones are some of the best.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/wendover-productions</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cannabis Legalization?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/cannabis-legalization</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a really intelligent discussion about the ramifications of cannabis legalization:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jo9Stp6KvYs?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>I don't recommend pot use because it tends to become addictive. I never use it myself even though it is legal in my state. But I do support nationwide legalization because this war on drugs is absurd, counter-productive, and we need to pave the way for legalization of psychedelics, the prohibition of which is a clear violation of 1st Amendment rights to freedom of religion:</p>
<blockquote><p>"Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— U.S. Constitution, 1st Amendment</p>
<p>Anyone who claims that psychedelics are not a religious/spiritual tool is inexperienced and ignorant of religious history and numerous scientific studies. If psychedelics are not an exercise of religion, nothing is. In the future, this will be recognized by the Supreme Court and the criminalization of these substances will go down in the history books as yet another example of 21st century barbarism. We ain't out of the Dark Ages yet.</p>
<p>P.S. Congrats to Canada for <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hzTA6PF4Ip4" target="_blank">finally legalizing cannabis</a> this week!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/cannabis-legalization</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Jesus Of Siberia</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-jesus-of-siberia</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you're stage Blue or Orange, get ready to be triggered:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n8BOMqks-gQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>That's how all religions start out. The guy seems enlightened as fuck.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-jesus-of-siberia</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Random Insight #001</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/random-insight-001</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Notice, you cannot be objective about a thing which you fear or hate</strong>.</p>
<p>Corollary: you cannot discover Truth, or embody Truth, so long as there is fear or hate in you. All fear and hate must be surrendered. All! Without exception. Even your fear of the danger of not being able to fear or hate any more.</p>
<p>"Hate" here isn't limited to violent rage. Hate includes: judgment, criticism, condemnation, demonization, anger, ill-will, vengeance, disgust, desire to destroy, having enemies, and justifications for your hate.</p>
<p>Mild forms of fear and hate are still fear and hate. Fear and hate can be very subtle.</p>
<p>All justifications for fear and hate are delusion. All attempts to explain why your fear or hate is valid, "good", necessary, or warranted, are delusion — only doubling down on your position.</p>
<p>Fear and hate are inversely proportional to Truth. The closer you approach Truth, the closer fear and hate drop to zero. Want to know how close you are to Truth? How much fear and hate is in you on a daily basis?</p>
<p>Without fear, there is no purpose for hate.</p>
<p>All fear boils down to fear of injury and death.</p>
<p>When your fear reaches zero, your experience of love will reach infinity. You will love every single molecule in the universe. A heart-wrenching, super-natural degree of love. Metaphysical love.</p>
<p>Strength, is your capacity to surrender fear and hatred. Strength is wisdom. The highest wisdom is the surrender of one's life.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/random-insight-001</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoda #009</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-009</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3769" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-spiral-dynamics-1.png" alt="yoda-spiral-dynamics" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-009</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Esalen Institute Workshops</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/esalen-institute-workshops</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you've never heard of the <a href="https://www.esalen.org" target="_blank">Esalen Institute</a> — you're in for a treat.</p>
<p>Esalen was an epicenter for the human potential movement back in the 1960's. Abraham Maslow used to lecture there. It's a bastion for stage Green/Yellow/Turquoise holistic teachings. Very, very New-Agey. Stage Orange people will feel unconformable here. It's located in scenic Big Sur, California, right on the coast, and it's still going strong after some 50 years.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3761" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/Esalen_01.jpg" alt="Esalen_01" width="615" /></p>
<p>You'll find some amazing <a href="https://www.esalen.org/learn" target="_blank">workshops and retreats</a> offered here, including yoga, meditation, neo-shamanism, love, relationships, consciousness, psychedelics, and much more. It's very similar to the kind of stuff I teach. You could also meet some exceptional people here who are into self-actualization.</p>
<p>Worth checking out if you've got some money saved up.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/esalen-institute-workshops</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Putin's Stage Blue Pandering</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/putins-stage-blue-pandering</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Since we're talking <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_5iLt1p-W1U" target="_blank">Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue</a> this week, here's a hilarious example of stage Blue propaganda in action.</p>
<p>See, Russia, like middle-America, is fairly conservative and traditionalist (stage Blue). This is largely Putin's base. Putin (Red/Orange) is a very shrewd politician and master-manipulator, so he knows that stage Blue gets triggered by stage Green. So what better way to activate his base than by fear-mongering about gays coming to take over traditional Russian culture?</p>
<p>Does Putin really care about gays? I would bet not. But he knows his conservative base cares very much about defending Russian culture. So he tosses them a bone or two by putting on a strong anti-gay front.</p>
<p>Watch this masterpiece of Spiral Dynamics manipulation:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zKD4i-4uTo8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/putins-stage-blue-pandering</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stage Blue Pandering</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/stage-blue-pandering</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Since we're talking <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue</a> this week, here's a hilarious example of stage Blue propaganda in action.</p>
<p>See, Russia, like middle-America, is fairly conservative and traditional (stage Blue). This is largely Putin's base. Putin (stage Red/Orange) is a very shrewd politician and master-manipulator, so he knows that stage Blue gets triggered by stage Green. So what better way to activate his base than by fear-mongering about gays coming to take over traditional Russian culture?</p>
<p>Does Putin really care about gays? <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m8xSZ9Fr4c0" target="_blank">I would bet not.</a> But he knows his conservative base cares very much about defending Russian culture. So he tosses them a bone or two by putting on an anti-gay front. A great way to mobilize Blue is to tell them how gays are taking over the world. Interestingly, here in America we got <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_ePLkAm8i2s" target="_blank">Alex Jones doing a similar thing</a>.</p>
<p>Watch this masterpiece of Spiral Dynamics manipulation:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zKD4i-4uTo8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>And then of course we've got examples of a legit stage Blue worldview — not pandering. Take a look a how a deeply stage Blue person — in this case, the former president of Iran — reacts to the idea of gay people. In his reality, gay people do not exist!</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RUE0tukdr4c?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>That's how significant the Spiral Dynamics stages are!</p>
<p>Here's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pxH_Rp9VIj8" target="_blank">another example from Mugabe of Zimbabwe</a>.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JZJNIgwubr4" target="_blank">Malawi, gays also don't exist</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n3ujZmHyfP8" target="_blank">The Dark History Of Gay Conversion Therapy</a></p>
<p>The reason I focus on this gay issue is because it's a relatively new cultural development, so we get to see cultural evolution resisted in real-time. This is how it's always been, for over 2000 years in every country in the world. Stage Blue resisted every new progressive innovation. Today it is gays. 150 years ago it was the end of slavery. 2500 years ago it was writing. Socrates famously rejected writing as a valid means of doing philosophy on the grounds that it would rot people's memories. (With writing, who needs to have a good memory?, Socrates reasoned.)</p>
<p>And even though many of today's politicians are themselves beyond stage Blue, a large portion of their constituents is not, so you shouldn't be surprised to see them pandering and riling up that Blue base.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/stage-blue-pandering</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fake Moon Landing?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/fake-moon-landing</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>These videos show pretty conclusively that the moon landing was <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">NOT</span></strong> faked:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/syVP6zDZN7I?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Additional evidence:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zPj60sy9Cfw" target="_blank">Moon Lighting</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OM5-BhMNXOI" target="_blank">Moon Gravity</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yhab86KoVjU" target="_blank">Flag Waving In Vacuum</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VmVxSFnjYCA" target="_blank">Retro-Reflectors</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eTYCz4ft8yw" target="_blank">Footprints</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L9mYWWHREag" target="_blank">No Wires</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Hooray for science!</p>
<p>Now, if only they would realize the moon is made out of consciousness! That would be a giant leap for mankind ;)</p>
<p>P.S. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zpkUjrC3-Ds" target="_blank">Astronaut ice cream is a lie!</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/fake-moon-landing</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #009</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-009</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"An American President may not marry his own sister (if he wishes to get reelected); an Egyptian Pharaoh had to marry his own sister."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— Robert Anton Wilson</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-009</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Samadhi Movie</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/samadhi-movie</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a nice high-level summation of nonduality. I like how the author integrates dozens of different traditions.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AQL6qcGqQ0Y?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/samadhi-movie</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Batman #008</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-008</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3492" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/batman-religions-disagree.png" alt="batman-religions-disagree" width="615" height="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-008</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Holy Shit</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/holy-shit</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Imagine someone sprinkled a bag of flawless diamonds into a giant steaming pile of horse manure.</p>
<p>That's religion in a nutshell.</p>
<p>What makes religion so persistent is that people refuse to give up the shit because there really are diamonds inside there. It's precisely this mixture of blinding brilliance and utter nonsense that makes religion so sticky. Atheists and rationalists fail to comprehend this dynamic, which is why religion baffles them. The rationalist, try as he might, just cannot satisfactorily explain why religion refuses to go away. It never occurs to him that there could be precious diamonds in the mix.</p>
<p>The Devil, knowing that most humans have a very weak capacity for discernment, simply hides the Truth in a deep pile of shit, which pretty much ensures it will never be found.</p>
<p>Think about this: if you had a precious diamond that you didn't want anyone to ever find, where would be the best place to hide it?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/holy-shit</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>May 2018 Solo Retreat - Part 3</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/may-2018-solo-retreat-part-3</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/273657347?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/may-2018-solo-retreat-part-3</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #008</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-008</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"One is impressed (and depressed) by the appalling sterility of the vast mass of minutiae that science accumulates, and the dearth of integrating principles."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— Benjamin Lee Whorf</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-008</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>May 2018 Solo Retreat - Part 2</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/may-2018-solo-retreat-part-2</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/273044255?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/may-2018-solo-retreat-part-2</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The God Debate</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-god-debate</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's an interesting debate between Jordan Peterson (theist) vs Matt Dillahunty (atheist). I usually don't like listening to debates because the truth of the matter never comes to light, but this one was about as good as debates get on this thorny topic. Of course the truth still didn't come out. Not even close. Both sides fundamentally misunderstand what God is. In fact, neither side actually defined what God is in nearly 2 hours of talking! Rather absurd. But still eye-opening to watch just to see the epistemic mistakes being made. Interestingly, although Matt Dillahunty seems to make more sense and be more "reasonable", Peterson is closer to the truth, although still wrong in many ways.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FmH7JUeVQb8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The problem is that neither man has actually become conscious of God, so both are speaking about a topic they have virtually no experience with. Peterson has come close, but not deep enough to really understand what God is, why it is, and what the ramifications are. Neither of them take seriously the possibility of direct consciousness of God. Peterson comes close (he mentions mystical experiences and psilocybin), but still too indirect about it. The whole debate is beating around the bush.</p>
<p>So I decided to do a little analysis of where each man goes wrong and where each man is right. Not to ridicule or judge them, but to help onlookers get some real traction on this God issue. Otherwise the debate is a total waste of time. You will listen to it, but you won't actually make any progress towards understanding God, or the numerous subtle mistakes the mind makes when thinking about God. So watch the debate, and then read this analysis.</p>
<p>Where Matt Dillahunty is wrong:</p>
<ul>
<li>God = Reality. You are misunderstanding what the word "God" is pointing to. God is not a bearded man in the clouds.</li>
<li>God is not a belief or concept, God is consciousness. Consciousness is infinite and formless so you cannot grasp it with mind or language or science.</li>
<li>God is empirical, but because God is Nothingness AND equivalent to reality itself, it is devoid of attributes and IS reality itself! So the "proof" you seek is your own existence.</li>
<li>Don't confuse "God is Nothingness" with "God does not exist", as if it's a validation of atheism. Nothingness exists. Atheism is wrong.</li>
<li>Atheism is a religion. It's a secular, rational ideology. So by going from fundamentalist Christian to atheist, you merely changed the content of your religion.</li>
<li>God is: consciousness, existence, Being, Nothingness, Absolute Infinity, YOU!, infinite intelligence, infinite power, eternal, omnipresent</li>
<li>God is not rational and cannot be "made sense of" because reality is an infinite strange loop.</li>
<li>You can become directly conscious of God.</li>
<li>God cannot be "proven" objectively because reality is subjective. In the same way that you cannot prove that you exist without appeal to subjectivity. Subjectivity is not a bad word, it is not a mistake. It's fundamental to reality. There is no reality beyond subjectivity.</li>
<li>Mankind has understood what consciousness is and what God is, very clearly, for over 5000 years. The problem is that the mind cannot grasp it.</li>
<li>Science cannot be done without language. And language cannot grasp being because it is a 2nd order thing, therefore language cannot grasp God.</li>
<li>You've turned skepticism into a dogma, falling into the very same trap from which you think you've escaped when you left fundamentalist Christian religion.</li>
<li>What you believe morally is largely irrelevant, what matters is your level of consciousness. The reason you can be an atheist and not kill people is because you're at Spiral Dynamics stage Orange consciousness. Creating a moral humanist code is irrelevant. Consciousness is the overriding factor. If you give a humanist moral code to stage Red or Blue consciousness, they will not follow it. Humanism is only possible at stage Orange or above.</li>
<li>Study Spiral Dynamics and realize that you are stuck in classic stage Orange consciousness. Rationalism stuck inside itself.</li>
<li>True spirituality isn't static like fundamentalist religion. True spirituality is free of dogma, free of beliefs — even moreso than skepticism. Skepticism taken to its ultimate conclusion becomes spirituality and reveals God. But you're not seeing that because you're not being skeptical enough! Skepticism goes full-circle, but you gotta take it MUCH deeper. Start doubting whether objective reality exists.</li>
<li>Let go of atheism, skepticism, rationalism, science, and your judgments about mysticism. It's okay. You'll be much better off. Your consciousness will skyrocket.</li>
<li>There are not multiple gods, there is only one God, because it is Absolute Infinity, so nothing can be outside it.</li>
<li>There are higher levels of consciousness which you have never accessed which will recontextual what you call "physical reality".</li>
<li>Consciousness is not a product of the brain, the brain is a creation within consciousness.</li>
<li>The brain does not exist. It is a hallucination within consciousness. Consciousness exists without need of brains.</li>
<li>You misunderstand psychedelic experiences because you are interpreting them within the materialist paradigm. That is, you assumes an objective external reality exists.</li>
<li>Your use of skepticism (as Peterson quite brilliantly points out) is incomplete. You are not being skeptical enough about rationality, skepticism, materialism, and pragmatism.</li>
<li>We are not physical creatures in a physical reality (explicit axiom made by Dillahunty) which is demonstrably false.</li>
<li>Conflation of Spiral Dynamics stage Purple & Blue religion with stage Turquoise mysticism. Fundamentalist Christianity is being confused with mysticism and nonduality.</li>
<li>Misunderstanding of the origin of religion.</li>
<li>Consciousness is NOT a biological phenomena.</li>
<li>You should be much more skeptical about the boundaries your mind draws between objects. They have no objective reality.</li>
<li>Science has never proven the existence of an objective external world. All scientific measurements are relative to the instrument used, and relative to your consciousness.</li>
<li>You should be much more skeptical about science and the materialist paradigm.</li>
<li>There is no acknowledgment that atheist/skepticism/rationalism constitute a paradigm — one paradigm out of infinitely many.</li>
<li>Lack of experience with psychedelics. A few LSD trips is NOT going to cut it, especially for a hardcore rationalist/skeptic like you because you're framing everything in the context of "physical universe, physical brain". The point of psychedelics is to use them to help you to undermine this materialist context.</li>
<li>Misunderstanding of mystical experience. You describe your own mystical experience, but I would not call that a mystical experience at all. That's like a drop in the ocean. You need to go much deeper. A mystical experience is not merely "some nice feeling one gets in a passionate church congregation". There are many depths of mystical experience, and what you described is weak-sauce. Not even 1% depth.</li>
<li>Lack of understanding that reality/truth cannot be symbolized or captured via language or concepts.</li>
<li>Reality absolutely cannot be described with a set of true/false proposition (as Dillahunty claims). This is what the Logical Positivists tried to do in the early 1920's and their efforts were completely shattered by Quine, quantum mechanics, Godel's incompleteness theorem, post-modernism, chaos theory, and developments within philosophy of language, philosophy of science, and epistemology. Wittgenstein tried to do what Dillahunty claims, and latter in his life he admitted it was an untenable and naive idea. Peterson was correct in asking Dillahunty, "Are you sure you want to go there?" Dillahunty shows a lack of familiarity with the last 100 years of philosophy of science & epistemology.</li>
<li>Reality is not causal. Cause and effect do not hold at higher levels of consciousness.</li>
<li>Science is as much a hallucination as the strawberry he hallucinated on LSD.</li>
<li>The point of psychedelics is not that you believe the hallucinations, but that you realize that EVERYTHING is a hallucination, including you sitting there right now.</li>
<li>Sam Harris is wrong about God. He is not awake. Please stop citing him as an authority.</li>
<li>Death is a conceptual hallucination. Be more skeptical about birth and death.</li>
<li>There is no meaning or value to survival. Survival and life is not better than death. Peterson did a great job of pushing Dillahunty on this point. Peterson was right.</li>
<li>The purpose of life is not survival. Life has no purpose. Survival or self-preservation is completely irrational and one should be very skeptical about the mind's desire for self-preservation. You cannot understand Truth so long as you are attached to self-preservation and survival.</li>
<li>Pragmatism isn't a feature, it's a bug.</li>
<li>There is no such thing as reality without consciousness.</li>
<li>Matt Dillahunty is God. The problem is that your present level of consciousness keeps your stuck within the ego-mind.</li>
<li>Mystical experiences are not "merely subjective" — they are not "experiences" at all. They are Absolute consciousness.</li>
<li>Science and skepticism are hallucinations within a dream. It is possible to awaken from them.</li>
<li>Dude, you need some 5-MeO-DMT up your ass ;)</li>
<li>Religion is NOT about morality, or society, or feeling better, or belief — religion is about METAPHYSICS.</li>
<li>How do you know that you exist? You should be much more skeptical about this. Try to prove that you exist and see what happens.</li>
<li>Evolution is not in contradiction with God. God is infinitely evolving.</li>
<li>The distinction between "natural" and "supernatural" is completely arbitrary and bogus. Everything is natural. Everything is supernatural. Your very existence is supernatural. You're just used to it, so you call it "physical" or "natural".</li>
<li>Likewise, the distinction between "physical" and "spiritual" is pure nonsense. Everything is spiritual. Everything is consciousness. Consciousness renders physicality in the same way that a movie screen renders a concrete wall or a video game renders a solid floor. Solidity and physicality are not features of reality, they are a relationship between apparent objects within consciousness.</li>
<li>"Mystical" isn't a bad thing, it's a good thing. Reality is fundamentally mystical. Quantifying and modeling reality, as science likes to do, does not remove its mysticism. It just makes you take it for granted. Everything is in fact mystical if you bother to examine it closely.</li>
<li>You need to study more serious nondual teachings like: Zen, Buddhism, Tantra, Kriya yoga, Sufism, Christian mysticism, etc.</li>
<li>All religion is based on truth, the problem is, the Truth is so radical the ego-mind cannot bear it, so it quickly corrupts it into silly myths, beliefs, rituals, customs, and dogmas. These days, after thousands of years, most religious teachings are bullshit, but they were originally based on Absolute Truth.</li>
<li>Metaphysics comes prior to science or physics, such that if your metaphysics is wrong (and it is) then your science and physics will never unravel the essence of existence, and your science will be crippled until you go back and get your metaphysics right.</li>
<li>Science has never proven the existence of: 1) an external objective world, 2) the self, 3) boundaries between objects, 4) the universal validity of reason. So why aren't you skeptical about all those?</li>
</ul>
<p>Where Matt Dillahunty is right:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fundamentalist Christians are nutcases and you were right to leave that tradition.</li>
<li>You are a legit atheist. Peterson should take your word for it.</li>
<li>Atheists don't have to be immoral murders and thieves. As long as an atheist is sufficiently conscious, he will not be too selfish/evil.</li>
<li>Skepticism is a good impulse. (But it must be taken all the way, which you are not doing.)</li>
<li>Survival and pragmatism runs the show. (But there is something beyond survival and pragmatism, which you are not yet aware of.)</li>
<li>Humanism is good. It's better than what came before it. (But mysticism is even better!)</li>
<li>Throwing Sam Harris off the stage is a good intuition ;)</li>
</ul>
<p>Where Jordan Peterson is wrong:</p>
<ul>
<li>Morality is a human invention. Evil does not exist. Bad does not exist. Meaning does not exist. Value does not exist. (This is Peterson's biggest mistake. These assumptions corrupt his entire understanding).</li>
<li>Morality comes from consciousness.</li>
<li>Religion is not about meaning, goodness, morality, creating a sane society, or psychology — religion is about METAPHYSICS.</li>
<li>Dillahunty is a true atheist. It is silly to deny Dillahunty's atheism.</li>
<li>The evils of Marxism have little to do with atheism. Evil comes from lack of consciousness or selfishness, NOT atheism. Lack of consciousness and selfishness is independent of one's religious beliefs. A religious person can be just a "evil" (selfish) as an atheist.</li>
<li>God is infinite degrees of freedom. Infinite freedom means infinite "evil", it's inevitable, so stop resisting it. Marxism was necessary. Post-modernism was necessary.</li>
<li>Society will not fall part without religion. Stop worrying about society devolving into chaos. There is a greater intelligence at work. So relax.</li>
<li>Please study Spiral Dynamics. You are resisting aspects of stage Green, which is holding you back.</li>
<li>The Marxism and Stalinism of the 20th century was Spiral Dynamics stage Blue, not Green! You feel threatened by the dangers of excessive Green, but Green is not that dangerous. What you should really worry about (if you want to worry) are the excesses of stage Blue. The Nazi's, Marxists, and Stalinist's of the 20th century which lead to tens of millions of deaths were not modern SJWs, they were stage Blue. Stage Blue, in excess, leads to authoritarian states (Hitler, Stalin, Mussolini, Roman Empire, British Empire, etc.). Modern soy-drinking SJWs are not going to form an authoritarian state. So you don't have to defend against this with God.</li>
<li>God and the devil are the same thing. God is the devil because call is everything. So God loves both good and evil equally, which in effect converts all evil into good. In God's eyes, there is no such thing as evil. Evil is a selfish, egoic reaction against things in the world which would threaten your survival.</li>
<li>It is possible to be a moral atheist. It is possible to a "good", humane atheist. Atheism does not mean you will be a murderer.</li>
<li>BEING is far superior to meaning. Drop your attachment and clinging to meaning, goodness, and value. Goodness is the natural state of BEING once the concept of "bad" is eradicated.</li>
<li>Nihilism isn't a bad thing, it must be fully embraced until it goes full-circle into divinity.</li>
<li>True morality comes from a complete surrender of ego and mind, such that there is nothing left to defend. No intellectual positions.</li>
<li>Too much conceptualizing, too much academic literature have created a wall between you and God.</li>
<li>If you want to really follow in the footsteps of Jesus, surrender all judgment. Especially all intellectual, academic judgment.</li>
<li>You are still taking intellectual positions, when you need to start surrendering them to move closer to God.</li>
<li>You are still in reaction against elements of Spiral Dynamics stage Green and stage Orange. Green must be surrendered to, not criticized.</li>
<li>Jordan Peterson is God. The problem is that your present level of consciousness keeps you stuck within ego-mind.</li>
<li>Dude, stop playing the academic game. You need: meditation, yoga, self-inquiry, 5-MeO-DMT. You are very close to grasping God, but you first need to stop waging all these intellectual wars. Stop reading books. Stop arguing.</li>
<li>God is not a psychological issue, God is a metaphysical issue. You cannot get to God through psychology, or philosophy, or literature.</li>
<li>Study more serious nondual teachings. What you're really after isn't Christianity or religion, you're after Nonduality, Awakening, Enlightenment. It's very difficult to get enlightened by studying Christian books. Christian books tend to be very corrupt, confusing, and misleading. Turn to more pure sources, then you can return to Christianity and fully understand it. The corruption is very easy to filter out once you've awoken a few times.</li>
<li>Let go of morality, good/evil, right/wrong, Christianity, academia, and judgment about post-modernism. It's okay. You'll be much better off. Your consciousness will skyrocket.</li>
<li>There is a palpable bitterness & anger which sours your message. Try doing some shadow work on it, or yoga, or psychedelics. Jesus' most important demonstration was embodiment of love. Your work would benefit enormously if your tone was more loving, less hostile, less aggrieved, less serious.</li>
<li>Don't take your worldview so seriously. It's all ultimately conceptual and meaningless. But you are on the right track and closer to awakening than Matt Dillahunty.</li>
<li>Watch out, your work is sometimes being used to empower Spiral Dynamics stage Blue people, which could create the very authoritarianism which you worry about.</li>
<li>Religion is not about metaphor or myth, it is about METAPHYSICS. The reason religions all around the world use metaphor and myth is because BEING/Truth/Absolute/Nothingness/Infinity cannot be symbolized. Mystical experiences are "direct", which means nothing about them can be said. Truth is prior to language. Thus metaphors and myths are employed.</li>
</ul>
<p>Where Jordan Peterson is right:</p>
<ul>
<li>God exists, and this is no mere belief or speculation.</li>
<li>Without consciousness, there is no reality or objective world.</li>
<li>Consciousness is deeply mysterious, irreducibly so. Consciousness is fundamental.</li>
<li>Consciousness is not localized to the head or brain. The entire universe is consciousness.</li>
<li>Science does not have an account of consciousness, not even close, not even partially, not even in theory.</li>
<li>Atheists make many groundless assumptions about reality and take many axioms on faith. Atheism itself is an act of faith. Reason is an act of faith. There is no reason why you should trust reason. In fact, there are many reason why you should distrust reason. Reason is weaponized by the ego-mind to for the purpose of self-preservation. Reason doesn't care about truth.</li>
<li>The world cannot be boiled down to a set of true/false propositions (as Matt Dillahunty claims).</li>
<li>Psilocybin is the real deal and psychedelics should be taken seriously. (Try some 5-MeO for an even realer deal ;)</li>
<li>Mystical experiences are to be taken seriously. They are far more than just "experiences".</li>
<li>Sam Harris is wrong.</li>
<li>It is not obvious that killing oneself is such a bad thing.</li>
<li>Self-preservation is unreasonable. There is no reason to live a good life or to be moral.</li>
<li>It is true that God is etched into the heart of every atheist, because every atheist IS in fact God! He just doesn't realize it yet.</li>
<li>Skepticism must be taken all the way. Nothing is self-evident to the true skeptic.</li>
<li>Rationality is a tool of the ego, and will often produce evil.</li>
<li>Those left-brain vs right-brain studies are legit and important. The left-brain is involved in symbolic, linear thinking whereas the right-brain is involved in non-symbolic, intuitive, non-linear thinking. The left-brain must become subordinate to the right-brain if one wishes to discover the ultimate existential truths about life. The left-brain serves the ego, so anything it says regarding truth must be suspect.</li>
</ul>
<p>If I was participating in this debate, the first words out of my mouth would be: "Everything in this debate room is God. You are God! God is Nothing and Everything. God is not a bearded man in the sky, God is consciousness. It is possible to become conscious of what consciousness is. Religion is not a matter of belief or old Bible stories. The origin of religion is the direct consciousness of consciousness." Okay, now we can have a productive conversation. Without such a frame, the discussion will devolve into vague intellectual abstractions, as it did.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-god-debate</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>May 2018 Solo Retreat - Part 1</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/may-2018-solo-retreat-part-1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I'm back!</p>
<p>I'll be posting 3 videos of my retreat here on the blog. Here is part 1.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/272706026?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/may-2018-solo-retreat-part-1</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hawaii Late Night Insights</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/hawaii-april-2018-late-night-insights</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/266992104?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/hawaii-april-2018-late-night-insights</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Exploring Psychedelics Conference 2018</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/exploring-psychedelics-conference-2018</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.exploring-psychedelics.org" target="_blank">Exploring Psychedelic Conference</a> is almost here! Learn about cutting-edge research and developments in the field of psychedelics. Featuring world-renowned experts in the field. It's a free event. A great chance to network.</p>
<p>It's held on May 24-25 in Ashland, Oregon. Organized by Martin Ball.</p>
<p>I was thinking of attending, but I'll be in the middle of my 30-day meditation challenge. So maybe next year for me.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/exploring-psychedelics-conference-2018</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Solitary Confinement Documentary</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/solitary-confinement-documentary</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Could you handle a year in solitary confinement?</p>
<p>Think of the spiritual growth possibilities! ;)</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/glS0ApOAaCw?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/solitary-confinement-documentary</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hawaii Retreat Intro</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/hawaii-retreat-intro</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/266766741?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/hawaii-retreat-intro</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mindfucked In Hawaii</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/mindfucked-in-hawaii</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/265940181?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>No new Youtube video this week. Taking time to integrate Hawaii and deciding how to proceed with life.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/mindfucked-in-hawaii</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Narcissistic Personality Disorder</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/narcissistic-personality-disorder</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>What most citizenry doesn't realize is that the world is run by people with <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/conditions/narcissistic-personality-disorder" target="_blank">narcissistic personality disorder</a>. It's really simple why the world is so crazy. The leaders of business, media, and government are often (not always) megalomaniacs. This can be hard to understand for people who are not megalomiacs, or who've have no direct experience with megalomaniacs. The assumption of "normal" people tends to be that "we are all basically the same", but that is not the case. The psyche of a megalomaniac is not the same as that of a "normal" person. It can be quite unreal to experience megalomania up close. It's an odd admixture of hunger for power, attention-whoring, deep insecurity, paranoia, self-delusional confidence, and lack of empathy. What makes this combination especially dangerous is the lack of empathy component.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/narcissistic-personality-disorder</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Osho Documentaries</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/osho-documentaries</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here are two great documentaries about Osho's cult in Oregon.</p>
<p>This is a great, detailed object lesson in <a href="/articles/understanding-islam" target="_blank">Collective Ego</a>. Taking spirituality/enlightenment "mainstream" is much trickier than it first seems. Because it always gets corrupted by ego, power, greed, sex, and politics. Being enlightened is NOT ENOUGH if you want to run a healthy spiritual community. A much deeper and wider set of skills is required, which Osho and his leaders did not have. Conscious leadership is a whole nother ballgame beyond personal enlightenment.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hBLS_OM6Puk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Gwx9nqknu-c?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/osho-documentaries</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #007</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-007</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"Be melting snow. Wash yourself of yourself."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— Jalal ad-Din Rumi</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-007</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoda #008</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-008</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3685" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-jihadi.png" alt="yoda-jihadi" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-008</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Batman #007</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-007</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3484" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/batman-how-is-that-possible.png" alt="batman-how-is-that-possible" width="615" height="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-007</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Essence Of Meditation By David Hawkins</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-essence-of-meditation-by-david-hawkins</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Cuts straight to the bone:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/G_eK-R9EDOk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-essence-of-meditation-by-david-hawkins</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Society Built On Psychedelics</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-society-built-on-psychedelics</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>What many Westerns do not appreciate is that there exist societies built entirely on psychedelics. Societies in which EVERY member has direct psychedelic experience with the spiritual world. In such a society, when someone mentions "spirits" it is not a dogma or superstition — they have an actual reference experience to which that word points, very much the opposite of the West.</p>
<p>Such societies still exist in remote regions of South America and Africa.</p>
<p>One native tribe in Ecuador — <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shuar" target="_blank">the Shuar</a> — has a special psychedelic brew for babies, another one for children, another one for adults, and another one for their hunting dogs!</p>
<p>As another example, the Bwiti tribe in Gabon, Africa, uses the extremely powerful psychedelic root bark Iboga in a similar way. It's not a secret reserved for reclusive shamans. Everyone in the tribe participates. Here's some footage to give you an idea:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3s6xiDEqsjU?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is what true self-help looks like, what true psychotherapy looks like, what true philosophy looks like, what true religion looks like.</p>
<p>Just imagine how different Western society would be if every baby born from today onward was given psychedelics and every teen required to go on a psychedelically-fueled vision question.</p>
<p>Actualized.org would be out of business. It's because Western society doesn't have these kinds of practices any more that we have so much neurosis, so many directionless people, and the need for Actualized.org and self-help.</p>
<p>Just some food for thought.</p>
<p>P.S. Do NOT try Iboga by yourself! Consuming it can be lethal and the trips can be hellish and last for days. That video was only shown to get across how native tribes do psychedelics. This is not something for you to emulate in your living room. Consider yourself warned.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-society-built-on-psychedelics</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Myers-Briggs On Pinterest</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/myers-briggs-on-pinterest</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a fun exercise for those who know their <a href="https://www.16personalities.com/personality-types" target="_blank">Myers-Briggs personality type</a>.</p>
<p>Go to Google.com and search your personality type like this: "pinterest INTP" or "pinterest ESTJ", and see what kind of cool stuff comes up.</p>
<p>That's it!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.pinterest.com/nansclark/intp/" target="_blank">Here's an example for INTP</a></p>
<p>(If you don't know your personality type, you can take the free test at the link above.)</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/myers-briggs-on-pinterest</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #006</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-006</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"The masses have never thirsted after the truth. Whoever can supply them with illusions is easily their master; whoever attempts to destroy their illusions is always their victim."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">— Gustave Le Bon</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-006</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Everest: Beyond The Limit</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/everest-beyond-the-limit</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's an amazing documentary which tracks a group of modern climbers as they attempt to summit Everest. One of my favorite reality TV shows that I've ever seen.</p>
<p>There are 3 seasons.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2ERjCQ5" target="_blank">Season 1</a></li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2ENijpj" target="_blank">Season 2</a></li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2EQViSk" target="_blank">Season 3</a></li>
</ul>
<p>This is the kind of TV that I love these days.</p>
<p>I watched this documentary a long time ago and it opened my eyes about Everest. It's incredible what these climbers go through. You're in for a treat.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/everest-beyond-the-limit</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Gödel On Materialism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/godel-on-materialism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">"The population [of the world is divided] into two classes: the workers and the intellectuals. The rulers find it hard to manipulate the population: so they use materialism to manipulate the intellectuals and use religion to manipulate the workers. Before [they] can conquer the world, they will have to have some rational religion... The founders of science were not atheists or materialists. Materialists began to appear only in the second half of the 18th century."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Kurt Gödel</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/godel-on-materialism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>On Your Deathbed, Total Consciousness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/on-your-deathbed-total-consciousness</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X48G7Y0VWW4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/on-your-deathbed-total-consciousness</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #005</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-005</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"Don't just blindly believe quotes you see on the internet."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Abraham Lincoln</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-005</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoga #007</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoga-007</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3463" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-fucked-up-skepticism.png" alt="yoda-fucked-up-skepticism" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoga-007</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoda #007</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-007</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3463" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-fucked-up-skepticism.png" alt="yoda-fucked-up-skepticism" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-007</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How To Find Psychics &amp; Healers</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-to-find-psychics-healers</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Isn't it amazing that in this day and age you can find psychics and paranormal healers through something as simple as Yelp.com?</p>
<p>You can even find 5-star-reviewed ones! So you can easily weed out the scammers and quacks.</p>
<p>Just go to Yelp and search your city for "psychic" or "medium" or "healer" or "spiritual healer" or "paranormal".</p>
<p>You can also use this trick to find:</p>
<ul>
<li>Yoga centers</li>
<li>Meditation centers</li>
<li>Buddhist centers</li>
<li>Reiki</li>
<li>Craniosacral Therapy</li>
<li>Acupuncture</li>
<li>Life coaching</li>
<li>All kinds of psychotherapists</li>
<li>Counseling & Mental health</li>
<li>Hypnosis / Hypnotherapy</li>
<li>Herbal medicine / Chinese medicine</li>
<li>Chiropractors</li>
<li>Naturopaths</li>
<li>Holistic doctors</li>
<li>Alternative medicine</li>
<li>NLP</li>
<li>Neurofeedback / Biofeedback / EEG</li>
<li>Monasteries</li>
<li>Ashrams</li>
<li>Temples</li>
<li>Shamans</li>
<li>Mystics</li>
<li>Astrology</li>
<li>Tarot</li>
<li>Float Tanks</li>
<li>Sleep centers</li>
<li>Massage</li>
<li>Etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>Just search for those terms. You'll be amazed at what kinds of helpful people and places you can find in your area.</p>
<p>Note: If you're skeptical of some of this "New Age" stuff, I understand, but this would be a good time to apply radical openmindedness. I'm not saying it's all gonna work for you — or cure your cancer — but you must test before you judge. Some of this stuff can be life-transforming and is very worthwhile to personally experience. If you're an ardent skeptic, just consider the follow common sense and pragmatic point: There's a good reason why there are literally THOUSANDS of such places on Yelp open for business, earning good money, getting hundreds of 5-star reviews, and getting lots of repeat customers — because it really works and helps people. No, it's not because most people are gullible and superstitious and easily susceptible to quackery and placebo. It's not as easy to build a sustainable 5-star business on pure quackery as skeptics assume. The much more likely explanation is that your materialist/rationalist paradigm is making you prejudiced against actually trying some of this stuff for yourself. Armchair skepticism just won't cut it when it comes to this stuff. You must put your time and money where your mouth is. If you do, you might discover that your rationalist worldview doesn't hold up to reality. Would you rather be right, or be healthy?</p>
<p>This one blog post could change your life, especially if you've got stubborn or subtle health issues like chronic fatigue, brain fog, bad PMS, depression, insomnia, ADHD, etc.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-to-find-psychics-healers</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Origins Of Mind</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-origins-of-mind</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I couldn't help following up on the presentation by Thomas Ray (see previous post) and reading his PDF, Origins Of Mind. The implications of his research are astounding. If you're really into understanding consciousness and why spirituality is so complex, I highly recommend you read and contemplate this PDF:</p>
<p><a href="/downloads/origins-of-mind.pdf" target="_blank">Origins of Mind by Thomas Ray</a></p>
<p>The second half of the PDF gets especially profound.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-origins-of-mind</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Don't Half-Ass Yoga</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/dont-half-ass-yoga</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I'm seeing a lot of people who got excited about doing yoga after watching my <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/the-importance-of-real-yoga" target="_blank">The Importance Of Real Yoga video</a> going about it in a half-assed manner. That is not gonna fly!</p>
<p>Yoga must be done rigorously in order for it to work. If you do yoga improperly, it could actually be counter-productive.</p>
<p>Here's are some critical tips for how to start yoga properly:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/258736862?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/dont-half-ass-yoga</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sitting Posture For Yoga &amp; Meditation</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/sitting-posture-for-yoga-meditation</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's an easy and simple sitting posture, perfect for staring your Kriya practice:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/258901224?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/sitting-posture-for-yoga-meditation</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Breaking Convention YT Channel</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/breaking-convention-yt-channel</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.breakingconvention.co.uk" target="_blank">Breaking Convention</a> is the International Conference on Psychedelic Consciousness held annually in the UK. It's one of the top psychedelic conventions. They feature hundreds of world-class pioneers and serious researchers in the fields of consciousness, medicine, and psychedelics.</p>
<p>Check out some of their amazing presentations:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCULcgad6brJAvldt3tFW-sQ/videos" target="_blank">Breaking Convention Youtube Channel</a></p>
<p>Here's just one mindblowing presentation from their collection:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6fMLCKBAosE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>By the way, the above kind of research is why I conjecture that enlightened masters have it easier than ordinary people. It is very likely that since everyone's brain is slightly different in constitution (due to genetics), it makes sense that a small percentage of the population would have lower seritonin-2 activity than normal, thus effectively making them naturally high on 5-MeO-DMT, which produces pure ego-loss and sense of cosmic consciousness. It would also make sense that certain yogic techniques can train the brain to deactivate seritonin-2 activity, thus producing ego-loss and cosmic consciousness. And this would also explain why New Age people become very woo-woo and into aliens and deities and astral projection and all sorts of trippy things like that, because their brains have a higher activity of seritonin-7 and load more mental organs into consciousness. It would also make sense that certain yogic techniques could train the brain for this too, thus developing siddhis (paranormal abilities).</p>
<p>And yes, NEVERTHELESS, the brain still does not exist! This is all relative talk. The Absolute blows all this talk away.</p>
<p>If this is making your mind choke, that's right! You're grappling with an infinite strange loop. You are not going to get at the fundamental nature of reality without paradox. The paradox must be so deep that it leads to the creation of the entire universe!</p>
<p>And here is a second presentation which I really liked:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GKesZXudgCo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>And another great one:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2q4VZUOGk2I" target="_blank">Rick Doblin MAPS MDMA Treatment For PTSD</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/breaking-convention-yt-channel</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dark Room Retreats &amp; 5-MeO-DMT</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/dark-room-retreats-5-meo-dmt</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I haven't tested this myself yet, but here's a very interesting lead to follow up on:</p>
<p><a href="https://forums.5meodmt.org/index.php/topic,50491.0.html" target="_blank">Dark Room Recipe</a></p>
<p>If this is true, to me, this would explain a lot about how early mankind discovered spirituality. It's such a simple technique that even a caveman can do it. You don't need mushrooms, you don't need fancy extractions of psychoactive substances, you don't need elaborate yogic techniques.</p>
<p>Think about it... Any ancient culture could have stayed in a pitch-black cave for 4 days straight. If that is enough to create a full 5-MeO-DMT whiteout — that is deeper than I have ever tripped on 5-MeO — that is enough to become conscious of the absolute nature of everything, deriving the purest spiritual wisdom directly from the source. Could this be the technique that the ancient Egyptians used? The ancient Jews? The ancient Meso-Americans? It would not be hard to construct a dark room inside a temple or shine or stone monument complex like the pyramids or ziggurats.</p>
<p>How cool would it be to travel back in time 7,000 years to ancient Egypt and learn all of their priests' secret spiritual techniques?</p>
<p>Here's a fascinating report from a woman who completed a 40-day dark room retreat!</p>
<p><a href="https://hridaya-yoga.com/reflections-on-a-40-day-dark-retreat/" target="_blank">Reflections On A 40-Day Dark Room Retreat</a></p>
<p>If you have experience with 5-MeO-DMT, you know what is feels likes. For the sake of science, try doing a 4 day dark room retreat and see if you can get the same kind of high. If so, this should prove beyond a shadow of doubt that 5-MeO-DMT is endogenously produced, and responsible for the deepest awakenings of the highest enlightened masters. If you run this experiment, be sure to post your results on the forum. I'd love to gather the data.</p>
<p>Here's <a href="http://dark-retreats.com/contact/" target="_blank">a place that offers</a> a Dark Room. (I haven't actually done it, so I can't vouch for that place).</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/dark-room-retreats-5-meo-dmt</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Batman #006</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-006</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3519" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/batman-absolute-infinity.png" alt="batman-absolute-infinity" width="615" height="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-006</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>It's Not Going To Stop, Till You Wise Up</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/its-not-going-to-stop-till-you-wise-up</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If spiritual purification was a song, this would be it:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dcIs3rAEytk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Always great to listen to...</p>
<ul>
<li>After you've failed</li>
<li>When you're stuck</li>
<li>When you're feeling depressed</li>
<li>When you're battling a stubborn addiction</li>
<li>When you're facing an impossible obstacle</li>
<li>After a breakup</li>
<li>When you just want to reflect on life</li>
</ul>
<p>All of your suffering is just the friction of your ego against the grinding gears of Truth.</p>
<p>Out of your saddest moments will come your greatest growth.</p>
<p>Those moments when you feel the most alone in life — when you feel that bitter sting of reality — are also the most alive. That is true spirituality. Don't run from it. Embrace it. Yes, it's difficult as fuck.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/its-not-going-to-stop-till-you-wise-up</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Does Nothingness Look Like?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-does-nothingness-look-like</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>When people hear the word "Nothingess", all too often they get a totally wrong idea about what that word is pointing to. Nothingness is NOT an empty void, a black screen, or a black hole.</p>
<p>Here's a better approximation of what nothingness looks like:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3621" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/consciousness-substance.gif" alt="consciousness-substance" width="500" /></p>
<p>Now keep in mind, this is just an analogy. A pointer. So don't start expecting to see the above flashy object in your meditation sessions. That's never going to happen.</p>
<p>What the object above is showing is the dream-like, immaterial, illusory, quality of consciousness. Consciousness is totally empty, like the above object. It is fluid and can take on an infinite number of shapes, with infinite resolution and zero limitation. It is vibrant, alive, and intelligent.</p>
<p>Can you see why the above object would be called Nothingness? Because it has no substance to it. It's pure appearance, and it can appear as literally anything. So we call it Nothingness, which is identical to Everythingness. Or, we could call it Infinity. Imagine if the above object was infinite in size and dimension such that it depicted every form imaginable. That would be what reality is, with your present experience being one of those forms.</p>
<p>Try this: Look around the room you're in right now, and notice that the whole room is Nothingness, just like the object above. Don't expect the room to disappear! Stop looking for black screen. Instead, notice that the room is pure appearance with no substance behind it. The room is like a hologram. Appearance is none other than Nothingness. The room AS YOU SEE IT RIGHT NOW, is Nothingness!</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"Form is emptiness, and Emptiness is form."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- The Heart Sutra</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-does-nothingness-look-like</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hawaii Solo Retreat Feb 2018 Videos</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/hawaii-solo-retreat-feb-2018-videos</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's how my Hawaii solo retreat went down. Lots of dirty details and wisdom in the Nightly Insights videos below.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/257069731?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Nightly Insights:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://vimeo.com/257076407/55657def2c" target="_blank">Day 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://vimeo.com/257082845/c701ca33fb" target="_blank">Day 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://vimeo.com/257094438/1c9c540e3a" target="_blank">Day 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://vimeo.com/257105798/2dc76133c7" target="_blank">Day 4</a></li>
<li><a href="https://vimeo.com/257209349/bfe2805c37" target="_blank">Day 5</a></li>
<li><a href="https://vimeo.com/257236894/ae578f10d8" target="_blank">Day 6</a></li>
<li><a href="https://vimeo.com/257331165/a51e3f469a" target="_blank">Day 7</a></li>
<li>Bonus: <a href="https://vimeo.com/257202091/a99b0bf020" target="_blank">Hawaiian Thunderstorm</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Note: Keep in mind, the Nightly Insights videos are raw, off-the-cuff, and unpolished. They were shot at the end of grueling sessions of meditation.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/hawaii-solo-retreat-feb-2018-videos</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What It's Like To Awaken</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-its-like-to-awaken</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3619" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/cc.gif" alt="cc" width="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-its-like-to-awaken</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hawaii Retreat - Feb 2018 - Pictures!</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-pictures</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I'm back from a week of meditation in Hawaii. Here's what it actually looked like. It's hard to imagine a more beautiful place to meditate.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3598" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-01.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-01" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3599" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-02.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-02" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3600" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-03.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-03" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3601" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-03b.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-03b" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3602" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-04.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-04" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3604" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-06.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-06" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3603" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-05.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-05" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3605" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-08.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-08" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3606" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-10.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-10" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3607" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-11.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-11" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3608" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-12.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-12" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3609" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-15.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-15" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3610" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-16.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-16" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3611" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-17.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-17" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3612" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-18.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-18" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3613" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-19.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-19" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3614" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-20.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-20" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3615" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-21.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-21" width="615" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3616" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-22.jpg" alt="hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-22" width="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/hawaii-retreat-feb-2018-pictures</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Batman #005</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-005</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3495" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/batman-spiritual-seeking-bad.png" alt="batman-spiritual-seeking-bad" width="615" height="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-005</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Proverbs #012</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-proverbs-012</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"Teach the tongue to say, 'I don't know'."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Hebrew proverb</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-proverbs-012</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Dangers Of Trumpism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-dangers-of-trumpism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I don't like to get too political or too alarmist, but the reality is that if you believe in holism, you ultimately cannot separate politics from personal development. Being conscious also translates into being a good citizen and taking responsibility for the community in which you live.</p>
<p>These days people take government totally for granted. As if a well-functioning government is a right or a guarantee. It is not! Government is not a service. You are not entitled to any rights or any fair treatment whatsoever. The only reason we have well-functioning government today (if we do) is because high-consciousness people put a lot of blood, sweat, and thought into orchestrating and defending it. The default position is not good government. The default position is corruption, theft, gross inequality, abuse, egotism, and domination. Free democracy is a very precious and fragile thing. You should be very thankful that you live under such a regime, if you do.</p>
<p>It is no coincidence that the ancient Greek and Roman philosophers were also deeply involved with politics — because mankind is a social creature, and community affects consciousness ENORMOUSLY. Perhaps the best example of this was Marcus Aurelius — one of the best Roman Emperors who also happened to be deep Stoic philosopher. In his work, The Meditations, you can clearly see how his level of consciousness affected his governing. Compare the thoughtfulness of someone like Marcus Aurelius and Obama vs Caligula and Trump.</p>
<p>So with that justification out of the way, I want to present a couple of really good videos about the troubling situation happening with the Trump presidency. This isn't your typical partisan mudslinging contest. This is really wise analysis from hard-nosed and experienced thinkers which you rarely hear on TV or Facebook.</p>
<p>Please note that I am not sharing these videos to convince you to become a liberal. Whatever your political leanings are, that's okay. What's being pointed at here is a meta-issue, beyond partisanship. I want you to start to think of how it would look if you started applying principles like consciousness to your relationship with your government. If you are not American, there are still lessons to be learned here. This really isn't about Trump per se, but about psychology, ideology, consciousness, groupthink, dogma, epistemology, tribalism, critical thinking, self-deception, ego, ecology, materialism, etc.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Azck1jY79cA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OTBUs1La7Uw?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Bonus videos from Noam Chomsky:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0YdBzwJCpo8" target="_blank">On Contact Interview - Part 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZkWVRlqzAMk" target="_blank">On Contact Interview - Part 2</a></li>
</ul>
<p>P.S. If you use these videos to become ideological, or to entrench deeper in your political position, you've missed the point entirely. Go meta!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-dangers-of-trumpism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #004</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-004</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"Whenever you feel like criticizing anyone, just remember that all the people in this world haven't had the advantages that you've had."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- F. Scott Fitzgerald</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-004</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoda #006</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-006</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3583" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-bitches-love-conscious-men.png" alt="yoda-bitches-love-conscious-men" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-006</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Off To Hawaii!</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/off-to-hawaii</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I'm about to start my second solo meditation retreat. This one's taking place on the Big Island of Hawaii, Hilo side. I booked a secluded cabin in the middle of the jungle near the volcano. It's on 20 acres of dense forest, filled with old Ohia trees and fruits trees like lechi, guava, bananas, and avocados. I'll be meditating outdoors on the 2nd floor deck. That is, if the mosquitoes let me.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3588" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-cabin-01.png" alt="hawaii-cabin-01" width="615" height="384" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3590" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hawaii-rainforest-01.png" alt="hawaii-rainforest-01" width="615" height="412" /></p>
<p>(These aren't actual images, but similar to where I'll be staying.)</p>
<p>Can't wait to get out there and meditate my ass off. It will be 8 grueling days of nonstop meditation and self-inquiry.</p>
<p>As I did with my Arizona solo retreat, I will do some filming outdoors and nightly debriefs with lessons learned. I'll post those a week or two after I return.</p>
<p>I feel more confident and prepared for this second retreat. In the last month my gains in consciousness from 3 deep psychedelic trips have been remarkable, and my new yoga practice is showing lots of promise. My mind has become quieter, my concentration ability has improved, and my inquiry process has honed-in. Now is the time for everything to come together into a major breakthrough.</p>
<p>I'll let you know how it goes.</p>
<p>Aloha! ;)</p>
<p>P.S. I have 3 more solo retreats planned for 2018. One more in Hawaii, one in the jungles of Costa Rica, and one probably in the piney forests around Seattle or maybe Oregon. I also have many psychedelic trips planned. All of it should produce a big transformation in my consciousness in 2018. At least that's the plan. You never know how things will unfold. One thing I hope you take away from my retreats is that this non-seeking advice you hear from certain corners of the spiritual field is total horseshit. You should work like a mule for your enlightenment, the way all serious spiritual masters did.</p>
<p>P.P.S. Weekly videos and blog posts will still be released. The hopper is loaded, so stay tuned.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/off-to-hawaii</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Noam Chomsky, Exposer Of Self-Bias</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/noam-chomsky-exposer-of-self-bias</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I like Nome Chomsky. He's a brilliant thinker. He's also quite controversial. Why? Is it because his political ideology is radically liberal? No, not really. People hate on him because fundamentally what Chomsky does is expose American self-bias. He preaches and practices a rare form of collective self-honesty. And of course what's the greatest sin one can commit against the collective ego? Self-reflection!</p>
<p>Getting unreflective Americans who hold as dogma that America is innocent of wrong-doing in the world to reconsider their self-biased position is tantamount to treason. It commits the greatest sin: disloyalty to self. The sudden realization that America may be one of the greatest perpetrators of evil in the world can be a difficult thing to stomach, especially because this is so rarely talked about in American media.</p>
<p>American media isn't conservatively biased or liberally biased so much as it is self-biased. Notice that you generally cannot go onto mainstream American media as an American and call America evil. If a major news anchor made such a statement, he/she would be immediately fired and spammed with death threats. All sorts of crazy ideas are tolerated in the media, except for that one. Why? Because it's too true! That level of self-honesty cuts too deep. It means that you, as an American, have blood on your hands. And who wants to hear that?? Certainly no American. The whole point of ego is to deny all responsibility for wrong-doing through self-justification, cherry-picking, and double-standards. The mind is like a good lawyer, always arguing on behalf of its own selfish ways.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jlWqItsDHxg?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NdD9uSrNFT4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Notice the parallels between what Chomsky points out about America's collective political ego, and what we're doing with self-actualization and spirituality, where we do the exact same thing but on a personal level.</p>
<p>If ego is the devil, then you are it. And so is your community, organization, corporation, nation, and species. What do all of these have in common? They are an imaginary boundary drawn around some portion of reality which seeks to privilege the included while marginalizing the excluded. Notice how this mechanism works, not only in yourself, but in the groups that you're a part of. Notice what happens when you stand up in a group and say, "Hey guys, what if we tried being less selfish?" Notice how the members in the group start to see you as a filthy traitor.</p>
<p>Just be careful, or you might get punched in the face. Egos get defensive and hostile when directly called out on their bullshit. You can see what I mean <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kbL5L4r4Ars" target="_blank">in the following video</a>. Notice the paradigm of the right-winger is us-vs-them rather than we-are-all-one. That's not just a political position. That's his level of consciousness because he doesn't yet understand that all human beings are one. He doesn't yet understand the value of self-reflection because in his paradigm it's framed as disloyalty to the self. And to a low-consciousness ego, that is the greatest sin. Which is why tribalism punishes disloyalty severely.</p>
<p>I don't agree with Chomsky on everything (his body of work is MASSIVE), but I do admire his willingness to confront the self-biases of his country. This is rare because facing one's own devilry is some of the hardest work the human mind can do.</p>
<p>Please Note: The issue of self-bias is a totally separate issue from your political ideology. Self-bias is a meta-issue which cuts across party lines and is independent of ideology. Self-bias is a problem regardless of whether you lean conservative or liberal. So be careful about making this meta-issue into yet another partisan debating point.</p>
<p>BTW, Chomsky is also an excellent example of life purpose done well. Take a look at his career and his consistent output of creative work. He's written like over 50 books and carved out a unique niche for himself, bridging the gap between hard-nosed academia and ordinary folk. If you're an intellectual-type, such a niche might work great for you.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/noam-chomsky-exposer-of-self-bias</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Batman #004</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-004</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3574" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/batman-you-are-god.png" alt="batman-you-are-god" width="615" height="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-004</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Proverbs #011</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-proverbs-011</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"Don't overwork a willing horse."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Russian proverb</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-proverbs-011</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Modern Humans Are 350,000 Years Old!</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/modern-humans-are-350000-years-old</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A new fossil of an anatomically modern human has been discovered in Israel which significantly changes our understanding of homo sapiens.</p>
<p><a href="https://news.nationalgeographic.com/2018/01/oldest-human-outside-africa-discovered-fossil-jaw-israel-science/" target="_blank">See article here</a></p>
<p>This is a really exciting development! Along with other recent archeological discoveries, the timeline of modern humans keeps getting pushed further and further back across all continents.</p>
<p>The stories we were told in history class are not correct. Ancient humans were much older and more advanced than our comfortable meta-narratives lead us to believe.</p>
<p>Speaking of comfortable meta-narratives, here's a radical idea: what if the story you've been told about how technology is making humanity better and better, is bullshit?? What if that's the reason you're so unhappy, so frustrated, so out-of-tune with reality? Think about that next time you sit down at your computer screen, blindly punching keys for 8 hours while sipping your chilled Diet Coke like an ape.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/modern-humans-are-350000-years-old</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #003</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-003</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"Every culture that's ever existed has operated under the illusion that it understood 95% of reality and that the other 5% would be delivered in the next 18 months, and from Egypt forward they've been running around believing they had a perfect grip on things and yet we look back at every society that preceded us with great smugness at how naive they all were. Well, it never occurs to us, then, that maybe we're whistling in the dark too!"</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Terence McKenna</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-003</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How To Spot A Sociopath</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-to-spot-a-sociopath</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that up to 4% of the population are sociopaths? Which means these people do not feel guilt, remorse, or empathy towards other human beings. Their brain physiology simply doesn't allow for it. Such people often become con-artists, scammers, and cult leaders — wreaking havoc and leaving behind a trail of ruined lives.</p>
<p>Here's a great article about <a href="https://www.naturalnews.com/036112_sociopaths_cults_influence.html" target="_blank">How To Spot Sociopaths</a></p>
<p>If you're a woman, be especially careful not to get sucked into an intimate relationship with such a man.</p>
<p>If you have a sociopath in your life, don't accommodate him or try to reform him. Cut him out of your life entirely.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-to-spot-a-sociopath</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoda #005</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-005</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-3468 size-full" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-mindfuck-you-it-will.png" alt="yoda-mindfuck-you-it-will" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-005</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hallucinogenic Fish</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/hallucinogenic-fish</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/meet-the-hallucinogenic-fish-that-can-give-you-lsdesque-nightmares" target="_blank">Meet The Hallucinogenic Fish That Can Give You LSD-esque Nightmares</a></p>
<p>Time to go on a fishing trip ;)</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/hallucinogenic-fish</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Batman #003</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-003</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-3476 size-full" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/batman-after-death.png" alt="batman-after-death" width="615" height="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-003</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #002</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-002</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"What prevents growth? Ungratified deficiency-needs, the attractions of safety and security, the functions of defense and protection against pain, fear, loss, and threat, and the need for courage in order to grow ahead."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Abraham Maslow</p>
<p>There you go. Why you're stuck, in a nutshell.</p>
<p>It's worth taking some time to contemplate this.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-002</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Life Lessons From &quot;Life Below Zero&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/life-lessons-from-life-below-zero</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Bonus video:</p>
<p>The National Geographic reality TV show <a href="http://channel.nationalgeographic.com/life-below-zero/" target="_blank">"Life Below Zero"</a> has many life lessons for self-actualizers.</p>
<p>The problem is that modern humans have no idea what "survival" really means, because modern society has made survival so convenient and so transparent. This might seem like a great thing, except that is makes you fundamentally unconscious of the entire process of life. Because even though you might not hunt and skin your own meat, you are nevertheless completely wrapped up in the process of survival even if you live in NYC — you just don't realize it.</p>
<p>The value of this show is that it helps to offset this ignorance.</p>
<p>I watched 4 seasons of the show and it gave me many profound insights about self-actualization. Here's what you can learn from it:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/250404090?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>You can find the show on Netflix.</p>
<p>Here's a preview:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WFhlhPfOVkM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Careful not to binge watch it.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/life-lessons-from-life-below-zero</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Proverbs #010</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-proverbs-010</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"Don't approach a goat from the front, a horse from the back, or a fool from any side."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Yiddish proverb</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-proverbs-010</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Simpsons Trip Report</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/simpsons-trip-report</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Remember this classic Simpson's episode?</p>
<p>Homer eats an insanity pepper at the Springfield Chili Cook-off which sends him on a hallucinatory mystical journey.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H3CyMWS7YXA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>You can only fully appreciate it if you've done psychedelics. The Simpsons at its finest.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/simpsons-trip-report</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoda #004</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-004</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-3462 size-full" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-2nd-chakra.png" alt="yoda-2nd-chakra" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-004</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Japanese Cats Say &quot;Nyan&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/japanese-cats-say-nyan</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes people get the idea that certain symbols like a cat's "Meow", aren't arbitrary because they mirror "the real thing". Well, think again! In Japan, cats don't say "Meow", they say "Nyan"! Which just goes to show how much we take cultural conventions for granted.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HDe9knU2h3I?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>And if you still aren't convinced, ask yourself what the hell kind of dog says, "Bow Wow"?!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/japanese-cats-say-nyan</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Deep Life Lessons From Bitcoin</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/deep-life-lessons-from-bitcoin</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the Xmas break while I was visiting my brother, he showed me some videos about the potential of Bitcoin. My brother is nerdy and really into investing and cutting-edge technology, so this was his cup of tea. And while I found the technology and investing aspects very interesting and exciting, what I loved most about these videos was the deep truths this speaker here reveals about the nature of power, corruption, hierarchies, government, democracy, society, psychology, closemindedness, and humanity. These are some of my favorite topics to think about in a big picture way, and this speaker blew me away with the clarity of his thinking.</p>
<p>So enjoy these two videos about Bitcoin, but don't take your eye off the ball! I'm not showing these to you because I want you to invest in Bitcoin. This is not a get-rich-quick-scheme. I'm showing these to you for the much deeper wisdom and lessons about human nature which they reveal. This will be important for the future, when I release episodes about the nature of power, corruption, evil, and society. Those are still topics which we've barely touched upon as we move forward towards assembling the big picture.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rc744Z9IjhY?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wSRN8PUhHX0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/deep-life-lessons-from-bitcoin</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Proverbs #009</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-proverbs-009</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"When a finger points at the moon, the imbecile looks at the finger."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Chinese proverb</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-proverbs-009</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Batman #002</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-002</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-3530 size-full" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/batman-what-about-science.png" alt="batman-what-about-science" width="615" height="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-002</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>George Carlin On Advertising Bullshit</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/george-carlin-on-advertising-bullshit</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AtK_YsVInw8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Carlin was under-appreciated as a philosopher.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/george-carlin-on-advertising-bullshit</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>True Love</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/true-love</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-3461 size-full" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/snake-mouse.gif" alt="snake-mouse" width="480" height="270" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/true-love</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Changing Perspectives Destroys Reality</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/changing-perspectives-destroys-reality</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Bonus video:</p>
<p>The mind's job is to prevent you from exploring too many diverse perspectives in life, because if you do, eventually the notion of "a reality" will completely collapse. Which is why almost everyone you encounter — including many good teachers — actively discourage you from exploring lots of perspectives.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/248109946?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/changing-perspectives-destroys-reality</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoda #003</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-003</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-3472 size-full" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-stupid-logic.png" alt="yoda-stupid-logic" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-003</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Venn Diagram Of Knowledge</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/venn-diagram-of-knowledge</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I see so many people who haven't contemplated epistemology much talking about "proof", science, and math — trying to raise objections from these domains. But the problem with that is they implicitly assume that the domain of things which can be communicated is identical with the domain of things which can be experienced or the domain of being/truth. This is a giant mistake commonly made by rationalists, materialists, and scientists. They just assume that if it cannot be "proven" or communicated, it must not exist. Nothing could be further from the case. The notion of "proof" and communicability is far, far weaker than the notion of reality. Many, many orders of magnitude weaker. The most profound and interesting aspects of reality are utterly beyond symbolization. Which of course means I cannot speak of them with you in the videos. And is the reason why you must investigate everything personally, for yourself.</p>
<p>Here's a rough idea of how the domains overlap. Note that science and math are limited to the red circle.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/knowledge-venn-diagram-1.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3414" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/knowledge-venn-diagram-1.png" alt="knowledge-venn-diagram" width="615" /></a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/venn-diagram-of-knowledge</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Batman #001</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-001</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-3454 size-full" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/batman-hallucination.png" alt="batman-hallucination" width="615" height="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-batman-001</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Are You A Mystic?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/are-you-a-mystic</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Some definitions of "mysticism" from various dictionaries:</p>
<ul>
<li>Belief that union with or absorption into the Deity or the absolute, or the spiritual apprehension of knowledge inaccessible to the intellect, may be attained through contemplation and self-surrender.</li>
<li>The experience of mystical union or direct communion with ultimate reality reported by mystics.</li>
<li>The belief that direct knowledge of God, spiritual truth, or ultimate reality can be attained through subjective experience (such as intuition or insight).</li>
<li>A theory postulating the possibility of direct and intuitive acquisition of ineffable knowledge or power.</li>
<li>A doctrine of an immediate spiritual intuition of truths believed to transcend ordinary understanding, or of direct, intimate union of the soul with God through contemplation or ecstasy.</li>
<li>Belief in the existence of realities beyond perceptual or intellectual apprehension that are directly accessible by subjective experience.</li>
<li>The term mysticism comes from the Greek, meaning "to conceal".</li>
<li>Mysticism is what lets you transcend the physical to experience enlightenment — let's just say you'll recognize it when it happens.</li>
<li>A person who tries to communicate directly with God.</li>
</ul>
<p>Some definitions of "mystical" from various dictionaries:</p>
<ul>
<li>Mysterious, unintelligible.</li>
<li>Obscure, enigmatic.</li>
<li>Of hidden or esoteric meaning.</li>
<li>Inducing a feeling of awe or wonder.</li>
<li>Having magical properties.</li>
<li>Inspiring a sense of spiritual mystery, awe, and fascination.</li>
<li>Having a spiritual meaning or reality that is neither apparent to the sense nor obvious to the intelligence.</li>
<li>The mystical experience of Inner Light.</li>
<li>Of or relating to supernatural agencies, affairs, occurrences.</li>
<li>Having a divine or sacred significance that surpasses natural human apprehension.</li>
<li>Having occult or metaphysical significance, nature, or force.</li>
<li>Involving or having the nature of an individual's direct subjective communion with God or ultimate reality.</li>
</ul>
<p>Rather illuminating, eh?</p>
<p>Consider, the only difference between a mystic and a non-mystic is that one is cognizant of the magic of existence while the other takes it utterly for granted, and moreover, assumes that any such cognizance is impossible or somehow an affront to reason. As in, "How dare you, sir, suggest that reality might be mystical! There's obviously nothing wondrous about it!"</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/are-you-a-mystic</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoda #002</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-002</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-3449 size-full" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-do-nothing.png" alt="yoda-do-nothing" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-002</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding Better Than Academics</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-better-than-academics</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Bonus video:</p>
<p>How is it possible to understand reality better than academics, scientists, and PhD's?</p>
<p>It would seem impossible, but it isn't!</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/245995815?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-better-than-academics</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #001</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-001</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"When one with honeyed words but evil mind persuades the mob, great woes befall the state."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Euripides, Orestes</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Here's looking at you, Trump.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-001</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>More Strange Loops!</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/more-strange-loops</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I found so many cool examples of strange loops while researching the <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/reality-is-a-strange-loop" target="_blank">Reality Is A Strange Loop</a> video, that I couldn't include them all! So here are some bonus goodies:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/boxloop.gif"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3429" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/boxloop.gif" alt="boxloop" width="400" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/cube-cube.gif"><img class="alignnone wp-image-3432" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/cube-cube.gif" alt="cube-cube" width="373" height="373" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/buildbox.gif"><img class="alignnone wp-image-3430" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/buildbox.gif" alt="buildbox" width="400" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/fourcircles.gif"><img class="alignnone wp-image-3431" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/fourcircles.gif" alt="fourcircles" width="420" height="315" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hand-recursion.gif"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3433" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/hand-recursion.gif" alt="hand-recursion" width="188" height="188" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/pizza-pizza.gif"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3436" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/pizza-pizza.gif" alt="pizza-pizza" width="400" height="250" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/tea-cup-recusion.gif"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3438" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/tea-cup-recusion.gif" alt="tea-cup-recusion" width="400" height="225" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/torus-twist.gif"><img class="alignnone wp-image-3434" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/torus-twist.gif" alt="torus-twist" width="361" height="361" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/penrose-loop.gif"><img class="alignnone wp-image-3439" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/penrose-loop.gif" alt="penrose-loop" width="330" height="330" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yin-yang.gif"><img class="alignnone wp-image-3435" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yin-yang.gif" alt="yin-yang" width="347" height="304" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/knotwave.gif"><img class="alignnone wp-image-3442" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/knotwave.gif" alt="knotwave" width="453" height="340" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/dotinversion.gif"><img class="alignnone wp-image-3443" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/dotinversion.gif" alt="dotinversion" width="475" height="356" /></a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/more-strange-loops</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Things I've Been Wrong About</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/things-ive-been-wrong-about</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>People tend to think of me as, "Leo has it all figured out." But that's actually an illusion. My knowledge is fallible as much as anyone's. That's the point of being conscious, openminded, and studying epistemology: so you are better equipped to recognize (and drop) mistakes in your web of beliefs. You cannot be perfect with your knowledge but you can be flexible enough to correct your errors (which most people never do).</p>
<p>So, I thought I'd share a list of all the things that — now in retrospect — I was wrong about in my videos. Keep in mind, I've grown enormously since I started shooting videos 5 years ago. In fact, it's embarrassing to even watch my own videos from just a year ago, because today I understand so much more. But that's just how it is when you're always growing.</p>
<p>So here's my list of mistakes (by no means a complete list):</p>
<ul>
<li>I was wrong about psychedelics. Initially, before trying them, I dismissed them as a distraction from consciousness work and enlightenment. Now, after much experimentation with them, I think they are the #1 tool for consciousness work.</li>
<li>I was wrong that God does not exist. Holy fuck is that the mother of all wrongs.</li>
<li>I was wrong for dismissing things like kundalini energy, chakras, and qi.</li>
<li>I was wrong about the metaphysics of the law of attraction. I no longer believe the law of attraction merely works through brute mechanical means.</li>
<li>I was wrong about paranormal phenomena. I used to believe they were all just New Age bullshit. That position is no longer tenable for me.</li>
<li>I was wrong about some of my dating advice for women. I now realize my advice was too shallow and male-minded.</li>
<li>I was wrong about some of my dating advice for men. My view of the topic was negatively affected by pickup, and today if I were giving dating advice for guys, my advice would be much more conscious and holistic. You can see this pivot by comparing my first How To Be A Man video and my second one: How To Be A Man - Part 2. Part 2 doesn't completely negate part 1, but it is deeper and more authentic.</li>
<li>I was wrong about some of my earliest characterizations of enlightenment as the ultimate fix for unhappiness and all your psychological neuroses. That is a half-truth. In reality, enlightenment, strictly-speaking, will not fix all your neuroses. Although it is usually a big leap in the right direction.</li>
<li>I was wrong in my Overcoming Addictions video where I claimed that AA doesn't have any deeper spiritual component beyond just curing one's addiction. This is a half-truth. Yes, AA is a spiritual-centered process, but the problem is that it is mostly spiritual only in name. It doesn't give you the tools to actually have direct spiritual experiences, nor does it give you the conceptual framework you need to properly understand what nonduality is. Another problem is that it creates an identity out of your addiction: "I am an alcoholic for life." Another problem is that is turns your social circle of friends into a bunch of alcoholics and highly dysfunctional neurotics, which is a bad influence on you, even if they are technically sober. You want to be emulating yogis and Buddhas, not ex-addicts.</li>
<li>I was wrong in my How To Control Anger video in the sense that I demonized and criticized angry people too harshly. If I had to shoot that video today, I would adopt a more compassionate, less judgmental tone.</li>
<li>I was wrong in my Why I Am Depressed video in the sense that I demonized and criticized depressed people too harshly. If I had to shoot that video today, I would adopt a more compassionate, less judgmental tone. Also, in that video I proposed ego-death (enlightenment) as the ultimate solution to depression. And while of course that's technically true, I now understand that most depressed people are nowhere near capable of making use of such advice. They need to grow themselves out of depression first, and only then will enlightenment become a realistic goal.</li>
<li>In some of my very early videos I talked about my vision and goals, which included things like becoming a millionaire and having threesomes. These are no longer part of my vision, and they look really naive, low-consciousness, and embarrassing in retrospect.</li>
<li>In some of my videos I had neglected to give more full credit to sources from whom I had gleaned insights. In retrospect I would cite sources better.</li>
<li>I am aware of having made some factual errors about history and science through my videos. These errors were pointed out to me by viewers in the comment sections. I can't remember them all right now, but one such example I can remember is: in one video I said that when you look up at the night sky and see the stars, many of those stars are not really stars but entire galaxies. Then a viewer pointed out to me that they ARE stars, as galaxies are only visible through a telescope.</li>
<li>I was wrong about my tone and style of delivery in various older episodes. In retrospect, I would adopt a more humble, more compassionate style.</li>
<li>I was wrong in my Understanding Absolute Infinity - Part 2 video where I mispronounced the Hebrew letter Aleph as "alf" rather than its proper pronunciation of "al-Eph".</li>
</ul>
<p>So as you can see, I'm far from perfect, and there's probably more I'm failing to remember, or that I haven't even become aware of yet.</p>
<p>The most important lesson to learn from this is: the goal is never perfect knowledge. That is impossible. There will always be some false beliefs and false facts in your web of belief. Even for an enlightened person. The goal is to maximize your awareness, maximize your openmindedness, and to minimize your ego, so that you can gradually purify your web of beliefs. You will have to stay epistemically vigilant for the rest of your life. As soon as you get cocky and think you've perfected your knowledge, that's when you've truly failed.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/things-ive-been-wrong-about</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Yoda #001</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-001</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-3424 size-full" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/yoda-cannot-avoid-metaphysics.png" alt="yoda-cannot-avoid-metaphysics" width="615" height="400" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-yoda-001</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Self-Inquiry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/self-inquiry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/chimp-gif.gif"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3416" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/chimp-gif.gif" alt="chimp-gif" width="500" height="700" /></a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/self-inquiry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Absolute Infinity Demo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/absolute-infinity-demo</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a little bonus that goes along with my <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/understanding-absolute-infinity-part-1" target="_blank">Understanding Absolute Infinity - Part 1</a> video.</p>
<p>This will help you wrap your mind around what infinity means.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/227827216?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/absolute-infinity-demo</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mainstream Conversations About God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/mainstream-conversations-about-god</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Mainstream conversations about God are absurd.</p>
<p>Here's a prime example. This guy wrote an entire book about God but has no idea what the word "God" points to. Yet he writes a book talking about how this concept of "God" evolved.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wBH5kiwag0s?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Well, sorry... but you can't understand how the concept evolved unless you understand that God is not a concept! That's like trying to explain the evolution of dinosaurs by studying the depictions of dinosaurs in Hollywood movies starting from the 1920's.</p>
<p>God is Nothingness. The concept of God evolved because people are too closedminded and lazy to actually self-inquire and have a direct experience of what the word is pointing to. Because the actual thing is way too radical for people to swallow. So it needs to be dumbed-down to fit the de facto materialist paradigm of the culture. Even devoutly religious people are still totally locked into the materialist paradigm. Which is why God is depicted as a human avatar, why heaven is a physical Garden of Eden with white pearly gates, and why hell is a dark fiery cave full of demons with horns and pointy tails. Religion is just materialism on stilts. Because the human mind doesn't know how to compute true immaterialism. Religion is an aping of the actual immaterialism which dawns at the highest levels of human consciousness.</p>
<p>This interview is like two children talking. The ignorance of it blows my mind. And this book will probably be read by 100,000 people, this interview watched by thousands of people.</p>
<p>And then we wonder why society is so confused, conflicted, and ideological.</p>
<p>This is not a conversation about God, this is a conversation about the delusions of the delusions of God. It's like watching the 3 stooges. But the tragedy is that people don't understand its a comedy. Even the two actors don't understand it's a comedy! Lol.</p>
<p>And hey, I'm generally a fan of TYT. They do a great job of calling out the corporate legalized bribery of the American political system.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/mainstream-conversations-about-god</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Corrupting The Youth</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/corrupting-the-youth</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Socrates was executed for corrupting the youth of Athens.</p>
<p>Of course! Because all the aging minds of Athens were already closed. Aging minds are very careful to control the access of information that young minds have. Not to protect the youth, but to protect themselves from having their aging consensus overturned.</p>
<p>The whole game of society is: "Don't you dare undermine my reality... or I will kill you!"</p>
<p>What "corrupting the youth" really means is: "Stop shaking the boat you fool! I just got comfy."</p>
<p>Controlling the minds of the youth is a critical function of all of societies. That is the quiet, unspoken-of construction site where paradigms are laid like down like stone monuments. A quiet war rages in every society over which faction of aging minds gets to tell the youth what is real.</p>
<p>Here's the whole secret to this game: the youth will believe the first thing you tell them.</p>
<p>So it's a race to who's first to whisper in their ear.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/corrupting-the-youth</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Storied Universe</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-storied-universe</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Imagine an alternative universe in which there is no matter, time, or space. There are no laws of physics. Instead, there are just stories. Every being here has a story because stories are all there are. Here, you aren't merely a being WITH a story, you must BE a story, because stories are the only building blocks of reality. Here, if it's not a story, it simply cannot be.</p>
<p>In such a universe, the major preoccupation of all beings would be defending their stories, because, well… their life literally depends on it. The greatest danger to a being would be the raveling of his story. That would be the definition of death: the end of my story. In such a universe, all beings would be deathly afraid of anything that might lead to the unraveling of their story. Such beings would gather together to co-create collective stories to make their individual stories seem more solid. These beings would form groups to fight one another, both ideologically and physically, in order to defend the "reality" of one collective story over another. In this universe, one town's collective story would threaten the reality of the neighboring town's collective story. And so they would go to war because their very sense of existence would hinge on it.</p>
<p>Sound familiar??</p>
<p>Well… Ta-da! That is our universe!</p>
<p>It's the only kind of universe that could possibly exist! Time, space, physics, brains, objective reality, mathematics, science, etc. are all just part of the story you're defending, you see? And the notion that these are not a story but REALITY, is itself just another story! Put a couple of stories together like that and you've literally got yourself a reality!</p>
<p>Now you object, "But Leo! Who is telling this story?"</p>
<p>The notion that there needs to be a who, is just another story!</p>
<p>So you object, "But Leo! Where is the story taking place?"</p>
<p>The notion that there needs to be a place, is just another story! You see? It's all a hallucination hallucinated by an infinite hallucination, all of it adding up to nothing — the only way anything can ever be.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-storied-universe</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>