<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=content&amp;type=forums_topic_post</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Which cities are at the top 5 according to spiral dynamics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37698-which-cities-are-at-the-top-5-according-to-spiral-dynamics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=472259</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16720-hampus/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="16720" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16720-hampus/" rel="">@Hampus</a> I don't really subscribe to the idea that you should move to a higher city in order to develop yourself.
</p>

<p>
	Far more important is how you manage your life, regardless of where you are.
</p>

<p>
	As long as you're in a physically safe and free society, that's basically good enough. The real work then begins. The inner work.
</p>

<p>
	If you are in an oppressive violent country, then that is important to resolve.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 09:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">472259</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did Leo grew up in a religous Home?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37584-did-leo-grew-up-in-a-religous-home/?do=findComment&amp;comment=472086</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="472083" data-ipsquote-contentid="37584" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564616713" data-ipsquote-userid="8090" data-ipsquote-username="Joseph Maynor">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 minutes ago, Joseph Maynor said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			You gotta re-program yourself to learn to love the process.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That would actually be inauthentic and untruthful for me.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 23:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">472086</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did Leo grew up in a religous Home?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37584-did-leo-grew-up-in-a-religous-home/?do=findComment&amp;comment=472081</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="472059" data-ipsquote-contentid="37584" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564615033" data-ipsquote-userid="13794" data-ipsquote-username="Inliytened1">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		26 minutes ago, Inliytened1 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Going to bars for beers and pickup.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Well, sex and intimacy are still meaningful to me. But the process of chasing after it is not.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 23:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">472081</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Richard Feynman on the problem with asking “why?”</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37690-richard-feynman-on-the-problem-with-asking-%E2%80%9Cwhy%E2%80%9D/?do=findComment&amp;comment=472064</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="472030" data-ipsquote-contentid="37690" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564612727" data-ipsquote-userid="9990" data-ipsquote-username="Truth Addict">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		56 minutes ago, Truth Addict said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Like, how is a devil going to stop being a devil and then open up to God if the devil is inherently limited?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Precisely because a devil is merely God in disguise! Really, there are no devils. A devil is just what we call it when God isn't aware that it's God.
</p>

<p>
	Also, devilry is inherently unstable and self-defeating. The suffering that devilry creates ultimately becomes so strong that the devil is forced to admit he is wrong. Either that or he doubles down and becomes an even bigger devil until finally physical death takes him.
</p>

<p>
	So now you see why death is such an important part of the divine plan of Love. Death is the safety valve which ensures that devils never ultimately prevail. A devil can only prevail in the short-term. God always prevails in the long-term: by killing you and freeing you of all your limits! Death is like the reboot button on your computer, for when it bugs out <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	Could you imagine if devils lived forever? Now that would be a problem. Fortunately, <u>all devils must die</u>. Unfortunately, you are a devil. Fortunately, you are also God <img alt=":D" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin@2x.png 2x" title=":D" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	Say... that's a good book title <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	The profoundly twisted irony is this: the devil only behaves like a devil in the first place because he can die! If the devil was immortal he would not act like a devil, he would act like God! If a devil should ever realize that he is actually immortal, he will stop acting like a devil and start acting like God. Ta-da!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 23:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">472064</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did Leo grew up in a religous Home?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37584-did-leo-grew-up-in-a-religous-home/?do=findComment&amp;comment=472052</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	To be more accurate, I just have a different kind of social life than most people consider a social life. My social life is through my work.
</p>

<p>
	For example you might ask if the Buddha or Gandhi had a social life. And the answer is, their social life was everything that revolved around their life's work. The same goes for me, except with the added wrinkle that we now live in the digital age, where the notion of "social" has expanded to include all of the activity happening through digital communication.
</p>

<p>
	If you include digital communication, my social life is quite significant.
</p>

<p>
	The very definition of "social life" is flexible and relative and changes across the ages.
</p>

<p>
	If you mean, do I go to the bar and drink beers with people, or attend dinner parties, or go bowling with friends? Definitely not. Such things are not interesting to me.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 23:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">472052</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=472038</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471581" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564570345" data-ipsquote-userid="11325" data-ipsquote-username="Enlightenment">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		13 hours ago, Enlightenment said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Jeffery Martin says it's about 1%, maybe he is wrong.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	He's using a very loose definition, something along the lines of: anyone who's ever be in a non-symbolic state. But that's very short of what I'm talking about.
</p>

<p>
	I don't consider Jeffery Martin enlightened. Not even close. He's still thoroughly materialistic in his explanations of reality & consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	His research is good, but far short of where this rabbit hole ultimately goes.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			You just seem to have unusual goals as a spiritual seeker.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	To me, escaping suffering has never been the goal. The goal has always been understanding reality.
</p>

<p>
	You are right, most people pursue spirituality rather selfishly & narrow-mindedly -- to escape pain or improve their life.
</p>

<p>
	The deepest sages I think pursue it for understanding & Truth, not to escape something negative.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I don't think there is the one right way to be spiritually, we can do whatever we want.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I generally agree. People are so different that they have different desires and needs.
</p>

<p>
	But also, not all roads lead to the same place, and there are many partial ways to go about spirituality.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471583" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564570453" data-ipsquote-userid="6765" data-ipsquote-username="ValiantSalvatore">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 hours ago, ValiantSalvatore said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>
		</p>

		<p>
			What kind of truth does he not understand ?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I don't get the sense that Shinzen actually knows what Truth is.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Who do you think emobdies and understands truth to the deepest level currently on the planet ?<br />
			Who do you think emobdies and understands love to the deepest level currently on the planet ?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I don't know. Answering this is problematic because I don't have access to anyone's mind but my own.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			What pratices are worth training from what you currently perceive to reach the deepest level ? I tried most techniques I've found and the ones recommended by you (besides kriya yoga) I don't really have a preference I get results with most of them, I just need to "up" my practice, which I am shooting for in the near future. I also receive the results described, I've been mostly practicing mindfulness and do-nothing. Also a fair amount of people receive real results from shinzen techniques, most join after praticing other techniques for years and they don't sound deep and shinzens advice does not sound all to deep then, and they don't talk about jhanas, power releams, enlightenment stages or insights, but mostly some life relevant matter about practice. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Shinzen's techniques are good. Will they get you to the deepest levels of understanding? Probably not. But that's okay, they don't need to. A toolbox needs more than one tool in it.
</p>

<p>
	Use Shinzen's techniques, but also don't stop there. Explore other things like psychedelics. I doubt you'll find a technique more powerful than 5-MeO-DMT. But that doesn't mean you should only use 5-MeO-DMT.
</p>

<p>
	An army doesn't just use nuclear weapons. It has all sizes of weapons in its arsenal because a nuclear weapon is not always the right weapon for the job.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			My point is what techniques regardless of differences generally yield tangible results ? And is it wise to train for e.g long with shinzens techniques when there are deeper truth to be realized ? Is that even possible with certain techniques ? Or is altering the physiology than the case ?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's hard to say. We don't have good science on this yet.
</p>

<p>
	Generally speaking good techniques to try are all the ones I've shared in the past:
</p>

<ul>
	<li>
		Meditation
	</li>
	<li>
		Self-inquiry
	</li>
	<li>
		Strong determination sitting
	</li>
	<li>
		Contemplation
	</li>
	<li>
		Psychedelics
	</li>
	<li>
		Vipassana retreats
	</li>
	<li>
		Solo retreats
	</li>
	<li>
		Yoga
	</li>
	<li>
		Dark room retreats
	</li>
	<li>
		Shamanic breathing
	</li>
	<li>
		Etc.
	</li>
</ul>

<p>
	These are well-worn methods that work for many people.
</p>

<p>
	And in the end, you gotta wonder, is there any other option? Those are the best techniques mankind has developed so far. So you might as well start tinkering around with them. With practice you should find whatever works best for you.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471586" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564571095" data-ipsquote-userid="5864" data-ipsquote-username="Nahm">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 hours ago, Nahm said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> That’s a rather perfect list imo, and a ‘how’ vantage point from those / on those would be one hell of a video. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	There will be future video about the many facets of awakening.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471635" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564578169" data-ipsquote-userid="5722" data-ipsquote-username="AlwaysBeNice">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		10 hours ago, AlwaysBeNice said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			No, not always, some animals like to play and show affection towards others, they also like to rest and meditate..
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	All of that is survival. You're still not appreciating what I mean by the notion of survival. It's a much deeper notion than most of you guys here yet realize.
</p>

<p>
	Rest, play, and showing affection is all part of survival. Without them a mammal would be dead.
</p>

<p>
	Animals don't meditate. You're projecting that onto them. They sit and do nothing sometimes. But I wouldn't call that meditation.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="472014" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564611152" data-ipsquote-userid="9432" data-ipsquote-username="archi">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, archi said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			You are like Shazam with your points, <img alt=":D" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin@2x.png 2x" title=":D" width="20" />. 
		</p>

		<p>
			You got me on Shinzen - I always had strange feeling that he misses something, aka seems to me still stuck in something.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Don't get me wrong, I still like Shinzen as a teacher. Nothing I say here is meant to attack or undermine the work of Shinzen or Ralston or whoever. I'm just adding some extra wrinkles to it.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Given you shared your opinion, how do you perceive Culadasa, wrt your 5 points above?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I don't know much about him. You'd have to ask him what he's become conscious of.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 22:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">472038</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did Leo grew up in a religous Home?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37584-did-leo-grew-up-in-a-religous-home/?do=findComment&amp;comment=472013</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471935" data-ipsquote-contentid="37584" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564603270" data-ipsquote-userid="15070" data-ipsquote-username="SunnyNewDay">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, SunnyNewDay said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Do you have a social life with friends, a girlfriend,  a dog, etc? Watch movies still? Play video games still? Are you just a normal person in person from the perspective of the average person?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I don't have a social life. Never cared to have one. It does not interest me.
</p>

<p>
	I rarely watch movies these days. Hard to find good movies. Most of them are juvenile superhero crap. Occasionally Hollywood makes a good movie for adults. But that's like twice a year. The rest is popcorn spectacles & money machines, which I don't care for.
</p>

<p>
	Occasionally I'll play a video game. When a good one comes out. But again, that's quite rare. Maybe once a year. I don't care for most games. It needs to be something original and deep or artistic.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 22:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">472013</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Which cities are at the top 5 according to spiral dynamics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37698-which-cities-are-at-the-top-5-according-to-spiral-dynamics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=472008</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471775" data-ipsquote-contentid="37698" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564591412" data-ipsquote-userid="16720" data-ipsquote-username="Hampus">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		5 hours ago, Hampus said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			According to leo are these cities in USA are at stage green:
		</p>

		<p>
			California,
		</p>

		<p>
			San Francisco
		</p>

		<p>
			All cities in Oregon
		</p>

		<p>
			Austin
		</p>

		<p>
			Mass
		</p>

		<p>
			Sedona AZ
		</p>

		<p>
			NY
		</p>

		<p>
			Seattle
		</p>

		<p>
			Hawaii
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Certainly not all cities in Oregon. Rural parts of every state/country are basically Blue.
</p>

<p>
	NYC has some Green aspects but also a lot of Orange. Many of the top cities in the USA are Orange/Green hybrids, not fully Green. A fully Green city would be very hippy-ish. Something like Sedona AZ maybe.
</p>

<p>
	Technically no city has a single color. Each part of the city has its own color, so it's tricky because we're talking about loose averages.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 22:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">472008</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Richard Feynman on the problem with asking “why?”</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37690-richard-feynman-on-the-problem-with-asking-%E2%80%9Cwhy%E2%80%9D/?do=findComment&amp;comment=472000</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471951" data-ipsquote-contentid="37690" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564604421" data-ipsquote-userid="9990" data-ipsquote-username="Truth Addict">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Truth Addict said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>
		</p>

		<p>
			Will Absolute Love still be present when someone is experiencing a hell realm? If so, then maybe Reality is not just Absolute Love, but also Absolute Torture/Hatred? Maybe Absolute Love is just an insight from high experiences (relative to feeling good)?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's the mindfuck of it: even the worst hell realm is still Absolute Love. The person just isn't aware of it in that moment.
</p>

<p>
	In a sense, it's a catch-22: the person is in the hell realm because their consciousness is in a limited state. That's what a hell realm is: a limited state of consciousness. A limited state is not wide enough to see the big picture. Seeing the big picture is necessary to understand that all states & realms are part of the flowering of Infinite Love. So from inside a hell realm it will seem like there is no love at all. But from outside the hell realm it is realized that that hell realm is indistinguishable from Love. If a person in the hell realm realized that it is Love, the hell realm would instantly transform into Paradise. But of course this is hard to do in practice because the hell realm so mesmerizes one's consciousness. It's like a bad dream. It's hard to break out when you're in it. But nor is it necessary to break out. What's more important is to realize that it isn't real.
</p>

<p>
	God's Love wouldn't be unlimited if it excluded hell realms. But the ego's POV is too limited to appreciate that. Luckily God has no such limitation.
</p>

<p>
	The duality or boundary between heaven & hell is itself made of Nothing/Love! Heaven is the realization that there is no difference between being in heaven or hell. The moment you realize the difference between the two is an imaginary duality, you will find yourself in Heaven. Heaven being an absolute -- has no opposite.
</p>

<p>
	Hell is the idea that there is a heaven separate from where you currently are -- and wishing to be there. The desire to be in heaven ironically produces hell because it is a denial and resistance of the present moment -- a denial of truth in favor of falsehood. So hell is falsehood or delusion. And Heaven is Truth.
</p>

<p>
	Neat, huh? <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 21:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">472000</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who's Interested In Conscious Politics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/35707-whos-interested-in-conscious-politics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471995</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	This video here shows her lack of political experience:
</p>

<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
	<div>
		<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iw03B9sNikM?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
	</div>
</div>

<p>
	Of course it's nice that's she's so open to changing her mind. But it also shows that she hasn't thought all her positions through.
</p>

<p>
	Don't get me wrong, I like her a lot. But success in politics requires more than being a spiritual guru. Spiritual gurus do not necessarily make the best politicians.
</p>

<p>
	Overall I'm thrilled that she's in the debates. She's helping elevate the political discourse which is what we badly need.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 21:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471995</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is this what awakening feels like ??</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37405-is-this-what-awakening-feels-like/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471908</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467035" data-ipsquote-contentid="37405" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563846140" data-ipsquote-userid="10476" data-ipsquote-username="Cocolove">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 7/22/2019 at 6:42 PM, Cocolove said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>
		</p>

		<p>
			Could you elaborate on jesus not being human? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No. It's a loose hypothesis I have. I don't know for sure.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Isn't the highest form of awakening realizing there is no difference between the ordinary world and enlightenment. Such that the goal isn't to be in a state where you are constantly g0d and never on autopilot, but to not see a difference in the two? As Daniel Ingram says mindfullness always waxes and wanes.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	There is no difference, but also there is.
</p>

<p>
	You are always in some state of consciousness. All states of consciousness are God, but you can only know that from certain states of consciousness. So your state of consciousness is absolutely important. You cannot be a donkey, for example. That is not an appropriate state of consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	If Daniel Ingram was a donkey, his enlightenment would disappear and no amount of Buddhism would help him.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 19:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471908</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did Leo grew up in a religous Home?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37584-did-leo-grew-up-in-a-religous-home/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471903</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12243-aaron-p/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12243" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12243-aaron-p/" rel="">@Aaron p</a> Yes
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 19:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471903</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How much truth does this video have?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37688-how-much-truth-does-this-video-have/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471900</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471518" data-ipsquote-contentid="37688" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564548972" data-ipsquote-userid="10800" data-ipsquote-username="Mikael89">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		14 hours ago, Mikael89 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			No it doesn't have any truth to it whatsoever.
		</p>

		<p>
			And I don't even need to click on the play button to understand that. The title is enough.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	LOL
</p>

<p>
	Way to keep an open mind, bro.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 19:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471900</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thought is Never Now</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37714-thought-is-never-now/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471897</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Hehe, if thought isn't now, when is it exactly?
</p>

<p>
	Thought is precisely now.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 19:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471897</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is there a divine plan to this life?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37684-is-there-a-divine-plan-to-this-life/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471887</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16561-beginner-mind/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="16561" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16561-beginner-mind/" rel="">@Beginner Mind</a> See my last vlog.
</p>

<p>
	The universe is structured in precisely such a way as to maximize Love. Every movement of every molecule and all the way up the chain of being is working towards this purpose. Including every pixel on this screen you're looking at and every character written on this forum.
</p>

<p>
	It's quite something to behold.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 19:16:13 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471887</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Richard Feynman on the problem with asking “why?”</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37690-richard-feynman-on-the-problem-with-asking-%E2%80%9Cwhy%E2%80%9D/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471881</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471579" data-ipsquote-contentid="37690" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564570151" data-ipsquote-userid="5317" data-ipsquote-username="How to be wise">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		8 hours ago, How to be wise said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			The problem with asking ‘why is reality precisely the way it is’ is that this question is coming from the mind.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No!
</p>

<p>
	There is definitely a reason why reality is precisely how it is.
</p>

<p>
	To dismiss this as "mind" is to make one of the biggest mistakes possible: it is to never realize why you created reality.
</p>

<p>
	Rather a shame not to know that.
</p>

<p>
	You honestly believe reality is here without a why? All of this precise structure and complexity with no explanation?? Just randomness? Just experience?
</p>

<p>
	Ha! Don't be gullible.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 19:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471881</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who's Interested In Conscious Politics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/35707-whos-interested-in-conscious-politics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471875</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15776-anderz/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15776" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15776-anderz/" rel="">@Anderz</a> Yeah, but she's also quite naive and politically inexperienced.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 19:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471875</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Have Become an Alchoholic</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37707-i-have-become-an-alchoholic/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471872</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Replace alcohol with psychdelics.
</p>

<p>
	The original cure for alcoholism via AA used LSD.
</p>

<p>
	Everyone forgot the LSD! Now it's all talk and no mysticism.
</p>

<p>
	The founder of AA used LSD to heal himself.
</p>

<p>
	P.S. Nothing wrong with AA. But understand that your problems go deeper than talk can fix.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 19:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471872</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471574</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471491" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564539057" data-ipsquote-userid="8874" data-ipsquote-username="Serotoninluv">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		8 hours ago, Serotoninluv said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			When you write “enlightened person”, does that suggest clarity and understanding in all those components? Or could an enlightened person have degrees of clarity and understanding? For example, deep, clear, integrated understanding in #2 / #3, yet several gaps of understanding in #4 / #5.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	In practice no. We usually use that word "enlightenment" quite sloppily to designate any degree of nondual realization. Often times the degree of it is minor and narrow.
</p>

<p>
	Many people who are conventionally called "enlightened" do not understand all of those 5 points I mentioned. And there are more points besides those 5.
</p>

<p>
	Binary designations are very misleading. You should always wonder: To what degree is this guy enlightened? What does he really understand? What specifically has he become conscious of?
</p>

<p>
	It's like if someone told you he's doctor. Okay, but that doesn't say much. What really matters is, How good of a doctor is he? Not all doctors are the same.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471499" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564541959" data-ipsquote-userid="107" data-ipsquote-username="electroBeam">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, electroBeam said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> How do you keep motivated about enlightenment if you are conscious that you will reincarnate as a tree?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You are the entire universe. What more do you want?
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Also why do you care about truth? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Because there is nothing but Truth. Nothing else matters. How could God not care about itself when there is nothing but itself?
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471502" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564543961" data-ipsquote-userid="5722" data-ipsquote-username="AlwaysBeNice">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, AlwaysBeNice said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			They don't use human ego mind, but they may be so immersed in god-consciousness, that they actually know without knowing.
		</p>

		<p>
			I mean, if I think of my glimpses I have at night, there also isn't a human knowing there either..
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	They are not immersed in God-consciousness. They are immersed is mindless survival and selfishness, as are most humans. They are totally clueless about God even though of course they are God all along. But they don't know that, and that's what matters: knowing it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 10:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471574</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is there a divine plan to this life?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37684-is-there-a-divine-plan-to-this-life/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471569</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	The divine plan is Love.
</p>

<p>
	The trick is understanding what that means.
</p>

<p>
	You would require infinite intelligence and selflessness to understand the plan. The plan is so grand that the ego literally cannot understand it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 10:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471569</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Richard Feynman on the problem with asking “why?”</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37690-richard-feynman-on-the-problem-with-asking-%E2%80%9Cwhy%E2%80%9D/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471567</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	All why questions ultimately lead to the question of Why is reality precisely the way it is? And the answer to that is: Absolute Love.
</p>

<p>
	Feynman was going in the right direction, but he did not go far enough, deep enough, wide enough to understand the ultimate WHY.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 10:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471567</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471484</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471481" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564536598" data-ipsquote-userid="5722" data-ipsquote-username="AlwaysBeNice">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		11 minutes ago, AlwaysBeNice said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I actually have no doubt they live in a deep state, very present, pure, just also the eyes of animals, 100% pure.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Of course they are very present, because they got no higher mind.
</p>

<p>
	They are pre-ego. Enlightened humans are post-ego. It's not the same thing. Your cat may be very present and pure, but he is not conscious that he is God. Whereas as a human can be. It is not enough to just be present. One must realize that he is God.
</p>

<p>
	An imbecile can be very present. That doesn't equate to metaphysical insight.
</p>

<p>
	You can do a frontal lobotomy on a human and he will become very passive and mindless like a cow. But that isn't God-realization.
</p>

<p>
	The point of all this work is not be present, it's to understand what reality is. If you're not crystal clear about what reality is and why reality is, then you've got more work to do.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 01:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471484</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471480</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16380-rodrigo-silva/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="16380" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16380-rodrigo-silva/" rel="">@Rodrigo SIlva</a> Tolerance varies from person to person.
</p>

<p>
	Assuming normal tolerance, I would stay under 4g of mushrooms and under 300ug of LSD. Even those doses can be very intense and challenging on the psyche to integrate.
</p>

<p>
	If I do mushrooms or LSD, I keep it at 2g and 150ug. But I'm probably unusually sensitive. Many folks would probably need to double or triple that to experience what I experience.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 01:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471480</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471478</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471477" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564535803" data-ipsquote-userid="343" data-ipsquote-username="Key Elements">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		10 minutes ago, Key Elements said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			you don't know how deep the rabbit hole went for other enlightened masters.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Of course technically I don't. I can't crawl inside their heads.
</p>

<p>
	But one can still make educated deductions.
</p>

<p>
	When an enlightened person is not able to properly answer questions about the nature of Love or Truth, that's a red flag. If Love or Truth are denied, something in their understanding is missing.
</p>

<p>
	To me the highest teaching is very simple:
</p>

<ol>
	<li>
		You are God.
	</li>
	<li>
		Infinite Consciousness is the only thing that exists.
	</li>
	<li>
		Everything is imaginary.
	</li>
	<li>
		Everything is designed for the sake of Absolute Love.
	</li>
	<li>
		Truth & Love are totally identical.
	</li>
</ol>

<p>
	Any teaching which does not state the above in clear & explicit terms, I am suspicious of. There are further nuances, but that's the core of spirituality/awakening.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 01:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471478</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471476</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16380-rodrigo-silva/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="16380" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16380-rodrigo-silva/" rel="">@Rodrigo SIlva</a> You can do a lot of work with LSD and mushrooms even without 5-MeO. Don't underestimate them.
</p>

<p>
	When you want to transition to 5-MeO is all up to you. There is no rush. But be careful with high doses of LSD and mushrooms. They can get really hairy. I would stick to medium doses at most.
</p>

<p>
	It's very important that you don't spook yourself off with one bad trip. A lot of newbies get spooked off because their doses are too high and they are unable to deal with the truths which are shown them. So they end up sweeping the entire field of psychedelics away under the rug. It's a form of denial.
</p>

<p>
	The wisest course of action is to proceed slowly, moderately, carefully, patiently, yet persistently and methodicly. Tortoise wins the race in the end. Aim for 50 to 100 trips before you start to get the hang of psychedelics. Anything less than that is noob-land.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 01:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471476</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471474</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471473" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564535089" data-ipsquote-userid="2261" data-ipsquote-username="mandyjw">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 minutes ago, mandyjw said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Everyone says that nonduality and truth can't be described using language and are just pointers blah, blah, blah
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I agree.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 01:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471474</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471472</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471467" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564534209" data-ipsquote-userid="343" data-ipsquote-username="Key Elements">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		18 minutes ago, Key Elements said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Yeah, but you were telling us that there are no brains; it's all maya and one with God, blah, blah, blah, and yet you trust neurotransmitters.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I'm still telling you that brains are imaginary, as are neurotransmitters. The word "neurotransmitter" is being used here in a relative, imaginary sense.
</p>

<p>
	It's not the neurotransmitters I trust, but the Truth which they help to unveil.
</p>

<p>
	If you were stuck in jail cell inside a dream and I told you to use the key to unlock the door, the key is still imaginary. An imaginary door requires an imaginary key. It would be foolish to reply to me, "Haha, Leo! If this is all a dream like you said, why are you telling me to use this key? Why do you trust the key?"
</p>

<p>
	When inside The Matrix, we speak in the relative truths of The Matrix world. One of those relative truths is brains and neurotransmitters. Once you've taken the neurotransmitters you'll realize neurotransmitters and brains are imaginary. But only AFTER you take them!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 01:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471472</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471461</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471459" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564533232" data-ipsquote-userid="5722" data-ipsquote-username="AlwaysBeNice">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		8 minutes ago, AlwaysBeNice said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Few things Leo.
		</p>

		<p>
			Masters can take you to psychedelic depth through eye contact etc.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No they can't. If they could the whole world would be enlightened by now.
</p>

<p>
	It's almost the opposite. No matter what a master does he will not enlighten you. That method of teaching is too indirect and crude.
</p>

<p>
	Once in a blue moon some student wakes up. The other 99% fail. The failures are just not publicized, for obvious reasons.
</p>

<p>
	I've met people who do vipassana for 15 years and still don't know what enlightenment is.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I also think you don't understand animals and their enlightenment, I would say they are enlightened.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	So a donkey knows that he's God but 7 billion humans don't? Haha!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471461</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471460</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/2261-mandyjw/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="2261" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/2261-mandyjw/" rel="">@mandyjw</a> Something like that.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471460</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to actually integrate all teaching of Actualized.org?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37630-how-to-actually-integrate-all-teaching-of-actualizedorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471453</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Reality is too massive to have it make sense all at once. You gotta eat the elephant one bit at a time until you realize, "Oh, that was leg, that was an ear, that was a tail."
</p>

<p>
	The perfect place to begin eating it is anywhere. Just trust that over the months and years you'll see patterns emerge.
</p>

<p>
	If Actualized.org is not comprehensive enough for ya, nothing will be. It's so comprehensive it will take you a decade to realize how comprehensive it is. That's not a mistake.
</p>

<p>
	One day you will realize: "Holy fuck this is HUGE! How is this even possible?" <img alt=":D" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin@2x.png 2x" title=":D" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471453</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What distinguishes an &quot;insight&quot; from a belief?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/36873-what-distinguishes-an-insight-from-a-belief/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471443</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471437" data-ipsquote-contentid="36873" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564529957" data-ipsquote-userid="9705" data-ipsquote-username="lmfao">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		21 minutes ago, lmfao said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Are you saying there's something beyond "what is"? But how can that be, if everything that "is" is just "is"?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	LOL
</p>

<p>
	Yes! There is INSIGHT and UNDERSTANDING.
</p>

<p>
	You cannot reduce those two to anything more fundamental.
</p>

<p>
	You must have an insight into what insight is. You do not understand what understanding is. Just notice that.
</p>

<p>
	This requires serious contemplation. It will not be explained to you in words.
</p>

<p>
	With deep enough insight you will realize that perception isn't even a thing. Perception is actually Being/Truth. "Perception" is a dualiatic notion, so be careful with just throwing that word around.
</p>

<p>
	A good way to contemplate what insight is, is to bring to mind specific examples of insight. For example, an insight was necessary for you to realize that whole numbers go up to infinity. At some point when you were a child you started counting: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5... and then at some piont it hit you: This can go on forever!!! That was an insight.
</p>

<p>
	Insights are often quite ordinary.
</p>

<p>
	I remember vividly when I was a kid the moment when I realized why a penis gets hard. It was a massive epiphany: "Oh, it needs to be hard to fit inside a hole!!! Wow! Of course!"
</p>

<p>
	That was quite an insight! <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	Nothing is obvious until you have an insight about it.
</p>

<p>
	Your birth was an insight. One day you had the insight: "Oh, I exist!" And on that day you came into being as a human.
</p>

<p>
	Insight is a mysterious thing. Which is why we call this mysticism.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 23:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471443</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471428</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470422" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564385847" data-ipsquote-userid="7210" data-ipsquote-username="ardacigin">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 7/29/2019 at 0:37 AM, ardacigin said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Leo, I understand this argument. It makes total sense. But when it comes to spiritual attunement and awakening, we are not talking about different species. What you extrapolate from the calculus example makes sense in the context of a donkey and a human's ability to learn math. Obviously, there are different. You can't find even one donkey who can do calculus. But within human beings, there is a vast degree of success in awakening.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Some people's reality and consciousness is so radically different they might as well be another species. You guys are underestimating just how radically different consciousness can be for humans. This is a common oversight because humans looks similar from outside appearances. But as you've been told, don't judge a book by its cover. This is what's happening with humans. Most humans simply assume that all humans are like them. This is a bad assumption unsupported by science, evolution, medicine, genetics, or other facts.
</p>

<p>
	It's as if you walk into a book store and treat all the books the same just because they are books. But there are huge differences between books even though they have a similar form. That similarity is superficial when you really dig into them.
</p>

<p>
	Some humans are like that donkey, they will never attain enlightenment. The reasons for this are nuanced and complex. Motivation is part of the equation. Most people do not have the motivation to do it. You cannot dismiss motivation as part of the "talent". Motivation is a huge factor. You cannot just train someone to be motivated about Truth. Yes, training helps, but there's much more to it than training. And who you can train also depends on who they are. Many people are untrainable.
</p>

<p>
	There is no reason whatsoever that all humans should be equally spiritually capable given how evolution works. The difference between a human and a donkey doesn't really exist. Brains evolve to become more and more capable of insight. There is no such thing as "a human brain" vs "a donkey brain". There is an infinite spectrum of brain structure -- from worms to aliens -- which allows for greater and greater insight capacity.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			This is what I meant by Shinzen Young's case study. Even if he is not the most enlightened guy in the world, his beginning point is really inspirational. And don't underestimate his achievements from that shaky foundation.
		</p>

		<p>
			His insight into perception and sensory experience is problematic, sure! But he can do 4 hours of SDS sits weeks in a row. And that was decades ago. He had stream entry only 4 years into the training. The permanent deal. Someone can easily say this is because he was spiritually talented but I don't think brushing off training is the correct mindset here. This guy was was only a little different from your average Joe prior to zen training.
		</p>

		<p>
			Consider how awake he would be if he flipped burgers at McDonald's vs living in a monastery meditating 10+ hours a day. How can you downplay training and environment so much?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I don't downplay any of that. That's all good and important.
</p>

<p>
	But my concern is not any of that. My concern is accessing the deepest level of consciousness and understanding. For that, training alone may not be enough for most people. That's all I'm saying.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Human beings have similar brains. Not perfectly similar but mostly similar. It is not like a donkey's and human's brain. If humans who train their minds get awakening and progress, so can 'most' people. Not everyone, maybe. But most people will make it work as long as they stick to it. 
		</p>

		<p>
			Otherwise, this absurdly turns into a victim mentality.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Not as similar as you imagine.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470433" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564387996" data-ipsquote-userid="11325" data-ipsquote-username="Enlightenment">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 7/29/2019 at 1:13 AM, Enlightenment said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			More than 0.0001% of the population is awake, about 0.1 to 1%. Of course to various degrees.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Nowhere near 0.1% of the population is awake. It's way lower than that. And when it comes to truly understanding the deep structures of God, it's less than 0.0001%.
</p>

<p>
	I would estimate that less than 0.1% of <u>awake people</u> truly understand how deep awakening goes and all of its many facets.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Leo, you seem to believe that genetics plays a huge role and is a big limiting factor for people when it comes to spirituality but not when it comes to sexuality, getting woman, you know "the black pill" guys?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's more important in spirituality than in getting women.
</p>

<p>
	Obviously if you look like Quasimodo that affects your chances attracting women. Although still not impossible.
</p>

<p>
	My biggest concern with the Red/Black Pill guys is that they use genetics as an excuse to not even try. They turn it into an egotistical ideology. Obviously I'm not saying that with spirituality. I'm not making some argument here about how you cannot realize God. I'm just saying your physiology plays an important role. So alter your physiology, alter your neurotransmitters! That is what spiritual technique is about.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			So if even on high doses of psychedelics you're still limited, how then can you say you've experienced Ultimate Reality? If this is true, humans will never discover the Ultimate Reality simply because they haven't evolved to discover the truth.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, you ARE still limited as long as you have a human body.
</p>

<p>
	But, that doesn't mean you can't access the Absolute. You can. You can access it deeper and deeper levels and facets. Degrees of depth here do not contradict each other, rather they build on top of each other. It's like this: you can learn some math, it will be valid math, but that doesn't mean you've exhausted your understanding of math. Math goes very deep. As you go deeper into it, the old math is still valid. So in this way you are accessing Truth but you have not exhausted Truth, because Truth is infinite. Your understanding of math can deepen forever.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Also, how can you know if Shinzen Young and other advanced meditators haven't experienced (at least as a temporary state) all the depths of awakening you talk about? I know that some people are very nihilistic and don't get so excited as you do, they simply have a totally different personality than you and no matter how amazing thing they will experience it will always seem dull when they talk about it. How an individual reacts and what conclusions he draws from the experience of God varies quite a bit.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's hard to articulate that here for you. I have had extensive hour-long conversations with Shinzen, asking him all sorts of nuanced metaphysical questions and his replies did not fully satisfy me. I see him as having gaps in his understanding. For example, he does not hold that enlightenment is Absolute Truth. He still hangs on to aspects of materialism, holding enlightenment as a subjective thing. I do not think he understands what Truth or Consciousness really is. I also don't think he understandings what Love really is.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470501" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564402080" data-ipsquote-userid="4029" data-ipsquote-username="student">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 7/29/2019 at 5:08 AM, student said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>
		</p>

		<p>
			Do you think people with spiritual giftedness can regress and change their brain chemistry?<br />
			Can they block their gift as to lose it? Can you make permanent damages and not be able to access it anymore? What they've been able to do one day, not being able to do it ever again?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Or can you voluntarily block it, reject it, and therefore lose it? Or some of its power.
		</p>

		<p>
			Or it is actually impossible lose the "foundation"?
		</p>

		<p>
			I am talking more exactly about neuroplasticity.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes
</p>

<p>
	If you think about it for a moment you should quickly realize that it must be possible to lose enlightenment because otherwise humans could not exist. To be human God MUST be able to lose awareness of itself as God. This is how you were born. And no matter how enlightened you get, you will eventually lose it in order to incarnate as a tree, worm, bird, human, alien, etc.
</p>

<p>
	You already have direct experience of being unawakened. How did you get there? Only one way: by losing your awakening. Everyone has lost their awakening, even the most enlightened people including Buddha and Jesus. Otherwise they could not awaken.
</p>

<p>
	Awakening is only possible because of unawakening.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470688" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564424433" data-ipsquote-userid="6765" data-ipsquote-username="ValiantSalvatore">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 7/29/2019 at 11:20 AM, ValiantSalvatore said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<strong>Also as far as I assume Shinzen does not deny sidhis etc. in his new video he even explains the neuroanatomy of how sidhis can occure and how the process of experiencing sound changes as well and which parts of the brain-body are involved</strong>. I also know he does shamanic rituals, not sure how deep they go, I know<strong> he tried psychdelics like LSD</strong>, and his story/history with procrastination and taking responsibility, even smoking grass, he speaks openly about this.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Nothing I said contradicts that. I never said he denies siddhis. I'm not just talking about siddhis in this thread.
</p>

<p>
	Trying some psychedelics doesn't mean much. It's a question of what one has become conscious of using them. Lots of people have tried psychedelics and have little understanding to show for it.
</p>

<p>
	My claim is not merely that Shinzen doesn't have all the possible siddihis. My claim is that his understanding of Truth itself is incomplete. He's not wrong, but it's not the deepest level. I'm  not contradicting him, I'm just saying there's deeper understanding, deeper insight, deep consciousness.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471387" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564522705" data-ipsquote-userid="343" data-ipsquote-username="Key Elements">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Key Elements said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Leo, I'm curious to know, how will this help you? Especially what you said on the last paragraph. If the consciousness is so "radical," how will this help? Does this mean, for instance, that you won't be reincarnated? Or, what? Did it make you less needy? Did it tell you something more about life?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	How it will help is a question of survival. That's not my interest. My interest is understanding reality for its own sake. Whether it helps or hurts is irrelevant to me. The Truth is whatever it is regardless of how it effects you.
</p>

<p>
	Any benefits that understanding of reality offers are secondary and beside the point (for me).
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Most of all, in one of your blog videos, you were saying that Shinzen Young's and Peter Ralston's enlightenment isn't that deep? Did they tell you exactly? No? Well, how deep do you want it? Don't they all point to the same thing after a certain point? Any form of "everythingness" that you see in your trips is still everythingness. To me, you don't know how deep are their enlightenment.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The deeper one goes, the clearer it becomes who has and who hasn't gone that deep.
</p>

<p>
	The things I've realized cannot be put into words in any way whatsoever nor taught in any way whatsoever. And yet I can intuit that Shinzen Young and Ralston have not realized what I have realized. If that sounds arrogant to you, I understand. But it is what it is from my POV.
</p>

<p>
	Shinzen doesn't understand Truth.
</p>

<p>
	Ralston doesn't understand Love.
</p>

<p>
	To me, those are important oversights. I would not be satisfied missing either of those understandings.
</p>

<p>
	Obviously these are my understandings of their attainments. I could be wrong. I'm not saying you should believe me. I'm just stating my best understanding of the situation at this time. Certain things they have told me do not square up with my deepest realizations. And I will doubt all teachers before I doubt my own deepest realizations.
</p>

<p>
	If the choice comes down to trusting 5-MeO-DMT and DPT vs trusting Shinzen and Ralston, I will trust the neurotransmitters. And no, that is not materialism. Direct consciousness is king, and that's what the right neurotransmitters facilitate. No human teacher can take you that deep. All human teachers and teachings are to be questioned and doubted. Including of course myself.
</p>

<p>
	- - - - - - - -
</p>

<p>
	P.S. Nothing I said here should be used to entrench a victim mentality. Keep two things distinct in your mind: 1) the actual mechanics of how humans awaken, 2) any stories you come up with for why you cannot awaken and why should give up or not even try. I am talking about #1 in this thread. #2 is self-deception you gotta be very careful with.
</p>

<p>
	When it comes to genetics and physiology you gotta make the best of the hand you've been dealt. Playing a victim is not a smart move regardless of how bad your hand is.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 23:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471428</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471404</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471299" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564515385" data-ipsquote-userid="7840" data-ipsquote-username="kieranperez">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, kieranperez said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Or... maybe that’s just <i>your</i> experience with 5-MeO and other substances. Maybe many people who encounter these substances didn’t have your own purification process or maybe you just didn’t need your own process. I find bilateral symmetry to be pretty much essential because of the amount of energy, trauma, inauthenticity, etc. all locked up and that process helps me and seemingly <i>many</i> others as well.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	If it helps you good. But it is not required for all people as Martin likes to declare.
</p>

<p>
	My point is that people have different requirements in their awakening process. It all depends on how your mind works.
</p>

<p>
	If something works for you, great. But be careful declaring that it will work for everyone or have importance for everyone or be necessary for everyone or is "the one and only true way."
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 22:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471404</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What distinguishes an &quot;insight&quot; from a belief?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/36873-what-distinguishes-an-insight-from-a-belief/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471283</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470991" data-ipsquote-contentid="36873" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564467570" data-ipsquote-userid="9705" data-ipsquote-username="lmfao">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 hours ago, lmfao said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>But how can understanding exist if there is no one for there to understand anything? How aren't these insights mere thoughts which trick you into leaving the realm of not knowing and pure perception? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Since the universe is consciousness, consciousness is capable of self-understanding and insight into the truth of things.
</p>

<p>
	God is able to recognize itself and this ability is present all throughout everyday life, science, and thought. Yes, thoughts can be tricky, but thoughts also can contain kernels of truth. How is that possible? Because the powr of insight is baked into language. Language is not just a bunch of scribbles on a page. Language is made sense of or understood by a much more profound quality of the universe.
</p>

<p>
	Perception is not the only game in town. The universe doesn't just perceive, is can also understand.
</p>

<p>
	Understanding is how you're able to make sense of the things I say and see the truth or falsehood in various sayings. But it goes deeper than language. You can understand how to turn on a faucet. What do you think that is? Don't take that for granted! You could not turn on a facucet without some level of true understanding.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			But I don't really get with what you're saying. Like what does it mean stop skepticism? Isn't the "final" state one can enter a state of pure not-knowing? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It means that once you become conscious of the Absolute, don't then fall back into doubting it.
</p>

<p>
	Like: "Well, was that really God? Maybe I'm not God after all? Maybe I was just hallucinating?"
</p>

<p>
	No! You are God! Stop doubting that. Don't make doubt your God. That would be putting the cart before the horse.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 19:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471283</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>My metaphor(s) for infinity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37663-my-metaphors-for-infinity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471278</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	A fractal of consciousness expanding in infinite dimensions.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 18:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471278</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo. Suffering.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37646-leo-suffering/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471275</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I explain some of that in my video: The Dark Side Of Meditation.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 18:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471275</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Afraid to take psycadelics because of risk of ruin my life</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37671-afraid-to-take-psycadelics-because-of-risk-of-ruin-my-life/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471273</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Psychedelics do not cause mental illness. This is mostly fearmongering.
</p>

<p>
	If you have an existing mental illness perhaps psychedics can make it worse. Perhaps. But they could also cure it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 18:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471273</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=471270</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="471194" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564503395" data-ipsquote-userid="16166" data-ipsquote-username="Goodpeace">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Goodpeace said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Is this a fact or a madness? The most important feature about the God molecule is the body pose!??
		</p>

		<p>
			 
		</p>

		<p>
			"If you, the reader, were to take away only one piece of advice from this entire book, it would be this: Bilateral symmetry is the key. It is the most important feature of nondual energetic therapy with psychedelics, 5-MeO-DMT or otherwise. If you are not working with bilateral symmetry, then you are not doing the actual work. It is just that simple. Anything other than bilateral symmetry is ego. This is a universal and consistent truth – no matter how big, how powerful, or how meaningful you take your experience to be – if you’re not in symmetry, you’re doing something other than the real work of nondual activation, and you are guaranteed that your ego is involved and running the show." ~ Martin Ball
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	In my experience the symmetry is not relevant much.
</p>

<p>
	Sure, you don't want to be all twisted up, but requiring some symmetry to realize God is ego itself.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 18:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">471270</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The DPT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/36240-the-dpt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470680</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470647" data-ipsquote-contentid="36240" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564420601" data-ipsquote-userid="16445" data-ipsquote-username="mindcentral">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		51 minutes ago, mindcentral said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Does anyone get nausea from plugging DPT?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I don't.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 18:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470680</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470386</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470383" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564370109" data-ipsquote-userid="107" data-ipsquote-username="electroBeam">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		15 minutes ago, electroBeam said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			If I was spiritually gifted, I would be having mystical insights no matter the environment or dysfunctions.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Why?
</p>

<p>
	You have to consider than even with your difficulties you might still be way ahead of most people on the planet.
</p>

<p>
	Just because you struggle with learning calculus doesn't mean you don't have a massive leg up on a donkey trying to learn calculus.
</p>

<p>
	Being talented or gifted doesn't mean life is easy. Probelms and challenges are always relative, so no matter how capable you are you will face challenges which will bend you to your limit.
</p>

<p>
	A donkey can carry 1000 lbs on his back before it breaks, you cannot. The donkey has you beat there. The donkey might look at you struggling to carry 200 lbs and laugh to himself, "What a whim!" But if you put 2000 lbs on the donkey his back will break. So the donkey is not free of struggle. Donkeys get more loaded up because they are expected to carry more than humans.
</p>

<p>
	If you observe nature carefully you will see that every physiological structure has its strengths, weaknessess, and breaking points. That is the nature of form. Every form has its limits.
</p>

<p>
	Form also always comes at the cost of flexibility. The more formed you are, the less flexible you are. Only God itself has infinite flexibility.
</p>

<p>
	Think of an object which is infinitely flexible. That's God! Ta-da! Notice, it must have no form.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 03:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470386</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470382</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470380" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564369525" data-ipsquote-userid="107" data-ipsquote-username="electroBeam">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 minutes ago, electroBeam said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Isn't past lives environmental factors - but over lifetimes haha?
		</p>

		<p>
			If the differences is explained through past lives, then the individual still put in heaps of effort and time, just in his past life. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, but it explains things better because over 50 lives a lot of difference between people can accumulate. It shows you that there may be levels of development or consciousness that you simply won't realistically be able to reach in one life.
</p>

<p>
	For example, wouldn't it be valuable to know that it took the Buddha 50 lives to reach his level whereas you're on life #3 right now? So, like, don't beat yourself up if you can't actualize his results.
</p>

<p>
	And even so genetics and physiology are still a factor. You have to account for why humans are more conscious than kangaroos and worms.
</p>

<p>
	There must be a spectrum of spiritual ability which goes from worms to lizards to kangaroos to chimps to humans and far beyond. Humans cannot be at the top. Not even close! There must exist much more conscious beings than humans.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 03:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470382</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470377</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470370" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564367531" data-ipsquote-userid="11730" data-ipsquote-username="TheAvatarState">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		34 minutes ago, TheAvatarState said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Yes, but couldn't this be fully explained by differences in development during upbringing? For instance, a single child could have a lot more alone time, possibly leading to more introspection and differences in attitudes towards other people.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No, it can't.
</p>

<p>
	Siblings are often raised in similar environments by similar parents and teachers yet they can come out very differently.
</p>

<p>
	One of the greatest unsolved mysteries of developmental psychology and spirituality is why some children and young adults advance through the stages so much faster than others. Practice and environment are certainly factors, but not the most important factor.
</p>

<p>
	Past lives are a good explanation here.
</p>

<p>
	Most people do not even care about metaphysics. Just to care about metaphysics already requires a certain type of mind/personality. I have cared about metaphysics from the very beginning. Without that, I would be just some regular dude flipping burgers at McDonalds. I'm not a gifted meditator but my metaphysical curiosity is through the roof and came built into my brain from birth. I did nothing to deserve it. At least in this life. Maybe I did something in a past life to earn it. I dunno. Or maybe I just won the genetic lottery. Out of 7 billion humans, surely some will be born will exceptional metaphysical curiosity. Humans are not minted in a factory like widgets. We have unique gifts.
</p>

<p>
	It's important that we be honest and acknowledge any gifts we may have. We also have unique weaknesses.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 02:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470377</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470366</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470365" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564366611" data-ipsquote-userid="107" data-ipsquote-username="electroBeam">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 minutes ago, electroBeam said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			does it really make sense to assume that the Buddha was enlightened because he as an entity is special
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	If you think the Buddha was a just your average guy off the street, you're really misdiagnosing how spirituality works.
</p>

<p>
	It takes an exceptional person to do what the Buddha did. What that means exactly is a mystery, but something special and extraordinary is happening on the inside.
</p>

<p>
	Past lives might be a better explanation. Whatever the explanation, it's not merely lack of effort or training.
</p>

<p>
	I want you to start noticing that people's brains and minds work is very different ways. We are not all the same. Some people think very differently by their natural constitution. Some constitutions are more suitable to spiritual work than others. Just observe people carefully and you'll notice the differences in how they think and see the world. It's quite stark and obvious. People do not see the world in the same way. It would be better to say: people live in different realities with some overlap.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 02:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470366</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470364</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470362" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564366134" data-ipsquote-userid="9705" data-ipsquote-username="lmfao">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		16 minutes ago, lmfao said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			 <a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Which people, and what neurotransmitter/brain differences do you believe to be significant?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Spiritually gifted folk. You can meet them in various spiritual circles. Healers, psychics, masters, yogis, sages, prodigies, shamans, witches, channelers, saints, etc.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Aren't the people who do the practices seriously just conscientious? Or does the word "serious" here refer to their ability to actually dive deep into the practice? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's a combination of factors: diligence, discipline, willpower, passion, focus ability, existential curiosity, openmindedness, baseline level of consciousness, appropriate personality type, and more.
</p>

<p>
	Notice, it's much easier to stick with a technique when is produces immediate significant results. Some people sit down to meditate and start having mystical experiences within days or weeks. This of course makes it much easier to stick with the habit compared to a person who meditates for 3 years and doesn't have a single mystical experience.
</p>

<p>
	I've met people who've sat down for one weekend, did 2 days of self-inquiry and awakened. That's totally unusual results. The average person can self-inquiry for 5 years and still not awaken.
</p>

<p>
	And it has to be this way. Otherwise half the people on the planet would be awake, but less than 0.0001% are. So you need some explanation for why that is. The explanation cannot just be that they're lazy or uninformed.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 02:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470364</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470361</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/107-electrobeam/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="107" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/107-electrobeam/" rel="">@electroBeam</a> Of course environment is very important. Genetics/physiology + environment + training/effort = all important
</p>

<p>
	The most successful people do well in all 3 categories.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 02:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470361</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>25mg 4-AcO-DMT Trip Report : On experiencing suffering</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37611-25mg-4-aco-dmt-trip-report-on-experiencing-suffering/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470356</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470133" data-ipsquote-contentid="37611" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564338468" data-ipsquote-userid="12740" data-ipsquote-username="FredFred">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, FredFred said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Some people suffer so much, some people live in constant pain.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's very humbling to realize. Yes, consciousness is capable of experiencing intense suffering. By experiencing some of that yourself you become more compassionate, loving, tolerant, and understanding.
</p>

<p>
	Try to imagine what it's like to live as a little child in Syria whose entire family was killed in a bombing. Yeah... that's some hardcore suffering and it goes on around the world by the millions every day. Makes you appreciate how good you have it in this life.
</p>

<p>
	Most people are totally ignorant of who deeply humans can suffer. Which makes those people arrogant and callous. Only through deeply suffering themselves will they come to realize their callousness and arrogance.
</p>

<p>
	4-AcO-DMT is a very powerful substance. Be careful with it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 01:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470356</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470354</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470301" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564356332" data-ipsquote-userid="524" data-ipsquote-username="Lynnel">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Lynnel said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			But what would happen if he used psychedelics ?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	He would likely discover new realms, depths, and aspects of consciousness.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Or do you think that psychedelics also only help you with achieving your potential and do not expand it beyond what would be possible "naturaly" without them ?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	They certainly take you beyond what would be natural for most humans. Of course even then there are still limits to what the body/mind can handle. Even the strongest psychedelic does not totally free you of human form.
</p>

<p>
	Some humans are like naturally high all the time because their brain chemistry is that way. This is quite rare, but still, not that rare. You can find such people.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Meaning then that people having amazing psychedelic experiences are quite gifted to begin with, giving a whole new meaning to the famous quote of "psychedelics don't work on stupid people".
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	They probably are somewhat gifted. But also, the psychedelic catalyses that by 100x-1000x. Which would be hard to do any other way.
</p>

<p>
	A psychedelic is similar to Jesus spending 40 days in the desert with no food or the Buddha sitting under the tree for 2 weeks straight without moving. Only it happens much faster and easier, not requiring so much suffering.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 01:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470354</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470352</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5722-alwaysbenice/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5722" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5722-alwaysbenice/" rel="">@AlwaysBeNice</a> I feel pretty confident that a kangaroo is ignorant of metaphysics. If you have evidence to the contrary, please share.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 01:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470352</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The DPT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/36240-the-dpt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470349</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14822-schahin/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14822" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14822-schahin/" rel="">@Schahin</a> Practically speaking you can make choices and steer your life. Using your intention properly is critical to personal and spiritual development. You are the CEO of your life. God has delegated this power to you, so use it well.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 01:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470349</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Suggestion for Leo.. please fix this</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37605-suggestion-for-leo-please-fix-this/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470294</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470293" data-ipsquote-contentid="37605" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564355420" data-ipsquote-userid="12728" data-ipsquote-username="Shadowraix">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 minutes ago, Shadowraix said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Could move to better forum software and migrate all posts with a script.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Ha! If only life worked so easy.
</p>

<p>
	This is one of the best forum softwares available. Months of work went into setting it up and getting to function well. Lots of money was paid to customize it for our needs.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 23:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470294</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470287</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470281" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564354425" data-ipsquote-userid="12728" data-ipsquote-username="Shadowraix">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 minutes ago, Shadowraix said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> hmm yes I see. I think the confusion stems that raising consciousness and getting access to Siddhis breaks things I *thought* were limits. Healing people, walking on water. How far can it go without releasing humanness? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Sidhhis do not remove all limits. Many limits still exist even if you are Jesus.
</p>

<p>
	It's very much like Neo in The Matrix. He learns to bend some of the rules but he is still constrained inside The Matrix. There are still many things he cannot do.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470287</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470268</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470266" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564352157" data-ipsquote-userid="12728" data-ipsquote-username="Shadowraix">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		11 minutes ago, Shadowraix said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			wouldn't many limits be self imposed?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The key is how you understand the word "self". That's an extremely loaded word.
</p>

<p>
	If Self is understood in the widest possible sense as God, then all of life is self-imposed and self-created. But that does not mean you as a human body are not bound by constraints. You as God have imposed constraints on yourself which you do not know how to undo without physical death.
</p>

<p>
	For example, God constrained itself to be that bird, but that bird has no idea how to break the constraints of bird-ness. That is the whole point of death, to escape one's self-imposed constraints. But you can't have it both ways. You can't be alive in a body yet totally unconstrained. The body is a serious constraint. Life itself is a constraint. All form is limited, whether you're a rock, a tree, a bird, a kangaroo, Albert Einstein, Jesus, a DMT machine elf, or whatever. Whatever you are is what constrains you to be less than infinite.
</p>

<p>
	You are lost in the labyrinth of your own consciousness and your only escape is death.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470268</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470264</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470263" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564351848" data-ipsquote-userid="8090" data-ipsquote-username="Joseph Maynor">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 minutes ago, Joseph Maynor said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Who told you you were a human?  What tells you you have limitations?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Try to hatch an egg. Post on YT when you succeed.
</p>

<p>
	Like I said: madness.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470264</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470261</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470253" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564351088" data-ipsquote-userid="2261" data-ipsquote-username="mandyjw">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		13 minutes ago, mandyjw said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			How can your perspective be so discouraging and yet so freeing at the same time? What is going on here? 🤣
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Is a bird outside in nature free or not?
</p>

<p>
	Seems free, but it is also extremely limited.
</p>

<p>
	It's important to understand the limits of a bird. It would be madness to try to ask the bird to solve calculus equations. Likewise it would be madness to try to ask a human to hatch an egg.
</p>

<p>
	An important part of growing up is learning your limits. Paradoxically acknowledging one's limits can be liberating, as one then surrenders to them and stops trying to act in some loftier, idealized way.
</p>

<p>
	Telling a child who's not suited for math to be good at math would traumatize the child and ruin his self-esteem because he will always feels inferior and not understand why. He will then blame himself for being defective or inadequate when in fact he's just suited to other things.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470261</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The DPT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/36240-the-dpt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470257</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14822-schahin/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14822" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14822-schahin/" rel="">@Schahin</a> No, I would not call anything destiny. Humans exercise a tiny portion of God's Free Will.
</p>

<p>
	God has infinite Free Will. But also all of that Will is fully put towards actualizing Love. So in a weird strange loopy sense, God has no choice but to actualized Infinite Love. Then again, God freely chooses Infinite Love. But then again that is because God is so Infinitely Intelligent that it would never choose anything less. Which means it cannot be anything but Love. And so it goes, round and round in a vicious circle. As it must, because free will vs destiny is another one of those pesky dualities which must eventually collapse.
</p>

<p>
	Contemplate this: what is the difference between free will and destiny?
</p>

<p>
	Eventually you'll see that the two poles must meet and become one.
</p>

<p>
	This issue is analogous to the wave/particle duality in quantum mechanics. The true nature of light is that it's not one or the other but has features of both. Likewise with free will and destiny.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 22:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470257</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Suggestion for Leo.. please fix this</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37605-suggestion-for-leo-please-fix-this/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470251</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	This forum software is too tricky for even God to fix.
</p>

<p>
	The reason it, this is a 3rd party platform. Which means I can't just go in there and make changes to the code willy-nilly because the code needs to be upgradable, making changes very tricky as new upgrades override old changes.
</p>

<p>
	Basically we are stuck with the forum as-is with only minor cosmetic changes. And even those are problematic as they get overridden.
</p>

<p>
	And because the code is so complex, every new update introduces new bugs and problems even if it solves old ones. So there's no perfection in this game.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 21:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470251</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470248</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470143" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564340208" data-ipsquote-userid="16166" data-ipsquote-username="Goodpeace">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Goodpeace said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Has anyone experienced that!??<br />
			Martin Ball writes in his Entheogenic Liberation: "because the client is moving into a state of unconditional love, the most common reaction is for individuals to scoop up the vomit in their hands and smear it over themselves, or even roll around in it. It’s messy, but profoundly beautiful, in its own way. You can literally see someone find love and acceptance for something they previously held as disgusting, shameful, unworthy, sinful, etc., and embrace and accept it in a state of absolute love. Such events tend to be deeply and profoundly healing for people, and moves them into deep acceptance of themselves and the world in a way that nothing else can."
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I've done over 70 psychedelic trips. Many very deep ones. Never once have I vomited. Totally unnecessary unless your body feels a need to do it. Healing happens regardless of vomiting.
</p>

<p>
	If you eat before the trip, you will almost certainly vomit on a heavy trip.
</p>

<p>
	Don't take Martin's method / attitude as the only one. It's one out of many. My trips tend to go differently than Martin's descriptions.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 21:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470248</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470242</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470220" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564347422" data-ipsquote-userid="7210" data-ipsquote-username="ardacigin">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		51 minutes ago, ardacigin said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			But Leo, I don't understand why you make such a statement. So many people get seriously enlightened using techniques and training methods. Even <a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/574-natasha/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="574" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/574-natasha/" rel="">@Natasha</a> who seems to have spiritual talent had done it using self enquiry. Without any practice, spiritual talent may or may not pan out. And relying on it and throwing in the towel is not a smart move.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You have to be very careful about biased selection.
</p>

<p>
	People certainly do become enlightened using those methods, but less than 1%. How do you account for the other 99% for whom the methods do not work? Just saying they are lazy is not a good enough explanation.
</p>

<p>
	The people who get enlightened using those techniuques are the ones who are already highly predisposed to it. You must be highly predisposed already just to do the practices seriously. Don't discount that.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			How can training be 'thin vineer'? That is too much of an extreme statement when clearly there is a difference between meditators and non-meditators. Very rarely can someone get seriously enlightened (beyond stream entry) without any practice. Some amount of training is essential even in spiritually talented individuals.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Training is important, but also not sufficent.
</p>

<p>
	You can train a donkey all you want but it will never reach the deepest levels of consciousness because of its fundamentally limited physiology.
</p>

<p>
	Ditto for humans.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			And again, just refer back to Shinzen's childhood. I don't see an inkling of potential talent there. And look where practice got him now. How can you view training as not essential?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Shinzen Young proves my point. I do not consider him to have reached the deepest levels of consciousness, and he's been at it for 40 years.
</p>

<p>
	Sure, he has gotten a lot better. But he does not understand the deepest mechanics of God. And he probably never will without better neurotransmitters.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470225" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564347785" data-ipsquote-userid="10453" data-ipsquote-username="moon777light">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		45 minutes ago, moon777light said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Jesus was born with a spiritual talent from his very birth, Buddha was materialistic prince until he left the palace. But Buddha still got enlightened to crazy crazy levels of consciousness
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The Buddha very clearly also had supernatural talent. Those talents just lay dormant until he left to be a monk.
</p>

<p>
	Just the decision to give up his kingdom and become a full time monk was already an extraordinary act which could only have been made by a spiritually advanced person.
</p>

<p>
	Stories say that the Buddha tried various yogic methods and aced them all within a few years. Clearly a sign of supernatural talent.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470235" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564348442" data-ipsquote-userid="10595" data-ipsquote-username="Jed Vassallo">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		34 minutes ago, Jed Vassallo said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			This seems to me like your contradicting your own teachings. If "Brains Do Not Exist", why are you pushing that brain differences and neurotransmitters are essential to Spirituality? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Be careful not to misunderstand my teachings.
</p>

<p>
	Life comes in a spectrum of spiritual abilities, from bacteria to kangroos to humans to aliens to God itself.
</p>

<p>
	Clearly a kangaroo is not going to fathom the depths of God no matter how much training. Why? Because of its physiological limits. It is too limited. Humans are better equipped. But still basically not good enough to fathom all of consciousness without augmentation. Humans lie all across the spectrum of consciousness. Some of us are totally retarded while others are Buddhas. This is certainly not explainable by lack of training, although training is often necessary to actualize our full potential. But what your full potential is, is highly constrained by physiology.
</p>

<p>
	Also, I am speaking about a lot more here than enlightenment. Consciousness is not merely about enlightenment. There is a width as well as a depth to it. Very few people explored the full width or depth alone, let alone both at once. So just saying, "But Leo, person X is enlightened" doesn't mean much. That is not a nuanced enough understanding of the spiritual terrain.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 21:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470242</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470209</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470207" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564346597" data-ipsquote-userid="11325" data-ipsquote-username="Enlightenment">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 minutes ago, Enlightenment said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Because many people 40+ years ago haven't had proper instructions on how to meditate properly like The Mind Illuminated. People often exaggerate how profound/superhuman levels they have reached
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No, that's not enough to explain it.
</p>

<p>
	There are people who access realms of consciousness with zero training which other people cannot access with 40 years of professional training.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 20:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470209</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470205</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="470184" data-ipsquote-contentid="37601" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564344598" data-ipsquote-userid="2261" data-ipsquote-username="mandyjw">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		33 minutes ago, mandyjw said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Beginner's luck is a real thing, because faith and belief are everything. The beginner hasn't been told how hard he has to work and how long he has to wait in order to be rewarded so he doesn't believe that it will take a lot of work and a long time.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	What I'm talking about goes way beyond beginners luck.
</p>

<p>
	I am talking about physiological brain differences and neurotransmitter differences which give people access to different realms of reality.
</p>

<p>
	Training is a thin vineer on top of this fundamental foundation.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 20:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470205</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Talent Is Overrated in Spirituality (Shinzen Young Case Study)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37601-why-talent-is-overrated-in-spirituality-shinzen-young-case-study/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470168</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	The more I study and explore spirituality, the more convinced I am that spiritual talent plays a bigger and bigger role. I have met and talked with people who access crazy superhuman levels of consciously totally effortlessly without training. And these people can go deeper than those who practice for 40 years.
</p>

<p>
	It's quite unfair and outrageous. This is like a dirty giant secret of spirituality and meditation which no one tells you about because they want to believe we are all equal.
</p>

<p>
	Well, the truth is, we are nowhere close to equal.
</p>

<p>
	My experiments with psychedelics back this up. There are levels of consciousness so radical that you will never access them if you lack the proper neurotransmitters.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 19:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470168</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>conscious politics part 2 --&gt; disagreement</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37478-conscious-politics-part-2-disagreement/?do=findComment&amp;comment=470161</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="469921" data-ipsquote-contentid="37478" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564316472" data-ipsquote-userid="15988" data-ipsquote-username="rnd">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, rnd said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I can't know the level of concsition of the candidatess accrurately.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Actually, if you study some Spiral Dynamics and if you work on your own consciousness, it becomes easy to assess the levels of consciousness of politicians. This allows you to size up people very quickly. You will come to recognize the common tropes of every stage of development. It can take as little as 5 minutes to size up a politician, especially if they are low in development.
</p>

<p>
	People are harder to size up once they get into Tier 2, but so few people are in Tier 2 that it's not a problem.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 19:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">470161</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did Leo grew up in a religous Home?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37584-did-leo-grew-up-in-a-religous-home/?do=findComment&amp;comment=469777</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6286-harikrishnan/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6286" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6286-harikrishnan/" rel="">@Harikrishnan</a> No, no, no.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 04:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">469777</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Radical Honesty - Share all your Secrets !</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37190-radical-honesty-share-all-your-secrets/?do=findComment&amp;comment=469733</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Locking this because I have a feeling people will share things they will later regret and then pester Mods to delete it.
</p>

<p>
	Remember, this is a public forum. Don't post things you don't want to be public permanently. Some things are best kept to yourself, close friends, therapists, and lawyers.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 01:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">469733</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did Leo grew up in a religous Home?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37584-did-leo-grew-up-in-a-religous-home/?do=findComment&amp;comment=469729</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	My Mom was loosely religious. She read me Bible stories when I was young. My Dad was scientific/amoral/atheist.
</p>

<p>
	My parents did not push any beliefs onto me. I was free to think as I liked.
</p>

<p>
	I was a pretty firm atheist by middle school because Christian metaphysics seemed silly. But in high school I realized that atheism too was a position and technically groundless and unjustified. But still I assumed it was right because the origin of God was not explained by religion as I knew it back then.
</p>

<p>
	I did not realize back then that it was possible for God to create itself.
</p>

<p>
	Now I am able to explain how Christianity & God really work to my Mom. And she basically understands. At least conceptually.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 01:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">469729</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The DPT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/36240-the-dpt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=469726</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14822-schahin/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14822" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14822-schahin/" rel="">@Schahin</a> The difficulty has to do with how you define "you". A person who has never awoken cannot resolve the issue of will because he assumes he is real. That you is illusory. You must discover the Universal You. Then we can talk.
</p>

<p>
	Ego assumes it is in control. But ego is illusory. So what then is actually in control? The Universal You.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 01:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">469726</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What’s going on with search function?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37533-what%E2%80%99s-going-on-with-search-function/?do=findComment&amp;comment=469116</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Search is hard. The forum's search cannot be changed.
</p>

<p>
	If you want powerful search learn to use Google like so:
</p>

<p>
	"site:actualized.org/forum xxxxx"
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 20:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">469116</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What does Leo mean by Imagination?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37515-what-does-leo-mean-by-imagination/?do=findComment&amp;comment=468635</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	That which happens inside a dream is imagination.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 21:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">468635</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=468588</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I would be careful doing lots of back to back doses.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 20:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">468588</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thoughts on plant spirits/entities, do they exist independent of your mind?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37454-thoughts-on-plant-spiritsentities-do-they-exist-independent-of-your-mind/?do=findComment&amp;comment=468255</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="468230" data-ipsquote-contentid="37454" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564009569" data-ipsquote-userid="5317" data-ipsquote-username="How to be wise">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, How to be wise said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			When Peter Ralston talks about the distinction between relative and absolute, he’s not really talking about it for himself. He’s making the distinction so that communication to unenlightened people can be easier. It’s unenlightened people who need that distinction. For enlightened people, Absolute is all that exists. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	He still subscribes to many relative truths in order to function in everyday life.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">468255</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Core of Christianity Contradicts Act.org</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37480-the-core-of-christianity-contradicts-actorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=468251</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Devil is a tricky word. It can definitely be misunderstood by newbies. Must be careful with it.
</p>

<p>
	But it's also a fun word, it's provocative -- which can be good as times -- and once you understand what a devil actually is (by watching my What Is The Devil video) then it becomes a very powerful concept for making sense of the world.
</p>

<p>
	It's important for newbies reach a point in their development where they realize, "Holy shit! I really am a devil, aren't I?" That takes maturity and honesty to admit. People who are in denial that they are devils are the biggest devils. Admitting you're a devil is already to have solved half your problems. This is the chief reason why I like to call people devils. It forces them to confront the fact that the devil is not an external force but an internal one. The ego loves to see itself as a hero and an angel. So telling an ego that it's the devil is very shocking and destabilizing to it. It's like poking a hibernating bear in the eye with a pointy stick.
</p>

<p>
	Of course an even deeper understanding comes when you realize that all devilry is actually love.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:35:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">468251</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=468249</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="468175" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1564002194" data-ipsquote-userid="10595" data-ipsquote-username="Jed Vassallo">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		3 hours ago, Jed Vassallo said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>  do you recommend doing that 10 -20, one trip per day, or every other day, or take more time in between?  
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You definitely can't do it every day when you first start. You'll need weeks and even months in between for integration. It should take you at least 1 year to do those 10-20 trips.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		3 hours ago, Jed Vassallo said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			And do you mean 10- 20 trips to get to the first breakthrough, or are you saying 10 to 20 Awakening trips before you really ‘get it’?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	10-20 awakening trips before you start to get it. They don't all have to breakthroughs, but many will be. You'll need many breakthroughs.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">468249</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who's Interested In Conscious Politics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/35707-whos-interested-in-conscious-politics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=468176</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="468024" data-ipsquote-contentid="35707" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563985896" data-ipsquote-userid="9510" data-ipsquote-username="Angelo John Gage">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 hours ago, Angelo John Gage said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I tell you what, I am hopeful that <span><a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> will present some Conscious Politics policies in his last video. That would be interesting to see. I believe he mentioned he would? Either way, that would be a PRACTICAL step to get those ideas out in the public, especially IF they are new and not left vs right partisan ideas.</span>
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, I will put forth many practical policies in Part 4.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 21:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">468176</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who's Interested In Conscious Politics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/35707-whos-interested-in-conscious-politics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=468172</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467836" data-ipsquote-contentid="35707" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563965682" data-ipsquote-userid="12370" data-ipsquote-username="Emeline">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		10 hours ago, Emeline said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> You are right I know we need corporations ... They could be yellow or green but most of the time they are orange and the ones who stole the word libertarianism from us were orange devilry like Monsanto ... And corporations like Monsanto are pure devilry  and exploitative monsters destroying the planet ... Corporations evolve in their level of development and consciousness...well maybe but it is VERY slow, does a corporation like Monsanto really evolved in any better ways since 1945? I am not sure ...
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Again, it's not so simple.
</p>

<p>
	Notice you are demonizing Orange.
</p>

<p>
	What's missing in your assessment is a lack of compassion for ignorance, which is what devilry is. And also, in your demonization you fail to see the good and love of Monsanto. The people working in that company have families to feed. And their products help feed half the world with cheap food. Without Monsanto many millions of people would starve because crops would be more expensive to grow.
</p>

<p>
	The rule is this: anything you think is bad and evil is actually good and necessary when seen from a higher elevation.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 21:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">468172</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thoughts on plant spirits/entities, do they exist independent of your mind?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37454-thoughts-on-plant-spiritsentities-do-they-exist-independent-of-your-mind/?do=findComment&amp;comment=468170</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5875-obeler/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5875" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5875-obeler/" rel="">@OBEler</a> You can't function in society or communicate with people without understanding relative truth.
</p>

<p>
	But relatvie truth isn't really a thing. Absolute Truth is the only thing there is. Everything you think is relative is actually Absolute.
</p>

<p>
	That's the delicious paradox.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 20:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">468170</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo is Wrong About Trump - Accountability Predictions</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37384-leo-is-wrong-about-trump-accountability-predictions/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467747</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467691" data-ipsquote-contentid="37384" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563940828" data-ipsquote-userid="13549" data-ipsquote-username="GenuinePerspectiveXC">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, GenuinePerspectiveXC said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			So you'd be perfectly fine having a relationship with a mentally retarded girl? 
		</p>

		<p>
			Lol.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	When all you have is a hammer, everything looks like a nail.
</p>

<p>
	Talking about IQ is not going to help improve society. It tends to do the opposite.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 06:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467747</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Core of Christianity Contradicts Act.org</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37480-the-core-of-christianity-contradicts-actorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467742</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467701" data-ipsquote-contentid="37480" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563941914" data-ipsquote-userid="14744" data-ipsquote-username="Aeris">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Aeris said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Does god like humans who hates gay and abortion ? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	God loves all.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 06:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467742</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Core of Christianity Contradicts Act.org</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37480-the-core-of-christianity-contradicts-actorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467741</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467687" data-ipsquote-contentid="37480" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563940493" data-ipsquote-userid="12100" data-ipsquote-username="Angelite">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Angelite said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> are you a Christian? Who are you to say things about Jesus that which you know not? Have you met him?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I am God. I invented Jesus. I invented Christians.
</p>

<p>
	<img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 06:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467741</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467740</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10595-jed-vassallo/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10595" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10595-jed-vassallo/" rel="">@Jed Vassallo</a> You won't know until you try. Treat this whole process like a mission to Mars. Each trip holds new surprises and wonders.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 06:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467740</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nature Of Pantheism &amp; What is Reality Vid (from latest vids)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37408-nature-of-pantheism-what-is-reality-vid-from-latest-vids/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467737</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Aloneness is really no different than togetherness.
</p>

<p>
	As a human you can commune with others.
</p>

<p>
	If you were extremely conscious you'd realize all others are you.
</p>

<p>
	The ego gets depressed about it because it does not understand the beauty of God.
</p>

<p>
	Remember as a kid playing with imaginary characters in your mind? Well, that's what you're doing now when you think of Leo, but on a Cosmic scale.
</p>

<p>
	Don't worry about it.
</p>

<p>
	Enjoy the illusion of togetherness. Then enjoy the truth of Aloneness. And bounce back and forth between them forever.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 06:08:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467737</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467735</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10595-jed-vassallo/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10595" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10595-jed-vassallo/" rel="">@Jed Vassallo</a> Probably depends on the person.
</p>

<p>
	When I trip these days there is no choice or efforting. God mode every time and regardless of substance.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 06:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467735</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo is Wrong About Trump - Accountability Predictions</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37384-leo-is-wrong-about-trump-accountability-predictions/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467679</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467677" data-ipsquote-contentid="37384" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563938610" data-ipsquote-userid="16039" data-ipsquote-username="possibilities">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		15 minutes ago, possibilities said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>  Given intelligence is the means by which cognition filters the utility of perception
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	This is just not true.
</p>

<p>
	Perception is filtered by your state of consciousness and level of ego development.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			what is your proposed alternative to intelligence?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Level of ego development, level of moral development, state of consciousness, and wisdom.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			IQ is a thing that attempts to measure intelligence, that is, general cognitive ability.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	IQ is not a proper measure of intelligence. You do not understand what intelligence really is. True intelligence is not IQ, nor anything close to IQ.
</p>

<p>
	Ironically, IQ is a very unintelligent way of conceiving of an measuring intelligence.
</p>

<p>
	True intelligence is one's ability to grasp larger and wider perspectives holistically while being fully aware that a perspective is just a perspective and never the truth. True intelligence is trans-rational, trans-linguistic, and unquantifiable.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Simply stating “you’re stage orange or below”, isn’t an argument.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Argument has nothing to do with truth or understanding.
</p>

<p>
	I am not here to make arguments. I am here to guide people towards evolving their understanding of themselves and the world.
</p>

<p>
	Saying "you're stage Orange" is precisely the relevant issue here. Making arguments is a distraction. You cannot understand the points being made because your cognition is hijacked by the stage of development you're at. Stage Orange wants arguments for everything without realizing that arguments are beside the point. You need to recognize the limits of the Orange worldview rather than defending it. No argument will move you up out of Orange. Rather to move beyond Orange you must realize that arguments and logic are incomplete and limited. There are much better ways of understanding reality than logic or math or science. And this cannot be understood through argument or formal proof. Ego co-opts all arguments and proofs to maintain its worldview.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 03:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467679</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo is Wrong About Trump - Accountability Predictions</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37384-leo-is-wrong-about-trump-accountability-predictions/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467675</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467199" data-ipsquote-contentid="37384" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563876104" data-ipsquote-userid="13549" data-ipsquote-username="GenuinePerspectiveXC">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		17 hours ago, GenuinePerspectiveXC said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>
		</p>

		<p>
			Here's my question then.  Do you seek to hangout with low IQ people yourself? 
		</p>

		<p>
			Would you want to immerse yourself in a low IQ society?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I do not look at the world through the filter of IQ at all. To me that is a narrow and foolish way of looking at people and societies.
</p>

<p>
	You are treating IQ as a fixed human quality but it isn't. The IQ of a society is like the wealth of a society. As a society grows it can raise the IQ of its members.
</p>

<p>
	The reason you're caught up on the issue of IQ is because you're at a stage Orange level of cognitive development, so you're stuck on rationality and quantifying the world. Given your worldview, if a thing cannot be qualified or rationally grasped, it isn't real and does not exist. You're not yet developed enough to notice that this is very limited and distorted way of looking at the world. You've also filled your mind with IQ ideology by watching videos and reading Reddit or whatever, which now colors how you see the whole world. But you're not yet conscious enough to see that that's just one out of an infinite number of models and perspectives, and a very crude and narrow one at that.
</p>

<p>
	You're also not conscious yet of the socially-constructed nature of IQ scores and tests. You hold IQ as some kind of biological absolute, which it isn't. You might as well be arguing that poverty is a genetic trait. This would be to misunderstand the social and systemic causes of poverty.
</p>

<p>
	If you want to evaluate people, level of ego development is the best metric. And ego development is fully changeable with practice, effort, and improvements to society. It is not a genetic absolute in the way that having 10 fingers is.
</p>

<p>
	I seek to hang out with wise people who are conscious enough to realize that reality is too complex and subtle to be quantified. But since such people are rare, I have to settle for dealing with the narrow-mindedness of rationalism and scientism.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 03:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467675</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Core of Christianity Contradicts Act.org</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37480-the-core-of-christianity-contradicts-actorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467671</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467666" data-ipsquote-contentid="37480" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563935969" data-ipsquote-userid="7639" data-ipsquote-username="SOUL">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		23 minutes ago, SOUL said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Why call anyone a 'devil'?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Because it helps to explain things like Evangelicals who go to church every week for 20 years but have no idea what Jesus was actually pointing at and who behave the polar opposite of what Jesus taught.
</p>

<p>
	It's important to understand that mainstream religions have been corrupted by devilry for thousands of years.
</p>

<p>
	An Evangelical who thinks that God hates abortion and gays is precisely being a devil. God loves abortion and gays.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 02:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467671</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467670</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16743-oldman/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="16743" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16743-oldman/" rel="">@oldman</a> Overall you're doing fine. This can be quite typical. It just sounds like the ego isn't fully ready to surrender yet.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467604" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563927743" data-ipsquote-userid="16743" data-ipsquote-username="oldman">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, oldman said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<ul>
			<li>
				Is my physical reaction "normal" or should I avoid 5-meo? I know your'e not a doctor.
			</li>
		</ul>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Fairly normal. Remember, the ego is wrapped up with the body. It's a tangled mess. If the ego is not ready to surrender then anxiety and heart rate will increase as it tries to fight off the ego-death.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<ul>
			<li>
				For those with 5-meo, dpt and N,N-dmt experience - is the heart rate/body fear part similar or different for you?
			</li>
		</ul>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	My first few trips I had a lot of fear and basically even a panic attack. But after many trips and ego deaths there is almost no fear now when tripping and heart rate hardly changes. It has become a smooth transition from duality & ego into nonduality & no ego.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<ul>
			<li>
				Do others have similar mind-body dissociation where the mind is chill and the body is going apeshit?
			</li>
		</ul>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I don't have that, but seems reasonable that that could happen. Your body probably has lots of emotional baggage stored in it from over the decades. It's good to let loose and shake/act that baggage out on psychedelics. That's a big part of the healing work. Sometimes the body has a lot of pent up energy which it wants to release or act out. Don't hold it back. Act it out without harming yourself or another.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<ul>
			<li>
				Does the body fear go away after more practice?
			</li>
		</ul>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It should because all fear is illusory in the end. Your probably underestimate how much practice is required. So keep practicing.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<ul>
			<li>
				Any recommendation on how to break through other than just add more material? 
			</li>
		</ul>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I'd recommend trying some other psychedelics like mushrooms or LSD. They can help you to deal with various baggage which will then make you pure enough for 5-MeO-DMT. You cannot go into full God-consciousness without being sufficiently pure and free of psychological baggage.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<ul>
			<li>
				Does the body calm down if you do break through?
			</li>
		</ul>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	A breakthrough can release a lot of pent up energy. The body can shake, move, vibrate, etc.
</p>

<p>
	Rather than going straight for a breakthrough I'd spend more time exploring the psychedelic space on mushrooms and LSD. Get comfortable in the psychedelic space. Have some pleasant trips. Contemplate consciousness. Move around and stuff. Then try to go for a 5-MeO breakthrough.
</p>

<p>
	I think you might be trying to go too quickly to the end. There is a lot to be gained from psychedelics even without a breakthrough. Trust that the breakthrough will come when you're ready for it. Dosage is not the most important thing, your level of purity and intent and tripping experience is more important.
</p>

<p>
	Basically, your first 10-20 trips are just like kindergarten. The key to success with psychedelics is patience and consistency. With practice the results will snowball into something amazing.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 02:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467670</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thoughts on plant spirits/entities, do they exist independent of your mind?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37454-thoughts-on-plant-spiritsentities-do-they-exist-independent-of-your-mind/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467661</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Infinite Consciousness can take the form of an infinite number of entities or beings which can interact with each other. But all of this is being imagined by Infinite Consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	In the absolute sense, everything is one. In the relative sense, entities have their own existence. In this sense an alien or a spirit is no different than a human or an animal. The "physical" realm is only one out of an infinite number of realms populated by all sorts of beings.
</p>

<p>
	All these realms and beings are ultimately you. Just like in a dream.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 02:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467661</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>TRIPPING ON ACID, ASK ME ANYTHING</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37487-tripping-on-acid-ask-me-anything/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467602</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Do not post on this forum while tripping.
</p>

<p>
	You are making a juvenile mockery of this powerful tool. 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467602</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who's Interested In Conscious Politics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/35707-whos-interested-in-conscious-politics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467597</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467574" data-ipsquote-contentid="35707" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563922392" data-ipsquote-userid="12370" data-ipsquote-username="Emeline">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Emeline said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Big corporate are monsters ... 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Careful. If only life were so simple.
</p>

<p>
	Corporations are necessary, a vital part of society, and they feed you many benefits and goods.
</p>

<p>
	The issue is one of right balance, not a blanket demonization of corporations. Corporations evolve in their level of development and consciousness just like humans.
</p>

<p>
	There are Red corporations, Blue, Orange, Green, Yellow, etc.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467597</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How is winning the lottery possible for those who don't create value?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37465-how-is-winning-the-lottery-possible-for-those-who-dont-create-value/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467548</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	People who will the lottery do not experience any real change in themsleves as a result of the win. They don't grow. The money only exacerbates all their egoic tendecies and so they are no happier for it.
</p>

<p>
	It's just a lucky event no different than finding a penny on the sidewalk. It won't solve anything.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 22:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467548</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How does photography work?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37472-how-does-photography-work/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467547</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Contemplate how a camera works in your dreams.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 22:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467547</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Core of Christianity Contradicts Act.org</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37480-the-core-of-christianity-contradicts-actorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467544</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	There's no contradiction at all.
</p>

<p>
	Christ is the son of God. Christ is God. You are the son of God. You are God. You are Christ. You are all humans. You are me. You invented Christianity and all other religions. The entire universe is happening in your mind.
</p>

<p>
	The apparent contradiction arises because people do not properly understand Christ's teachings, because they are using ego to interpret them. A devil cannot read the words of Christ properly. Modern mainstream Christians are devils.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 21:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467544</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A question to Leo on his Conscious Politics Part 2 Video</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37469-a-question-to-leo-on-his-conscious-politics-part-2-video/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467541</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Objective here means that a stage Yellow person has enough cognitive development to stand outside his own bias. This is only possible at Tier 2 and up. Tier 1 minds are not aware of how self-bias warps their perception of reality. Nor do they appreciate the importance of transcending self-bias.
</p>

<p>
	Rememeber, ego distorts all perceptions.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 21:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467541</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>conscious politics part 2 --&gt; disagreement</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37478-conscious-politics-part-2-disagreement/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467537</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	You are responsible for creating the entire universe.
</p>

<p>
	But this is way too much for you to accept right now.
</p>

<p>
	Again, it all boils down to your circle of concern and your level of consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	Your notion of responsibility is very limited.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 21:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467537</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>[Help Needed] Feeling Hopeless in the Struggle</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37421-help-needed-feeling-hopeless-in-the-struggle/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467218</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Psychedelics are good for busting you out of a rut. They can show you a life beyond struggle. Which then becomes something worth growing towards.
</p>

<p>
	I don't understand why 4 years of work hasn't improved your life. Why is the struggle so bad?
</p>

<p>
	Remember, this whole journey of self growth is supposed to be enjoyable. Don't do it because someone said you have to do it. Do it because it's what you're interested in naturally. What else are you gonna do?
</p>

<p>
	It might also be a good idea to take a break from personal development for a while. Come back to it later. Go enjoy life a bit. Follow what you're naturally passionate about, not some lofty ideal.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467218</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who's Interested In Conscious Politics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/35707-whos-interested-in-conscious-politics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467198</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1329-shiva/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1329" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1329-shiva/" rel="">@Shiva</a> Firstly, European regulations seem to be stronger than US regulations.
</p>

<p>
	Secondly, the lobbyist corruption problem is enormous and sneaky in the US. Corporations give millions of dollars of donations to influence elections and policies. It is legalized bribery via corporate PACs, fundraisers, think tanks, donations, gifts, lunches, dinners, golf, etc, etc.
</p>

<p>
	And it does not stop there. Corporate lobbyists actually get hired into government and when they leave government they go right back into the corporation and consult them on all the best ways to lobby government. It's the revolving door. Right now Trump has appointed the biggest lobbyists to head the regulating agencies like the Department of Education, the EPA, the FCC, etc. Their goal is specifically to dismantle regulations on their industries.
</p>

<p>
	Ajit Pai, the guy who killed net neutrality was Verizon's biggest lobbyist against net neutrality. Now he runs the FCC. It's absurd. The biggest oil company lobbyist now runs the EPA.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467198</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Who's Interested In Conscious Politics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/35707-whos-interested-in-conscious-politics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467189</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467177" data-ipsquote-contentid="35707" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563869649" data-ipsquote-userid="8214" data-ipsquote-username="andyjohnsonman">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		41 minutes ago, andyjohnsonman said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			What is the difference between lobbying and bribery? It seems the same to me.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That is a big problem.
</p>

<p>
	Although it is possible to lobby without paying money or using other corrupt ways.
</p>

<p>
	You can't really stop groups from lobbying government. That's part of democracy. But they should not be able to influence using money or other gifts.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 08:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467189</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467154</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467123" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563860676" data-ipsquote-userid="13774" data-ipsquote-username="nowimhere">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, nowimhere said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			But do you spend the entire trip in the prone position?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No. About 10 minutes is sufficient. After about 10 mins the substance will be fully absorbed and you are free to move around. I usually lay prone for the first 10 minutes and then sit up as the trip starts to really kick in.
</p>

<p>
	I recommend sitting upright during the trip so you are not disoriented. With eyes open.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 06:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467154</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Disgusted By Own Ego –&gt; Change –&gt; More ego?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37459-disgusted-by-own-ego-%E2%80%93-change-%E2%80%93-more-ego/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467153</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="467118" data-ipsquote-contentid="37459" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1563859990" data-ipsquote-userid="520" data-ipsquote-username="QandC">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, QandC said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Is wanting to become a more lovable person and to be selfless just another devilry?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	For fuck's sake no! That is God!
</p>

<p>
	The solution you're looking for is LOVE! Practice being more loving towards yourself and others.
</p>

<p>
	Replace guilt with love. Love is God! Not ego.
</p>

<p>
	You are being egotistical when you judge yourself so harshly. Treat yourself with kindness.
</p>

<p>
	Doubt is good at the beginning of this journey. But at some point you gotta drop doubt and replace it with absolute faith in Love.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 06:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467153</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Contemplating the true power of absolute consciousness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37451-contemplating-the-true-power-of-absolute-consciousness/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467095</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16094-rickybalboa/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="16094" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16094-rickybalboa/" rel="">@RickyBalboa</a> Unfortunately when it comes to understanding God, nothing but direct experience will work.
</p>

<p>
	Channel your curiosity into contemplation and tripping.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 04:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467095</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why many awakened philosophers were atheists?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/37441-why-many-awakened-philosophers-were-atheists/?do=findComment&amp;comment=467089</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Maybe "quite a few" is too generous. "An exceptional few" would be more accurate.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 03:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">467089</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>