<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=content&amp;type=forums_topic_post</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 08:25:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568860</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568855" data-ipsquote-contentid="22318" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580976799" data-ipsquote-userid="6221" data-ipsquote-username="Matt23">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		13 minutes ago, Matt23 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			For me, it's like finding an elephant eating a zebra alongside a bunch of lions after a kill...  does not compute.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's why you must be careful with your stereotypes and categories.
</p>

<p>
	For some people, the idea of a smart black man also does not compute. Which is the very source of racism.
</p>

<p>
	An overly simplistic mind is a dangerous and ugly thing.
</p>

<p>
	The devil you see in others is the devil inside your self.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 08:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568860</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568857</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568855" data-ipsquote-contentid="22318" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580976799" data-ipsquote-userid="6221" data-ipsquote-username="Matt23">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 minutes ago, Matt23 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			He's gay, so I associate that with being more liberal and open minded.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Everything is relative.
</p>

<p>
	Pete is far more liberal and openminded than the average person in the country, and certainly the South.
</p>

<p>
	But is he as liberal as TYT hosts who love to bash him? No
</p>

<p>
	Pete is a moderately liberal guy which is decent for someone from the Mid West. He's not from San Francisco.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 08:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568857</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568852</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568837" data-ipsquote-contentid="22318" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580973801" data-ipsquote-userid="6221" data-ipsquote-username="Matt23">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		54 minutes ago, Matt23 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Wasn't Buttigieg involved in some pretty unethical, racist, and illegal dealings with getting the police department in his hometown to be all white cops?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's one way to look at it. But are you really sure that's the proper way to look at it? Where did you get this perspective? From TYT? And you just blindly accept it as unbiased?
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			If so, this kinda baffles me if he's also gay...  I'm imagining, if he's racist and involved with those types of people and going to those extremes (I think TYT did a report on the scams/fraud or whatever it was) for racist values, I just don't see how he could be openly gay in that environment and have supporters.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Calling him a racist is pretty silly.
</p>

<p>
	Racism is a complex and nuanced issue. There is personal racism and systemic racism, which is much more subtle. Someone can have no personally racists attitude and yet still be part of upholding a systemically racist institution for many complex reasons, chiefly, his own survival.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I guess I see the gay identity and racist identity as not being compatible... yeah, within his person I could see it, but socially?  ... I dunno.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	He's not some open racist. You're saying it as though he's a KKK member. This is absurd.
</p>

<p>
	The accusation is that he inappropriately fired a black police chief due to political influence. But even this requires serious proof. There are many reasons why he could have fired him. Maybe you should listen to Pete's version of the story before jumping to conclusions.
</p>

<p>
	One can have biases and blindspots without being explicitly racist. In fact, most of us have such biases. If I put you into a position where you had to fire a black police chief to feed your family, you'd probably do it without blinking an eye. And you would never ever consider yourself a racist for doing so.
</p>

<p>
	Of course being gay does not automatically make one a champion for African American rights or justice. Mostly likely Pete just grew up in a white bubble where African American rights were not even a topic of conversation or concern. He would have to go out of his way to care about that.
</p>

<p>
	I grew up in such a white and affluent part of the US that I didn't even know racism was a thing until well after college. When you live in a great part of the country, you don't even know what injustice is. The notion that a cop would treat a black person different than a white person was impossible to even imagine where I grew up. It would be like worrying about people eating dogs.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 08:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568852</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What I've Been Upto</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45155-what-ive-been-upto/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568849</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1354-elvisn/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1354" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1354-elvisn/" rel="">@ElvisN</a> Sounds like you got a serious innate tolerance to LSD.
</p>

<p>
	125ug should be enough to start awakening. But people are different. If you are autistic or something, your brain chemistry is way different.
</p>

<p>
	125ug for me is an epic trip into full God-mode. At 700ug I doubt I would even stay in my body or ever return to this Earth.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 07:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568849</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Absolute Truth Important Questions</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45214-absolute-truth-important-questions/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568846</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568798" data-ipsquote-contentid="45214" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580966453" data-ipsquote-userid="19150" data-ipsquote-username="harisnaim95">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, harisnaim95 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			How do we know we are recognizing Absolute Truth,
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Absolute Truth is Absolute. It is prior to knowledge.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			when we are (relatively) limited in our consciousness?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You are not limited in consciousness. You just imagine you are.
</p>

<p>
	Consciousness is infinite and unlimited.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Is mysticism 'a belief in direct experience' (as the dictionary likes to describe it as)?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Mysticism is not a belief. It is consciousness of the Absolute.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			One definition of mysticism is: belief that union with or absorption into the Deity or the absolute, or the spiritual apprehension of knowledge inaccessible to the intellect, may be attained through contemplation and self-surrender. Another important one is: the belief that direct knowledge of God, spiritual truth, or ultimate reality can be attained through subjective experience (such as intuition or insight).
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That is a correct definition, but you don't understand the significance of what it means. So while it seems like you might understand it, you actually don't because you haven't had your first mystical experience yet.
</p>

<p>
	Beliefs about mystical experience are not mystical experience. And there is no substitute for mystical experience if you want to understand mysticism.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Even if we let go of beliefs, we are slightly 'faith-based', at least in the process, if I am correct.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No. There is no need to have faith in the Absolute Truth because it is Absolute. It is true under all possible conditions. There is no possibility of it being false or wrong or doubted.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I know direct experience is all we have,
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You say you know that, but actually you're not conscious of what that means.
</p>

<p>
	You don't understand that direct experience is all there could ever be.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			How do we know there's nothing (or no meaning) beyond what our theories are here?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Absolute Truth is not a theory.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Because we are essentially using the mind in the first place to say that we are just imagining that there is something beyond it. I've reached the point where I can't even believe that other people have thoughts or are thinking! I'm just assuming or guessing that they probably are, but it's just assumptions! I could be hallucinating this, so I get that point. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	For you, yes, the Absolute is just a theory/assumption. But of course that's not the actual Absolute, that's just a thought in your mind, which is an illusion.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			So for that reason, even though this isn't necessarily solipsism, how would we know that there isn't a God that is outside this existence, like how materialists and monotheistic religions describe it?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You are God. God is everywhere and nowhere, everything and nothing. There is no outside because inside and outside are both imagined by God.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Like for example, a Creator that 'just is' and is 'Being', while we are simply it's creation? I know the chain of infinite regression and that potential question of 'who created the Creator/what caused the cause'. But what if that question is invalid, and just as we would say 'Is-ness' is 'Is-ness', what if that type of Creator could also have 'just been'. But at the same time I can't trust my mind as I am imagining all these possibilities and God can probably be infinite possibilities. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, God has always just been. God is eternal, outside of time. God imagines time.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I realize it is all imagination, as I am mentally constructing it all. But for all intents and purposes, I could be insane and not even know it.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, you could be insane. So what? What's new here? You could be insane at any point in time and not realize it.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			And the Absolute Truth could be something else.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Absolute Truth is something else from everything you're thinking it is.
</p>

<p>
	But Absolute Truth cannot be other than what it is, since it is Absolute and the only thing exists.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			So I guess, we are just making our best guesses and having direct experiences and then fitting a 'story' around this reality to even say that it's imagination/mind of God?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	YOU are making guesses because you are stuck in your mind.
</p>

<p>
	But those who are conscious of the Absolute know it absolutely and it is not any kind of story. It is reality itself.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			What if I am imagining that imagination is all there is? You know what I mean lol? I know Leo would say that's just me imagining that, but I can't trust my mind for that either. See it's crazy lol (but fun) 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, notice how your own mind eats itself in contradictions and strange loops.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I know my words are limited, but essentially, how do I know I'm not being 'arrogant in my abilities'?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You ARE being arrogant. You have no mystical abilities yet. You're just thinking about stuff in sloppy ways and taking it seriously.
</p>

<p>
	Arrogance is a function of the mind. When the mind is silent, what arrogance can there be? Mysticism teaches you how to silence your arrogant and delusional mind.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Why should we trust anyone with their theories on Absolute Truth (when we can't even trust our own mind). 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You shouldn't trust anyone. Least of all your self.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Essentially even if we re-contextualize our reality based on our direct experience and other spiritual teacher's theories, it still feels like a belief.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No, you should carefully distinguish between belief & theories vs direct experience. These are two very different things.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			In reality, deep down inside, I feel like I really don't know. And just letting go and going with the flow seems easiest to me after this realization. You do you though. Thanks. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's the most truthful thing you've said in your whole post: "I don't know". The problem is, while you mouth those words you still take your own mind's stories and conclusions seriously. Which means, while you say you don't know, actually your mid is filled with all sorts of false knowledge. beliefs, and assumptions. To truly not know it is not enough to just mouth the words, you must actually do the work to clear your mind of a lifetime of garbage knowledge.
</p>

<p>
	You have to really appreciate that your own mind is the enemy here. Thinking about stuff is not the same as direct experience or consciousness. You can think about the Absolute for a million years and you will be no closer to it.
</p>

<p>
	You have to be very careful about convincing yourself that you understand a thing when you really don't. You speak as though you understand things like the Absolute, consciousness, God, not-knowing, direct experience, thought, belief, etc. But it's clear from where I sit that you have no clear consciousness of what these words refer to. You have not done the contemplative and meditative work to distinguish these things in your experience, so they are all muddled up and confused. That's okay. That's where everyone starts. But you must be honest about this with yourself.
</p>

<p>
	The most important thing you have to understand about this work is that this is not armchair philosophy. Mysticism is serious business. More serious than science. There is real work to be done to excavate your entire mind and psyche. We are talking about years and decades of careful and focused contemplation and introspection. And there are many, many ways you could fuck it up. Hundreds of ways to trick yourself and delude yourself. Only after you have successfully navigated past years of mental traps will you maybe, maybe, get a glimpse of the Absolute. And it will horrify you so much that you will run away. Then, if you dare return, it will take you many more years to finally be able to look the Absolute in the straight in face and start to understand what it really is. And even so, you could still fuck it up at any point. An impure ego-mind can distort the Absolute at any point.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 07:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568846</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>nudity, porn &amp; masturbation, why are they still considered bad behavior?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45216-nudity-porn-masturbation-why-are-they-still-considered-bad-behavior/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568834</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Nothing wrong with sex, but it is one of the lower joys of life.
</p>

<p>
	Most people's lives involve: sleep, eat, shit, work, fuck.
</p>

<p>
	There are higher ways to live.
</p>

<p>
	An awakening beats an orgasm every time.
</p>

<p>
	If you're pre-occupied with sex, you're stuck on living from chakra 2. Which is pretty low. At some point you'd be wise to outgrow that. Doesn't mean you have to stop having sex, but it just becomes less of a priority in your life.
</p>

<p>
	Of course lots of people judge sexual openness because they suppress their own sexuality.
</p>

<p>
	Also, peoples' sex drives differ. Some low, some high.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 07:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568834</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>nudity, porn &amp; masturbation, why are they still considered bad behavior?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45216-nudity-porn-masturbation-why-are-they-still-considered-bad-behavior/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568830</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Good God. You got enough tit there to sink the Titanic.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 07:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568830</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568825</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	You Bernie supporters are overlooking a very simple fact: election irregularities happen often in American politics. This is nothing new. Voting is a messy process. If you give them time, they will go back and double-check everything. But you're so impatient that you don't want to give them time. You automatically assume something nefarious and scream for instant results like children.
</p>

<p>
	Sure, you might wish everything worked flawlessly, but that's not how it's ever been. We live in reality. Iowa actually was more transparent than ever this year. And it's their effort to improve the system which ironically screwed it up.
</p>

<p>
	As if you've never tried to improve something in your life and it ended up coming out worse. People with honest intentions screw things up all the time.
</p>

<p>
	This whole incident is a textbook example of self-bias. And you still don't understand how deep the problem of self-bias goes. You are acting out your stage Green ideology, like unconscious monkeys. And then you wonder why politics is so dirty. You are making it dirty by flinging shit around. If you want a conscious society, first, start acting consciously.
</p>

<p>
	What you're doing here is not conscious politics. It's business as usual with a progressive ideology.
</p>

<p>
	This is a good example of what happens when Green goes too far in its desperation to defeat Orange and Blue.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 06:56:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568825</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568822</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568779" data-ipsquote-contentid="22318" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580962760" data-ipsquote-userid="16458" data-ipsquote-username="Keyhole">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Keyhole said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> I wonder if you perhaps maybe underestimate folks who are lower on the SD model's ability to sense that disconnect in communication.  I can be in my most egotistical state and still in the back of my mind see that there is something that is not integrated.  I imagine most people can sense this to some degree, even if they choose to sit with beliefs or act from a lower consciousness framework.
		</p>

		<p>
			What do you think?
		</p>

		<p>
			Do you think people are that obtuse, that they can't see it at all?
		</p>

		<p>
			That said, the stage blue/orange man seems genuinely baffled by green's perspective.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, people are that obtuse. You can see it because you are probably exceptionally conscious and developed.
</p>

<p>
	Most people are very closedminded and see the world in black/white, I'm-right/you're-wrong.
</p>

<p>
	Tucker Carlson is quite obtuse. His worldview does not account for relativity or multiple perspectives.
</p>

<p>
	Or course Cornel West is much more able to understand Tucker than Tucker is able to understand him. Cornel West is a world class intellect. Tucker Carlson is an ideological hack.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 06:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568822</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568821</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18068-johnny5/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="18068" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18068-johnny5/" rel="">@Johnny5</a> I think it should still be as strong as without vinegar. 20% is not that big a difference.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 06:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568821</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568815</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	The point of adding a few drops of vinegar is to help the freebase dissolve. It often refuses to dissolve into water.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 06:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568815</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo? Why? Ego-Collapse Awakening Video Contradictions</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45211-why-leo-why-ego-collapse-awakening-video-contradictions/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568814</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568780" data-ipsquote-contentid="45211" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580963379" data-ipsquote-userid="19150" data-ipsquote-username="harisnaim95">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, harisnaim95 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10595-jed-vassallo/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10595" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10595-jed-vassallo/" rel="">@Jed Vassallo</a>
		</p>

		<p>
			I honestly have realized the truth of what you guys are saying, but then again, I can't trust my mind. I guess that may be a strange loop in itself lol, I don't know. Thanks again. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No you have not. You're not even close yet.
</p>

<p>
	Awakening is completely outside your ability to think or imagine. It is like a new dimension of reality which you have no idea even exists or how to access it.
</p>

<p>
	This is extremely tricky stuff.
</p>

<p>
	Imagine dying and discovering something on the other side of life. That might give you a sense of how radical awakening is.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568792" data-ipsquote-contentid="45211" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580965062" data-ipsquote-userid="19150" data-ipsquote-username="harisnaim95">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, harisnaim95 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			So <a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> just to quickly clarify; I guess you meant don't do auto-pilot with the ego-mind/attachment to a certain sense of reality still in place, but allow true auto-pilot, which happens after the ego is surrendered? I hope I'm 'correct' with that. Thanks. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The problem is you don't know what "true" is. You don't know what true auto-pilot is because you are not conscious enough to distinguish truth from falsehood. You don't know what truth means yet.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 06:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568814</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568777</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568767" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580958682" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Here’s a good video on the topic that really explains why it’s perfectly rational to be suspicious of intent to corrupt the process.
		</p>

		<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
			<div>
				<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nDO2kHGEoY0?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
			</div>
		</div>

		<p>
			 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	This video is garbage.
</p>

<p>
	96% of results are now in. Looks like it was a very tight race but Pete won. Deal with it. You owe Pete an apology. Pete's estimates were most accurate.
</p>

<p>
	This is the difference between being oriented towards truth vs survival.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 04:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568777</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Leo? Why? Ego-Collapse Awakening Video Contradictions</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45211-why-leo-why-ego-collapse-awakening-video-contradictions/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568776</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I think you're misunderstanding what surrender and letting go means. It doesn't mean to act on all your impulses because many of those can be of the ego.
</p>

<p>
	The key you're missing is consciousness. You can't really fake that. Your level of consciousness is crucial. An ego cannot just ape being God and reap the benefits. You need to actually have an awakening and do work to raise your consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	The ego is incapable of surrender, really. It will fight tooth and nail. It will play games. It will pretend to be spiritual. Etc. It takes a lot of work to get past all that bullshit.
</p>

<p>
	For an ego, life will not be smooth and effortless, it will be filled with suffering and struggle.
</p>

<p>
	None of your stories or meanings are Absolute Truth. Absolute Truth is what dawns after you realize everything the mind says is relative and basically bullshit.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 04:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568776</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568746</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568735" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580952819" data-ipsquote-userid="17661" data-ipsquote-username="Bno">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		29 minutes ago, Bno said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			They didn't plan on the results getting delayed. They're only doing that now because they thought they could get away with rigging the results
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	So they didn't plan it, yet somehow, magically, the app failed to load for hundreds of precinct captains when it came time to report results?
</p>

<p>
	They thought they could just not report results for 2 days by blaming a fully functioning app? And get away with it? As if nobody would come forward and report that the app functioned perfectly?
</p>

<p>
	Your conspiracy theory is more of a joke than flatearth.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 01:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568746</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568744</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Here's a stage Blue/Orange Christian's politics vs a stage Green Christian's politics:
</p>

<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
	<div>
		<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kuc6C2_Txmw?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
	</div>
</div>

<p>
	Quite illuminating how they talk past one another.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 01:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568744</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568726</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568725" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580951811" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		16 minutes ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Pete is the second most popular establishment Democrat in the polls. So, he’s put all his campaign money into ads in the first states... especially Iowa. So, his plan already rides heavily on having strong numbers in Iowa especially. So, this certainly dovetails nicely with that plan.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It also dovetails nicely that he won Iowa precisely because he sunk so much money into campaigning there. Coupled with the fact that Biden barely met the 15% threshold so Biden's voters were forced to choose Pete.
</p>

<p>
	If Biden under-performed it makes sense that Pete over-performed. Biden voters are not going to Bernie by and large.
</p>

<p>
	You are interpreting things in accordance with your biases. There are far less nefarious explanations of what happened.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			So, what I’m saying is that Pete is benefiting from the app malfunctioning in the sense that they are releasing the results gradually (in the districts that Pete was stronger in), and releasing the results from areas with more delegates that Bernie was stronger in.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	If Pete actually had a victory, then Pete is hurting from the app malfunction the most because he badly needed a clear victory because he's not going to win New Hampshire or Nevada or South Carolina most likely. Pete's only real chance of beating Bernie was to get a clear victory in Iowa. Bernie didn't need a clear victory as badly as Pete because Bernie should get a clear victory in New Hampshire and elsewhere. And Bernie has endless support and donations.
</p>

<p>
	If you were a Pete supporter, you would be pissed. Assuming Pete won. Which looks likely right now.
</p>

<p>
	If you sunk all of your money into one election, as Pete did, you need a clear victory there. So Pete is hurt the most by the situation as long as he didn't do anything fraudulent to cause it. I'm willing to give Pete the benefit of the doubt that he is not a totally corrupt fraud. If it turns out he is, well, he should go to jail for election rigging. But bring solid proof. That's a serious criminal charge. That's like calling someone a child molester. You better have proof. You don't call people child molesters just to be on the safe side. That's a highly damaging accusation.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 01:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568726</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568724</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568718" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580950061" data-ipsquote-userid="17661" data-ipsquote-username="Bno">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		29 minutes ago, Bno said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			 The court ruled that as a private entity, the DNC can choose whoever they want as their nominee.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	But not through a fraudulent vote counting system.
</p>

<p>
	There are laws against gross fraud like that.
</p>

<p>
	You can't just not count the votes of a black nominee because he's black, for example. That would never fly.
</p>

<p>
	If the DNC staged a fake app error in order to delay publishing the real results, that too would fall under fraud.
</p>

<p>
	It's clear that the app did not work as intended. Precinct captains had difficulty getting the app to download and work properly.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568724</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568712</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568690" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580946028" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		49 minutes ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Also, my broader point is to say that politicians shouldn’t be financially invested in a company whose app reports the election results.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I agree politicians shouldn't have conflicts of interest.
</p>

<p>
	But even to say that Pete is financially invested is a stretch. Buying services from a technology company is not to be invested in it. Companies routinely provide services to various clients.
</p>

<p>
	I'm pretty sure deliberately creating an vote counting system which misreports votes in favor of one candidate would be illegal. If a campaign was caught doing that it would be a massive scandal, there would be legal charges, and the entire election would be nullified.
</p>

<p>
	There is no evidence for any of that.
</p>

<p>
	To suggest Pete paid $50,000 to buy the election via a corrupt app is absurd. You better have solid evidence when making such a claim instead of saying "Err on the side of caution." You are erring on the side of slander.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568712</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568688</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Enough bullshitting.
</p>

<p>
	Back to the contemplation salt mines.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 23:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568688</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>If your greatest concern is election integrity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45150-if-your-greatest-concern-is-election-integrity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568686</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568545" data-ipsquote-contentid="45150" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580924090" data-ipsquote-userid="58" data-ipsquote-username="Juan Cruz Giusto">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		6 hours ago, Juan Cruz Giusto said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
			<div>
				<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nDO2kHGEoY0?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
			</div>
		</div>

		<p>
			 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	This is gross projection.
</p>

<p>
	Nothing objective or factual about this commentary. It's pure speculation.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 23:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568686</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568685</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568679" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580945130" data-ipsquote-userid="17661" data-ipsquote-username="Bno">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		10 minutes ago, Bno said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> You keep ignoring this
		</p>

		<div class="ipsEmbeddedOther ipsEmbeddedOther_limited">
			<iframe data-controller="core.front.core.autosizeiframe" scrolling="no" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/index.php?app=core&module=system&controller=embed&url=https://twitter.com/caitoz/status/1224866964008357890?s=19" style="height:649px;"><br />
			</iframe>
		</div>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yeah, that's called a bug.
</p>

<p>
	You ever program a database server?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 23:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568685</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Conscious Politics or Just Social Democracy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45193-conscious-politics-or-just-social-democracy/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568682</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18485-husseinisdoingfine/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="18485" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18485-husseinisdoingfine/" rel="">@Husseinisdoingfine</a> If you want to see the next natural stage of evolution of society, Northern Europe is the place to look. They have done it already.
</p>

<p>
	America is not going to magically leap-frog Northern Europe with some utopian system. First we must reach Northern European levels, then we could innovate further. Northern Europe still has private property. And even Northern Europe is facing nationalist backlash. So they are struggling just to maintain stage Green without falling back down to Orange or Blue.
</p>

<p>
	What we need is to focus on is raising the bulk of the populace from Blue & Orange into Green. That is very practical and we know we can do that. We know what that looks like. It is not communism or even full socialism. It is social democracy a la Northern Europe.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 23:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568682</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568674</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568633" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580938255" data-ipsquote-userid="15394" data-ipsquote-username="whoareyou">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, whoareyou said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			How do you ignore the fact what DNC did in 2016?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I don't. That was a distinctly different issue.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			You always tell people that about their blind spots and their "survival agenda", yet you don't see yours. Oh the irony.
		</p>

		<p>
			What happened with this app is a huge concern, and to throw the "conspiracy theory" card is beyond ignorant and lazy.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Your projections aren't my problem.
</p>

<p>
	The app is a concern. But you are the one throwing around conspiracy theories without any evidence other than your paranoid projections.
</p>

<p>
	If evidence comes out of rigging, I'm happy to look at it. So far there is no such evidence and it is highly unlikely there will be. Not totally impossible, but definitely highly unlikely.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568637" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580939269" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Don’t be naive Leo. It’s far wiser to err on the side of caution in this case and prepare for the worse case scenario.
		</p>

		<p>
			Your assumption that there is no corruption happening, when that’s quite probable and there’s a long track record of corruption in the DNC, enables devilry. 
		</p>

		<p>
			What happens if everyone thinks like you do Leo? Devils run away with the election while fools give them the benefit of the doubt.
		</p>

		<p>
			The fact of the matter is that the creator of the Shadow app’s husband is Mayor Pete’s senior strategist. And he paid over $42k to that company... supposedly for other services.
		</p>

		<p>
			Also Bernie’s numbers, as he was tracking the numbers too for consistency purposes, have shown so far that he has a strong lead over Pete.
		</p>

		<p>
			So, I implore you to consider how unwise it is for you to just give those that stand to lose so much from a Sanders sweeping victory the benefit of the doubt.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	My priority is truth, not survival.
</p>

<p>
	What you are doing is projecting and speculating wildly.
</p>

<p>
	Pete had his people in every polling location. Bernie had his people in only 60% of polling locations. So it's reasonable that Pete's internal numbers are more accurate than Bernie's.
</p>

<p>
	Either way it seems the election was very close for both of them. The difference is not material. They seem to both be winners here. The fact that you don't like Pete on ideological grounds is irrelevant. Pete clearly got a lot of votes and that makes sense because Biden and Klobuchar were not viable in many polling locations, so of course they went to Pete, not Bernie.
</p>

<p>
	Bernie is still winning the popular vote, so I don't know what you guys are bitching about. Bernie had a great night and it's actually very good for Bernie that Pete basically killed Biden. Bernie should be able to defeat Pete going forward. Biden was the biggest threat to Bernie. If the DNC was rigging the election they would do it in favor of Biden as he was the frontrunner and has strong black support. The whole theory of rigging here makes on sense. You can't rig Pete's support. Moderates clearly support him.
</p>

<p>
	By denying Pete his votes you are being anti-Democratic. Notice that. You have to admit that many moderates just don't like Bernie. That's not rigging, that a problem for your progressive ideology which you have to cope with. Just because you like Bernie doesn't mean he should win.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 23:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568674</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Conscious Politics or Just Social Democracy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45193-conscious-politics-or-just-social-democracy/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568655</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	The point is not just that capitalism was necessary at one point in the distant past, but that it is still important today. At least parts of it are.
</p>

<p>
	Abolishing private property is not going to work in practice. Things can sound nice in theory but that doesn't mean it will work.
</p>

<p>
	When most humans in society are stage Blue and Orange, private property is necessary. Even if everyone was stage Green private property would still be necessary.
</p>

<p>
	One of the problems with Marxism from day 1 was that its ideals were way too advanced for the people's development level. Maybe if 80% of the population was Turquiose then you could get by without private property, but that will take another 1000 years to reach. And even that is questionable.
</p>

<p>
	As long as the political quiz is not some scam to harvest user data. Be careful with those. Lots of scammy quizzes on the net. Don't be a sucker for them.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 22:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568655</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Eating Honey As A Main Food Source</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45200-eating-honey-as-a-main-food-source/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568627</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/5-health-fitness-nutrition/">Health, Fitness, Nutrition</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568625" data-ipsquote-contentid="45200" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580936461" data-ipsquote-userid="15007" data-ipsquote-username="Billy Shears">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 minutes ago, Billy Shears said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I'm just wondering, but didn't you lately mention that you try to avoid too much sweet foods, especially fruits?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 21:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568627</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Purity Relative?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45206-is-purity-relative/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568617</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	He who's love is most unconditional, is purest.
</p>

<p>
	When all fear and judgment has been vanquished from your mind, you are pure.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 20:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568617</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568616</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568610" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580932687" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		34 minutes ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			How do you know they actually paid for another service and it wasn't just a way to funnel money to the company? 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	And how do you know Bernie isn't a reptilian?
</p>

<p>
	Sometimes a cigar is just a cigar.
</p>

<p>
	Your paranoia is not about truth, it's about preserving your survival agenda.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			"To him who is in fear everything rustles."                 -- Sophocles
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	As you stoke up fear, you become a tool of the devil.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 20:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568616</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Eating Honey As A Main Food Source</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45200-eating-honey-as-a-main-food-source/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568592</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/5-health-fitness-nutrition/">Health, Fitness, Nutrition</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I eat quite a lot of raw honey. Probably 1 jar per week.
</p>

<p>
	Not sure how healthy it is. I like to believe it's healthy. Of course 1 jar/week is nowhere near enough to live off of. It would be quite gross to only eat honey all day. Makes me want to vomit just thinking about it.
</p>

<p>
	And I would also worry about pesticides when eating that much.
</p>

<p>
	Good honey is also expensive.
</p>

<p>
	But it makes for a nice quick energy-boosting snack.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 19:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568592</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568591</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18298-bazooka-jesus/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="18298" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18298-bazooka-jesus/" rel="">@Bazooka Jesus</a> I've never bothered with converting anything. Never found it necessary.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 19:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568591</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568588</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Of course it would be nice if all voting was federally administered with the full resources of the federal government rather than some Iowa hillbillies.
</p>

<p>
	But they say they have a solid paper trail. If that's true, I wouldn't worry about it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 19:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568588</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568587</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568585" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580929568" data-ipsquote-userid="11747" data-ipsquote-username="purerogue">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 minutes ago, purerogue said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Doubt that they would let some unknown Indian company to make app for elections. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Wouldn't surprise me at all. Companies use sub-contractors all the time.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 19:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568587</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568583</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568581" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580929335" data-ipsquote-userid="11747" data-ipsquote-username="purerogue">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 minutes ago, purerogue said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			This is not some complicated software it is just simple app
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It is also not developed by a trillion dollar company.
</p>

<p>
	They probably outsourced this app to some Indian developers for $10,000.
</p>

<p>
	People are used to software developed by trillion dollars companies which functions flawlessly (and even that's not true), then they complain about some locally developed mom-and-pop shop app.
</p>

<p>
	Have you seen how many buggy apps there are on the App stores?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 19:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568583</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568580</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568579" data-ipsquote-contentid="22318" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580929259" data-ipsquote-userid="14905" data-ipsquote-username="fridjonk">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 minutes ago, fridjonk said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> What if you were to make a separate threads of the positives for each stage. Like "Positive Stage-Blue Examples". 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Post 'em here.
</p>

<p>
	Positive and negative are inseparable.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 19:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568580</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568577</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Just want to remind everyone: this thread has a lot of silly and negative examples of Blue because they are flashy, funny, and all-too-easy to find. (I'm guilty of this.) But there are also many healthy and positive examples of Blue.
</p>

<p>
	Don't get the idea that Blue is always idiotic. Without Blue, civilization would collapse.
</p>

<p>
	This too is stage Blue:
</p>

<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
	<div>
		<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uFFlHFgYmpU?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
	</div>
</div>

<p>
	 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 18:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568577</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I'm to serious... how to stop that?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45202-im-to-serious-how-to-stop-that/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568574</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Meow
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 18:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568574</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568567</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568555" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580925749" data-ipsquote-userid="17661" data-ipsquote-username="Bno">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		46 minutes ago, Bno said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<div class="ipsEmbeddedOther ipsEmbeddedOther_limited">
			<iframe data-controller="core.front.core.autosizeiframe" scrolling="no" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/index.php?app=core&module=system&controller=embed&url=https://twitter.com/KyleKulinski/status/1224707108660240384?s=09" style="height:306px;"><br />
			</iframe>
		</div>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Apple and Microsoft, both trillion dollar companies, release software updates which break their whole system and require immediate patches.
</p>

<p>
	And you expect some rinky-dink Iowa app to not have bugs?
</p>

<p>
	This is a joke, not evidence of rigging.
</p>

<p>
	Alternative media's vision is way too clouded by their hatred of the establishment and desire for Bernie to win. Textbook definition of projection and confirmation bias.
</p>

<p>
	The mind only sees evidence which validates its ideology.
</p>

<p>
	If you would only be willing to admit that's true: you don't know, and if you were patient, you'd get to the truth of the matter. But the ego-mind isn't interested in truth, it's interested in survival. And thus evil is born. Your mind is the source of the evil you decry. But you are too busy surviving to see it.
</p>

<p>
	And you wonder why there's so much evil in the world. Look in the mirror, if you dare.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 18:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568567</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568565</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568512" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580920723" data-ipsquote-userid="18298" data-ipsquote-username="Bazooka Jesus">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Bazooka Jesus said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Huh? I thought plugging freebase is no problem?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It is no problem
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 18:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568565</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reality crisis - am I talking to myself?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45196-reality-crisis-am-i-talking-to-myself/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568562</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568551" data-ipsquote-contentid="45196" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580925419" data-ipsquote-userid="10053" data-ipsquote-username="billiesimon">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		36 minutes ago, billiesimon said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I'm asking because I don't know if it's just me or not
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	What's the difference?
</p>

<p>
	Who could tell you?
</p>

<p>
	What is a "me"?
</p>

<p>
	Watch the video: How Authority Works. You don't get it yet.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 18:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568562</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>If your greatest concern is election integrity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45150-if-your-greatest-concern-is-election-integrity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568538</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/17661-bno/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="17661" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/17661-bno/" rel="">@Bno</a> Turn inward in silence and observe your own biases and attachments.
</p>

<p>
	There is no need to have a discussion with me.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 17:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568538</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reality crisis - am I talking to myself?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45196-reality-crisis-am-i-talking-to-myself/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568534</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10053-billiesimon/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10053" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10053-billiesimon/" rel="">@billiesimon</a> If you are talking to yourself then there's no point in asking us since you are talking to yourself.
</p>

<p>
	So why are you asking? What truth do you hope to gain here? Ask yourself.
</p>

<p>
	It's a silly as asking a liar if he is gonna lie to you. If he's a liar, you can't believe his answer. And if he's not a liar, you don't need to ask at all.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 17:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568534</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Conscious Politics or Just Social Democracy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45193-conscious-politics-or-just-social-democracy/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568525</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568369" data-ipsquote-contentid="45193" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580894179" data-ipsquote-userid="18122" data-ipsquote-username="LfcCharlie4">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 hours ago, LfcCharlie4 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			nowhere was there, or will be, a great 'awakening' of man in which we collectively decide that we've had enough of our government and move on to a society built on 'Love'.
		</p>

		<p>
			Humans don't change their societies do; organizing an ideology on the basis of getting people to open up their chakras or some shit is empirically illogical, theoretically unsound, and lacking a scientific basis.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	A) There is no real discussion with such people because they are just parroting Marxist dogma. They are not contemplating anything about reality for themselves. They thing Marxism is best, period.
</p>

<p>
	B) They have no clue what Love is or means.
</p>

<p>
	C) Society is always moving towards greater Love, regardless of what Marxists say or do. Some "Great Awakening" is not needed. And of course these Marxist have no clue how significant even one individual awakening is.
</p>

<p>
	D) Humans do change. Spiral Dynamics shows that humans can be at very different levels of development. And even way beyond Spiral Dynamics. A human cannot be considered independently of its culture and society. So changing society changes humans and vice versa.
</p>

<p>
	E) Don't forget that Marxists adopt scientific materialism as a dogma, so their understanding of politics and reality cannot go very high. They have no clue how central consciousness is to the development of society and humans. To dismiss this by making fun of chakras is just ignorant. Total strawman.
</p>

<p>
	F) All their "logic" is self-biased. Logic has nothing to do with truth.
</p>

<p>
	G) Individual growth is crucial for developing an advanced society. This is not mutually exclusive with also developing social infrastructure. Both are crucial.
</p>

<p>
	H) These Marxists are so reactionary to captialism that their whole worldview gets distorted and biased by their judgments and hatreds, unable to see some of the important necessities of capitalism, and that there is more than just capitalism vs socialism to consider, there are meta issues at stake, and that capitalism and socialism are not really polar opposites or enemies.
</p>

<p>
	Ideological retorts will not do here. One must deeply contemplate the nature of all things for oneself. Marxism's fundamental flaw is its materialist metaphysics and epistemology. That puts a glass ceiling on how high it can go. And it has a structual problem of being an ideology. It is not conscious of itself and incapable of deep self-reflection.
</p>

<p>
	A monkey with a Marxist ideology is still a monkey. And dangerously ignorant.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568525</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>If your greatest concern is election integrity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45150-if-your-greatest-concern-is-election-integrity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568506</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568416" data-ipsquote-contentid="45150" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580908597" data-ipsquote-userid="10476" data-ipsquote-username="Cocolove">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		3 hours ago, Cocolove said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			conspiracy likely but who knows
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No it isn't
</p>

<p>
	Watch your self-biases.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568506</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iowa Caucus App</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45201-iowa-caucus-app/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568503</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568462" data-ipsquote-contentid="45201" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580916789" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			The App was funded by Pete Buttigieg's campaign
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No it wasn't. The Bittigieg campaign paid money to Shadow for other tech services it provided. Not for the app.
</p>

<p>
	Get your facts straight.
</p>

<p>
	You guys are way too into this conspiracy shit. Everything is a conspiracy against Bernie. Sometimes a bug is just a bug.
</p>

<p>
	You ever write software? You know how many bugs it can have?
</p>

<p>
	There is no indication of any rigging. Just a logistical failure.
</p>

<p>
	If evidence emerges, then we can discuss further.
</p>

<p>
	Until then, be patient and we should have the results verified soon.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568503</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Peculiar Charity-Sponsored Cult-Like Organization</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45179-peculiar-charity-sponsored-cult-like-organization/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568495</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568409" data-ipsquote-contentid="45179" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580907715" data-ipsquote-userid="15734" data-ipsquote-username="thibault">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		3 hours ago, thibault said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			but I was also pretty baffled as he does seem pretty charismatic and charming
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	But?
</p>

<p>
	That's how con artists and narcisists are.
</p>

<p>
	I had a bad vibe from him the first time I saw someone post about on this forum. He seems like a bullshitter. But I could be wrong. I know nothing about him. Just his vibe.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568495</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Divided consciousness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45151-divided-consciousness/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568354</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567847" data-ipsquote-contentid="45151" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580812584" data-ipsquote-userid="18979" data-ipsquote-username="Strangeloops">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		21 hours ago, Strangeloops said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			How can God/The universe be conscious of me typing this text and you, or the whole creation at the same time? If its one then how come everything except this direct experience right here is just a fantasy in this mind? From this view this is all there is. People or things that is not present in this experience does not exist.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's far more twisted than that.
</p>

<p>
	Your thinking about consciousness is far too limited. Consciousness is unlimited. So your inability to imagine how is irrelevant. Conscious isn't limited to your human mind.
</p>

<p>
	All there is, is absolutely everything.
</p>

<p>
	How? How can it have any limits? What would limit it? What would stop it? Anything that might stop it is itself, which means it cannot be stopped. It has unlimited power. Imagine that: unlimited power.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 08:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568354</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Good video on the insubstantiality of white identity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45188-good-video-on-the-insubstantiality-of-white-identity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568350</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	If being human is an illusion, certainly being white is an illuison.
</p>

<p>
	100 years ago Einstein showed that time and space were relative. And yet today people still think being a white human is grounded in something real? Lol
</p>

<p>
	If freaking time and space ain't real, what chance do you have of being real?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 07:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568350</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568304</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	This lady is priceless:
</p>

<div class="ipsEmbeddedVideo ipsEmbeddedVideo_limited">
	<div>
		<iframe allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZU_7ik80uiQ?feature=oembed" width="480"></iframe>
	</div>
</div>

<p>
	 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 05:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568304</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A warning to those trying to reach enlightenment through psychedelics.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45185-a-warning-to-those-trying-to-reach-enlightenment-through-psychedelics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568259</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Why don't you apply the same logic to meditation or driving a car?
</p>

<p>
	Every time a new technology comes out some caveman will say, "But it's better to do it the old fashioned way. More pure."
</p>

<p>
	So then by this logic you should wipe your ass with your hands. Sure, you could use TP, but what have you sacrificed? Why are you deluding yourself out of desperation? Why don't you patiently wash the shit off your hands each time? This will toughen you up. It will make you a read man. What kind of Buddha are you if you cannot stand a bit of shit between your fingernails? Only a desperate and greedy person would seek a better way. It's bound to backfire. This is antithetical to being human. God wants you to wipe you ass with your hangs like the Buddha did. My guru wiped his ass with his hands therefore so should everyone else. For sure your knowledge of your ass will be tainted if you don't get the full experience of wiping it with your hands. You will not understand the ins and outs of ass-wiping fully. Your technique will be bad. The gods will be displeased and not give you blessings. The gods gave you two hands for a reason, one to eat your food and the other to wipe your ass.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 03:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568259</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568254</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7639-soul/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7639" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7639-soul/" rel="">@SOUL</a> Do not derail this thread further with this.
</p>

<p>
	If you want agrue about paths start a new thread.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 03:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568254</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Be Willing To See Your Denied Capacity For Being The Outright Devil</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45177-be-willing-to-see-your-denied-capacity-for-being-the-outright-devil/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568174</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Be willing to see your inner JP <img alt=":P" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue@2x.png 2x" title=":P" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 01:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568174</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Peculiar Charity-Sponsored Cult-Like Organization</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45179-peculiar-charity-sponsored-cult-like-organization/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568171</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Lots of red flags around Athene.
</p>

<p>
	As soon as you spot a manipulator, that's the biggest tell-tale sign of devilry.
</p>

<p>
	Truly selfless and awakened people have no desire to control or manipulate others, not even for their own good or awakening. Not even to save the world. Manipulation itself is ignorance, greed, and fear made manifest.
</p>

<p>
	God has no desire to manipulate people. Only a dispassionate hope that they wise up and awaken.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568171</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568168</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568151" data-ipsquote-contentid="45124" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580861672" data-ipsquote-userid="7639" data-ipsquote-username="SOUL">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		36 minutes ago, SOUL said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I'm not doing the 'work' because decades ago I have awakened to the realization there is nothing to do, no work, no accomplishment to achieve and no truth to attain. Working to have no ego is like trying to ban your own self from the forum of your own being which attempting to do often is just fodder for more self suffering.
		</p>

		<p>
			Liberation is presence of being in the moment free of self suffering....everything else is story telling so just tell a joyful story if one must tell one.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's is a half-truth.
</p>

<p>
	In a sense it's right. But in another sense it's deeply problematic to hold this view.
</p>

<p>
	I don't care how awake you may be, you've got more work to do, more things to become conscious of. If you're not here to do inner work, then you have no reason to be here at all. And feeding newbies the idea that they have no inner work to do leads them down a cul de sac of inaction, laziness, and apathy.
</p>

<p>
	The ego would love nothing more than to believe it needs to do no work.
</p>

<p>
	After you've done a ton of work, then you can talk about how you don't need to do work.
</p>

<p>
	It's like a billionaire talking about how work is unnecessary. Yes, for him it's unnecessary because he's already done enough to live off the interest. But this is not appropriate advice for people who struggle to pay for food.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568168</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson vs Infinity?? Uh oh...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45126-jordan-peterson-vs-infinity-uh-oh/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568131</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568126" data-ipsquote-contentid="45126" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580855971" data-ipsquote-userid="18893" data-ipsquote-username="Endangered-EGO">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		24 minutes ago, Endangered-EGO said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>  I would love to see him have a full blown Kundalini awakening. It would heal his auto-immune illness and turn one of the most known "rational Christian philosopher" (for the lack of a better term) into a Mystic. The biggest Problem with Christians (those here in Europe, your Christians in the US are more similar to the ones we had in the middle ages) is, they believe that the Devil tries to bring them of the path by doubting the religion.<br />
			<br />
			Ironically, by blindly following the bible or some deluded priests they fall into the Devils trap... I believe they first need to understand that their religion is not just a conceptualization of the truth that Jesus saw, but also a philosophical interpretation by those who wrote and taught it.  <br />
			<br />
			A lot of catholic priests here in Europe are borderline mystics. They simply need the tools. Once it reaches the Vatican, Christianity WILL develop. Priests have mystical experiences (mostly Love), they just need a little push into the right direction.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You make a lot of simplistic assumptions there.
</p>

<p>
	None of that works as easy as you portray.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 23:02:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568131</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson vs Infinity?? Uh oh...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45126-jordan-peterson-vs-infinity-uh-oh/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568113</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18893-endangered-ego/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="18893" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18893-endangered-ego/" rel="">@Endangered-EGO</a> Radical openmindedness is the key. And he don't have it.
</p>

<p>
	Fear, judgment, and closedmindedness are the only things keeping you from God.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 21:42:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568113</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson vs Infinity?? Uh oh...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45126-jordan-peterson-vs-infinity-uh-oh/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568086</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18474-sizeable-oof/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="18474" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18474-sizeable-oof/" rel="">@Sizeable Oof</a> Stop with your silly expecations and you'll see there is no problem.
</p>

<p>
	Love is all around. Just look.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 20:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568086</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568064</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="568060" data-ipsquote-contentid="45124" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580844320" data-ipsquote-userid="14907" data-ipsquote-username="Derek White">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		8 minutes ago, Derek White said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> How do you plan to deal with the gender wars happening in the relationships sub?
		</p>

		<p>
			The arguments are endless, they are not there to learn.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, it's a problem.
</p>

<p>
	I have spoken out against it and will continue to do so.
</p>

<p>
	I also try to lock down such threads after a while.
</p>

<p>
	But to some extent is has to be allowed to play itself out. People are where they're at. Most people see the world through the POV and self-biases of their gender and refuse to see it from the other side. This requires a Tier 2 meta perspective which many people here lack and I certainly can't beat it into you.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 19:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568064</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to love your thoughts and feelings?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45161-how-to-love-your-thoughts-and-feelings/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568063</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11561-javfly33/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11561" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11561-javfly33/" rel="">@Javfly33</a> Just sit still and be in silence.
</p>

<p>
	Relax, breathe, enjoy the silence.
</p>

<p>
	Of course your monkey mind will not allow this. Which is why we train in meditation, yoga, etc.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 19:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568063</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I have been psychologically &quot;castrated&quot; as a boy, how do I regain my fire</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45171-i-have-been-psychologically-castrated-as-a-boy-how-do-i-regain-my-fire/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568061</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Create an inspiring vision for your life and discipline yourself to work towards it.
</p>

<p>
	See Life Purpose Course. This will make you feel empowered rather than dwelling in victim-hood.
</p>

<p>
	Spend lots of time visioning. Vision is crucial here.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 19:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568061</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo Gura PUA</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/44823-leo-gura-pua/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568059</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I think it's time to lock this one down. It is turning into a distraction for the ego-mind.
</p>

<p>
	I wish you guys were more conscious of how your mind creates these distractions from contemplating your self-biases.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 19:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568059</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568054</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567767" data-ipsquote-contentid="45124" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580799516" data-ipsquote-userid="6826" data-ipsquote-username="Annoynymous">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 hours ago, Annoynymous said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> would you ban a racist in this process? I think you should because i have seen racist in your Society forum. Don't you think that's toxic too?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	We have banned racists in the past.
</p>

<p>
	If we see clear racists posts we will definitely take action on them. Point them out to us. It has to be a clear example of racism though. Keep in mind that most people have a bit of racist in them.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 19:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568054</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bernie crushes Biden on the first assault</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45154-bernie-crushes-biden-on-the-first-assault/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568010</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/31-society-environment-government-politics/">Society, Environment, Government, Politics</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Do not spread conspiracy theories on this forum.
</p>

<p>
	I expect you guys to be above such nonsense.
</p>

<p>
	Admit that you do not know.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 17:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568010</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Innate value</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45120-innate-value/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568008</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12603-identity/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12603" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12603-identity/" rel="">@Identity</a> Don't confuse what's in the life purpose course with awakening.
</p>

<p>
	Life purpose is relative, awakening is Absolute.
</p>

<p>
	The point is that value is relative. There is relative value in knowing your values.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 17:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568008</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Enlightenment - is that what's really going on?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45159-enlightenment-is-that-whats-really-going-on/?do=findComment&amp;comment=568004</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Please don't speak of things you have no idea about.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 17:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">568004</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Innate value</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45120-innate-value/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567800</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8395-buba/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8395" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8395-buba/" rel="">@Buba</a> Just do the work.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 08:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567800</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Innate value</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45120-innate-value/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567766</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567751" data-ipsquote-contentid="45120" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580795518" data-ipsquote-userid="8395" data-ipsquote-username="Buba">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Buba said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			So even years of meditation will not bring this bliss, peace, feeling valuable?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Peace comes when you realize value is an illusion.
</p>

<p>
	Let go of needing to feel valuable. Notice that peace remains in its place. Simple.
</p>

<p>
	The point of years of meditation is to forget all about value. When you were a toddler you had zero value and life was great. As a teen you started to chase value and life started to suck. The more you chase value the worse you will feel about life.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I know people who are not enlightened, awakened, but don't feel incomplete and easily accept whatever life throws at them.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No they don't. You merely assume they do and they are good at acting.
</p>

<p>
	There is no completeness so long as you identify with being human. A human is by definition not the whole Universe and therefore always incomplete.
</p>

<p>
	What you seek is awakening and you don't even know it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 06:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567766</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Transcending physical pain</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45060-transcending-physical-pain/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567740</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	If you become conscious enough you can see that pain itself is a self-bias. There is no reason why pain is worse than pleasure. This preference is a self-bias and distortion of truth.
</p>

<p>
	But that requires some crazy levels of consciousness outside the ability of most people. Don't even dream of it unless you are a full-time monk.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 05:16:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567740</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567703</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7068-mondsee/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7068" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7068-mondsee/" rel="">@Mondsee</a> Even a blind squirrel occasionally finds a nut.
</p>

<p>
	Doesn't mean anything.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 02:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567703</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567690</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567627" data-ipsquote-contentid="22318" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580773730" data-ipsquote-userid="7068" data-ipsquote-username="Mondsee">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Mondsee said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I sometimes doubt this. I have had quite deep conversations with a muslim friend who is incredibly trapped into Islamic dogma, and have had him grasp much better how a piece of garbage in the woods <em>is </em> God (we were literally walking out in nature, and I used that as an example) than other hyper-scientific and "progressive thinking" friends understand that different religions are all referring to the very same thing, in the same ways that different languages all serve the same purpose of communication. "Oh no no no..." they'll say... "some religions are way worst than others, and by no means are they about the same!!! the only thing that they have in common are the stupid people who follow them"... well, haha there may also be a little bit of truth in that, but we never get passed an evasive response like that because they're literally allergic to anything that gets remotely away from their materialistic rationality. Their minds are just as paradigm locked for the rest of their lives, never to find God.<br />
			<br />
			Edit: the fact alone that I have this muslim friend (and other super religious friends) is something I attribute to the fact that I <em>can </em>understand them. My "scientific" friends are absolutely incapable of this, and thus they will "tolerate" religious people, but they are unable to have an actual close friendship with them, as I can.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It seems that way on the surface, but in practice that Muslim is less morally and cognitively developed than an atheist.
</p>

<p>
	Of course there are exceptions. I'm speaking more broadly.
</p>

<p>
	Stage Orange is more developed than Blue. That Muslim has yet to go through the atheist and rationalist stage and in practice he will be a bigger devil.
</p>

<p>
	If he is a stage Green Muslim then he might be above the typical atheist. But stage Green Muslims are a tiny percentage of the population.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 01:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567690</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567688</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567648" data-ipsquote-contentid="22318" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580775404" data-ipsquote-userid="10476" data-ipsquote-username="Cocolove">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Cocolove said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			but should we not let blue kids pray in public schools?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No one is stopping a kid from praying in public school.
</p>

<p>
	That's not the issue. The issue is that those who complain about not being able to pray in public school actually have the hidden agenda to disseminate their favorite religion via public school. They want to use government to promote their religion and indoctrinate kids.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 01:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567688</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I have self-hatred due to my sexuality</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/44976-i-have-self-hatred-due-to-my-sexuality/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567686</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Try self-love
</p>

<p>
	Didn't Christ teach you to love? If not, WTF was he teaching you?
</p>

<p>
	Why must you turn Christ into a devil?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 01:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567686</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tao Te Ching - Tao Of Nature</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45116-tao-te-ching-tao-of-nature/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567683</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5821-pluto/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5821" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5821-pluto/" rel="">@pluto</a> There are substantive questions to ask and understand of reality/Tao.
</p>

<p>
	You can play cute Zen games, but in practice this confuses people and discourages contemplation.
</p>

<p>
	Contemplation is crucial. Just sitting around is not good enough.
</p>

<p>
	The nature of Tao requires contemplation and profound questioning.
</p>

<p>
	After 10,000 hours of contemplation, yes, then you can just sit.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 01:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567683</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567623</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567618" data-ipsquote-contentid="22318" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580772932" data-ipsquote-userid="7068" data-ipsquote-username="Mondsee">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		5 minutes ago, Mondsee said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Welp, what I see is all of my very best friends from college being deeply deeply locked in the scientific rational paradigm, having no understanding or tolerance whatsoever for anything that comes slightly close to religion. They weren't brainwashed into religion as children, but that didn't end up any better... I am able to fully empathize with both worlds, and that's because I've experienced both of them fully, and transcended them.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Technically it is better. But yes, that's a separate problem.
</p>

<p>
	It is better to deal with a science zealot than a religious zealot.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 23:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567623</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Need help understanding a shroom trip</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45064-need-help-understanding-a-shroom-trip/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567622</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18428-joshi3/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="18428" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18428-joshi3/" rel="">@Joshi3</a> Stop this. You're digging yourself deeper into mind.
</p>

<p>
	Just sit and admit you don't know. Sit silently. Nobody is ever going to give any existential answers. You can only get them in the silence. Stop asking for answers. Each answer you ask for only deludes you further.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 23:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567622</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>First real experience of absolute oneness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45072-first-real-experience-of-absolute-oneness/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567617</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16951-daniels/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="16951" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/16951-daniels/" rel="">@DanielS</a> Good work. Welcome to spirituality.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 23:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567617</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson vs Infinity?? Uh oh...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45126-jordan-peterson-vs-infinity-uh-oh/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567611</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Those are valid points. The only problem is that he isn't following his own advice.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 23:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567611</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Innate value</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45120-innate-value/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567610</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567261" data-ipsquote-contentid="45120" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580737825" data-ipsquote-userid="8395" data-ipsquote-username="Buba">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		9 hours ago, Buba said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Has anybody found this innate value? Does anybody feel worthy and complete? How did you find it? Is spiritual awakening a must for it?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You become complete when you realize that all value is relative and worthiness is non-existent.
</p>

<p>
	That's the whole point of awakening, to become complete.
</p>

<p>
	Your thinking about this whole problem is precisely backwards, which is why you try and try and keep failing. And you will always fail until you realize that value, worth, and incompleteness are illusions.
</p>

<p>
	You can't become complete so long as your mind is attached to a finite and relative identity.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 23:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567610</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jordan Peterson vs Infinity?? Uh oh...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45126-jordan-peterson-vs-infinity-uh-oh/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567537</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Can you give us the gist of it?
</p>

<p>
	I don't want to listen to a man with sand in his vagina.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 21:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567537</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Iam from the future 2050</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45132-iam-from-the-future-2050/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567535</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Plot twist: Dr Phil is the real cyborg <img alt=":P" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue@2x.png 2x" title=":P" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 21:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567535</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Issue with David Deida's book</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/44947-issue-with-david-deidas-book/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567481</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567324" data-ipsquote-contentid="44947" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580745013" data-ipsquote-userid="15951" data-ipsquote-username="Parththakkar12">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 hours ago, Parththakkar12 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Deida says the opposite though! He says that the Masculine in the Absolute sense is Consciousness which is stoically present with the Feminine, which is all form. It's the Feminine which is coming at the Masculine in ever-changing ways!! I didn't quite get this, cuz from what I know, masculine energy is forward-moving energy and femininity is receptive as you're saying.
		</p>

		<p>
			What do you think he means when he says this?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	He is speaking from a more metaphysical/spiritual perspective there.
</p>

<p>
	They are not contradictory. The point is that masculinity is grounded and stable while femininity is floaty and more playful.
</p>

<p>
	You can be grounded, stable, and active, and penetrate the world with your energy all at the same time.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 20:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567481</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dear ''older'' women, how should I speak to you?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45129-dear-older-women-how-should-i-speak-to-you/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567477</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Do not ask women how to speak to them. Be a man. Have some spine.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 20:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567477</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Majoring Philosophy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45118-majoring-philosophy/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567475</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Major in it if you want, but don't pursue it academically. It's a waste of time. You will not get to the Truth that way.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 20:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567475</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567473</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I've <u>never</u> kicked someone out for having a victim mindset.
</p>

<p>
	That's not the issue here.
</p>

<p>
	Edit: oops, left out the "never".
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 20:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567473</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What if the &quot;infinite&quot; is finite and is just the entirety of the Now?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45108-what-if-the-infinite-is-finite-and-is-just-the-entirety-of-the-now/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567469</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18790-4201/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="18790" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18790-4201/" rel="">@4201</a> This is the point in the conversation where a Zen master slaps you hard across the face.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 20:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567469</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Concern About Stage Red Rap Music...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45006-my-concern-about-stage-red-rap-music/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567464</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Someone please make a deepfake video of Sadhguru rapping.
</p>

<p>
	Want bitches, yes or no?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 20:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567464</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Blue Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22318-spiral-dynamics-stage-blue-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567462</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7068-mondsee/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7068" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7068-mondsee/" rel="">@Mondsee</a> That's like saying, "My parents molested me as a child, but now I've overcome it and I'm grateful for who its made me."
</p>

<p>
	Good for you, but most molested kids don't get over it so easily.
</p>

<p>
	This is not a matter of judgment but a matter of creating paradigm lock in a child's mind. Which is as big a problem as molesting a child.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 19:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567462</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What if the &quot;infinite&quot; is finite and is just the entirety of the Now?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45108-what-if-the-infinite-is-finite-and-is-just-the-entirety-of-the-now/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567403</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18790-4201/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="18790" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18790-4201/" rel="">@4201</a> You are lost in mind.
</p>

<p>
	Sit silently and observe the consciousness of the present moment.
</p>

<p>
	You have to train yourself to drop useless mental activity.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 18:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567403</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567399</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15437-chumbimba/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15437" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15437-chumbimba/" rel="">@Chumbimba</a> That's perfectly fine.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 18:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567399</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567395</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567393" data-ipsquote-contentid="45124" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580752766" data-ipsquote-userid="16020" data-ipsquote-username="Raptorsin7">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 minutes ago, Raptorsin7 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Makes sense. Devils never admit they're devils lol
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Well, to be fair, these can be tough judgment calls and my judgment calls are relative. But then again, this whole forum exists in the relative domain and someone has to moderate it.
</p>

<p>
	It's never a pleasant decision to ban someone. I would rather not have to ban anyone. But as I get too permissive people take advantage. Over the years I've found that it's almost impossible to reform a problematic user. I guess that's why society invented prisons.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 18:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567395</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567392</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567387" data-ipsquote-contentid="45124" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580752582" data-ipsquote-userid="16543" data-ipsquote-username="TheAlchemist">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		3 minutes ago, TheAlchemist said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Just checking if it's still ok to be critical at times on this forum?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, no problem.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 17:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567392</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567389</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567385" data-ipsquote-contentid="45124" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580752542" data-ipsquote-userid="16020" data-ipsquote-username="Raptorsin7">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		6 minutes ago, Raptorsin7 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Will you give them a chance to explain why they were acting like that?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No because once such a person is identified I have found that there is no correcting their behavior no matter how much I reason with them. The whole point is that if such a person was open to correction or reason, they wouldn't be identified as needing a ban in the first place. Such people are not aware of what they are doing and cannot help themselves act how they act and think how they think.
</p>

<p>
	Any time a person is a banned, the response is always the same: they blame me and they always have a story about how they are right. After that, there is definitely no reasoning with them.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 17:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567389</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567386</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Running this forum has made me appreciate how difficult of a job police have.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 17:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567386</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What if the &quot;infinite&quot; is finite and is just the entirety of the Now?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45108-what-if-the-infinite-is-finite-and-is-just-the-entirety-of-the-now/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567381</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18790-4201/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="18790" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/18790-4201/" rel="">@4201</a> You are not aware. That's the problem. Thinking you're aware vs being aware are two different things.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 17:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567381</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tao Te Ching - Tao Of Nature</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45116-tao-te-ching-tao-of-nature/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567378</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			"Stop seeking to realize the mystery of life"
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	This is bad advice.
</p>

<p>
	Do the opposite.
</p>

<p>
	The rest is pretty good.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 17:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567378</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo critique</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/44998-leo-critique/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567373</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567177" data-ipsquote-contentid="44998" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580718414" data-ipsquote-userid="6221" data-ipsquote-username="Matt23">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		9 hours ago, Matt23 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Haha... ugh... life goes on.  
		</p>

		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> If you're so enlightened, how the hell could that antelope eat popcorn without opposable thumbs!? ...  Check and Mate
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Enlightened antelope has telekinetic abilities, of course.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 17:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567373</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Purging Bullshitters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45124-purging-bullshitters/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567370</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Just a heads up, I'm in the process of checking and banning people on this forum who are consistent bullshitters, keyboard jockeys, naysayers, spreading misinformation about awakening, or are not doing the work.
</p>

<p>
	I have less tolerance for such things these days.
</p>

<p>
	Make sure you're here with an open mind to learn, that you are non-ideological, and that you are doing the work.
</p>

<p>
	As much as I like keeping this forum democratic and open to all, the reality is that far too many people come in here who aren't doing the work and just distracting others from doing the work.
</p>

<p>
	These are always difficult determinations to make, but without it the quality of the forum goes too low.
</p>

<p>
	Most of you are okay, so don't worry. It's usually only a tiny handful of people who consistently drag things down.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 17:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567370</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What if the &quot;infinite&quot; is finite and is just the entirety of the Now?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45108-what-if-the-infinite-is-finite-and-is-just-the-entirety-of-the-now/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567367</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/17376-maya-el/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="17376" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/17376-maya-el/" rel="">@MAYA EL</a> Then you don't need to be on this forum.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 17:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567367</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Explanations for lack of interest in women</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45068-explanations-for-lack-of-interest-in-women/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567192</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567187" data-ipsquote-contentid="45068" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580722108" data-ipsquote-userid="14907" data-ipsquote-username="Derek White">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		34 minutes ago, Derek White said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Earlier you said masculinity is imposing one’s will on the world.
		</p>

		<p>
			Would you then say that masculinity is devilry? Since imposing one’s will means to manipulate the world into being a certain way, freezing it, and defending and attacking other forms.
		</p>

		<p>
			Is masculinity = survival = devilry?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No, I wouldn't mix those two notions.
</p>

<p>
	Masculinity/femininity are different ways of interfacing with reality.
</p>

<p>
	Have you never heard of a she-devil? <img alt=":P" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue@2x.png 2x" title=":P" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 09:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567192</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What if the &quot;infinite&quot; is finite and is just the entirety of the Now?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45108-what-if-the-infinite-is-finite-and-is-just-the-entirety-of-the-now/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567183</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567178" data-ipsquote-contentid="45108" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580719375" data-ipsquote-userid="11325" data-ipsquote-username="Enlightenment">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		29 minutes ago, Enlightenment said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Well, it will invalidate the whole notion of the Ultimate Reality, if you can get higher and higher and it doesn't seem to end
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No, Ultimate Reality is right here, right now. Infinity is right here, right now, always. There is nothing but Infinity.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 09:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567183</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Explanations for lack of interest in women</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/45068-explanations-for-lack-of-interest-in-women/?do=findComment&amp;comment=567172</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="567167" data-ipsquote-contentid="45068" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1580714665" data-ipsquote-userid="14907" data-ipsquote-username="Derek White">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		25 minutes ago, Derek White said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Have you actually tried to reduce your sex drive?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I would rather just accept and love myself as I am. Be careful demonizing sex.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 07:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">567172</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>