<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Leo's Blog: Infinite Insights - Actualized.org</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leo's Blog: Infinite Insights - Actualized.org]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 10:45:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Social Distancing</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/social-distancing</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you are in the US, it's gonna get really bad in the next 2 weeks. Make sure you stay at home as much as possible. 20% percent of severe coronavirus cases are people between the age of 20 and 44.</p>
<p>If you are young and catch this virus, your chances of ending up in the emergency room is 1 in 5. No joke. And in 2 weeks you will be lucky if you can find a hospital in a major city with an open bed. You really want to avoid this thing.</p>
<p>Do not socialize. Do not hang around people. Do not touch objects outside your house without gloves. Do not come within 6 feet of people. Do not hang out in busy public places like restaurants or stores. Just get your groceries with gloves and go the fuck home.</p>
<p>Update: The following in-depth article was shared on the Forum by user Matt23:</p>
<p><a href="https://medium.com/@tomaspueyo/coronavirus-act-today-or-people-will-die-f4d3d9cd99ca" target="_blank">Coronavirus: Act Today Or People Will Die</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/social-distancing</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Boost Your Immune System Now</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/boost-your-immune-system-now</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Corona virus public service announcement:</p>
<p>The virus seems to hurt most those with the weakest immune systems. The best thing you can do right now is to boost your immune system with supplements, vitamins, powerful antioxidants, and good nutrition. This should be done prior to infection and doubled down upon if you start noticing flu-like symptoms.</p>
<p>Here are supplements I recommend you buy. I make no money off these supplements.</p>
<p>Basically anything which boosts your immune system:</p>
<ul>
<li>Chaga mushrooms (tincture or powder)</li>
<li>Mushroom immune support (tincture or pills; these usually contain a mix of many species)</li>
<li>Black Elberberry (tincture or pills)</li>
<li>Enchinacea (tincture or pills)</li>
<li>Garlic (pills)</li>
<li>NAC (pills)</li>
<li>L-Glutathione Reduced (pills)</li>
<li>Beta Glucan (pills)</li>
<li>Astaxanthin (12mg pills)</li>
<li>Vitamin C (1,000mg timed-release pills)</li>
<li>Vitamin D3 (5,000 IU softgells)</li>
<li>Colloidal silver (20-30PPM liquid bottle, not eyedropper or nasal spray)</li>
</ul>
<p>And generally, any other supplement which is proven to boost one's immune system. You can do some basic research to find others if the above are out of stock. There are also many different brands and many online stores besides Amazon (which might get sold out). You can buy these supplements individually or sometimes in various "immune booster" blends. Either way is fine. You can also buy them at local grocery stores, pharmacies, and vitamin shops. Sometimes finding them locally is easier, so don't give up hope if they are sold out online.</p>
<p>I suggest you stock on up on the above, take some daily for the next month or two, and triple down on the dosages if you start to feel sick. It is safe to mega-dose Vitamin C and Vitamin D3 for short periods of time. I would do so immediately if I felt sick. A mega-dose of Vitamin C might be 5,000mg to 10,000 per day and a mega-dose of Vitamin D3 might be 10,000 to 20,000 IU. I would only mega-dose a few days at a time if I was sure I was sick.</p>
<p>The government should really be passing out these supplements to everyone for free, but of course that's not gonna happen, so it's up to you to take responsibility for you and your family's health. Don't expect your doctor to know about these supplements. Doctors work within a very narrow-minded medical system, ignoring all natural and herbal remedies.</p>
<p>Note: I am not saying these supplements & vitamins are a "cure" for the corona virus. I'm merely saying your body will stand a much better chance of fighting the virus if you supply it with the raw nutrients it needs. Your recovery will hinge on the strength of your immune system, which hinges on your diet and nutrition. Taking these supplements on time could make the difference between having a mild flu vs ending up in the ER or dead. Raw juicing of fruits and veggies should also be helpful, although that requires going to the grocery store frequently, which isn't the best idea.</p>
<p>Don't panic, just get prepared and take this virus seriously. Start limiting your public exposure because this thing is gonna get a lot worse before it gets better. I would expect most countries to get locked down very soon.</p>
<p>This is also a great opportunity to become mindful of how SURVIVAL dominates all human thought and behavior, both individually and collectively. Notice just how wrapped up your mind is in survival. Your mind is not interested in truth, fairness, or love. It's interested in a warped, biased perception of reality which serves the narrow survival goals of your limited self-identity. From this one dynamic all the rest of your problems emerge.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/boost-your-immune-system-now</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Billionaire Election</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-billionaire-election</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This explains it all:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iIbJIdW9HSg?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-billionaire-election</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leaving For Solo Retreat - March 2020</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/leaving-for-solo-retreat-march-2020</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I'll be doing an intense solo retreat for the next 25-30 days.</p>
<p>See you when I get back.</p>
<p>The site, store, and forum are still fully operational.</p>
<p>Thanks for your support.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/leaving-for-solo-retreat-march-2020</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What It's Like To Smoke Salvia Divinorum</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-its-like-to-smoke-salvia</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/394606946?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Warning: I advise extreme caution when using salvia. This is a dangerous substance only for experienced psychonauts. A trip sitter is mandatory. Be prepared to completely lose your mind & sense of reality.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-its-like-to-smoke-salvia</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Anand's Twitter</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/anands-twitter</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I don't spend much time on Twitter. But if you're gonna follow one political commentator, Anand Giridharadas is one of the best:</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/AnandWrites" target="_blank">https://twitter.com/AnandWrites</a></p>
<p>His critiques of hyper-capitalism are sharp and devastating.</p>
<p>This is what serious progressivism looks like. Serious progressivism is not college kids protesting for trans rights. It's someone like Anand going for the jugular of unchecked capitalism. Everything else is a sideshow.</p>
<p>American capitalism is in the process of cannibalizing itself. But most elites are in denial about it because they want to keep milking the cow until it drops dead.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/anands-twitter</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Build Your Skillz</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/build-your-skillz</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you want to break out of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/how-to-escape-wage-slavery" target="_blank">wage slavery</a> and become successful what you need is to develop serious skill, like this example. Skillz are how you become a somebody in the world.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qyW12gDeWPI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Would you hire this guy if you needed some drawing work done? You couldn't say no! He's too good to be ignored. Everyone wants to work with skilled people. It is like honey that attracts all the ants.</p>
<p>You are not going to make it far in life without building a unique and powerful skill set. Building a skill set takes time, patience, focus, vision, and passion.</p>
<p>See my <a href="https://www.actualized.org/life-purpose-course" target="_blank">Life Purpose Course</a> for help finding your direction in life. It's very practical and gives you the core principles you need to move forward with building your unique skill set. Building a skill set takes a lot of time, so there's no time to waste. Get started now! The better your skill set the more money you will make, the more creative freedom you will command.</p>
<p>BTW, my skill set is articulating understanding. Not to brag, but I'm really, really good at it. Which is why you watch my videos. How did I get so good? I practiced it in my mind for 20+ years. Why did I do that? Because I love it.</p>
<p>So, Step #1: Find what you love and master the shit out of it.</p>
<p>Step #2: Profit!</p>
<p>If you live in a poor or underdeveloped country where life is difficult, your best way to rise out of that muck is to train up an incredible skill set. That is your passport to freedom. And yes, you can do it. But you need a clear vision and sense of direction.</p>
<p>The beauty of building a skill set is that it can be done virtually anywhere and it can be done virtually for free. You can build up an amazing skill set in a village in Iraq. Which allows you to bootstrap yourself from nothing to something.</p>
<p>So roll up your sleeves, lock yourself in a room, and build your skill set.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/build-your-skillz</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tribe Meets White Man For First Time</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/tribe-meets-white-man-for-first-time</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Amazing raw footage! Try to put yourself in the epistemic position of the tribesmen. Notice how their minds simply cannot make sense of what is happening. That's because their limited paradigm cannot account for what is happening in their direct experience. It's very much like a psychedelic breakthrough trip. It's clearly real, but your mind has no clue how to explain it, and of course you're terrified it might be dangerous.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7a7IaS3ml4g?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is exactly what it's like for humans to meet advanced aliens. And exactly what it's like for humans to meet God. God can be present in your direct experience but your mind will not be capable of making sense of what God is, let alone how it is possible that God could be YOU!</p>
<p>Humans who have never had a breakthrough dose of psychedelics are like those tribesmen, with no clue of the world that exists outside their little tribal village.</p>
<p>This video is also what it's like for a materialist scientist to encounter mysticism. Mysticism is like that white man. It makes no sense to the rational mind because it's so much more advanced.</p>
<p>Teaching about God feels like being that white guy trying to give food to those terrified and puzzled tribesmen. Imagine trying to explain to them what a video camera is.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/tribe-meets-white-man-for-first-time</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What The Hell Is Socialism?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-the-hell-is-socialism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Great discussion which ties together concepts from my videos: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/conscious-politics-part-1" target="_blank">Conscious Politics</a>, <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/understanding-relativism-part-1" target="_blank">Understanding Relativism</a>, and <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/how-society-evolves" target="_blank">How Society Evolves</a>.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/z6J3ROV4IPc?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>When it comes to understanding shifts on the political spectrum the key notion that people do not understand or explicitly state is Relativity. All political ideologies and positions are completely relative. So what looks "extreme" or "radical" left or right wing only appears that way given a particular vantage point. There is  no "radical" in the absolute sense. But this notion is too radical for mainstream news people to speak. A great confusion results when news people speak of liberal, centrist, or conservative positions as if these are fixed, absolute quantities. All scientific scales are relative, and even more so political scales, but this point is lost on mainstream news anchors.</p>
<p>There is no such thing, in politics, as staying in the middle. Because the very notion of "a middle" does not exist! "The middle" is always defined relative to the extremes. Your mind literally cannot know what "the middle" is unless it has extremes to contrast it with. And since the extremes are always moving, so is "the middle." By trying to stay in "the middle" you're actually naively fooling yourself that politics isn't changing when it is.</p>
<p>Yesterday's radicalism is today's "middle". And yesterday's "middle" is today considered barbaric or criminal. Don't forget, the middle between truth and falsehood is still falsehood. The middle between non-slavery and slavery is still slavery. So being in the middle is not as safe and sound as it first seems. Don't try to be in the middle. Try to be truthful, conscious, selfless, and loving. That is the best position. And in an ego-obsessed society, truth, consciousness, selflessness, and love are seen as radical.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-the-hell-is-socialism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Essence</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/spiral-dynamics-essence</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you struggle to remember what the Spiral stage colors mean, here's a quick and simple reference. This is Spiral Dynamics distilled to its essence.</p>
<p><a href="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/Spiral_Stages_03.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4542" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/Spiral_Stages_03.png" alt="Spiral_Dynamics_Stages_Chart" width="615" /></a></p>
<p>(click image to enlarge)</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/spiral-dynamics-essence</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Global Mind</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/global-mind</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Watch this time lapse of how the global mind is coming online:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6dkiqJ_IZGw?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is the real meaning of globalization.</p>
<p>The Earth is wiring itself for unity — reaching out and reconnecting to lost parts of itself. Becoming more integrated and whole.</p>
<p>This is a poignant example of what I was talking about in my video: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/division-vs-unity" target="_blank">Division vs Unity</a>.</p>
<p>There is no stopping this. We cannot ever go back. The only way forward is ever-higher integration of the species.</p>
<p>Reminds me of this image which shows the mind's level of interconnectedness by default vs on a psychedelic:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3917" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/image001.jpg" alt="brain on psychedelics" width="615" /></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/global-mind</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lula - Visionary Leadership</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/lula-visionary-leadership</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is what visionary leadership sounds and looks like.</p>
<p>This is a speech by former Brazilian president Lula da Silva just before his unlawful imprisonment.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MJm08zHWaKA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>"There is no use in trying to stop my ideas."</p>
<p>"They're already in the air and you cannot imprison them."</p>
<p>"There is no point in trying to stop my dreams. Because when I stop dreaming I'll be dreaming through your minds and dreams."</p>
<p>"There's no point in thinking everything's going to stop the day Lula has a heart attack."</p>
<p>"That's nonsense."</p>
<p>"Because my heart will be beating through yours, and there are millions of hearts."</p>
<p>"The powerful can kill one, two, or 100 roses, but they'll never stop the arrival of spring."</p>
<p>- - - - - - - -</p>
<p>That is the power of Selflessness. It is the ultimate power. The power of God.</p>
<p>It touches your soul because deep down you feel the highest Truth is Selfless. And you yearn to be guided towards Truth despite all your devilry.</p>
<p>Talk about a man who understands that <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/reproduction-is-an-illusion" target="_blank">reproduction is not limited to biology</a>.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/lula-visionary-leadership</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Psychonaut Lemurs?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/psychonaut-lemurs</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yYXoCHLqr4o?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>My kind of beasties ;)</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/psychonaut-lemurs</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Religion Goes Corrupt</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-religion-goes-corrupt</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I'm not a huge fan of Morning Joe's centrist views, but this was a nice example of them calling out devilry:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fLDnhL648qI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Joe has done a good job in the Trump era of not jumping into the cult of Trump and calling out his own side. This takes integrity and objectivity.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-religion-goes-corrupt</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Through The Looking Glass</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/through-the-looking-glass</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I want to introduce you to the phrase, "Through the looking glass". It's a great phrase to keep in mind if you're going deep into the existential work that we do here.</p>
<p>The phrase comes from the title of Lewis Carroll's famous novel, Through The Looking Glass, sequel to Alice In Wonderland. In the sequel Alice goes through the looking glass — looking glass is just an old fashioned word for a mirror — and of course discovers a strange and wacky alternative universe.</p>
<p>"Through the looking glass" is a metaphorical expression which means: on the bizarre side, in the twilight zone, in a strange parallel world where things are weird, loopy, and upside-down.</p>
<p>So what's the point?</p>
<p>The point is, consciousness has dimensions to it which are through the looking glass. Strange, bizarre, loopy, surreal, maddening. This physical dimension of conscious which we call Earth is just one tiny dimension out of infinite others which are not limited by the laws of physics, logic, or even sanity. These strange realms can be scary and shocking to the unprepared mind that only expects reality to fit its narrow logical categories. It's important to keep this in the back of your mind as you start doing spiritual work. Be prepared that one day you will find yourself through the looking glass. When it happens to you, don't freak out, don't panic. Stay calm and remind yourself that this was supposed to happen. This was the point of your work.</p>
<p>Especially you're going to use psychedelics you'll come to appreciate the significance of this phrase. Keeping these words in the back of your mind might help you to avert a bad trip.</p>
<p>What do you do when you suddenly find yourself through the looking glass? Enjoy the scenery, like an explorer in some uncharted land. As Terence McKenna said, "God is some kind of lost continent in the human mind." Or more accurately, the human mind a tiny island in the mind of God.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/through-the-looking-glass</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Explaining God For Dummies</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/explaining-god-for-dummies</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/389630844?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/explaining-god-for-dummies</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Open Your Eyes</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/open-your-eyes</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>It grows on you.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mkeOoWquAqk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/open-your-eyes</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>New Logo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/new-logo</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A new logo for Actualized.org has been in works for several years. It took a long time because I wanted to come up with something I'd be really happy with. Then, after much brainstorming and searching, finally in a trip it came to me.</p>
<p>So here it is:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/actualized_new_06.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4525" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/actualized_new_06.png" alt="actualized_new_06" width="615" /></a></p>
<p>It represents Maslow's Pyramid of Needs, which was the originating idea behind the whole site, but now with the final step of transcendence.</p>
<p>It is an interesting story that when Maslow first created his pyramid of needs, the highest stage — the pinnacle — he called Self-Actualization. But then in the final years of his life he added one last stage, which he called Transcendence, which of course stands for enlightenment. That's where your whole journey ends. Or should we say begins, as everything goes full-circle with Transcendence, where beginning and end merge into One.</p>
<p>In the end your journey will end exactly where it began, but everything will be different as God has been actualized.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/new-logo</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wicked Strange Loop</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/wicked-strange-loop</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>User "<a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14162-yog/" target="_blank">Yog</a>" on the forum found this amazing <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/reality-is-a-strange-loop" target="_blank">strange loop</a> that I wanted to share with everyone:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/strange-loop-stone-01.gif"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4522" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/strange-loop-stone-01.gif" alt="strange-loop-stone-01" width="320" height="400" /></a></p>
<p>That's how the ultimate nature of reality is. God created itself, without a beginning or end.</p>
<p>Impossible, yet here you are.</p>
<p>If your rationality cannot handle strange loops, your rationality will not be sufficient to understand reality (not even conceptually, never mind actually). The origin of reality exists in a place where formal logic cannot go. That's because formal logic cannot handle self-reference / self-reflection.</p>
<p>You have to learn to think in ways that accommodate paradox and strange loops.</p>
<p>And if you ever want to understand God fully, know this: complete comprehension of God will obliterate your whole mind. You will literally not be able to think your name or your birth any more. All explanations of reality will get expunged in the stark light of pure God-consciousness until only Void remains. Notions such a time, space, matter, humans, objects, history, science, cause & effect, logic, life, birth, death, will all be annihilated and transcended. You will be left dumb and mute.</p>
<p>Absolute Infinity, Absolute Truth, Absolute Love</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/wicked-strange-loop</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Are You A Light Worker?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/are-you-a-light-worker</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I know, I know, it sounds so New Agey, but this term "light worker" is quite informative if you happen to be one but don't realize it yet.</p>
<p>Here's a list of 20 qualities of light workers:</p>
<p><a href="https://thoughtcatalog.com/brianna-wiest/2018/03/20-signs-youre-whats-known-as-a-lightworker/" target="_blank">20 Signs That You Are A Light Worker</a></p>
<p>If that's you, it's important to recognize it early and structure your life accordingly. As a light worker you cannot live the typical traditional life that everyone around you is living. You are different and you need to carve out a unique path in life which honors your unique values, strengths, and abilities.</p>
<p>If you're a light worker but you're trying to live a traditional life, you're going to suffer a lot without knowing what exactly is wrong.</p>
<p>If you identify as a light worker, you should really take my <a href="https://www.actualized.org/life-purpose-course" target="_blank">Life Purpose Course</a>, it was designed just for you. It's not easy to live a life of purpose because society does not teach you how. I created the course after figuring out how to do it for myself.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/are-you-a-light-worker</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>On Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/on-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A devil is one who has mistook devilry for God, and God for a devil.</p>
<p>Devils swarm, like moths around a campfire.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/on-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Register To Vote 2020</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/register-to-vote-2020</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you're American, it's important you vote in the upcoming Democrat primaries. It's important not just for America's sake but for the world.</p>
<p>It's no longer good enough to only vote in the November General Election. You must get active in the primaries.</p>
<p>It's not too late. Go register. Some states require that you register as a Democrat to participate in the primary. Do that if you must. I did. You can always unregister afterwards. Mark the date of the primary on your calendar. Many states have early voting, so mark that on your calendar. Voting is super easy in most places.</p>
<p>Now, the million dollar question: Who should you vote for?</p>
<p>Vote for the person who is most conscious, most loving, most Spirally developed, AND who has a reasonable chance of winning. Don't throw your vote away on candidates polling at <5%.</p>
<p>Of course, in the end, you will only vote as high as your Spiral stage of development allows. If you are Blue-Orange, you will like Biden and Klobuchar. If you are solid Orange you will like Bloomberg and Buttigeg. If you are Orange-Green you will like Warren, Yang, Tulsi, Steyer. If you are solid Green and above you will like Bernie. If you are solid Orange or below you will likely hate Bernie.</p>
<p>Remember, your vote is 90%+ determined by your level of consciousness and nothing else. The rest is bullshit excuses your mind is making up to justify your position. All of your justifications are coming from your level of consciousness and nothing else. You can't help reveal your true colors by who you vote for. There is nothing original about what your mind is doing.</p>
<p>Personally I endorsed Bernie Sanders 1 year ago and I'm sticking to it.</p>
<p>It is also helpful to donate money now if you can to the candidate of your choice. But don't fool yourself: a donation is not a substitute for voting in the primary. Voting is crucial and if you really care about the development of mankind, it is your duty to vote for the most developed humans to run society.</p>
<p>Important issues are at stake:</p>
<ul>
<li>The rise of nationalism & authoritarianism</li>
<li>The perpetuation of soulless, unchecked, unjust, and unsustainable capitalism</li>
<li>Environmental destruction that will affect mankind for a century to come</li>
<li>The perpetuation of a corrupt healthcare system that kills tens of thousands needlessly every year</li>
<li>War with Iran</li>
<li>The senseless drug war</li>
<li>And more!</li>
</ul>
<p>The time for talking and squabbling is over. Now is time for action at the ballot box. Encourage your friends and family to do the same.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/register-to-vote-2020</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Please Let Me Rob You, I'm Woke</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/please-let-me-rob-you-im-woke</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for the repeated Anand talks, but I'm just addicted listening to him speak on neoliberalism. He's so good at articulating the current stage Orange/Green transition that the developed world is going through:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8KBlH269dIs?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is a discussion about the end of Stage Orange. Picture a numb rat gnawing its own tail to the bone until one day it suddenly realizes: "Oh! That's my tail I've been gnawing on!" That is how stage Orange transitions into stage Green.</p>
<p>But really what Anand talks about is only the tip of the iceberg.</p>
<p>The role of good public intellectuals is to question and deconstruct the myths of prior generations to create a new upgraded culture that shapes how people think about things to enable the next level of society.</p>
<p>An outdated culture leads to people thinking and acting in foolish and self-destructive ways en masse because most people simply follow whatever culture they are programmed with in their youth. Average people need visionary yet down-to-Earth intellectuals to shows them new ways to think about the world. Yes, even CEOs of Fortune 500 companies, politicians, and big name scientists need visionary intellectuals to show them how to think. Being successful or well-respected does not make you a good thinker. Often just the opposite because the culture most-rewards those who reinforce the status quo, not those who challenge it. The thing is, a Fortune 500 CEO is not thinking deeply about how to think deeply. He's just acting out old thinking routines that got him to where he is, but won't get him higher.</p>
<p>What isn't well understood is that the next level of society doesn't just come automatically through better technology. There needs to be new intellectual architecture put in place because the old intellectual architecture can only take us so far. More technology without an upgraded intellectual architecture is like giving chainsaws to children.</p>
<p>Right now we are living in an era where the old intellectual architecture is starting to strain and buckle under its own weight.</p>
<p>The role of Actualized.org is to build and popularize new intellectual architecture. These teachings are not just here to help you personally master your life but to create new ways of thinking that will enable the next 100-500 years of societal evolution. Which is why I use a lot of political examples nowadays in my teachings. I'm trying to show you that personal development and social development are deeply interconnected so that once you do self-actualize, you will link your self-actualization, awakening, and success to the uplifting of mankind. So your growth, your awakening, your life purpose, and your career/biz will all be integrated. This is going to be more and more necessary in the future. The days of going to a dead-end job and punching the clock are coming to an end. Factory jobs are coming to an end. The jobs of the future will require passion, self-determination, creativity, and consciousness. What do we do when robots take all our menial jobs? We train and develop ourselves to be powerful creatives, artists, visionaries, leaders, and lovers. We develop those things which robots don't have (at least yet): creativity, vision, artistry, intuition, wisdom, consciousness, empathy, humanity, spirit, love. But this cannot happen on auto-pilot. This requires that everyone consciously participate in crafting their life from any early age. And this requires that people be shown how to do this. Someone needs to take them by the hand and lead them through the process. And even beyond that, society needs to build new infrastructure that makes this process easy, natural, and normal — so your peers aren't looking at you like some freak for doing this. Right now these systems haven't been built yet, which is why it's so difficult. Most humans are only used to doing things which mankind has already well-pioneered. Something like going to school is only easy these days because social systems were pioneered for several thousand years. If you had to do school on your own, without social support, less than 1% of people would do it. It would be 100x harder.</p>
<p>The most important thing we need to train our children is how to connect their passion for life with life-long self-education, a career grounded in on a sense of life purpose, personal development, spiritual development, and then also social development. Without these kinds of citizens society is ineffective and dysfunctional as the majority of people are not passionate about their personal lives and therefore disengaged from being of service to others.</p>
<p>Imagine a society in which a majority of citizens are passionate about their careers and their careers are about being of genuine service to others, not just mindless profiteering or widget-making. That is the future, but it will be a rocky transition to get there. Design your life to fit into this mold of the future.</p>
<p>Those billionaires and Fortune 500 CEOs might seem like they are living a life of purpose, but they are not. They are living an unconscious life of chasing success and status, which is not the same as life purpose. Life purpose is how you would do conscious work if success, money, and status were irrelevant.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/please-let-me-rob-you-im-woke</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;Flood The Zone With Shit&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/flood-the-zone-with-shit</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I love how transparent Steve Bannon is about his devilry:</p>
<blockquote><p>"The real opposition is the media. And the way to deal with them is to flood the zone with shit."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Steve Bannon</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/1/16/20991816/impeachment-trial-trump-bannon-misinformation" target="_blank">Vox Article - How Misinformation Overwhelmed Our Democracy</a></p>
<p>In a sense this makes him an ineffective devil because he's too honest about his devilry. Devilry can't survive long in transparency. It has to be opaque.</p>
<p>But anyway, that is precisely how devilry works. It perpetuates falsehood simply by muddying the waters so much that average people cannot tell the difference between truth and falsehood. This is a broader tactic of devils that takes place not only in politics but with religion and spirituality. Many people these days are so sour on religion, spirituality, and anything smacking of the New Age because these important zones have been flooded with shit over the centuries. This makes it very difficult for people to find Truth/God. The zone has been so flooded with shit that most people think that Truth and God a myth. And in such a state, the devil wins. The devil doesn't need a proper victory — in fact he can never get one because devilry is falsehood — but he can squeak out a short-term psuedo-victory by muddying the waters.</p>
<p>Be on the lookout for those in society who make careers out of muddying the waters. Don't become pawns in their game. To have a high-functioning society it's crucial that public figures don't manipulate truth for personal gain.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/flood-the-zone-with-shit</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Gender Real?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/is-gender-real</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Male/female is a duality. And if you've been following along with my videos, you should understand by now that all <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/understanding-duality-part-1" target="_blank">dualities</a> (without exception) are untenable and groundless and must collapse at some point. This is a fundamental principles of reality. But all this sounds so philosophical and abstract that people still cannot wrap their minds around how something as concrete and "physical" as male and female could be a collapsable duality. Aren't males just clearly males and females just clearly females? Of course not! And this has nothing to do with political correctness or LGBTQ rights. This is an existential matter.</p>
<p>Here is the starkest proof:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8S79UN856EE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Ask yourself this existential question: at what precise point did this fish go from female to male? And if a female fish can turn into a male fish, what does that mean for the categories of "male" and "female"? In what sense are they real? What are these categories grounded in?</p>
<p>And before you make a rebuttal such as, "Well, but these fish aren't human so they don't count", remember that fish vs human is also a duality! Which is also ultimately groundless and must collapse:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C6ruIZYddhk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Ask yourself this existential question: at what point does an organism go from being a fish to being human? Do such categories exist outside of your mind?</p>
<p>The above examples are perplexing to people who believe in absolute rigid categories, but they are totally expected to people who understand that all categories are relative dualities which are destined to collapse when stretched far enough.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/is-gender-real</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Corruption Looks Like</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-corruption-looks-like</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Amazing interview, showing how <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/how-corruption-works" target="_blank">corruption</a> happens behind the scenes:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9JKraI_Rh6g?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QUXht__f3Rk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Of course this is exactly as one would expect Trump's influence to be. His massive ego is like the gravity well of Jupiter, pulling in every other ego in the region and corrupting it. That's how corruption spreads itself. It lures in the greedy and the ignorant with promises of quick and easy wealth, power, fame, and sex — all the things an ego craves the most. Trump's Washington hotel is an actual den for the congregation and breeding of devils.</p>
<p>This is <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/what-is-the-devil" target="_blank">how devilry works</a>.</p>
<p>Good work here by CNN. Without this kind of transparent reporting devils would run rampant. Notice how devils can only survive in the shadows. They cannot survive long in the light. Which is why there is such an attack these days on the media. Once a bunch of devils get into power, their first job will be to corrupt every source of light and transparency. Devils must create a shadowy environment in order to roost. That's exactly what Trump has been doing from day one with his "fake news" campaign.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-corruption-looks-like</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>TurboTax Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/turbotax-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/1/21045779/irs-turbotax-free-file-h-r-block-tax-preparation-new-rules" target="_blank">IRS Puts A Stop To TurboTax Corruption</a></p>
<p>The above news story explains how Inuit, maker of the popular tax filing software TurboTax, spent millions of dollars to lobby the US government against easy and free tax filing options. That's is devilry 101. That's how self-bias corrupts all governments.</p>
<p>Intuit is a publicly traded company with a market cap of $69 billion, $2.25 billion cash-on-hand, 8,2000 employees, and the CEO's salary is $21 million per year . Yet they cannot help rigging the government in their favor, regardless of how it hurts average citizens. Because their concern is not what's best for the citizens but what is best for Intuit. Why does the CEO get paid $21 million per year? Precisely because he works night and day to ensure that such devilry passes successfully. But of course he is not conscious of what he is doing. In his mind all of this is justified as normal, necessary, and even good. Because it is good! It's good for his survival which is linked to the survival of the company. You don't earn $21 million per year by being nice. You earn it by being a devil.</p>
<p>Now imagine that this is happening on a massive scale, with thousands of companies rigging the government to increase their profits. Now it's apparent why government is so ineffective and stuck. It's being debased from a thousands sides by a thousand parties.</p>
<p>Our government is like a noblewoman turned cheap whore, getting fucked in every orifice by an eager gaggle of desperate men. But if you stop and ask any one particular man in the gaggle whether there is any problem with this situation, he will say No, because it is normal, all his friends are doing it, the gaggle is 1000 men long, and how else is he supposed to get his needs met? And of course his need is insatiable. You'd think $21 million per year would be enough to be satisfy, but that only whets the appetite. And beside which, even if one of them quit in disgust, another one would eagerly take his place.</p>
<p>This is why getting money out of politics is the #1 most important political reform. And also why it's the most difficult.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/turbotax-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Taking A Break</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/taking-a-break</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I have decided to take a break from releasing videos for a while to rejuvenate my creative juices and work on myself. 7 years of constantly releasing videos with hardly any breaks takes its toll on creativity — which is one of my highest values. Yes, YouTuber burnout is a genuine phenomenon. The ever-present low-grade stress of having to constantly release great and original videos for years on end starts to eat away at the soul and feels creatively stifling — like being a one-trick pony. I have multiple creative projects and research projects which I want to work on besides releasing videos, and since the videos are so labor intensive and constant, this prevents me from working on other things that I'm passionate about, including my own development. For the kind of work that I do there needs to be a delicate balance between outer work and inner work. Outer work is work I do for you — for the world to consume. Inner work is work I do for myself which nobody directly sees, but which shapes the totality of my outer work in the future. So what I'm doing now is shifting priority from outer work to inner work. This means less immediate creative output, but laying a deeper foundation for the future.</p>
<p>I plan to take at least 1 month off, starting from last week.</p>
<p>And I have decided to make this a new yearly habit. From now on, every year I will take at least 1 month off purely for personal time — not for meditation retreats or others rigorous work, but just unplanned personal time. I find this is essential to do if you are highly creative person. You just cannot be at peak creativity 365 days of the year. That's not a good schedule for highly creative people. Counter-intuitively, more becomes less and less becomes more. So for now I'm planning to take the entire month of December off each year, but I may adjust that in the future to some other month or even months, depending on what my psyche calls for.</p>
<p>Fear not, I'll be back with more videos and new insights soon. There are literally 100s of important topics yet to cover. We just have to pace ourselves properly, as this is not a sprint but a marathon.</p>
<p>I will still be somewhat active on the forum, and the rest of the site will still be fully operational, so if you want to buy the book list or the Life Purpose Course, all of that still works.</p>
<p>Thanks for your support and for sticking with me through the highs and lows.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/taking-a-break</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding Africa's Underdevelopment</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-africas-underdevelopment</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Geography plays a huge role in shaping how countries, ethnicities, and cultures develop:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_AQZTW1ua3g?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Check out that channel for more awesome videos about geography. You can't understand the development of mankind without understanding geography. Geography dictates climate, resources, building materials, farming, livestock, tribes, migration, cuisine, culture, language, technology, war, disease, genetics, and more.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/understanding-africas-underdevelopment</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>US Assassinates Top Iranian Leader</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/us-assassinates-top-iranian-leader</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Well, the greatest concern about Trump's presidency — him starting a foolish war — has finally come to fruition.</p>
<p>Imagine if Iran had assassinated the US Vice President while he was traveling in a Canadian airport. That's the equivalent of what happened.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9Z0XjA0tWko?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>An accurate headline in today's morning paper would read: "US Assassinates Top Iranian Leader In Act of War". But you will not see such a headline in the US media because of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/self-bias" target="_blank">Self-Bias</a>. Of course the US will spin this as "self-defense". That's an interesting phrasing since "self-defense" — as in, ego-defense — is what this is really about. The ego always justifies its devilry as self-defense, even when it is aggression. Because the ego's notion of "self-defense" is infinitely elastic and self-biased.</p>
<p>Egotistical, unconscious, and ignorant leaders cannot help themselves start wars. Bush and Trump are cases in point. Dumb and dumber.</p>
<p>The current situation is the direct result of Trump's and the Republicans' eagerness to tear up the Iran nuclear agreement. It was obvious to even an uninformed laymen that reneging on that agreement was a very bad idea. And of course the opposition to that agreement was an act of ego.</p>
<p>It is the duty of conscious citizens to stand up and say, Not in our name! American citizens should not tolerate such devilry from our own. This is what being objective and truthful means in the real world. It is the ability to call out the self-bias and wrong-doing of your own team as soon as it happens, not giving them a pass because they are closer to you. A devil is a devil, even if he sleeps in the bed next to you.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/us-assassinates-top-iranian-leader</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Survival In A Nutshell</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/survival-in-a-nutshell</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I like how this tiny clip shows the whole predicament of survival in a nutshell:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3WySwhj2SwE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>What did this lady want? Love. But look how greedy she became when she didn't get the love she wanted. Then look how the Pope reacted to someone taking his love by force. That's survival on both sides.</p>
<p>This is what parents are doing to children; children are doing to parents; spouses are doing to spouses; businesses are doing to customers; customers are doing to businesses; businesses are doing to businesses; nations are doing to nations.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/survival-in-a-nutshell</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lost - Sunlounger Chill Remix</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/lost-sunlounger-chill-remix</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_bJ7RCFxR88?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>"Look at the peace inside, giving way to the gods of destruction."<br />
"Full of desire. You feel afraid that there's nothing left."<br />
"The ocean is dry. Do you feel hollow?"<br />
"Nowhere to hide. Nothing to swallow."<br />
"When you can't recognize, anything solid."<br />
"Where do you turn, when you can't buy it?"<br />
"What can you believe in now? With no love to follow."<br />
"Now that you have lost yourself, can anything help you now?"</p>
<p>"Just let your fears go. You might find your way back home."<br />
"Let your fears go. You might find that you're not lost."<br />
"Just let your fears go. You might find your way back home."<br />
"Let your fears go. You might find that you're not lost."</p>
<p>"What did you learn? What was it worth?"<br />
"What did you yearn for? Everything's lost now."</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Some guidance for the lowest point in your spiritual journey.<br />
Lose yourself so you may find yourself.<br />
May you find your way back Home.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/lost-sunlounger-chill-remix</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Love, Death, and Robots</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/love-death-and-robots</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the holiday break my brother showed me this series on Netflix called Love, Death, and Robots. It's a collection of 18 short sci-fi stories in animated form. What pleasantly surprised me was the depth and quality of the storytelling.</p>
<p>Three of the episodes caught my attention as having some profound spiritual significance:</p>
<ol>
<li>Beyond The Aquila Rift — the ending is profound in that it shows that truth can be an ugly thing which most people don't have the courage to stomach. Most people don't realize how shocking and radical truth is, which is why it must remain hidden. Before you ask for the truth, make sure you can handle it. Tis a good life lesson.</li>
<li>Zima Blue - the entire arc of Zima-the-artist shows the interconnection between art, spirituality, and truth. Most artists don't realize that what they're really seeking with their art is Spirit. Zima found it, but it cost him his life. And of course his final deconstruction was shocking to everyone watching. Zim's arc is the spiritual path in a nutshell.</li>
<li>The Witness — the ending is a delicious <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/reality-is-a-strange-loop" target="_blank">strange loop</a>. If you're still not clear what a strange loop is, here it is.</li>
</ol>
<p>After you watch these three episodes, my commentary above will start to make sense.</p>
<p>Here's the trailer for the show, although I think the trailer sucks at selling it, so don't judge by the trailer. You must watch to understand.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wUFwunMKa4E?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/love-death-and-robots</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>See Salamander Grow From Single Cell</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/see-salamander-grow-from-single-cell</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Speaking of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/division-vs-unity" target="_blank">Division vs Unity</a>, here is it in the flesh:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SEejivHRIbE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is how Consciousness divides itself.</p>
<p>Can you fathom how amazing this is? How amazing You are?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/see-salamander-grow-from-single-cell</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazing Resonance Experiment</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/amazing-resonance-experiment</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Really cool:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wvJAgrUBF4w?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/amazing-resonance-experiment</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Miracle Awakening</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/miracle-awakening</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/380008679?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/miracle-awakening</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ego-Collapse Awakening</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/ego-collapse-awakening</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/379494071?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/ego-collapse-awakening</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Racial Unity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/racial-unity</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a selfish argument against racism and nationalism: if all the world's races interbreed, humans will literally become more beautiful and sexually attractive. Have you noticed that mix-raced people tend to be more hot?</p>
<p>Here's the proof. These images represent the averaged faces of every major ethnicity. Averaging faces (blending/unifying them) makes them more attractive to the human eye. Now imagine if we did a meta-average of all the ethnicities into one face. So, to put it starkly, it's in your best interest for all races to fuck each other ;)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/average_face_women.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4484" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/average_face_women.jpg" alt="average_face_women" width="615" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/average_faces_men.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4485" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/average_faces_men.jpg" alt="average_faces_men" width="615" /></a></p>
<p>Hint: If you want to have the most beautiful babies possible, have sex with someone who's a different race than you.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/racial-unity</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Zizek On Our Current Political Situation</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/zizek-on-our-current-political-situation</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Great essay by Zizek. He has an excellent nose for sniffing out hidden mechanisms of devilry and bullshit:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qxz4zkO_ce4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Just be careful, his position of materialism, atheism, and anti-mysticism is delusional. He does not know what he's talking about when he speaks of God, consciousness, or love. The rest is good.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/zizek-on-our-current-political-situation</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Dirty Secrets Of Capitalism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-dirty-secrets-of-capitalism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Unlike most billionaires, this billionaire is doing a great job at overcoming his self-bias:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/th3KE_H27bs?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>We need more millionaires and billionaires to speak out against the devilry of neoliberal economics. Unfortunately most of them are so comfy it makes them blind to the systemic rigging. A lot of millionaires and billionaires hold libertarian and capitalist ideologies because that's what serves their survival, and allowed them to rise to the top.</p>
<p>It would be almost impossible for someone who's conscious of the devilry of neoliberalism to run a giant Fortune 500 company like Microsoft, Amazon, Apple, Facebook, Disney, Exxon, Boeing, Walmart, Coca Cola, AT&T, etc. To run such companies requires that management and investors bullshit themselves about how good and fair it all is. All of these companies need to believe that giant monopolies, low taxes, and deregulation are good for society. Without such a positive mythology, management and investors would have an existential and moral crisis.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left;">"It is difficult to get a man to understand something when his salary depends on his not understanding it."</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Upton Sinclair</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-dirty-secrets-of-capitalism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>MLM Cults</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/mlm-cults</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a nice intro to how Multi-Level Marketing cults work. Be sure to avoid these like the plague:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VeDHHt26ibQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>You'll never get rich this way because fundamentally this job generates no creative value. It's a parasitic system that feeds the leeches at the top.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/mlm-cults</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Misunderstanding Love</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/misunderstanding-love</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This short clip epitomizes how <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Stage Blue</a> misunderstands <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-green" target="_blank">Stage Green</a>:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZGuYEDEkIPY?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>I love this clip because it so clearly demonstrates how the ego-mind can literally see love and peace as "evil". That's the essence of devilry: to call love evil and truth falsehood. When a devil sees or hears love, he calls it evil. When a devil sees or hears truth, he calls it falsehood. He does all this unconsciously with an air of smug self-righteousness. And then he actively rallies those in his circle to his distorted perspective, as this allows the distortion to take on the appearance of truth. This is the universal mechanism of devilry. Learn it well because you will see this over and over again throughout your life.</p>
<p>Genuine morality is not a set of man-made rules to follow. Genuine morality is the recognition of Self-Love. It cannot be written down in a book or even taught. The trick with teaching Love is that although it sounds simple, childish, utopian, and airy-fairy, it's actually the most advanced of teachings because it requires of the student a certain level of consciousness and being. To someone at a low level of consciousness, a teaching about Love will seem utopian, unscientific, immoral, and even evil. Which is why someone like Jesus, if he were alive today, would actually be demonized by the right-wing as a communist SJW.</p>
<p>Of course the Beatles did a lot of LSD, so they had direct mystical experiences of Love — which they then sang about. But none of this fits a right-wing rule-based view of morality. Which is of course why LSD and other psychedelics were quickly outlawed in a predominantly stage Blue society (1960s). Psychedelics are the single greatest threat to people like Ben Shapiro (Stage Blue) and what's more, they don't even know it. They just instinctively stay far away from it. See, the ego-mind is so good a self-deception that it can stay far away from things that threaten its worldview without the person even having to consciously understand why. The ego-mind will rationalize it in a way that only entrenches one deeper in one's paradigm, making the self-deception indistinguishable from reality and almost inescapable.</p>
<p>How do you validate Spiral Dynamics? With examples like this. It's remarkable how well Spiral Dynamics explains and predicts such examples. It's like people operate on just a handful of scripts: Blue, Orange, Green << that explains 80% of current human behavior! Amazing, huh?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/misunderstanding-love</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cornel West &amp; Mehdi Hasan Interview</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/cornel-west-mehdi-hasan-interview</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Brilliant questions and answers:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d8KaUS3OUaI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/cornel-west-mehdi-hasan-interview</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Exposing Neo-Liberal Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/exposing-neo-liberal-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Tis a thing of beauty to watch Anand Giridharadas demolish the neo-liberal fantasy.</p>
<p>This is what exposing devilry looks like:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7m2AumufJfw?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h3Kc-vIukTA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is a top-notch example of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-green" target="_blank">Stage Green</a> at its healthiest and most cogent. This is what Jordan Peterson and his fanboys are missing. This is what JP smears as "Cultural Marxism". This is what the right-wing is in denial about. This is what the culture wars are distracting from. This is the real political discussion that is never shown on TV.</p>
<p>Neither nationalism, nor libertarianism, nor technology, nor higher economic growth can solve this problem. We face a new set of collective challenges which require a Stage Green worldview to start to address.</p>
<p>BTW, if you're not in America, you might wonder, "But Leo, how do your American examples help me?" Not so fast! The principles we're studying here in these mostly American examples apply to all countries. If you're in a less developed country then these are the problems you'll face once your country reaches peak Stage Orange like America. And it will happen sooner than you think. Maybe it will take 50 years, but your country will face these same problems, and probably already is. That's what Spiral Dynamics shows us. That's the value of studying structure. Don't get hung up on local details. China, India, Russia, Brazil... they're all gonna have to find solutions to corporatism run amok, gross income inequality, and what is fundamentally plutocracy.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/exposing-neo-liberal-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Former Users Describe Heroin High</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/former-users-describe-heroin-high</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>To be clear, I don't recommend you ever experiment with heroin or opioids because they are super addictive and run counter to our work.</p>
<p>But it's psychologically and metaphysically illuminating to read about why people do heroin:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/kwxkbv/ex-users-describe-the-first-time-they-tried-heroin" target="_blank">Vice.com - Former Users Describe the First Time They Tried Heroin</a></p>
<p>The bottom line is: people do heroin because it brings them closer to God, and they don't know of any other healthy way of getting there. Most of them don't even know that what they're connecting with is God. That's how ignorant the situation is.</p>
<p>God is the greatest high in the world. What do you think monks, mystics, and yogis are chasing? They are heroin addicts minus the heroin.</p>
<p>Once you experience God, no other feeling will satisfy you. And in true going-full-circle fashion, that's how the best thing in the world becomes the worst thing in the world. Heaven becomes hell. So the wise find ways of reaching heaven without the life-shattering side-effects. It takes more work, but it's worth it.</p>
<p>P.S. Psychedelics can take you even closer to God than heroin and are anti-addictive. But they will still leave you with the suffering and heartbreak of losing your connection to God after the trip ends. Of course your connection to God cannot ever truly be lost because you are God. But you will lose awareness of this basic fact, sucked back into the Matrix of ego and social obligation.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/former-users-describe-heroin-high</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Complexity Of Life</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-complexity-of-life</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Biologists are only starting to get an idea of how complex and astounding life truly is:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9euW5iCjKDo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>"I still remember the moment. It's something I will never forget. The hair on my hands just stood up."</p>
<p>Why did the hair on his hands stand up? Because his mind caught a glimpse of Infinite Intelligence. That's God! But he doesn't realize that yet since he's looking at these cells from the materialist paradigm. How much more awesome it becomes when you realize that these cells are occurring within an Infinite Mind — what's more — YOUR Infinite Mind, created by You!</p>
<p>When some spiritual fool tells you life is simple, remember this video. Life is infinitely complex, and the only way it can work at all is because it is managed by an Infinite Intelligence that tracks every single detail with infinite precision, perfectly.</p>
<p>Only a naive human can convince itself that this whole process can be modeled and analyzed by the human mind. No model will ever do it justice. This is just the tip of an infinite iceberg.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-complexity-of-life</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Manufacturing Consent</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/manufacturing-consent</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Noam Chomsky has done some excellent work exposing how the media serves as a self-deception and reality-construction machine for the survival of the status quo and various collective egos.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/34LGPIXvU5M?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tTBWfkE7BXU?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>If you want to learn more, you can read Chomsky's classic book: <a href="https://amzn.to/2DhJeXq" target="_blank">Manufacturing Consent</a>. It's a great lesson in how self-biased American media is. But of course this dynamic isn't only limited to American media. It's all media worldwide. In fact, the less developed the country, the more self-biased and corrupt the media tends to be. America is actually one of the best, compared, say, to Russia, China, or Iran.</p>
<p>The most amazing thing about this entire ideological machine is that the people at the top are not themselves conscious of what they are doing. The people in positions of power most engaged in deceiving the masses are themselves fully self-deceived. Chasing money & profits, as media elites and CEOs like to do, is the chief self-deception.</p>
<p>The key mistake that conspiracy theorists make is that they give those at the top too much credit. They assume those at the top are acting consciously and intelligently, but actually, they are the blind leading the blind. The media executives, the shareholders, the CEOs, the presidents, the VPs, the millionaires, the billionaires, the tech tycoons... they're all very unconscious people. They just happen to be great at manipulating and making money — which must be distinguished from true intelligence and consciousness.</p>
<p>Society is a conspiracy of idiots who are so ignorant they do not understand that they have formed a conspiracy to deceive each other! — a circular firing squad of ignorance. And the conspiracy theorists are some of the biggest idiots of the bunch, feeding the cycle even further by distracting from the root issues. Plot twist: conspiracy theorists are the false flag! This machine of ignorance is so deep and wide-spread that it's almost impossible for any one conscious human to dismantle or change. Small efforts at reform are made around the edges by visionaries and sages, but this takes decades and centuries to be felt. Which is why something like awakening or God cannot be made mainstream. Awakening is the most dangerous thing to this whole machine because Truth cannot be monopolized for profit or power. Which is why awakening is not taught in schools and universities. Of course schools and universities are all part of this machine, since indoctrinating the children is the most important piece of the self-deception.</p>
<p>This is the cleverness and devilry with which the illusion of self is maintained. Quite jaw-dropping when you realize it for what it is. It takes so much energy to maintain this house of cards. And all ultimately because... fear of death, fear of love, fear of God.</p>
<p>Of course it does no good to demonize all this, as that only adds to the problem of ignorance. You must accept all this as what you are and approach the problem with compassion for all involved.</p>
<p>The biggest business in the world is not oil or computers, it's eyeballs. He who controls the most eyeballs controls the world. See my videos: <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/the-deep-problem-of-marketing" target="_blank">The Deep Problem Of Marketing</a> and <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/how-to-escape-wage-slavery" target="_blank">How To Escape Wage Slavery</a>.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/manufacturing-consent</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazon's Corporate Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/amazons-corporate-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a leaked training video that Amazon shows to all of its workers. Pretty gross North Korean -style propaganda.</p>
<p>Keep in mind, the right to unionize is a legally protected right in America.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AQeGBHxIyHw?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>That's some world-class level bullshit.</p>
<p>Next time you order cheap stuff from Amazon don't forget all the suffering caused by your survival.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/amazons-corporate-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Preachers Justifying Private Jets</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/preachers-justifying-private-jets</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Don't underestimate the power and shamelessness of the human mind to justify its own survival to itself:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AdH2DGSXjss?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9LtF34MrsfI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>"We're in <del>soul</del> ego business here."</p>
<p>Seem absurd? Structurally, your mind does exactly the same thing every day. Does this kind of thing outrage and baffle you? That's because you do it yourself! But of course you deny it. You get offended and upset that you might have any structural likeness to the above example. You project your own self-bias onto others as outrage so that you can feel innocent and righteous by comparison.</p>
<p>See how sneaky your devil mind is?</p>
<p>Justification, self-bias, devilry — these are all structural. Don't get distracted by the content of private jets or religion. This has nothing to do with private jets or religion. This is all about survival. You might be the most rational, scientific person in the world, and still you do this kind of self-justifying structurally.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/preachers-justifying-private-jets</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inside The Psyche Of Stage Red</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/inside-the-psyche-of-stage-red</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a candid real-world account of what it's like to work for a Spiral Dynamics Stage Red leader:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/REGdYGVoKTk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The people who work with Trump on his policies have no idea of his level of cognitive development. They assume he is a stage Orange CEO type (like many of them are). But he's far less developed. This is only shocking if you've never studied developmental psychology.</p>
<p>It was obvious before his election that this would be Trump's leadership style.</p>
<p>The problem with a selfish leader is that eventually most of his followers and supports get so hurt and disgusted by his selfishness that they turn on him and start a mutiny out of a need to protect themselves. This is proper, as it is the karma which selfishness creates. There cannot be an extremely selfish general on the battlefield, for example, because eventually even his most loyal troops will be forced to turn on him, because his selfishness will threaten their survival agenda.</p>
<p>A leader who is more selfish than his followers cannot last. Sooner or later they will eat him alive. Just like there is a problem with leading from too high on the Spiral, there is a problem with leading from too low on the Spiral. Successful leadership requires that the leader be one or two levels above his followers. Otherwise things become unsustainable. Trump is less cognitively, morally, and spiritually developed than most of his cabinet. If this happened on a ship, they'd throw the captain overboard.</p>
<p>The funny thing about selfishness is, people are too selfish to tolerate a selfish leader for long. Sharks eat their own kind. A leader needs to be someone a follower can look up to and aspire to be like. Otherwise, why follow him? Who wants to follow someone who is less developed than they are? Such situations breed resentment and discontent since they are fundamentally backwards. The more capable resent having to follow the less capable. The more moral resent having to follow the less moral.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/inside-the-psyche-of-stage-red</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I Always Look Orange</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/i-always-look-orange</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The Trump admin is <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/energy-environment/459884-trump-administration-rolls-back-obama-era-lightbulb-rules" target="_blank">rolling back new Obama-era light bulb efficiency standards</a>, which is sad enough by itself, but Trump's justification for it is just such a classic example of egotism:</p>
<blockquote><p>"Number one, to me, most importantly, the light's no good. I always look orange. And so do you."</p></blockquote>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/K_iFi1qH8Cg?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>It's little gems like this that tie a bow on all our work about ego and self-bias.</p>
<p>FYI, <a href="https://amzn.to/33jgb0H" target="_blank">CFL bulbs</a> are very toxic when shattered (don't buy those), but the <a href="https://amzn.to/34uhGcM" target="_blank">new LED bulbs</a> are not toxic and they produce high quality light at any color temperature you want. Personally, I upgraded all the incandescent bulbs in my apartment to LED bulbs 3 years ago and have been very happy with them. The new LED bulbs have a great quality of light and they last for 5-10 years! I have not replaced a light bulb in 3 years. It's so convenient. It's a revolution in lighting. If you haven't upgraded to LED, you're missing out. They are 5x more energy-efficient than incandescent bulbs, produce zero heat, and only only cost about $3-$10 each. Every building in the world should be using LEDs. I like the 2700K color temperature best. It gives off a warm homey yellow glow, almost the same as the classic incandescent bulbs. Or if you prefer white light, go for the 5000K color temp. There's no need to buy incandescents ever again.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/i-always-look-orange</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chemical Corruption</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/chemical-corruption</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>An eye-opening look into how corrupt chemical companies can be:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wsoqJFQT3Kk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>BTW, if you cook your food on those black, cheap, Teflon non-stick frying pans, I recommended ditching all of them and buying yourself a set of high quality stainless steel pans without any kind of chemical coatings. For example, Telfon is so poisonous to birds that if you roast some nuts to feed your pet parrot, the parrot will die from eating them. Now imagine what those kinds of chemicals are doing to your body and brain.</p>
<p>If the future I will release some videos about how to detox heavy metals and chemicals from your body and brain. This is actually a crucial elements of improving your life. If your brain is filled with toxic chemicals like mercury, lead, arsenic, and others like Telfon, you will not be able to self-actualize properly. This can seriously affect your health and mental function, including your ability to meditate, concentrate, and do consciousness work.</p>
<p>Chemical toxicity is the leading cause of things like auto-immune diseases, thyroid diseases, cancers, ADD, autism, crime, and overall societal dysfunction. Most people have no idea how bad it is. You could be suffering from it and have no idea. The good news is, there exist effective methods for detoxing this stuff and healing yourself.</p>
<p>These days you have to be very careful about what you put in your body and keep in your household. You never know when you're consuming something filled with toxic chemicals. It could be your make up, shampoo, soap, mouthwash, toothpaste, paper towels, drinking water, coffee, tea, food packaging, laundry detergent, carpet, dental fillings, etc. So watch out. Educate yourself and be a mindful shopper. If you have kids, be careful what you feed and wash them with. Toxic chemicals in their brain will affect their ability to do well in do well in school, socialize, and self-actualize.</p>
<p>In a nutshell: clean up your household and pay a bit extra for more natural products which contain less chemicals. The cheaper things are, the more toxic chemicals they usually contain.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/chemical-corruption</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Profound Quotes #016</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-016</link>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"An aimless life is always a troubled life. Every individual should have an aim. But do not forget that the quality of your aim will depend the quality of your life. Your aim should be high and wide, generous and disinterested; this will make your life precious to yourself and to others. Whatever your ideal, it cannot be perfectly realized unless you have realized perfection in yourself."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- Sri Aurobindo</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/profound-quotes-016</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Internal Workings Of CNN</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/internal-workings-of-cnn</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Speaking of the media, here's an illuminating look into the inner workings of CNN:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CJASlSNRxv8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>I think Jeff Zucker is an intelligent and decent guy, but he does not understand the depth of the problem of what "reporting the truth" means. Truth is much more tricky than merely fact-checking some wrong information, because who gets to say what counts as valid fact-checking? You can't just assume that "facts" exist! What if "facts" are really how your mind constructs reality? Who's construction should we trust? Yours? Mine? Jeff Zucker's? A billionaire's? An atheist's? A Muslim's? A Christian's? A Buddhist's? A scientist's? A white person's? A black person's? etc. What if each person has their own "facts"? What do you do then?</p>
<p>I'd like you to notice that everything talked about in the above video is really an issue of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Epistemology" target="_blank">epistemology</a> (human knowledge). The question of "What is true?" is an epistemic question. Notice that this question is not merely philosophical, it has serious real-world consequences. How do you maintain a high quality society when people cannot agree with each other's perspectives on truth, or when some segments of society have really warped versions of truth? How do we deal with that as a society? How does CNN deal with it? How does Facebook deal with it? How does Google deal with it? How do you deal with it? How do your parents deal with it? What if the majority of the population believe in falsehood? How do you go about correcting that when they believe it's a fact?</p>
<p>Notice how challenging and deep this issue is. This is not merely a Trump problem. Epistemology has been a root problem for mankind since the dawn of civilization. We are always arguing about what is true, what is reasonable, what is biased, what is opinion, what is fact, and what is the proper interpretation of things. Have you wondered about why this is? What causes this? You'd think that if reality was an objective fact, we'd all agree on it by now. You'd think that if reality was an objective fact it would be impossible to mislead people about it. Yet human history shows the opposite. Masses of people are mislead all the time. How can this be? And can you be sure you aren't one of those who's misled? After all, if people are easy to mislead, you are person, therefore you must be easy to mislead.</p>
<p>Notice that before one can answer the question of the proper way to act, or make any proper plans, one must first answer the question of What is true? If your perspective of reality is so distorted that you see the world upside-down, your plans and actions will also be upside-down, doubling down on the problem. The solution to any serious problem is, first and foremost, to see the problem with undistorted perception. In many cases taking that first step is enough to resolve the problem. But most people want to jump straight into action, ignoring the first step by dismissing it as "mere philosophy" or "theory". But what good is pressing the accelerator pedal when you haven't first figured out which direction is True North? Undistorted perception is NOT "just theory".</p>
<p>Life's most important problems can only be solved by a shift in perspective & understanding. In such cases, there's something deep you're not conscious of about the problem which makes it manifest over and over again, and it will not stop until you see through to the root of it by properly using your mind.</p>
<p>Most problems are the result of the improper use of one's mind. Think about that.</p>
<p>People who casually blame CNN, The New York Times, "main stream media", "Jewish media", Hollywood elites, Silicon Valley, Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, and yes, even Fox News, do not understand the depth of the epistemic problem. The problem of disseminating "truth" is the most challenging problem that mankind has ever faced. We still haven't figured out how to do in over 10,000 years of trying. Schools, universities, parents, government, the media, science, religion, and every spiritual school all face this fundamental problem. Devils will ALWAYS corrupt the purest sources of truth because falsehood is necessary for survival. Not understanding this triples the problem.</p>
<p>When you understand the depth of what I'm saying here you will realize that epistemology is the most important topic that mankind can study, research, or teach. Yet precisely because this is so, it is not studied or taught almost at all. Devils are not interested in epistemology. It doesn't suite their schemes. So our problem then becomes: how do you teach 7 billion devils proper epistemology when their lives hinge on them not learning it? This problem is more challenging and more important to solve than the problem of building a colony on Mars. Yet it gets no attention and no funding.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/internal-workings-of-cnn</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why The Media Is Corrupt</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-the-media-is-corrupt</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/368190025?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-the-media-is-corrupt</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spirituality &amp; Politics</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/spirituality-politics</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Excellent discussion of what I call <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/conscious-politics-part-1" target="_blank">Conscious Politics</a>:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5mP38NGImsc?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/spirituality-politics</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wolf PAC Anti-Corruption Speech</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/wolf-pac-anti-corruption-speech</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Perfect timing!</p>
<p>On the day I release my How Corruption Works video, this video gets released:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DyXspSJITpY?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is the #1 most important political issue. Get all money out of politics NOW!</p>
<p>If you're not an American, your country probably has a similar problem, and probably worse.</p>
<p>Cenk is a great example of visionary leadership and life purpose. When you see examples of visionary leadership, take notice and study how it works. What are the principles of visionary leadership?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/wolf-pac-anti-corruption-speech</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Killer Strange Loop</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/killer-strange-loop</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aX_vB4sYmgE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/killer-strange-loop</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Real Leadership Looks Like</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-real-leadership-looks-like</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>This man needs to be elected President so he can LEAD.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3ZhkKATtqtU?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/V7wlnI4Koco?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is conscious politics in the flesh!</p>
<p>He has the strongest, most conscious, most loving vision for the next stage of America's evolution and he has the experience and balls to actualize it. Don't take such a rare leader for granted. After he's gone, there won't be another like him for a generation. He is a leader 40 years ahead of his time. Within 50 years, all of his plans will become the taken-for-granted norm regardless of whether he wins the Presidency or not.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-real-leadership-looks-like</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Infinite Life</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-life</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Check out this wonderful YT channel called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBbnbBWJtwsf0jLGUwX5Q3g/" target="_blank">Journey To The Microcosmos</a>. They feature videos on microscopic life. Notice the complexity and intelligence of even microscopic organisms.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OmoL8LlQwWQ?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kux1j1ccsgg?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>There's more:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PZoaKzEXzi8" target="_blank">Stentors</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U3PLUeD_JAg" target="_blank">Rotifers</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Try to imagine how unaware of the larger cosmos these little lifeforms are. Now imagine that you as a human are as unaware of a higher reality as these little guys are of human reality. This gives you a proper sense of how limited your consciousness is and how much more you have to become conscious of.</p>
<p>Your body is a super-organism composed of billions of tiny individuated organisms all working together perfectly to create the larger unity that is the human you. Yet none of those organisms are aware of the larger unity they create. Likewise, humans have no idea of the larger unity they create. And so it goes to infinity. Such is the intelligence of God's design. The intelligence of it is infinite.</p>
<p>Consciousness is alive at all scales, from infinitely small to infinitely large. In fact there is no such thing as small and large because the scale extends infinitely far in all directions and all dimensions. There is no difference in scale between a human, a moss piglet, and the Milky Way galaxy.</p>
<p>You are not truly awake until you are conscious of how intelligent consciousness is at all scales — of how every scale dovetails perfectly into higher and higher unities which extend upward to infinity. This is the body/mind of God, dreaming an infinite number of dreams and interweaving them together seamlessly into one Grand Unity. A cradle for infinite life. A fractal of all possible lifeforms, branching out forever — your human self is one tip of one branch.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-life</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Is Fascism?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-is-fascism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a good intro to the psychology of fascism which most people do not understand:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IMpFcUXq2_w?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The funny thing about fascism is, fascism can only flourish when people are ignorant about what fascism is and therefore blind to their own participation in it.</p>
<p>In other words, a fascist does not understand he's a fascist. A fascist thinks he's a patriot. Unfortunately this stuff is not taught well in schools. Schools do not teach our citizens how easy it is to get sucked into fascist ideology, instead it demonizes Nazis, which makes people complacent.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-is-fascism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Big Picture Of Global Politics</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-big-picture-of-global-politics</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/364396211?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-big-picture-of-global-politics</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Trump Presidency In A Nutshell</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-trump-presidency-in-a-nutshell</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's presidency explained in 39 seconds:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v2XtkXIRCVg?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-trump-presidency-in-a-nutshell</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Actualized Launches On Patreon</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/actualized-launches-on-patreon</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Actualized.og has launched on Patreon.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YYoNpU9rY_k?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>If you'd like to support my work, <a href="https://www.patreon.com/actualized" target="_blank">click here</a>. $5/mo is the recommended donation.</p>
<p>Thanks for your support.</p>
<p>If you can't afford it, don't worry about it.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/actualized-launches-on-patreon</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Is Neo-Liberalism?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-is-neo-liberalism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A great introductory video:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/myH3gg5o0t0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>There is also:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EkBpqLWFNg4" target="_blank">Part 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zsgwVz0D6rI" target="_blank">Part 3</a> (not as good as parts 1 & 2)</li>
</ul>
<p>The most tricky ideologies are those which aren't seen as ideologies at all. How can you begin to let go of a thing you're not even aware you're holding?</p>
<p>It's not that Neo-Liberalism is bad per se, it's that it is starting to show its limits and must evolve into some higher, better system. Every system must evolve to accommodate higher consciousness and love, or die. And actually, death is nothing other than evolution. The next 100 years for America and much of the developed world will be about finding the next evolutionary step beyond Neo-Liberalism. What that is we don't exactly know. It won't just be old-school socialism. It will be something else. Perhaps a strange hybrid system. Like all technological advances, we'll have to find it through trail and error. That trail and error will manifest as social turbulence, which we've been seeing more and more of lately. As 3rd world countries start to reach parity with the 1st world countries, as the world becomes more global and equalized, there will be a lot of turbulence because old systems will have to dissolve while millions of people cling to them.</p>
<p>We are like a snake just beginning to shed its skin.</p>
<p>But fear not! This world circumstance also presents many exciting opportunities. What will be your role in helping mankind evolve into the 21st century? Contemplate that. Don't just be a passive leaf blown by the wind. Decide to be an active participant in this process of evolution. Decide what role you want to play, or someone else will decide it for you. Also decide to be on the right side of history, which is always the side which seeks to expand consciousness and love to more living beings.</p>
<p>In this sense your job in life is very simple: to decide in which specific ways you want to manifest your love.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/what-is-neo-liberalism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Buddhism StackExchange</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/buddhism-stackexchange</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Funny to find that there's a StackExchange about Buddhism. Maybe some of you will find it useful.</p>
<p><a href="https://buddhism.stackexchange.com/questions?tab=Votes" target="_blank">Buddhism StackExchange</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/buddhism-stackexchange</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fundamentally Misunderstanding Religion</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/fundamentally-misunderstanding-religion</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I'm a big fan of Noam Chomsky's political analysis, but when it comes to his thinking about metaphysics and religion the following video shows just how crude it is:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aZ51k8EiKh0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is one of the world's greatest scientists, yet he's clueless about metaphysics and spirituality.</p>
<p>Here Chomsky is basically parroting the standard paradigm of scientific materialism / realism, which fundamentally misunderstands why religion exists.</p>
<p>The source of religion is NOT wishful thinking nor superstition, as many scientists believe. The irony is that holding such a view is deeply unscientific. Such a belief can only be held by people who have never engaged in serious spiritual practice or metaphysical inquiry.</p>
<p>Ignorance like this is unfortunately common among some of our greatest scientists. And that is because they do not make a serious study of epistemology, metaphysics, or spirituality. And the reason they don't is because their belief that spirituality is bullshit is an example of confirmation bias. If you believe that spirituality is bullshit, you will never do the spiritual practice required to discover that it's not bullshit. So from your POV it will always appear as though there is no evidence that spirituality isn't bullshit. Because your fundamental premise — that reality must be material and non-mystical — is wrong. Yet you are not openminded or intellectually curious enough to question it.</p>
<p>All of that is just an example of terrible epistemology and sloppy science. If you are a serious scientist you understand that you cannot pre-judge the results of an experiment before running it. But why then do you pre-judge spirituality and metaphysics before practicing it? Can you see your own hypocrisy here? This is no different than refusing to look into a telescope to see if Jupiter is a real planet because you have already decided that Jupiter isn't real, therefore it would be a waste of time to look. It's viciously circular logic. This vicious circularity isn't just a bug, it's feature. Such circularity is necessary to create a paradigm lock, which is necessary to construct a worldview, which is ultimately necessary for your mind to construct "reality". There is no "reality" without circular logic. Circular logic is how you construct the "physical world"! Ta-da!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/fundamentally-misunderstanding-religion</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Strange-Loopy Rollercoasters</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/strange-loopy-rollercoasters</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a fun example of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/reality-is-a-strange-loop" target="_blank">strange loops</a> from the Rollercoaster Tycoon game:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EbjqWThzXME?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>See, I told you this stuff has real-world consequences.</p>
<p>Strange loops are fundamental to the structure of reality.</p>
<p>If you're gonna be doing lots of psychedelics, you better have a solid theoretical understanding of what strange loops are because your mind will encounter some hairy ones and they will mindfuck you.</p>
<p>So when one day you realize that you crawled out of your own vagina — remember, I told you so ;)</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/strange-loopy-rollercoasters</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Projection Projecting Projection</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/projection-projecting-projection</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The trickeries of the mind never cease to amaze. Case in point, this article by David Kupelian:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.wnd.com/2019/01/democrats-and-the-dark-art-of-projection/" target="_blank">Democrats And The Dark Art Of Projection</a></p>
<p>Which is a master class in how to project one's own projections onto others by accusing them of projection! The boldness of it is impressive.</p>
<p>In this article a <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">stage Blue</a> worldview is projecting it's limited cognitive, moral, and spiritual development onto a <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-green" target="_blank">stage Green</a> worldview, thereby seeing Green as lower than Blue — which is precisely backwards. Green appears to be lower than Blue when seen from Blue's limited POV. But since Blue doesn't acknowledge that POVs are relative, Blue isn't aware of itself as a POV, thereby confusing itself with truth. A big part of what it means to be at stage Blue is that you cannot see your POV as just one POV among many others. If you were conscious of that, you'd grow out of Blue.</p>
<p>Notice that the reason this can happen is precisely because all points of view are relative, so there is no baseline to ground any point of view. So if you imagine that your opponents are projecting, they are! — according to your projection, which you imagine you are not doing. If you imagine you aren't projecting, that's enough to make it seem like you're not projecting. But of course all points of view are imaginary to begin with. Which is precisely what projection is trying to deny: "No, I'm not making stuff up, I'm just stating the truth while you're making stuff up!" << Yeah, that's something you're making up! "No I'm not! You are!" << You made that up too!</p>
<p>The #1 rule of projection is: the more you project, the more you accuse others of projecting, the more you deny your own projections.</p>
<p>To be really effective at projection you must attack the person you're projecting upon for projecting onto you before they've even made that accusation. By accusing them first, you deny them the ability to call you out for your projection. This is classic, classic gas-lighting.</p>
<p>So, for example, if you're cheating on your spouse, you must accuse your spouse of cheating on you before he/she accuses you. This makes it much harder for him/her to accuse you, even though you're the one who's cheating. You'd think that the cheater wouldn't be so obnoxious as to accuse the person he's cheating on of cheating on him (only a shameless asshole would do that), but its precisely because you think he wouldn't do it that he does do it! Because he can use your expectations of decency to cloak the truth from you. That's devilry 101. Devilry is all about finding bold ways of presenting falsehood as truth and truth as falsehood.</p>
<p>Projection is one of the trickiest mechanisms of self-deception. A <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Spiral Dynamics stage Blue</a> mind especially tends not to notice its own projections.</p>
<p>Do liberals engage in projection? Of course. Most people do. But conservatives engage in it far more. And conservatives are much more likely to deny that they are projecting. Part of what it means to be more cognitively and spiritually developed on the Spiral is that higher stages are more aware when they are projecting while lower stages are totally in denial about it. It takes a lot of consciousness work to escape projection entirely. 99.9% of people cannot escape projection because they simply haven't done enough serious self-reflection. Transcending projection requires a profound understanding of how <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/self-bias" target="_blank">Self-Bias</a> works, which again, most people are in denial about.</p>
<p>We'll talk more about projection in a future video since it's such an important topic.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/projection-projecting-projection</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>This Work Is Not About Belief</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/this-work-is-not-about-belief</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>All of my teachings are worthless unless you validate them in your direct experience. This stuff is far too profound to be heard or believed. Belief in what I say is a great obstacle to this work. You will spend years believing me only to realize that you made a big mistake. Yet at the same time, actively disbelieving me — trying to debunk me or debate me — is an even greater mistake. The correct method is to listen to what I say, consider it as an advanced possibility, and do the work to validate this possibility and feel it as your living reality. This work is about transforming your experience of reality.</p>
<p>I have no desire to make you believe in God or my teachings. What you believe is such a shallow level that it is irrelevant as far as this work goes. What matters is what you're conscious of, what state of consciousness you're in, and what the meta, cognitive structures of your mind are. This work is not about the contents of your mind. This work is structural. Think of this difference as the difference between apps vs the OS or BIOS on a computer. In our work here, we're not interested in changing the apps of the human mind, we're interested in changing the OS & even the BIOS. This work is meta work. This work is experiential. This work is about changing what reality is for you. You don't even know what that means yet. It will take you years of work just to appreciate what was just said. And that's as it must be. You can't know what you're missing until years of trial and error.</p>
<p>It would speed things along greatly for you to realize that we are not interested in getting you to believe things here. Anything you believe is far too shallow to help you. Belief is like a veil of fakery which obscures the doing of the real work. So be careful not to get tricked into thinking you are doing the work when you are merely rearranging your beliefs. The real work requires hours upon hours of precise mindfulness and accurate self-observation. Precision and accuracy in this work is important.</p>
<p>Towards this end it would help you greatly to distinguish between what is a belief, and what is not. Spend some time observing in your direct experience what is a belief, and what is not. Get really clear about this without getting caught up in the trap of judging whether a belief is true or false. What's more important than whether a belief is true or false is that you are conscious that it is a belief regardless. For example, "The Earth is round" is a belief regardless of whether its "true". Just because a belief is "true" does not mean it isn't problematic or doesn't distort your experience of reality. In this sense, scientific beliefs can be more problematic than religious ones because scientific beliefs are not usually acknowledged to be beliefs, or problematic — yet they are both.</p>
<p>Notice the distinct difference between believing a thing and direct experience. Notice that experience does not care what you believe. Although of course your beliefs greatly distort and color your experience.</p>
<p>And even though I call all this "work", you must find a way to do it so that you enjoy the process, rather than making it some chore that you must do. You will never be successful in this work as long as it feels like a chore. You must find a way to connect it with your passion for life. It must become an organic part of your life.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/this-work-is-not-about-belief</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>This Is Love</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/this-is-love</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zTLPjgqjLVA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>People often associate Love with happiness and sweetness. But they overlook the brutality of real Love.</p>
<p>You are never going to understand Love at an existential level until you confront Love at is rawest form, as shown above. Don't mistake Love for something that pleases your ego.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/this-is-love</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Enron Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/enron-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Another textbook example of devilry:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e5qC1YGRMKI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This sort of stuff happens on Wall Street every day. Ordinary people don't understand how much white collar crime goes on in America (and all over the world).</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/enron-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Theranos Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/theranos-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I just love finding juicy examples of devilry like this because it's so illustrative of how devilry works:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3CccfnRpPtM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/theranos-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Infinite Intelligence Communication #001</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-intelligence-communication-001</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I have discovered a powerful new chemical which allowed me to have a direct communication with Infinite Intelligence.</p>
<p>Download the transcript below:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/infinite-intelligence-001.docx" target="_blank">Infinite Intelligence Communication #001</a></p>
<p>Warning: radical openmindedness required.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/infinite-intelligence-communication-001</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stage Orange Corrupting Video Games</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/stage-orange-corrupting-video-games</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you're an avid gamer you've probably noticed the corruption which has infected the video game industry over the last 10 years: micro-transactions, loot boxes, gambling, season passes, games-as-service, bullshit limited editions, pre-mature bug-ridden releases, and other scammy tactics. Well, that's the epitome of stage Orange.</p>
<p>Here's but one perfect example:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/g-BuUqsd71w?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>As a gamer, make a distinction between Stage Orange vs Stage Green games. Stage Green games are more about heart and artistry than profits and milking gamers.</p>
<p>I love this example because it shows you how down-to-Earth and relevant Spiral Dynamics is.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/stage-orange-corrupting-video-games</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microdosing Research</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/microdosing-research</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6AfFM8pfy4s?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/microdosing-research</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>My Critique Of Zizek's Critique Of Buddhism</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/my-critique-of-zizeks-critique-of-buddhism</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Let's do a little critical philosophy. First, watch Slavoj Zizek's video critique of Buddhism. Then watch my point-by-point rebuttal. It's fun and you will gain some valuable insight doing this.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IlCkLqz20W8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/355488809?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>P.S. I am not a Buddhist and I have my own critiques of Buddhism which I didn't go into here.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/my-critique-of-zizeks-critique-of-buddhism</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Psilocybin &amp; Personality Change</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/psilocybin-and-personality-change</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I found this video insightful. According to this research, psychedelics are one of the only and the most powerful tools for personality change.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9kSoka5iSi4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Of course this is not limited to psilocybin. All psychedelics lead to personality change. Especially the most powerful ones like 5-MeO-DMT, DPT, and N,N-DMT.</p>
<p>If you want serious personality change what you need is to not just a psychedelic trip, but specifically you need a psychedelic breakthrough. A breakthrough is not an ordinary trip. A breakthrough means that life as you knew it is over. You have gone beyond human life, beyond physical reality, beyond science, beyond religion, beyond memory, beyond language, beyond all teachings, beyond your birth. You have entered the realm of the impossible & the insane. Your entire paradigm of reality has been shattered to the point where you cannot even remember what the old paradigm was. You have escaped the labyrinth of your own mind. You have broken reality. You have left The Matrix. It is the most significant event in your life.</p>
<p>Don't worry, you'll know it once you're there.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/psilocybin-and-personality-change</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rethinking Human History</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/rethinking-human-history</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/354866618?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/rethinking-human-history</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Liberia: Land Of True Freedom</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/liberia-land-of-true-freedom</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A forum member (Ero) shared this video on our forum and I thought it was important share it with you all.</p>
<p>Most people today simply have no appreciation of what survival is like without a decent government. The following is what you get without government, courts, laws, police, regulations, infrastructure, roads, sewers, education, public health care, welfare, etc. This is the true "free market". This is what real freedom looks like. But are you sure you want it?:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZRuSS0iiFyo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Only when you appreciate the above do you understand why government is so crucial. And you see why consciousness cannot be raised en mass without high quality government & infrastructure. This romantic idea that you can just go be a monk somewhere in a cave is a childish fantasy. Reality is far more complex than that. Living in caves doesn't scale across thousands of people. If even only 1% of the population decided to live as monks in caves, there would be such a cave shortage that monks would be killing each other in the night to secure their caves such that the piles of corpses and garbage would rise so high as to block the sun.</p>
<p>The above is Spiral Dynamics stage Purple & Red at its unhealthiest.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/liberia-land-of-true-freedom</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Are My Videos So Long?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-are-my-videos-so-long</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/354368822?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-are-my-videos-so-long</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introducing Slavoj Zizek</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/introducing-slavoj-zizek</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I disagree with him on some fundamental points — he certainly doesn't understand nonduality, Buddhism, Love, or Spiral Dynamics — but he's an interesting and complex thinker that offers some serious good food for thought on political issues and collective human nature.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e2O6f2R9PZI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>He's the entertaining and intellectually-stimulating kind of neurotic ;) You can find a bunch of his videos on YouTube just by searching his name. He makes some very good structural critiques of capitalism. He has a pretty good grasp of the devilry behind ideology. By studying his videos you can deepen your understanding of ideology. Which is a topic I talk about all the time, even if I don't always call it that.</p>
<p>I admire the authenticity of his neuroticism.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/introducing-slavoj-zizek</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aliens Confirmed</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/aliens-confirmed</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9D0eyl7-XQA?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/aliens-confirmed</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How To Test For Self-Bias</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-to-test-for-self-bias</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Some additional points to pair with my <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/self-bias" target="_blank">Self-Bias</a> video.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/353704681?title=0&byline=0&portrait=0" width="615" height="345" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-to-test-for-self-bias</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Harrison Ford On Nature</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/harrison-ford-on-nature</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>"Nature doesn't need people, people need nature."</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WdSmnlVC_yk?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The world needs your conscious engagement. What are you waiting for?</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/harrison-ford-on-nature</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Fyre Festival Fiasco</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-fyre-festival-fiasco</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's an amazing Netflix documentary about the infamous failed Fyre Festival. Some good lessons to learn here about con-artistry and how the human mind works. This is what late-stage capitalism looks like:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uZ0KNVU2fV0?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>How fitting that their logo was a solid block of Orange.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-fyre-festival-fiasco</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Amazing Cornel West</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-amazing-cornel-west</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Cornel West is fucking amazing! One of the greatest orators of our time. Spiritually advanced too. He gives Christianity and academia a good name.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gAYLKvUeWNo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Notice his understanding of love and his expanded circle of concern. This is a marker of high moral development: a love that extends to all beings. An abundant generosity which does not demonize others.</p>
<p>Notice also his boldness. He is not "neutral" to both sides. He calls devilry out by its name. Because true love is a radical thing. It rattles the status quo. It speaks truth to power.</p>
<p>If Jesus was alive today, his politics would probably look like those of Cornel West.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-amazing-cornel-west</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The War On Government</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-war-on-government</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Sadly it's trendy today for young people to feel like government does nothing for them. This kind of nihilistic, cynical apathy is deeply problematic because it plays right into the hands of those who rig the system.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eozs2ZmqYmM?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-war-on-government</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Plutocracy Doesn't Work</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-plutocracy-doesnt-work</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q2gO4DKVpa8?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/why-plutocracy-doesnt-work</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Trust The Force</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/trust-the-force</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>At some point in your spiritual journey you will reach a point where you must switch off your targeting computer — let go and trust your highest wisdom and intuition.</p>
<p>This scene captures it perfectly. George Lucas had an amazing ability to convey spiritual concepts:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zR7CeC-rqiE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>That is what you must do to master life.</p>
<p>This can be scary for many rationalists, materialists, and skeptics to do because in their paradigm a thing isn't real unless it is "hard" quantifiable. Anything short of that is dismissed as wishful thinking, "faith", sentimentality, or pseudoscience. The only problem with that is, Truth and Consciousness are infinite, so they are not quantifiable. To quantify it would be to limit it. To make it "hard" would be to weaken it. This is what a lot of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-orange" target="_blank">Stage Orange</a> conventional thinkers don't understand. The deepest aspects of life are not quantifiable in principle. Why would you assume they could be?</p>
<blockquote><p>"Not everything that counts can be counted, and not everything that can be counted counts."</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: right;">-- A sign supposedly hanging in Einstein's office at Princeton</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/trust-the-force</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Health Insurance Devilry</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/health-insurance-devilry</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In this video a former health insurance executive admits to being a devil, falsifying the debate on universal healthcare to maximize profits. Now he has seen the light and is working to redeem himself:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/djD-OeIJ2G4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>A devil who realizes his devilry becomes a vehicle for Love. Devilry ends through consciousness, and no other way, because devilry is nothing but lack of consciousness. To defeat darkness all you must do is turn on the lights.</p>
<p>What you must understand about corporate executives is that they — like all devils — do not understand that they are devils. They are unconscious survival machines.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;">"Forgiven them father, for they know not what they do."</p>
</blockquote>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/health-insurance-devilry</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Wise Patriot, Round Two</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-wise-patriot-round-two</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I love this guy's down to Earth political analysis:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gUxQY0xHEFY?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>This is a grounded example of stage Green politics. Stage Green is not all crazy college feminist protestors as you sometimes see portrayed by right-wing YouTube or Jordan Peterson and his ilk.</p>
<p>There are serious, practical, reasonable, and masculine stage Green thinkers. As you would expect, since healthy stage Green doesn't negate stage Orange but transcends AND includes it. Healthy Green is built on a foundation of healthy Orange. What Green adds to Orange is empathy & a recognition of the importance of collective issues. While Orange believes all problems in society can be resolved through individualism and personal success, Green understands that this is necessary but insufficient. Collective responsibility is just as important. Green contrasts sharply with Blue in that it is able to appreciate the value of diversity & multiculturalism in a way that Blue is totally blind to. Green can look through the eyes of different cultures while Blue cannot. Green's masculinity is also more grounded, more comfortable with the feminine, whereas stage Blue & Orange masculinity tends to be a juvenile bravado which struggles to appreciate the feminine beyond child rearing and personal sexual gratification.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-wise-patriot-round-two</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Knock Down The House</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/knock-down-the-house</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A great documentary which gives you an inside look at how American politics works:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_wGZc8ZjFY4?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>It's available on Netflix. I highly recommend watching it if you're interested in Conscious Politics.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/knock-down-the-house</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Life In Venezuela</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/life-in-venezuela</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>An eye-opening look into Venezuela's largest slum by an independent Youtuber:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jN5LZR4ejkg?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IYVkFcWqcIo?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Note: Venezuela is not an example of the evils of socialism. It's an example of a grossly underdeveloped country. This is a distinction folks commonly fail to make. Socialism cannot work in an underdeveloped country because survival needs are simply too pressing so selfishness and corruption run rampant. Stage Red/Blue countries are not developed enough to sustain socialist ideals. Which is why socialism failed in places like the Soviet Union and North Korea but aspects of it have succeeded in Northern Europe. A totalitarian state which adopts a socialist veneer is still structurally a totalitarian state. The content of the ideology is irrelevant because what runs the show is the structure, which in this case is totalitarian. The reason aspects of socialism have succeeded in Northern Europe is because those states evolved way beyond totalitarianism before they started toying around with socialism.</p>
<p>Not that I consider myself a socialist. Just pointing out a common mistake I see in politics. People routinely misunderstand the causes of Venezuela's situation. Their problem is developmental and infrastructural, not ideological. Corruption is a massive problem which has choked up their entire system.</p>
<p>It's the same problem as a criminal trying to act like a spiritual man of God. It doesn't work because it's just a veneer. Structurally he's still a selfish, egotistical criminal. No amount godly language or godly ideals will change that. To embody spirituality he'd have to first outgrow his criminality. Likewise, adopting a socialist ideology in a totalitarian state only serves as an Orwellian disguise. In theory the state is for the people, but in practice it's every man for himself, looting as much wealth under the table as possible while maintaining the facade of selflessness.</p>
<p>So the lesson of the 20th century is not that socialism is evil but that socialism should not be adopted by underdeveloped countries at Stage Blue or below because they cannot sustain it. Socialism would only be possible at Stage Green or above. But even then, I still have critiques of socialism and I don't support its blanket adoption. Aspects of it need to be cherrypicked and hybridized with capitalism.</p>
<p>We see in China that socialism has also not been sustainable because China has not yet evolved past Stage Orange capitalism. So even though China puts on a veneer of socialism, structurally it's very capitalistic and also totalitarian because it cannot help itself. You can't shortcut structural development with a flowery ideology. If only it were so easy. Moralistic ideology is not growth! It's a fake front designed to say that no growth is necessary because it has already been actualized. It's the same problem as saying that you are a devout follower of God, yet you have never actually become conscious of what God is. Talking about God without first being conscious of God is idol worship. It will not make you godly because the structure of your consciousness is still dualistic.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/life-in-venezuela</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Most Corrupt Countries In The World</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-most-corrupt-countries-in-the-world</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's some really interesting research on corruption:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.transparency.org/news/feature/corruption_perceptions_index_2017" target="_blank">Corruption World Map</a></p>
<p>Corruption is basically a measure of <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/collective-ego" target="_blank">Collective Ego</a>, or the consciousness level and the developmental level of a country. The less conscious a group of people are, the more corrupt their country is.</p>
<p>If you want to quantify which countries are the most evolved, don't measure their GDP, measure their corruption index. If you want to know whether a country is advancing forward or regressing backward, look to see if their corruption index is improving decade after decade.</p>
<p>You want to live in a country which has the least corruption. Unless you're a corrupt devil, in which case you want to exploit that corruption to benefit your survival.</p>
<p>A quick way to gauge whether a specific policy proposal is high consciousness or low consciousness is to ask the question: Does this reduce or increase corruption? You'd be amazed by how many laws, bills, and proposals actually increase corruption! This is by design. Corruption can't help but to spread itself.</p>
<p>If the corruption index of your country is below 50, then you're in a sketchy part of the world and development will be harder for you. Not impossible, just harder. Countries below 50 will have a lot of Spiral Dynamics <a href="https://www.actualized.org/articles/spiral-dynamics-stage-blue" target="_blank">Stage Blue</a> and countries below 40 will have a lot of Stage Red & Purple. Don't create a victim mentality about it. Do the best you can with the cards you've been dealt. And if you were born in a country with a corruption index above 50, consider yourself very lucky. You don't even understand how bad life can get. You have been totally spoiled. Be grateful and use this gift to make something of your life and uplift the world. Countries below 50 badly need help from the countries above 50. Be careful not to demonize countries below 50. They need your help, not your scorn.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-most-corrupt-countries-in-the-world</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Green New Deal Town Hall</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/green-new-deal-town-hall</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A substantive discussion of how to address climate change. An example of conscious politics happening in the real world.</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yoFaQ9foV8I?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez is an amazing conscious politician, uncorrupted by corporate money.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/green-new-deal-town-hall</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Political Spiral Stages</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/political-spiral-stages</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Slide from my Conscious Politics - Part 2 video:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/political-spiral-01.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4305" src="https://www.actualized.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/political-spiral-01.png" alt="political-spiral-01" width="615" /></a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/political-spiral-stages</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Taste Of Infinity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-taste-of-infinity</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a small look into the mind of God:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zXTpASSd9xE?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Contemplate: How is it possible to zoom into a thing forever? What does this mean about the nature of reality?</p>
<p>Just the fact that this fractal exists should already clue you in that consciousness must be infinite. Otherwise how could you be conscious of it? If an infinite object was loaded into a finite mind, the mind would crash. Hence the mind itself must be infinite.</p>
<p>Consider this: In a finite reality it would be impossible to count up from 1 to infinity. This is only possible because consciousness is actually infinite.</p>
<p>But how can the human mind be infinite? Because the human mind is a virtual machine running inside the infinite mind of God. God's mind is running an infinite number of virtual machines, all which are themselves infinite. That's what Georg Cantor called the Absolute Infinite set. It is the super-set of all possible sets. The mindblowing nature of infinity is that you can divide it into an infinite number of parts, and each of those parts will be its own infinity. Infinity within infinity within infinity — to infinity! In other words, infinity literally allows you to create something from nothing, because infinity is endless and bottomless.</p>
<p>Consider this: If you have an infinite number of apples in a basket, you can pull out one apple, eat it, and you will still have an infinite number of apples left. You just created an apple from nothing! Ta-da! This is how God creates the universe. Its mind is not bound by any physical limitation or lack. It cannot lack anything because it is an unlimited fount of creativity. All it has to do to create a thing is subdivide itself. But it can subdivide itself infinitely many times, so it never loses anything in the process of creation. Even after God subdivides itself an infinite number of times to create all human minds, it still remains an infinite Unity. The Absolute Unity of all possible divisions. Absolute Unity turns out to be identical to division. Going full-circle.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/a-taste-of-infinity</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How Nazis Win Elections</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-nazis-win-elections</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If you're a student of history you've probably wondered, "How in the hell did Hitler get democratically elected? It doesn't make sense that people would willing support a guy like that."</p>
<p>Well, this is how:</p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6qvB5tHRNOI?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p></p><p class="video_box"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gu7n0_gVgTc?rel=0&vq=hd720" width="615" height="345" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Trumpism is a case study in demagoguery, collective self-deception, group think, cult psychology, ideology, egotism, devilry, ignorance, unconsciousness, selfishness, division, projection, scapegoating, demonization, judgment, denial, self-bias, confirmation bias, corruption, xenophobia, racism, and fear.</p>
<p>All the epistemic stuff we cover in-depth on Actualized.org all comes together in the real world like this.</p>
<p>A toxic brew of the most pathological aspects of Spiral Dynamics stage Red, Blue, and Orange.</p>
<p>You might wonder, But why do people eat it up? Because they are at those same levels of development/consciousness themselves. Birds of a feather flock together. Your politics directly correlates with your values, which correlates with your stage of ego development. You can only vote for a leader as high as your vision can see. So egotistical, ethnocentric people gladly vote for egotistical, ethnocentric leaders, especially when the leader pushes their fear buttons.</p>
<p>Watch out, the 2020 election is going to get very nasty. Trump's demagoguery will hit an all time high as his ego gets cornered by his own manipulations. One of the hallmarks of a giant ego is that it refuses to yield or admit wrong-doing or defeat. When Trump loses, he will have to deny it to himself and his supporters somehow. And there begins the heavy-duty devilry. There will likely be blood.</p>
<p>This is what happens when a dense ego is put into a position of power. It's not an issue of left vs right, the issue is density of ego.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/how-nazis-win-elections</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Highest Purpose</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-highest-purpose</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Pasting this from my personal journal:</p>
<p>My highest purpose is to lead people to Infinite Consciousness, Infinite Love, Infinite Selflessness, and Infinite Understanding. I am to show people what the highest form of leadership looks like. My entire life is dedicated to this cause. I am to lead people to the realization of Infinite Love and Infinite Beauty by embodiment and demonstration of Infinite Love in my own life. I am a vehicle for God's highest Love for mankind. The function of my human existence is to demonstrate the Goodness and Magnitude of God to those who lack the vision to see it. I am to use the gift of my extraordinary human mind to communicate God's highest intentions. I am not to hold back my love out of fear or selfish need. I am to be fearless and selfless and endure any consequences and suffering which will arise from such a path. The endurance of these obstacles and pain is part of my purification process. The suffering I endure will only make me more loving and understanding of the suffering of others, who are none other than myself. I am to shed all ill-will, malice, and judgment towards others, for I cannot help but see them as myself. In the end, the love and selflessness I radiate will inspire and transform the world. My reward will be the love I radiate and Infinite Understanding of the universe. My understanding will reach superhuman levels beyond all human comprehension or and strain the human self to contain. There is no doubt that this my way. I will have many critics and naysayers, but none of them will deter me because all of them I will be overcome simply by radiating more love because I understand that their ignorance is their limited way of showing their love. I understand that all hatred, judgment, and violence is just a condensed form of love. Through total self-understanding I will become incapable of seeing wrong or evil, even in those who seek to harm me. By the end of my human life the highest potential of a human life will have been actualized. The details of how all of this unfolds will be unimportant, as it will simply unfold as it must. My body and mind is at the highest service of Universal Intelligence. The point of no return has already been reached so no further decision is necessary. All of this is self-evidently true. When I lose track of my highest purpose (and I will) I am to return here and re-read this statement, re-grounding myself in that which is undeniable.</p>
<p>Actualized 2.0 is coming. Brace yourself for a sledgehammer of Love.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.actualized.org/insights/the-highest-purpose</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>