<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=content&amp;type=forums_topic_post</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:47:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Thoughts on Culadasa (John Yates) - My Practice Method</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34102-thoughts-on-culadasa-john-yates-my-practice-method/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410097</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7210-ardacigin/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7210" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7210-ardacigin/" rel="">@ardacigin</a> Sounds very solid. Keep it up and you should see awesome gains.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410097</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is the universe just a mind/thought of God?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34096-is-the-universe-just-a-mindthought-of-god/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410095</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7840-kieranperez/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7840" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7840-kieranperez/" rel="">@kieranperez</a> I'm not clear what you wrote, but anyways...
</p>

<p>
	Whatever thoughts arise in your human head/mind are of course God's doing. God does not think somewhere elsewhere from human minds. When God is thinking, it's using a human to do it because thinking requires form. So God as a formless entity technically cannot think unless it first materializes a human who then becomes a vehicle for thoughts.
</p>

<p>
	So you might say that God as formlessness cannot do anything at all, but at the same time it can materialize all of physical reality and then whatever physical reality does, is equivalent to God doing stuff.
</p>

<p>
	So formless God cannot eat a cheeseburger (because eating is form), but it can spawn a Big Bang, wait 14 billion years, spawn a cow, spawn a human, spawn a chef who cooks the cheeseburger, and then have the human eat the cheeseburger. That's how God eats cheeseburgers <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	God as formlessness lives vicariously through all form. Remember, form and formlessness are identical. So God literally is the taste of the cheeseburger. Ta-da! <img alt=":D" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin@2x.png 2x" title=":D" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	Or think of it this way: when you're playing a video game you cannot directly enter the world of Mario as a human. But you can live through that world as the Mario character. To manipulate Mario's world requires that you use Mario as the interface. You become Mario while also being a human who's distinct from Mario. Mario can die but it does not harm you.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410095</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thoughts on Culadasa (John Yates) - My Practice Method</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34102-thoughts-on-culadasa-john-yates-my-practice-method/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410092</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7137-yonkon/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7137" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7137-yonkon/" rel="">@Yonkon</a> My opinion of him has not changed much. I don't think he is ultimately awakened, but he doesn't need to be in order to teach what he teaches, and he's more than enough awake for you. He's an excellent meditation teacher.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410092</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410084</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8874-serotoninluv/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8874" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8874-serotoninluv/" rel="">@Serotoninluv</a> You can probably handle it.
</p>

<p>
	Each trip will go deeper and deeper, and wider and wider. There will certainly be significant cumulative effects.
</p>

<p>
	With this method you're cramming years of spiritual growth into a single week. So be prepared for some ego-backlash and unexpected stuff. In a sense it must disrupt your old life. This can be both great and problematic when you return.
</p>

<p>
	I highly recommend it for very serious, seasoned spiritual aspirants with a very solid theoretical and practical foundation, and high emotional maturity. Not for newbies.
</p>

<p>
	Don't be too surprised if this kind of work makes your depressive or even suicidal for a while. You need to be stable enough to weather such storms. The payoffs though are HUGE.
</p>

<p>
	To handle a solid week of 5-MeO requires pushing yourself. The ego will want to stop somewhere half-way through as it gets overwhelmed with Truth.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410084</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Strange Loops Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/22929-strange-loops-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410083</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14564-montecristo/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14564" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14564-montecristo/" rel="">@montecristo</a> Love it! <img alt=":D" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin@2x.png 2x" title=":D" width="20" /> Delicious paradox
</p>

<p>
	This is a good thread. We need more strange loops in here!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410083</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can God think?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34098-can-god-think/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410081</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	If you are thinking, God is thinking.
</p>

<p>
	God can even fart! <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410081</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thoughts on Culadasa (John Yates) - My Practice Method</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34102-thoughts-on-culadasa-john-yates-my-practice-method/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410080</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Yes, it's great stuff. No nonsense mindfulness meditation a la Shinzen Young.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410080</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I am not the one who is moving my fingers</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34091-i-am-not-the-one-who-is-moving-my-fingers/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410077</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="409932" data-ipsquote-contentid="34091" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556289164" data-ipsquote-userid="6475" data-ipsquote-username="Anirban657">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 hours ago, Anirban657 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			It is just a conceptual realization though, not direct experience.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's not good enough. It doesn't count unless it's direct experience.
</p>

<p>
	Also, you ARE the one moving the fingers. Who else is there but YOU? You are all there is! You are the entire universe moving those fingers. The only problem is that you've confused yourself with being limited to a human body/mind. Start thinking of yourself as the entire universe. That will help a bit to give you proper perspective. But merely thinking you are the universe is still not enough. You must directly experience that it is so. This requires awakening. The boundary between self and word must collapse.
</p>

<p>
	Be careful not to just believe me. Belief is the enemy here, even if it's positive belief or belief in nonduality. True nonduality is not a belief.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 19:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410077</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Logic True?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34095-is-logic-true/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410074</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5492-123456789/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5492" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5492-123456789/" rel="">@123456789</a> Take a closer look. They are all circular.
</p>

<p>
	You must break through the illusion of knowledge. No knowledge is actually possible.
</p>

<p>
	You cannot take science at face value in this work. You MUST contemplate for yourself.
</p>

<p>
	Even more fundamentally, all human language is circular. And science is a human language. You cannot do science, math, or logic without language.
</p>

<p>
	So really what you should start contemplating is, What the fuck is language? How is language possible AT ALL?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 18:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410074</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Logic True?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34095-is-logic-true/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410068</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="410067" data-ipsquote-contentid="34095" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556303799" data-ipsquote-userid="5492" data-ipsquote-username="123456789">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		18 minutes ago, 123456789 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1329-shiva/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1329" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1329-shiva/" rel="">@Shiva</a> In the case of scientific models we have very clearly defined variables.Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Actually no scientific variable is every clearly defined.
</p>

<p>
	Science has no definition for matter, gravity, energy, time, space, or any other fundamental property of nature. Because reality is groundless and nondual it is impossible to define. Any definition is partial, circular, and ultimately groundless.
</p>

<p>
	Check for yourself. What is energy exactly? What is matter? What is time? If you investigate this you'll discover that no scientist actually knows. You'll just be chasing your own tail. All scientific definitions must be circular. Energy is defined in terms of the unknowns of time, space, and matter. Matter is defined in terms of the unknowns of energy, time, and space. Time is defined in terms of the unknowns of matter, energy, and space. Space is defined in terms of the unknowns of time, energy, and matter. In this way, nothing is truly ever known but an illusion of knowing is created like a house of cards.
</p>

<p>
	See my videos on:
</p>

<ul>
	<li>
		Quantum Mechanics Debunks Materialism
	</li>
	<li>
		The Metaphysical Implications of Godel's Incompleteness Theorem
	</li>
	<li>
		Jacques Derrida, Deconstruction, Post-Modernism & Nonduality
	</li>
	<li>
		Reality Is A Strange Loop
	</li>
</ul>

<p>
	That should get you started in the right direction.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 18:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410068</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Logic True?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34095-is-logic-true/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410058</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5492-123456789/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5492" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5492-123456789/" rel="">@123456789</a> Like I said this requires decades of contemplation work. Contemplate your own examples.
</p>

<p>
	For example: Einstein's theory of General Relativity is only true at macro levels. It does not work at the micro levels of quantum mechanics. But even if it did, that still wouldn't make a difference because General Relativity is not true in your dreams or in a video game.
</p>

<p>
	And in the end, it's still only an approximation at best of only certain kinds of physical phenomena. There are a trillion things which General Relativity does not account for.
</p>

<p>
	Not to even mention that General Relativity is not possible at all outside the context of the human mind. General Relativity literally does not exist for a donkey. Because General Relativity is a symbolic human invention and projection onto reality. The remarkable thing is that it has any predictive power at all (but again, only relative to human life and human consciousness).
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 18:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410058</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Logic True?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34095-is-logic-true/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410050</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="410043" data-ipsquote-contentid="34095" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556301638" data-ipsquote-userid="5492" data-ipsquote-username="123456789">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		32 minutes ago, 123456789 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>Â How comeÂ we are able to predict the future using scientific models (which are based on formal logic)?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Firstly, scientific models are NOT based on formal logic. Again, "formal logic" is a loaded word. There are an infinite number of different formal logics. So which one are you gonna base your scientific model on? They all contradict each other. You must do empirical research to determine whether your logic squares with reality. Often times it won't!
</p>

<p>
	In quantum mechanics particles do not follow Aristotelian binary logic. So physics has long ago debunked the naive notion that reality follows binary logic.
</p>

<p>
	The question of What is science? and How come science works? is a very tricky one. It takes decades of study and contemplation to understand it.
</p>

<p>
	In short, scientific models contain very partial and limited relative truths. They are true only under very very narrow circumstances and contexts. Just because some aspects of reality are predictable does not mean that reality is logical. In fact it tends to work the other way around: Whatever humans call "logical" is however reality happens to behave in contexts which are relevant to humans. For example, if chairs had a habit of turning spontaneously into cats whenever you sat on them, your mind would grow accustomed to that behavior and call it "logical".
</p>

<p>
	In practice, what you call "logical" is just whatever reality happens to do around you. If everyone you knew walked around naked on the street, you'd eventually start calling that logical. Because in fact it is impossible to distinguish between logical and illogical things. That is a matter of relative perspective. What's logical to me is not logical to you, and vice versa. Or to put it another way, YOU are the sole arbiter of what counts as logical. Whatever you insist is logical, becomes logical (for you). Whatever you insist is illogical becomes illogical (for you). Logic has no normative power. So if someone wants to be "illogical", they are free to do so and no amount of reasoning, argumentation, or evidence will convince them otherwise. Because they are only "illogical" relative to your judgment of them. They are not illogical in any absolute sense.
</p>

<p>
	There actually exists no standard to determine what counts as logical. It must be this way because reality is nondual and empty/groundless. Anyone who tries to ground reality in logic will fail. This was rigorously demonstrated back in the early 20th century. Logical positivism and the attempt to formalize reality with a finite system of symbols failed spectacularly. As it should have. Reality is not quantifiable or formalizable.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 18:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410050</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Logic True?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34095-is-logic-true/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410037</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	You have to be very careful to distinguish formal logic from the word "logic" as it is commonly used in mainstream culture.
</p>

<p>
	Certainly formal logic is not what you use to run your life. Not anywhere close it.
</p>

<p>
	And even in the case of formal logic, did you know that there are an infinite number of different formal logical systems with varying truths? So which one are you gonna say is the truest one? How will you decide? By using some meta-logic? But then there are an infinite number of meta-logical systems with varying truths. So you'll need a meta-meta-logic, and so on to infinity.
</p>

<p>
	As Kurt Godel proved, no logical system which is complete is consistent. And no logical system which is consistent is complete. This is because Truth is infinite and cannot be captured in a finite set of symbols.
</p>

<p>
	Most people who tout themselves as being "logical" have no clue what logic really is and its limits. In everyday life the ego co-opts logic to commit devilry. Even the craziest and most deluded people think they are being "logical". So how can you trust logic then? You could think you are being perfectly logical whilst you are totally deluded. So logic is no guarantor of truth.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 17:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410037</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410014</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Most people would not be able to handle days or weeks of 5-MeO. Remember that I only did that after YEARS of prep, and it was not easy. Don't try that at home. You'll have a psychic breakdown.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 16:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410014</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Logic True?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34095-is-logic-true/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410012</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	What is it you mean by "logic"? That's a super-loaded term.
</p>

<p>
	Contemplate: What is logic?
</p>

<p>
	It certainly isn't true in any absolute sense.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 16:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410012</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>J.Peterson &amp; S.Zizek : The Happiness debate</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34024-jpeterson-szizek-the-happiness-debate/?do=findComment&amp;comment=410008</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6625-george-fil/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6625" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6625-george-fil/" rel="">@George Fil</a>Â It's too generous to call Peterson a stage Yellow thinker.
</p>

<p>
	Zizek too is probably more Green than Yellow.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 16:46:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">410008</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I did push and pull to a girl and she get mad HAHAHA! How can i counter this?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33952-i-did-push-and-pull-to-a-girl-and-she-get-mad-hahaha-how-can-i-counter-this/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409801</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12765-bejapuskas/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12765" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12765-bejapuskas/" rel="">@bejapuskas</a>Â Being the devil that you are, youÂ are already a master at lying. So no need to practice it any more.
</p>

<p>
	<img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 07:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409801</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>One = zero = Infinity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34076-one-zero-infinity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409798</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15340-zeroisinfinity/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15340" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15340-zeroisinfinity/" rel="">@zeroISinfinity</a> Relative life vs Absolute life is a duality too.
</p>

<p>
	With lots of awakening you will mergeÂ the two worlds into one, such that your everyday life becomes infused with Spirit, Divinity, God, Goodness, Intelligence, and Love.
</p>

<p>
	More work is required! So back to the self-inquiry salt mines! <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 07:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409798</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>No 'do-er'...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34040-no-do-er/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409795</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="409787" data-ipsquote-contentid="34040" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556259838" data-ipsquote-userid="4000" data-ipsquote-username="Shaun">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		45 minutes ago, Shaun said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I am still wondering if my ego is the only ego/point of view in manifestation? Is there a clear answer to this? Could <a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> please answer this if possible?Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Lol, your ego is unreal!
</p>

<p>
	I have already answered that in The Radical Implications Of Oneness video.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 07:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409795</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, Do Not Peak In Until April 24th</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33828-leo-do-not-peak-in-until-april-24th/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409794</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Thanks guys! You take the edge off getting old.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 07:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409794</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>J.Peterson &amp; S.Zizek : The Happiness debate</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34024-jpeterson-szizek-the-happiness-debate/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409793</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="409770" data-ipsquote-contentid="34024" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556255442" data-ipsquote-userid="15106" data-ipsquote-username="NorthRise">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, NorthRise said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>
		</p>

		<p>
			I guess I like to understand other people's perspectives even if they're extremely limited, but it's definitely a major distraction.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That is good. I support studying all kinds of perspectives.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			There are so many opinions out there on social and political issues that it's hard to differentiateÂ insight vs. Ignorance.Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I will do some meta politics topics in the future where we look at the fundamentals of what politics is, how it works, and how it fits with spirituality.
</p>

<p>
	Those will be very powerful videos, unlike any political analysis you've ever seen. It will not be about any particular political candidates or partisan grabage.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 07:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409793</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Subscribing to no religion while parents want you to go to church</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34075-subscribing-to-no-religion-while-parents-want-you-to-go-to-church/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409767</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Classic conflict of stage Blue vs stage Orange
</p>

<p>
	That can be difficult if your parents are solid Blue. They will not be openminded enough to allow it. But you might be able to convince them.
</p>

<p>
	You could try to explain to them how meditation will lead you to God. And then when they go to church you stay home and do meditation. Emphasize the mystical aspects of their religion. Every serious religious practitioner does meditation/prayer/contemplation. Guide their religiosity to spirituality.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 04:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409767</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>One = zero = Infinity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34076-one-zero-infinity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409766</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Number is a duality
</p>

<p>
	Each number is a division. How many divisions can you make? 0 to infinity and everything between.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 04:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409766</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>No 'do-er'...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34040-no-do-er/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409763</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13735-omarcos/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="13735" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13735-omarcos/" rel="">@oMarcos</a>Â No, sleep is not awakening. Sleep is unconsciousness, awakening is consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	After you awaken deeply you can be conscious even during deep sleep. It's sorta like existing in a pure void.
</p>

<p>
	Sleep is a tricky thing. The fact is you don't really know what sleep is. That requires contemplation.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 04:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409763</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question for Leo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34064-question-for-leo/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409762</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6286-harikrishnan/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6286" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6286-harikrishnan/" rel="">@Harikrishnan</a> Yes, he's nondual and there are many nondual sufi writings.
</p>

<p>
	Rumi isÂ one.
</p>

<p>
	Ibn Arabi is another.
</p>

<p>
	Hafiz is another.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 04:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409762</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>J.Peterson &amp; S.Zizek : The Happiness debate</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34024-jpeterson-szizek-the-happiness-debate/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409761</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15106-northrise/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15106" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15106-northrise/" rel="">@NorthRise</a>Â Why torture yourself with low-consciousness videos when so many high consciousness videos exist?
</p>

<p>
	There is not enough time in the word to listen to every foolish debate on Youtube.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 04:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409761</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>No 'do-er'...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34040-no-do-er/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409738</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15534-gadasaa/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15534" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15534-gadasaa/" rel="">@Gadasaa</a> You were never actually born. You imagine it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 01:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409738</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>No 'do-er'...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34040-no-do-er/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409722</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="409717" data-ipsquote-contentid="34040" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556237274" data-ipsquote-userid="15534" data-ipsquote-username="Gadasaa">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		19 minutes ago, Gadasaa said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>Â This is what's giving me the most trouble. If i try to remember what i was before i was born, it's just nothingness, no memory, no consciousness, just blank which is same as death. And how can you say this is godhead?Â Â This life is only thing I've ever known, nothing else.Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That is not what I am talking about.
</p>

<p>
	You are talking about an imagined unconscious state. I am talking about total consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	You cannot understand because you have not yet awoken. Once you awaken you will understand what was being pointed at.
</p>

<p>
	Your ideas of awakening are never going to match actual awakening. That's what makes this so challenging.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409722</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question for Leo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34064-question-for-leo/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409716</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14842-caitwin/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14842" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14842-caitwin/" rel="">@Caitwin</a> The most useful thing would be to distinguish between dualistic philosophies vs nondual ones. If it's dualistic it can still have some nuts of wisdom, but it will also contain a lot of misguided things.
</p>

<p>
	If you're using impure sources you will waste a lot of time sorting the the truth from the delusion.
</p>

<p>
	Sometimes I start reading a book, see too much dualistic delusion, and just stop reading. Such an impure source is not worth the effort to untangle when crystal clear sources exist.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 23:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409716</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spiral Dynamics Stage Turquoise Examples Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/23206-spiral-dynamics-stage-turquoise-examples-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409715</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Be careful. Just because someone is a mystic or is enlightened does not automatically put them at Turquoise.
</p>

<p>
	The whole point of Spiral Dynamics is to differentiate between stages of development and awakening. They are not always correlated.
</p>

<p>
	Don't just assume that your favorite sage/mystic is Turquoise.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 23:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409715</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question for Leo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34064-question-for-leo/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409690</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="409661" data-ipsquote-contentid="34064" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556228090" data-ipsquote-userid="5761" data-ipsquote-username="ajasatya">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, ajasatya said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			for some reason, they become addicted to mental masturbation!
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The mind is a very powerful tool. Precisely because it is so powerful it is easy to get lost in the labyrinth of one's mind -- an endless labyrinth of symbols and ideas which tend to validate themselves no matter how misguided they are.
</p>

<p>
	Using the mind properly requires serious training, otherwise it falls into gross delusions.
</p>

<p>
	Unfortunately almost nobody teaches how to properly use the mind. People either teach how great the mind is, or how terrible the mind is, but not how to use the mind wisely.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 22:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409690</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>No 'do-er'...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34040-no-do-er/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409670</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="409598" data-ipsquote-contentid="34040" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556218692" data-ipsquote-userid="14341" data-ipsquote-username="Paul92">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		3 hours ago, Paul92 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			xactly.. I've only ever known being 'me'. And I have a sense of self. Maybe not as 'Paul', I recognise that is just a name. But I find it difficult to be able to drop the sense of self. What are we left with?Â 
		</p>

		<p>
			It's like you say we are God. Or a bit of God. Does that make us all individuals then on a certain level?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You are confused about who/what you are. This is how most normal people are. At the same time they identify with being the body, the mind, and also not that. They are unsure and confused. The mind plays these games where one minute it thinks its the body, another minute it thinks its a human, another minute it thinks its the voice heard in the head, another minute it thinks it was born, another minute it thinks its some kind of "soul", another minute it thinks its God, and so on.
</p>

<p>
	The purpose of self-inquiry is to become very strict with yourself and force yourself to confront this shell game that the mind plays. What are you REALLY? Not as a belief, but what the fuck are you? If you claim that you are real, then you must be able to clearly specify what is it that's real. The body? The voice? The memories of childhood? The feelings of pain? If we put a gun to your head right now, what is it that you fear will die? << That is the false self.
</p>

<p>
	Getting clear about the false self is just as important as discovering the True Self. You can't disidentify with something unless you first clearly realize that you're identified with it. You might be identified with your childhood memories and not even realize it. So you have to ask yourself very seriously, "Am I identified with my childhood memories? Is that what I actually am?" And so forth with any other possible identifications until you eliminate them all. What will remain is nothing, which is what you actually are.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 21:53:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409670</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What's the difference between complete mockery and spiritual teachings?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34049-whats-the-difference-between-complete-mockery-and-spiritual-teachings/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409668</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/2261-mandyjw/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="2261" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/2261-mandyjw/" rel="">@mandyjw</a> If you have young kids who demand a lot of your time you may just have to focus on them for a few years until they are more independent and then return to serious spiritual pursuits.
</p>

<p>
	In the meantime you can study theory and maintain a mild daily practice of 30-60 minutes. You can also do a few yearly meditation retreats or psychedelic retreats.
</p>

<p>
	Sometimes in this work you must inch your way up. Be creative. Find ways which fit your existing obligations.
</p>

<p>
	But also, don't fool yourself into thinking that watching Borat is spiritual work. You must be brutally honest about whether the techniques you're using are actually raising your consciousness.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 21:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409668</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can consciousness work make you more deluded?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34057-can-consciousness-work-make-you-more-deluded/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409663</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			"By a misperception of emptiness a person of little intelligence is destroyed. Like a snake incorrectly seized."
		</p>

		<p style="text-align:right;">
			â€” Nagarjuna
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The ego-mind will most-definitely misinterpret truth. Ignorance cannot help being ignorant. You can count on that.
</p>

<p>
	By understanding this you will be a little less likely to do it. But you will still not be immune.
</p>

<p>
	You must be careful and study many high-quality sources, and think for yourself.
</p>

<p>
	Also understand that mistakes are part of the process. No one walks the spiritual path without making some mistakes. Trial and error is how we grow. The key is to stay vigilant enough to correct yourself. You need to have enough theory under your belt to know when you've veered off course.
</p>

<p>
	It's okay to be a bit deluded here or there so long as you know what the right course ultimately is.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 21:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409663</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Oh god... Actuality and Not knowing are the exact Same ðŸ˜†</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34065-oh-god-actuality-and-not-knowing-are-the-exact-same-%F0%9F%98%86/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409660</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Being = "Knowing"
</p>

<p>
	God "knows" a thing by being it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 21:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409660</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question for Leo</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34064-question-for-leo/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409657</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14842-caitwin/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14842" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14842-caitwin/" rel="">@Caitwin</a> Not a fan. There are much better philosophies to read.
</p>

<p>
	Try Nagarjuna or Plotinus instead.
</p>

<p>
	Remember, there is A LOT of dualistic delusion within Western philosophy, so be careful not to waste your time wading through bullshit. Go straight for the highest nondual teachings.
</p>

<p>
	You can easily spend 20 years reading Western philosophy and still not get any closer to Truth. With that said, there is the occasional gem and I still encourage everyone to think through philosophical questions for themselves. Philosophy is not meant to be read or believed, it must be DONE! -- as in: contemplate everything for yourself.
</p>

<p>
	The power of philosophy lies more in the questions than in the answers. If you are not contemplating for yourself, you are not actually doing any philosophy.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			"All philosophies are mental fabrications. There has never been a single doctrine by which one could enter the true essence of things."
		</p>

		<p style="text-align:right;">
			â€” Nagarjuna
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Â 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 21:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409657</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I did push and pull to a girl and she get mad HAHAHA! How can i counter this?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33952-i-did-push-and-pull-to-a-girl-and-she-get-mad-hahaha-how-can-i-counter-this/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409604</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7997-mm1988/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7997" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7997-mm1988/" rel="">@MM1988</a> There is skill and there are principles to dating, just like there is with golf, tennis, driving a car, or meditation.
</p>

<p>
	You are framing what I said as "This is so inauthentic and artificial". But once you actually internalize the skill of proper texting, it will become authentic and natural.
</p>

<p>
	Every skill you learned was at one point inauthentic and artificial, from mathematics to reading to writing to typing on the computer.
</p>

<p>
	I am not saying you need to keep a file of canned text messages. Once you understand the principles of texting with a girl, you can generate an infinite number of spontaneous texts. Without learning this skill, your text messages will suck and you will lose girls by committing stupid mistakes which only years later will you understand why.
</p>

<p>
	People expect to be good at sex and dating "naturally" without any deliberate practice. Because love is supposed to be "natural". This is a silly double-standard. Nowhere else in life do you adopt this attitude. If you want to be good at something you must train and recognize principles. Girls will appreciate it when you don't creep them out with your texts.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 19:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409604</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What's the difference between complete mockery and spiritual teachings?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34049-whats-the-difference-between-complete-mockery-and-spiritual-teachings/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409589</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/2261-mandyjw/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="2261" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/2261-mandyjw/" rel="">@mandyjw</a> This is why most people will not get enlightened. It's too radical and it requires serious focus.
</p>

<p>
	You will not wake up without scheduling some week-long retreats every year. Waking up requires intense and prolonged focus. 60 minutes of focus will not do it.
</p>

<p>
	Or try psychedelics. That's the most realistic way for ordinaryÂ people to get a taste of awakening. It's fast amd effective, unlike meditation.
</p>

<p>
	With all that said, you can still maintain a daily meditation habit.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 18:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409589</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>No 'do-er'...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34040-no-do-er/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409584</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="409431" data-ipsquote-contentid="34040" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556192902" data-ipsquote-userid="14523" data-ipsquote-username="Jkris">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		6 hours ago, Jkris said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14785-waken/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14785" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14785-waken/" rel="">@Waken</a> This is what I am not getting all.There is a rock solid I feeling or me feeling in the field of awareness which is what the mind claims to be I or me or sense of seperate self.
		</p>

		<p>
			So seeing doesn't help ? Does it ? This I or me feeling is permanant in the waking state.ocassionally momentarily there is no I or me feeling when one is fully involved in some activity.A longer duration of this absence of I feeling during activity is also called the flow.
		</p>

		<p>
			But how to get rid of this I or me feeling is the riddle question ?Â 
		</p>

		<p>
			Even in the gaps of absence of thoughts this I feeling remains ðŸ¤”
		</p>

		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It requires a change in state of consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	The sense of I is more than just a feeling, thought, or belief. It's anÂ entireÂ state of being such that you know no other possibility.
</p>

<p>
	Changing that state requires a lot of concentration practice, or kriya yoga, or psychedelics.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 18:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409584</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, did you need a wingman to have success in dating?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33899-leo-did-you-need-a-wingman-to-have-success-in-dating/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409402</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408507" data-ipsquote-contentid="33899" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556013546" data-ipsquote-userid="10053" data-ipsquote-username="billiesimon">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 4/23/2019 at 2:59 AM, billiesimon said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> bu the way, did you start alone or immediately with a wing?Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Both
</p>

<p>
	The first time I went to a club I went solo.
</p>

<p>
	Then I quickly got some wings. They were helpful for something me the ropes and venues.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 09:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409402</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Porn is heroin</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34004-porn-is-heroin/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409400</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Use responsibly
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 09:55:34 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409400</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I did push and pull to a girl and she get mad HAHAHA! How can i counter this?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33952-i-did-push-and-pull-to-a-girl-and-she-get-mad-hahaha-how-can-i-counter-this/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409392</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408946" data-ipsquote-contentid="33952" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556094340" data-ipsquote-userid="7997" data-ipsquote-username="MM1988">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 4/24/2019 at 1:25 AM, MM1988 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Then I see what other guys write to girls, like really "gay" stuff with heart smileys and shit. And girls seem to go crazy for it, these guys have a deeper connection with her than the guy who only writes her in a matter-of-fact style and then tries to get physical out of the blue.
		</p>

		<p>
			Havent you seen that when a girl fancies a guy they text each other all the time, shes constantly on her phone. A PUA would tell you to never do that and ignore her. I listened to this PUA stuff, set all these rules for myself what to do and what not to do and it backfired in my face every time. I'm still working on getting all these PUA concepts out of my head, its pure neurotic poison, thats just what it is.
		</p>

		<p>
			I think your advice on this topic is heavily biased by your PUA phase Leo. No offense at all but I think If dating happened naturally and not in a forced way as a PUA late in your 20s I think your advice on this would be A LOT different.Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I was only talking about pre-sex communications. Once you have sex with her, then you can text her more seriously.
</p>

<p>
	You must distinguish between pre-sex and post-sex behaviors. They are very different.
</p>

<p>
	Pre-sex, while you're dating, there must be some gaming going on. After she falls in love with you, you can cut the gaming.
</p>

<p>
	You don't need to manipulate her too much via text. The key is not to display neediness and desperation. The biggest mistake made with pre-sex texting is that the guy fucks it up by trying to say too much, trying to be too edgy/cocky/funny. Trying to attract her via text doesn't work. So actually my advice is to not game girls via text. Use texting mostly to handle dating logistics laced with bits of humor.
</p>

<p>
	Make your texts totally non-needy and unimportant. Don't be sending her long letters via text. Never try to logically convince her of meeting you. All that crap will blow you out very fast.
</p>

<p>
	Here are good kinds of texts pre-sex:
</p>

<ul>
	<li>
		Hey gurl, let's grab a coffee.
	</li>
	<li>
		Coffee! Lets go
	</li>
	<li>
		Saw this shirt at Walmart and thought it would be perfect for you [insert pic of ugly shirt]
	</li>
	<li>
		Meow...
	</li>
	<li>
		Moo
	</li>
	<li>
		Hey dork
	</li>
	<li>
		Let's hang out
	</li>
	<li>
		When you free this week?
	</li>
	<li>
		Let's do something this week
	</li>
	<li>
		How's the recovery going? (from last night's club/bar)
	</li>
	<li>
		You're the weirdest gurl I met last night.
	</li>
	<li>
		I want to build you a mansion out of Legos and stock it with exotic baby animals.
	</li>
	<li>
		Reading a book
	</li>
	<li>
		Chillin by the pool
	</li>
	<li>
		Making juice
	</li>
	<li>
		Clipping my toe nails, thought you should know
	</li>
	<li>
		Trimming my nose hair, thought you should know
	</li>
	<li>
		Going to club XXXXX tonight. You?
	</li>
	<li>
		You remind me of a dog I just saw
	</li>
	<li>
		You seem great and all but I'm trying to figure out what's wrong with you. I bet you snore like a pig.
	</li>
	<li>
		I want to stick a scorpion in your pants
	</li>
	<li>
		Hope this isn't too forward but I mailed you this basket of puppies [insert pic of basket of puppies]
		<ul>
			<li>
				A few of them might arrive dead, I was too cheap to swing for overnight shipping
			</li>
		</ul>
	</li>
</ul>

<p>
	That kind of stuff. Keep it lite and chill. Zero investment is key.
</p>

<p>
	This is the extent of pre-sex texting.
</p>

<p>
	NEVER, EVER get sexual via text unless you've already had sex with her a few times. It comes off way too creepy and needy. Act like you don't care about sex.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 09:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409392</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>No 'do-er'...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34040-no-do-er/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409386</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14341-paul92/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14341" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14341-paul92/" rel="">@Paul92</a> Paul as a biographical, biological, physical entity is constructed fiction. A narrative.
</p>

<p>
	But there is a True You -- the True Self/No-Self/Nothingness/Void/God. Your true nature is not human but God. You are God thinking it is Paul. So when you realize that you are actually God, you will also realize that God has Will. God has infinite Will, in fact. Paul's will is a tiny splinter off God's infinite Will.
</p>

<p>
	So in a sense you will discover Paul was never really in control.
</p>

<p>
	But then you will also discover that since you are God, you control and create everything. As God, you have Will which you can use to create. So literally God allocates a tiny percentage of its infinite Will to this body of Paul's so that it could create a life. As a human your creative capacities are not infinite, they are limited so long as you are in a human form. If you exit the human form your creative power will be infinite, you can literally materialize physical objects out of thin air. But at this point you're not a human any more, you are the Godhead. You are that which you were before you were born.
</p>

<p>
	In the end, everything is God's choice. But the kicker is, you're God! But simultaneously you're human <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	None of this is to be believed. You must discover if it is true through consciousness practices.
</p>

<p>
	The more conscious you become the more of God's Will will be at your disposal. Eventually you and God will merge into one such there will be zero distance between your lifting a finger and God willing it so.
</p>

<p>
	The definition of a devil is someone who thinks he is separate from God. The devil seeks to separate itself from God and rule using his own will. But the devil is always just a partition within God. So the devil is tricking itself into thinking that it is in control. Eventually the devil must surrender control and accept that it was God all along. This merges the devil back into God as if the separation never even happened. That's nonduality in a nutshell. Nonduality polarizes into duality and then depolarizes back into nonduality.
</p>

<p>
	God is the doing non-doer <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 09:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409386</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>College/University</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34018-collegeuniversity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409345</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15629-jj13/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15629" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15629-jj13/" rel="">@Jj13</a> A spiritual university is called an ashram or a monastery.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 04:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409345</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, Do Not Peak In Until April 24th</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33828-leo-do-not-peak-in-until-april-24th/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409344</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="409340" data-ipsquote-contentid="33828" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556165829" data-ipsquote-userid="15647" data-ipsquote-username="Anthony Purdy">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		29 minutes ago, Anthony Purdy said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Do you like birthday cake?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Sounds like there's a catch <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 04:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409344</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>God works in mysterious ways. Jordan Peterson can serve you in unexpected ways.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34030-god-works-in-mysterious-ways-jordan-peterson-can-serve-you-in-unexpected-ways/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409311</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Enough bullshit.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 01:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409311</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>J.Peterson &amp; S.Zizek : The Happiness debate</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34024-jpeterson-szizek-the-happiness-debate/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409287</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Lol
</p>

<p>
	Blind leading the blind on stilts off a cliff.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 23:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409287</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dose anyone know any good books or documentary etc on how the astral world works?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34027-dose-anyone-know-any-good-books-or-documentary-etc-on-how-the-astral-world-works/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409249</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10518-tom-t/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10518" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10518-tom-t/" rel="">@Tom T</a> See my book list, Paranormal section.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 21:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409249</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409245</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11237-now-is-forever/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11237" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11237-now-is-forever/" rel="">@now is forever</a> A bank robbery is a life-threatening situation. Police use overwhelming force in order to make sure people don't fuck with them. Which maintains the peace you enjoy.
</p>

<p>
	If you pull out a gun in a public area, you should expect to get shot by police. This is not inhumane. But obviously the police need to be well-trained not to use excessive force, especially against minorities. But if someone is waving a gun around in public, shooting him is not inhuman. If he has no gun, then he shouldn't be shot but tazered.
</p>

<p>
	It's not so complicated. It just requires good police training and accountability.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 21:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409245</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Had faith in Leo and found god</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34011-had-faith-in-leo-and-found-god/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409244</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/3501-thomast/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="3501" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/3501-thomast/" rel="">@ThomasT</a> Awesome! Glad you found God. <img alt=":D" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin@2x.png 2x" title=":D" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	Not sure why you needed to fly all the way to Mexico though. Bufo ceremonies are done in Europe all the time.
</p>

<p>
	Here's one:Â <a href="https://www.psilohuasca.com/" rel="external nofollow">https://www.psilohuasca.com</a>
</p>

<p>
	I know Octavio Rettig travels to Europe as well.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 21:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409244</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, Do Not Peak In Until April 24th</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33828-leo-do-not-peak-in-until-april-24th/?do=findComment&amp;comment=409242</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Awwww... Thanks a lot ya'll <img alt=":x" data-emoticon="" height="29" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wub.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wub@2x.png 2x" title=":x" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 21:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">409242</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408969</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5317-how-to-be-wise/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5317" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5317-how-to-be-wise/" rel="">@How to be wise</a> Which is why most of society is not enlightened and never will be. Most enlightened people just sit around and do nothing. You don't see enlightened people in the military or police force or 99% of other basic jobs.
</p>

<p>
	If everyone got enlightened tomorrow, society would completely collapse, worse than a nuclear war.
</p>

<p>
	In practice, enlightened people depend on the rest of society functioning unconsciously, in the same way that the police depend on criminals committing crimes.
</p>

<p>
	Enlightenment does have a certain elitism to it. It cannot really work unless society is advanced enough to support it. Or unless you are totally off on your own living in a cave. But even then you need someone to bring you food.
</p>

<p>
	In practice what happens is that an enlightened person is so rare the he can survive off his followers and fans.
</p>

<p>
	And also, in practice, if you are conscious enough to not suffer, you will be resourceful enough not to place yourself into a job where you have to shoot people.
</p>

<p>
	Then again, you can still probably be an enlightened police officer if you really wanted. I don't see why that necessarily requires suffering. There's no real contradiction shooting a bank robber. You shoot him because he's breaking an important law. Your job in this case is to defend society against devils, which ultimately helps society to awaken.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 09:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408969</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to survive whilst working towards life purpose?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33841-how-to-survive-whilst-working-towards-life-purpose/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408962</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5651-space/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5651" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5651-space/" rel="">@Space</a> That is the million dollar question.
</p>

<p>
	There is no easy answer. Becoming financially comfortable whilst starting from scratch is very challenging, requiring creative thinking, strategy, focus, discipline, hard work, vision, and a bit of luck.
</p>

<p>
	In practice you will have to claw your way to the top using whatever means available.
</p>

<p>
	One very helpful piece of advice is to keep your living expenses as low as humanly possible. At least for the first 5 years of your LP, until you get established.
</p>

<p>
	Another possibility is to move to a very cheap part of the country, or even a 3rd world country as you develop your skills. Again, this is to keep your expenses as low as possible and buy yourself time to build skills.
</p>

<p>
	Another possibility is first build some more marketable skills which can help you pay the rent. For example it's possible to learn some programming skills, which tend to be well-paid.
</p>

<p>
	Another possibility is to work a relatively high-wage job for a year or two in order to save up a nest egg. There are some jobs which require zero experience and zero education but still pay well.
</p>

<p>
	Another possibility is to get a lower job but within your chosen field/industry. For example if you want to direct movies, rather than trying to get hired as a director (which is virtually impossible), try to get hired as an assistant to the director. Then you can prove yourself to the director and he might be willing to hire you in the future as a producer. Etc. Finally then you will become a director.
</p>

<p>
	Another possibility is to get a part-time job which allows you time to work on building your skills at home.
</p>

<p>
	Etc.
</p>

<p>
	You have to be very creative, opportunistic, and flexible when starting out.
</p>

<p>
	I spent 4 years building an entirely unrelated business to earn enough money to finally follow my LP. It was a huge detour and not at all easy or pleasant. But it was worth it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 09:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408962</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why Survival is a Dire Need?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33951-why-survival-is-a-dire-need/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408957</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6826-annoynymous/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6826" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6826-annoynymous/" rel="">@Annoynymous</a> If it wasn't you could not be here asking this question.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 09:04:48 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408957</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408949</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408938" data-ipsquote-contentid="33950" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556093026" data-ipsquote-userid="5317" data-ipsquote-username="How to be wise">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		44 minutes ago, How to be wise said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			But how can you do all of that without suffering. Believing the thought â€˜someone needs to be stoppedâ€™ by definition creates suffering. Fighting anything internally creates suffering. You can fight it externally, as long as you do not fight it internally. Are you saying we canâ€™t survive without suffering?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Suffering IS a survival function. The only reason anything suffers is because it cares to survive.
</p>

<p>
	Suffering can be transcended through consciousness at the individual level, but at the collective level that's another story.
</p>

<p>
	Why are you framing it as "someone needs to be stopped"? You can act against devilry without being attached to it, and hence avoid suffering.
</p>

<p>
	I am not saying you need to fight anything internally.
</p>

<p>
	I can vote against Trump without hating him. I can be conscious that he is me, but that he must still not be allowed to hold power. I can support the existence of a police department without suffering simply by understanding that police is needed for a decent society. This just requires some understanding of how government works.
</p>

<p>
	You can work to build a decent government without becoming an ideological partisan zealot about it.
</p>

<p>
	In fact, anything that can be done with suffering and attachment can also be done without suffering or attachment.
</p>

<p>
	You seem to be conflating action and education with suffering.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 08:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408949</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408931</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11747-purerogue/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11747" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11747-purerogue/" rel="">@purerogue</a> Precisely.
</p>

<p>
	When the rubber hits the road, you will run crying to government to save your ass from the devils who want to rape you.
</p>

<p>
	The people who take government for granted are the ones whoÂ already feel totally safe because government has provided them with that safety without them even being aware of it.
</p>

<p>
	That's how good government is.Â It's amazing! Like magic!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 07:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408931</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408926</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5317-how-to-be-wise/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5317" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5317-how-to-be-wise/" rel="">@How to be wise</a> Well, practically, if you don't believe some people need to be stopped you cannot create a police force nor enforce any laws.
</p>

<p>
	So you can act too cool for school, but that's only because someone else has worked their ass off to create a police force so that you can sit comfortably it your room without getting your throat slit.
</p>

<p>
	Survival demands action of you. If you are okay with dying, fine. Then you will die. See ya in the next life.
</p>

<p>
	Do not take government for granted. Without a good government you would be a slave. And good government does not happen by accident. It requires intense battle and effort against devils who would wish to enslave you.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 07:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408926</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How to prepare for death?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34010-how-to-prepare-for-death/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408924</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15652-choseyfrozey/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15652" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15652-choseyfrozey/" rel="">@ChoseyFrozey</a> Psychedelics are the most effective method for facing death without totally dying.
</p>

<p>
	Start with a small dose and slowly work your way up.
</p>

<p>
	Any psychedelic can produce ego-death.
</p>

<p>
	You can't really prepare for it. It will just blindside you, you'll be dead before you realize what just happened. And then you will laugh as you realize death is a joke.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 07:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408924</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Human characteristics and qualities</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33982-human-characteristics-and-qualities/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408922</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408481" data-ipsquote-contentid="33982" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556010544" data-ipsquote-userid="13487" data-ipsquote-username="nistake">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		22 hours ago, nistake said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Is there any way to find out what personality trait comes from primordial personality and from ego?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Get rid of the ego and see what remains <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 07:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408922</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408910</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5317-how-to-be-wise/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5317" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5317-how-to-be-wise/" rel="">@How to be wise</a> As I have told you before, you have bastardized spirituality into an absolutist position which denies relative reality and relative truths. This is pathological Zen devilry.
</p>

<p>
	You are shirking your responsibilty as a creator. Nothing needs to happen, but that doesn't mean we cannot decide to execute Hitler for being a vicious devil.
</p>

<p>
	We get to decide how we want life and society to unfold. If you want to sit back and do nothing, that's fine, but that is your choice. Do not act like you are not making a choice. By not making a choice you've made your choice.
</p>

<p>
	Whatever choice we make becomes God's will.
</p>

<p>
	Reality makesÂ things happen through YOU! Not for you. If you choose to not prepare for winter, winter will come and you will starve to death. Reality will not magically feed you. Reality gave you enough smarts to not be so stupid as to ignore winter.
</p>

<p>
	You are exhibiting a dangerous level of naivete.
</p>

<p>
	Nonduality does NOT mean inaction or indifference.
</p>

<p>
	To escape personalÂ suffering into some Nirvanic formless state and then to act like nothing else matters because you are free of suffering is perhaps the highest form of Zen devilry I have seen.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 06:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408910</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thoughts On Sadhguru</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/2666-thoughts-on-sadhguru/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408888</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14265-clouffy/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14265" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14265-clouffy/" rel="">@clouffy</a> Contemplation and observation.
</p>

<p>
	If something is true, it is happening in your experience and you can observe it happening.
</p>

<p>
	So all you really have to do is look at what is actually happening without adding your own stuff to it.
</p>

<p>
	The tricky part is that you add A LOT of your own stuff to it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 05:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408888</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>It's all fine and well being &quot;in the moment&quot;, but...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33796-its-all-fine-and-well-being-in-the-moment-but/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408881</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408872" data-ipsquote-contentid="33796" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556084377" data-ipsquote-userid="14265" data-ipsquote-username="clouffy">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		10 minutes ago, clouffy said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> actually, i'm interested in how you monitor yourself amidst all this? Truth is powerful, and it could be of great destruction if you are not careful and turn into a zen devil
		</p>

		<p>
			how do you self monitor, leo? it just sounds so hard and contexts (social/ cultural) are changing so much that there is no one absolute guide to adhere to
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	There is no formulaic answer.
</p>

<p>
	It's a delicate tight rope act. Following one's heart and intuition is a good rule of thumb. But that already assumes you've got a pure heart and goodÂ intuition, which not all people have.
</p>

<p>
	Mostly I keep myself safe by cross-referencing 100s of diverse sources and by understanding that my mind is self-deceptive.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 05:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408881</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nonduality and Flow-state</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34001-nonduality-and-flow-state/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408873</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408795" data-ipsquote-contentid="34001" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556070871" data-ipsquote-userid="12710" data-ipsquote-username="The Blind Sage">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		3 hours ago, The Blind Sage said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Is flow state a quasi 'mystical experience'?
		</p>

		<p>
			Whenever I get into flow (usually in high stake situations in sports, adventure sports etc) I will think right after the experience 'holy shit how did I manage to do that?'Â 
		</p>

		<p>
			Then I wonder-where did the 'I' go during that moment? My sense of self dissapeared for the duration and it it felt like time stopped...its quite difficult to subjectively explain the feeling because its so foreign.
		</p>

		<p>
			Hence, I was wondering if this is a glimpse into no-mind.Â How does flow state relate to nonduality?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	There is some similarity but it is also not really a mystical or nondual experience at all. You are still deeply unconscious in a flow state.
</p>

<p>
	It is similar in the sense that the sense of I is gone and thoughts are gone. But awakening is much more radical.
</p>

<p>
	Flow state shows you how nice it feels to not have ego controlling your life. But it gives you no understanding of what reality, Self, or God is.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 05:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408873</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Average IQ of actualised.org followers?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34007-average-iq-of-actualisedorg-followers/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408869</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408861" data-ipsquote-contentid="34007" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556083673" data-ipsquote-userid="14265" data-ipsquote-username="clouffy">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		10 minutes ago, clouffy said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> godddammit, why is he tricking us then?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You are tricking yourself.
</p>

<p>
	All spiritual sayings require proper interpretationÂ within the proper context.
</p>

<p>
	He is not necessarily saying what you think he is saying.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408861" data-ipsquote-contentid="34007" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556083673" data-ipsquote-userid="14265" data-ipsquote-username="clouffy">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		10 minutes ago, clouffy said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			being able to make the quantum leap/ shift in consciousness requires a certain type ofÂ <strong>logical intelligence</strong>Â toÂ <strong>conceptualise nonduality</strong>Â and untangle "spiritual concepts" using words/ lingustics as an entry point.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No, almost the opposite.Â 
</p>

<p>
	All that nonduality requires is to shut off the mind and sit in silence and concentrateÂ for long periods of time.
</p>

<p>
	Concepts and thinking are the #1 obstacle.
</p>

<p>
	Sitting in silence and not thinking is not so easy if you are addicted to thinking (which everyone is).
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 05:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408869</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;My Descent into the Alt-Right Pipeline&quot; Good video on internet radicalisation.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33875-my-descent-into-the-alt-right-pipeline-good-video-on-internet-radicalisation/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408862</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408828" data-ipsquote-contentid="33875" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556078666" data-ipsquote-userid="12536" data-ipsquote-username="Andreas">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Andreas said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			If this is such a great and advanced truth, why is it so that only you understand but not the greatest mathematicians working in number theory?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Not just I understand it. Thousands of people do. But most mathematicians don't because they don't question metaphysics. Their entire pursuit is conceptual.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Are they just too unconscious?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes
</p>

<p>
	Mathematical skill has littleÂ to do with one's level of consciousness.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Why should I, from my perspective, spend what seems like a very long time to try to figure out a question not even the greatest mathematicians know the answer to?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	If you don't care to know, then you will remain ignorant. Reality has no obligation to make itself known to lazy people.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Can you see how this might beÂ perceived as cultlike behaviour?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, from your perspective I sound dangerous, deluded, and crazy.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408837" data-ipsquote-contentid="33875" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556080789" data-ipsquote-userid="12536" data-ipsquote-username="Andreas">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		49 minutes ago, Andreas said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Then why is it not wrong to say that there is no such thing as Santa Claus if some kid tells me so? Am I being unconscious? <img alt="xD" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/laugh.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/laugh@2x.png 2x" title="xD" width="20" />Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That is a relative truth.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 05:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408862</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding duality VS none duality</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34005-understanding-duality-vs-none-duality/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408829</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	It's too advanced for you. Move on to a more basic self-help video.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 04:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408829</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;My Descent into the Alt-Right Pipeline&quot; Good video on internet radicalisation.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33875-my-descent-into-the-alt-right-pipeline-good-video-on-internet-radicalisation/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408826</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12536-andreas/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12536" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12536-andreas/" rel="">@Andreas</a> These are tricky metaphysical questions which I don't want to waste my time explaining unless I sense that I am talking to a very openminded person who is going to be capable of thinking outside the box.
</p>

<p>
	These things cannot be argued at you. You must take responsibility to contemplate them on your own.
</p>

<p>
	If you want to understand what 2+2=4 means, start by contemplating: What is a number? What is equality? What is truth?
</p>

<p>
	These are questions which takes years to contemplate.
</p>

<p>
	The greatest mathematicians on the planet do not understand such things. It cannot be explained to you in a forum post. This is very serious stuff. Argument, proof, and reason count for virtually nothing here because all of those have been co-opted by ego.
</p>

<p>
	If you truly understood what a number is, or what truth is, it would collapse your entire reality.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 03:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408826</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Average IQ of actualised.org followers?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/34007-average-iq-of-actualisedorg-followers/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408825</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408822" data-ipsquote-contentid="34007" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556077319" data-ipsquote-userid="14265" data-ipsquote-username="clouffy">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 minutes ago, clouffy said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			tho sadhguru talks aboutÂ <strong>everyone having equal capability in looking inwards</strong>
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	If that is true, why did Sadhguru need 2 lifetimes of practice?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 03:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408825</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;My Descent into the Alt-Right Pipeline&quot; Good video on internet radicalisation.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33875-my-descent-into-the-alt-right-pipeline-good-video-on-internet-radicalisation/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408790</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408789" data-ipsquote-contentid="33875" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556068589" data-ipsquote-userid="12536" data-ipsquote-username="Andreas">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		5 minutes ago, Andreas said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Yes of course I am unconsciousÂ because I disagreeÂ with your opinion. Stigmatization is not an argument. If you are so developed and understand all of this, why canâ€™tÂ you answer even one of my questions?Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I did answer your questions but you are incapable of understanding what I am saying because you insist on maintaining your paradigm.
</p>

<p>
	What I am telling you is outside that paradigm. So this conversation cannot go any further.
</p>

<p>
	You are not appreciating how tricky the mind is. You cannot trust anything your mind says. It's all games and lies.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 01:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408790</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;My Descent into the Alt-Right Pipeline&quot; Good video on internet radicalisation.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33875-my-descent-into-the-alt-right-pipeline-good-video-on-internet-radicalisation/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408787</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408786" data-ipsquote-contentid="33875" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556067814" data-ipsquote-userid="12536" data-ipsquote-username="Andreas">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		16 minutes ago, Andreas said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			How would the statement 2+2=4 not be right?Â 
		</p>

		<p>
			How come the â€˜highestâ€™ value of the â€˜most developedâ€™ stage be â€˜absolute truthâ€™ if there is no truth?Â 
		</p>

		<p>
			If there is no right or wrong, how come your statement that there is no right or wrong be right?Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You can't understand that at your current stage of development and consciousness.
</p>

<p>
	At your stage of cognitive development you simply take objective reality for granted, as a given. But there actually isn't such a thing.
</p>

<p>
	Your MIND is constructing "physical" "reality". The reality you construct is precisely of the sort which allows you to survive as yourself. Everything you consider "real" is filtered through your ego to make sure it allows the illusion of a self to survive as the illusion that it is, without you realizing that it is an illusion.
</p>

<p>
	If you weren't doing this, you'd be dead and a physical world would not exist.
</p>

<p>
	2+2=4 is a relative truth. It is true because you say it is and by how you situate it within your entire scheme of conceptual understanding. It is not an Absolute Truth.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 01:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408787</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>It's all fine and well being &quot;in the moment&quot;, but...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33796-its-all-fine-and-well-being-in-the-moment-but/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408784</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	This is why you cannot boil this work down to some stupid platitude like "be in the now".
</p>

<p>
	This work is much more complex and subtle than newbies imagine it to be.
</p>

<p>
	The ramifications of nondual awareness are enormous and they cannot be formalized.
</p>

<p>
	This is why post-awakening a lot of integration work is required. Your mind has to do work to figure out how to adopt Truth/Absolute to everyday life. And it is VERY EASY for your mind to distort the Truth and embody it incorrectly.
</p>

<p>
	Hitler could come to your house with a flamethrower and if you're naive, you might tell yourself something like, "Just be in the now" and that will be a huge mistake.
</p>

<p>
	It takes great intelligence to apply high spiritual teachings and principles. Newbies and fools will make terrible mistakes.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408784</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sadhguru, Building Spiritual Infrastructure in the World</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33983-sadhguru-building-spiritual-infrastructure-in-the-world/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408766</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408761" data-ipsquote-contentid="33983" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556064312" data-ipsquote-userid="2261" data-ipsquote-username="mandyjw">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		9 minutes ago, mandyjw said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>Â Dangers along the lines of getting into something "dark" or dangers with not being focused enough to go deep? Or both?Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Mostly dangers of being too unfocused or too conceptual.
</p>

<p>
	Theory and practice must be delicately balanced. Few people know how to strike this balance. They mostly veer off too much in one direction or the other.
</p>

<p>
	If you like my work, being too conceptual will be one of your biggest obstacles. If you don't like my work, studying too little theory will be one of your greatest obstacles.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408766</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;My Descent into the Alt-Right Pipeline&quot; Good video on internet radicalisation.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33875-my-descent-into-the-alt-right-pipeline-good-video-on-internet-radicalisation/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408762</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408444" data-ipsquote-contentid="33875" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556006886" data-ipsquote-userid="12324" data-ipsquote-username="Quicksilver">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		16 hours ago, Quicksilver said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Isnt this a great example on how self actualization and transcendence leads to the inability to act?
		</p>

		<p>
			We are here in a thread where not only we cannot agree on what is right vs wrong, but we cant also agree on the existence of the notions of right and wrong...Â 
		</p>

		<p>
			How are we gonna get anywhere?Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	There is no right or wrong. It's all relative to survival.
</p>

<p>
	Hence there is conflict and disagreement, and it will always exist.
</p>

<p>
	Action is not achieved through total consensus. Power prevails. There are winners and losers.
</p>

<p>
	Don't blame this on self-actualization or transcendence. This is life. You cannot escape survival dynamics.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408762</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sadhguru, Building Spiritual Infrastructure in the World</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33983-sadhguru-building-spiritual-infrastructure-in-the-world/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408758</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408757" data-ipsquote-contentid="33983" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556063796" data-ipsquote-userid="2261" data-ipsquote-username="mandyjw">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 minutes ago, mandyjw said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Should we just whore ourselves out indiscriminately to all religions and spiritual teachers without settling down with any of them then? I'm definitely starting to develop a wandering eye.Â <img alt="xD" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/laugh.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/laugh@2x.png 2x" title="xD" width="20" />
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	There are some dangers to that approach as well. There are dangers everywhere.
</p>

<p>
	But overall I am highly in favor of studying 100s of sources or you will become deluded. Then again, you will probably also become deluded if you study 100s of sources.
</p>

<p>
	It's hard to avoid delusion.
</p>

<p>
	Personally I study at least 100 sources and I know I would have been screwed by now if I hadn't.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 23:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408758</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408756</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408742" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556060874" data-ipsquote-userid="8874" data-ipsquote-username="Serotoninluv">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		48 minutes ago, Serotoninluv said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Do you think that some mind-bodies naturally resonate with psychedelics more than others? My mind-body was in full resonance from the beginning and that guy in the video is resonating with elf beings on low doses.Â Â Yet, some mind-bodiesÂ are more like â€œmeh, that was a waste of timeÂ and effortâ€.Â 
		</p>

		<p>
			It seems like most people could benefit from a few trips, yet I wonder if some people have natural traits and resonate 20x better with psychedelics.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, of course. Haven't we stated this already?
</p>

<p>
	"Psychedelics don't work on stupid people." -- Terence McKenna <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408746" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556062403" data-ipsquote-userid="7889" data-ipsquote-username="lostmedstudent">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		22 minutes ago, lostmedstudent said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> i dont have LSD at the moment, i have AL-LAD, would the starting dose be the same? half a blotter (i thinnk 75microg too)
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yeah, about the same.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 23:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408756</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sadhguru, Building Spiritual Infrastructure in the World</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33983-sadhguru-building-spiritual-infrastructure-in-the-world/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408752</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408740" data-ipsquote-contentid="33983" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556060676" data-ipsquote-userid="2261" data-ipsquote-username="mandyjw">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		48 minutes ago, mandyjw said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> It's incredible to me how lopsided people can be and still be awakened to some degree. I guess that can be called the grace of God. Perfection in imperfection.Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's because very few people understand the breadth of this work. It's not only deep, it's broad. Psychological and sociological aspects of it cannot be ignored the way that many narrow nondual teachings assume.
</p>

<p>
	An integral approach is not done by almost any teacher or school. Thus horrendous gaps result.
</p>

<p>
	A lot of spiritual folks are in denial about the work's breadth. They want it to be as simple as someone like Eckhart Tolle or Rupert Spira makes it seem. But it just isn't.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408743" data-ipsquote-contentid="33983" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556060973" data-ipsquote-userid="50" data-ipsquote-username="Empty">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		43 minutes ago, Empty said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> You are not humble at all, my friend!
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I am what I am.
</p>

<p>
	My function is to teach people here.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 23:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408752</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408730</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408729" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556059447" data-ipsquote-userid="13735" data-ipsquote-username="oMarcos">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 minutes ago, oMarcos said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			can you bad trip with 1g shroom, let's say, for the most sensitive fragile minds
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Sure
</p>

<p>
	You could give yourself a panic attack without even taking psychedelics. It all depends on how your use your mind.
</p>

<p>
	To trip well you need to be relatively emotionally even-keeled. If your emotions and mind are all over the place, if your life is mess, you're not stable enough to trip, the ego is too fragile and insecure. You need more basic personal development work first in that case.
</p>

<p>
	Tripping requires maturity and self-control.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 22:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408730</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sadhguru, Building Spiritual Infrastructure in the World</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33983-sadhguru-building-spiritual-infrastructure-in-the-world/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408723</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408699" data-ipsquote-contentid="33983" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556056575" data-ipsquote-userid="2261" data-ipsquote-username="mandyjw">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		47 minutes ago, mandyjw said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Â I'm just shocked that he doesn't know or sayÂ more about it when he does such intense Vipassana meditations.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I'm not really familiar with what he does.
</p>

<p>
	But it's very easy to do years of Vipassana but not be awakened or really understand the depth of consciousness work. In fact I would say that most Westerners who practice Vipassana have no idea what awakening or nonduality really are. Because they are following a very narrow practice on blind faith.
</p>

<p>
	I have met people who have done Vipassana for 5-15 years but have no idea what the world enlightenment means. Not to mention many other aspects of spiritual work.
</p>

<p>
	This work goes so deep and has so many layers to it that you should NEVER assume that a person who does any kind of practice is awake or understands spirituality. It's all too easy to turn spiritual practices into narrow robotic habits and dogmas.
</p>

<p>
	Sam Harris supposedly also does meditation and has even had some degree of realization of no-self. But his worldview is still thoroughly materialistic and dualistic, and he is still missing 98% of spirituality. This is extremely common in the West especially. Westerners tend to dabble in spirituality while thinking to themselves that they've figured it all out. This is to be expected.
</p>

<p>
	As a general rule of thumb:
</p>

<p>
	When someone talks about spirituality, does spirituality, or teaches spirituality -- NEVER, EVER assume that they are at the highest stages of it. Always be skeptical. Especially with Westerners. True masters are very rare. Fully comprehensive teachings are very rare.
</p>

<p>
	Most people who do spirituality are doing it very poorly, pathologically, and half-assing it. This is to be expected given that almost no one understands the full scope of the mind's self-deceptiveness.
</p>

<p>
	Even awakening will NOT make you immune to self-deception. So watch out!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 22:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408723</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 5-MeO-DMT Mega-Thread</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/8019-the-5-meo-dmt-mega-thread/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408719</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408703" data-ipsquote-contentid="8019" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556056877" data-ipsquote-userid="7889" data-ipsquote-username="lostmedstudent">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		29 minutes ago, lostmedstudent said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> hi Leo,
		</p>

		<p>
			will it be clear that it is a breakthrough?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, very clear.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			i am asking this because i have tried psychedelics 3 times now and my experiences can be summarized as follows: <strong>1st </strong>time shroom, very mild high, totally in touch with reality, did not have any insights <strong>2nd</strong> time ayahuasca in a ceremony, felt my body dissolve and panicked for about 30s, but also did not get any insights, <strong>3rd</strong> time, the worst yet, i took too big of a dose (shroom), and it was just plain weird, i totally lost contact with reality, like i couldnt tell whats real and whats a dream and i kind blacked out and was brought to the hospital... i remember during the peak that i had some realizations but because i overshot it, i dont remember much...
		</p>

		<p>
			what do you recommend in this situation? do you see some obvious mistakes in the way i am proceeding?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Sounds like you still haven't found the right sweet spot.
</p>

<p>
	Some substances are better/easier than others. Mushrooms can be twisted and hard to understand. Ayahausca can be overwhemling and very uncomfortable for newbies.
</p>

<p>
	What I recommend is tightening up your protocols and tripping in a very controlled manner.
</p>

<p>
	You could try the following routes:
</p>

<ul>
	<li>
		1g of mushrooms >> 2g of mushrooms >> 3g of mushrooms >> until you hit your sweet spot
	</li>
	<li>
		75ug of LSD >> 125ug of LSD >> 200ug of LSD >> 250ug of LSD >> until you hit your sweet spot
	</li>
</ul>

<p>
	This must be done in a good comfortable quiet setting, free of distractions, free of people, and other nonsense. You must do it on an empty stomach and you must sit still and contemplate about the nature of reality with your eyes open. Your intention must be pure & serious.
</p>

<p>
	If you did all that, I don't see how you wouldn't have some nice breakthroughs.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 22:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408719</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazing BatGap Interview - Harri Aalto (Enlightened Since 4)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33857-amazing-batgap-interview-harri-aalto-enlightened-since-4/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408714</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408698" data-ipsquote-contentid="33857" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556056507" data-ipsquote-userid="524" data-ipsquote-username="Lynnel">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		22 minutes ago, Lynnel said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Didn't you state somewhere that long-term psychedelic use was dangerous ? 60 trips seem like a crazy lot.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	60 trips is not a lot. That's just the beginning.
</p>

<p>
	That's like saying that 60 days of meditation is a lot when people meditate for 1000s of days to get amazing results.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 22:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408714</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408710</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408708" data-ipsquote-contentid="33950" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556057336" data-ipsquote-userid="2261" data-ipsquote-username="mandyjw">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 minutes ago, mandyjw said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> I know, my only concern is that if Trump was impeached before his term was up that we would beÂ in for even WORSE ego backlash. It's hard to know how long it needs to take to play out.Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That of course is unknown. It could get worse, it could get better. We don't really know.
</p>

<p>
	Impeachment might not be the right move. Voting him out would probably be the best solution. All of this will get resolved in the future.
</p>

<p>
	Worrying too much about backlash is not a good general approach because it's fear-based. Rather than worrying about how a devil will react against your good action, just act in the highest good. Deal with the consequences as they arise.
</p>

<p>
	Devils will always bitch and moan against progress. This does not mean that we appease the devils and stop pushing for progress. Sometimes a battle is necessary. Seeking to maintain peace at all costs is too simplistic a strategy for navigating the complexity of life and politics. A very delicate balancing act is required.
</p>

<p>
	Don't be a doormat for devils. The highest spiritual teachers are NOT doormats. Jesus, Gandhi, MLK, etc were very vocal against devilry.
</p>

<p>
	Just be careful that when standing up against devils you yourself do not become a devil. That is the great trap. It's very hard to avoid.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 22:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408710</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408707</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408705" data-ipsquote-contentid="33950" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556056950" data-ipsquote-userid="2261" data-ipsquote-username="mandyjw">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		7 minutes ago, mandyjw said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Trump is just fulfilling the role of ego backlash after having Obama in as President. What stage was Obama really? Yellow? Imagine being stage red or blue and having a stage yellow President. You're going to think he's the Devil.Â Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, that's right. But the question is, what are we gonna do about it? Hitler was also an ego backlash against the German loses in WWI.
</p>

<p>
	Be careful not to fall into a false fatalism here. Because you could easily make a fallacious argument like this: "Well, since Hitler was elected by the people, that must be the will of God, so I guess we should just let Hitler do whatever he wants."
</p>

<p>
	No! No! No! You get to decided every second what kind of reality you want to create. And deciding to let a Hitler run wild without limit would be a lack of responsibility.
</p>

<p>
	It was God's will that people elected Hitler. It was God's will that Hitler kill many Jews. But it was also God's will that Hitler was resisted, stopped, and killed. See? God's will is a very complex thing which waxes and wanes.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 22:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408707</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408702</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408700" data-ipsquote-contentid="33950" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556056746" data-ipsquote-userid="13735" data-ipsquote-username="oMarcos">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		3 minutes ago, oMarcos said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>Â in last video series (1 or 2 idk)Â you said that if there is a war, that's because it should be happening, isn't that the same as a tyrant being allowed to rule (even if it is temporary)?Â or were you truly meaning something else more subtleÂ 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, but what you're overlooking is that if we kick the tyrant out of power, that too SHOULD be happening.
</p>

<p>
	Reality is deciding itself in every moment. There is no fatalism in nonduality. You and we are all determining how we want reality to unfold. Do you want to sit by and let a tyrant run lose, or do you want to contain him? The choice is yours/ours. What kind of world do you want to create?
</p>

<p>
	This issue of will and choice is extremely subtle and sophisticated.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 22:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408702</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408697</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408694" data-ipsquote-contentid="33950" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556056043" data-ipsquote-userid="5317" data-ipsquote-username="How to be wise">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		11 minutes ago, How to be wise said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Is that really true? Why?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You'll understand when a tyrant locks you and your family in a cage.
</p>

<p>
	See, people are all cool with tyranny until they get on the receiving end of it. Then they hate tyranny with a passion.
</p>

<p>
	Most people are so myopic they never expect that their favorite tyrant would ever harm them. Not realizing that it is the modus operandi of tyrants to only care about themselves. Trump does not give a shit about you. He is like a rabid dog, which will bite its master.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 21:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408697</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazing BatGap Interview - Harri Aalto (Enlightened Since 4)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33857-amazing-batgap-interview-harri-aalto-enlightened-since-4/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408695</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408495" data-ipsquote-contentid="33857" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556012164" data-ipsquote-userid="11325" data-ipsquote-username="Enlightenment">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 hours ago, Enlightenment said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			And yet I awakened to some degree (no-self insight, stream-entry, Location 1, or whatever we may call it) literally after my first 20 minutes mantra meditation ever, which I did out of boredom when scrolling youtube and saw some TM video. Since then I moved way beyond that and also trained high concentration (this was actually harder for me than awakening).
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Well, that's extremely rare. I would call that a spiritual gift of its own.
</p>

<p>
	Yes, some people literally sit down, do a few days of meditation or inquiry and BAM! -- they awaken. But this is very, very rare. Don't count on that happening. Obviously if that happens, great! Consider yourself very lucky. You won the spiritual lottery.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 21:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408695</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What am I doing wrong?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33981-what-am-i-doing-wrong/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408690</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408421" data-ipsquote-contentid="33981" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556001704" data-ipsquote-userid="15633" data-ipsquote-username="Dlenger1">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		15 hours ago, Dlenger1 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> I already noticed that the intellectual answers are not authentic insights.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's good progress!
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I have no idea yet how I can experience something formless.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's the trick! There isn't a "how". Formlessness cannot be reached through any method or process. Formlessness just is. You are it. You cannot reach it through any steps because it is the zero-th step. It is impossibly direct.
</p>

<p>
	Although psychedelics can put you there in minutes.
</p>

<p>
	The reaching of formlessness is a spontaneous occurrence, like a lightning strike. You cannot predict it or make it happen. But you can increase the odds by intensifying your inquiry & concentration.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408454" data-ipsquote-contentid="33981" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556008673" data-ipsquote-userid="4000" data-ipsquote-username="Shaun">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		13 hours ago, Shaun said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> I experience that I am consciousness and all else is an appearance within but I don't understand how it is legitimate to say that the thoughts and feelings are not me. Consciousness is all there is and the thoughts and feelings are also consciousness, so how can they ultimately not be me?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Of course they are a part of you -- because everything is a part of you. But they are not essential to you. For example, a thought or feeling can arise and then disappear. It's disappearance does not change your essence. So what you are -- your essence -- is independent of all arising phenomena.
</p>

<p>
	What you're missing is that you must distinguish yourself from all form. You have to separate the formlessness which right now is intermixed and confused with various forms. Then, later, you will realize that formlessness and form are in fact identical. But at the same time, they can be distinguished! It's a paradox.
</p>

<p>
	Your first awakening experience is you realizing that formlessness is distinct from all form. It's you realizing that Consciousness/You is distinct from any content that arises.
</p>

<p>
	It's sort of like a TV realizing that it is distinct from the images it displays. In the unenlightened state you are like a TV which is attached to the forms it displays, not realizing that in fact all forms could disappear without affecting the TV's existence.
</p>

<p>
	What you are looking for with self-inquiry is PURE CONSCIOUSNESS. Consciousness without any forms.
</p>

<p>
	But be careful, what I said above does not mean that any particular forms must be eliminated. So don't get some silly idea in your head that your sensory field will somehow turn off or go black. That's not what I mean. I mean you must realize that the sensory field is always occurring within formlessness. Like water is always occurring within some container. The True Self is the container. Find yourself as the empty container which holds the world. Right now you are so identified with the world that you cannot see the transparent container.
</p>

<p>
	Form = the material world
</p>

<p>
	Formlessness = the transparent container which holds it
</p>

<p>
	And ultimately, Form = Formlessness
</p>

<p>
	That's what "nonduality" means: not two.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 21:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408690</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408682</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14744-aeris/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14744" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14744-aeris/" rel="">@Aeris</a> And what if Hitler was actually killing Jews for the good of the world? Should we allow him to keep doing that?
</p>

<p>
	Your mental gymnastics are impressive.
</p>

<p>
	Trump is a devil, plain and simple. There is no higher strategy with him.
</p>

<p>
	Of course in the Absolute sense, Trump is part of the total perfection. But that does not make him some strategic genius here to save mankind. If Trump is allowed free reign, he will cause a lot of harm. Such tyrants need to be stopped. The entire universe will conspire to stop his devilry. Or rather, his devilry will be the cause of his undoing.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 21:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408682</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why infinite intelligence made awakening hard to attain?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33947-why-infinite-intelligence-made-awakening-hard-to-attain/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408678</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408668" data-ipsquote-contentid="33947" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556051636" data-ipsquote-userid="10800" data-ipsquote-username="Mikael89">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		27 minutes ago, Mikael89 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			But people are now going to say: "They already are enlightened."
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That is a very dumb phrase. 99.999% of people are not enlightened.
</p>

<p>
	Enlightenment means consciousness of one's true nature. Without CONSCIOUSNESS of it, there is no enlightenment even though, yes, you are still God. But you don't know you're God, hence not enlightened.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 21:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408678</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sadhguru, Building Spiritual Infrastructure in the World</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33983-sadhguru-building-spiritual-infrastructure-in-the-world/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408674</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408442" data-ipsquote-contentid="33983" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556006494" data-ipsquote-userid="2261" data-ipsquote-username="mandyjw">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		12 hours ago, mandyjw said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			"My main ambition as a historian is to be able to tell the difference between what's really happening in the world and what are the fictions that humans have been creating for thousands of years in order to explain or in order to control what's happening in the world."
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Hehehe...
</p>

<p>
	That's a very tall order. That will require massive personal awakening.
</p>

<p>
	The problem is, all of history is a fiction. So he's gonna have a real hard time doing that within the context of history.
</p>

<p>
	The only way to achieve his goal is to become a mystic.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 20:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408674</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why infinite intelligence made awakening hard to attain?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33947-why-infinite-intelligence-made-awakening-hard-to-attain/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408664</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="407769" data-ipsquote-contentid="33947" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1555923355" data-ipsquote-userid="15598" data-ipsquote-username="Voladores">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 4/22/2019 at 1:55 AM, Voladores said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>Â Leo, I have a question aboutÂ this enlightenment thing, should one work towards it as soon as possible in life, or is it better to experience life fully in all aspects, and then when you're fed up with everything, you can transcend yourself? Sometimes it seems to meÂ that many people are obsessed with becoming enlightened just because they can't tolerate themselves anymore, and use it as spiritual bypassing.Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You must discover what is right for you. You must walk your own path.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 20:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408664</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Politics and spirituality (duality video part 1)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33950-politics-and-spirituality-duality-video-part-1/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408662</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408649" data-ipsquote-contentid="33950" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1556046740" data-ipsquote-userid="11463" data-ipsquote-username="Pouya">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Pouya said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> unfortunately I can't see politics with higher consciuosness.
		</p>

		<p>
			I consider politics as massive ego games. How can it be really spiritual?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	EVERYTHING IS SPIRITUAL. It's just a question of how conscious are you about whatever you are doing. How conscious is your job, your business, your family, your relationships, your friendships, your finances, your entertainment, your art, your government, your politics, your science, your speech, your thinking, your emotions, etc.
</p>

<p>
	Spiritual just means: degree of consciousness, from zero to infinity.
</p>

<p>
	Low spirituality = massive ego, massive devilry, maximum suffering
</p>

<p>
	High spirituality = little ego, unconditional love & goodness, minimal suffering
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 20:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408662</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fasting before an LSD trip</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33885-fasting-before-an-lsd-trip/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408420</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	It's not necessary to fast or have a special diet for long before the trip. Just make sure you trip on at least 4 hours of empty stomach and it will be fine.
</p>

<p>
	Fruits are good prior to and after the trip. Although usually after a deep trip I get very hungry and need more food than just some fruit. So have snacks handy. Often times I will half-way into the trip, and it creates no problems. As long as you're past the peak. Don't snack until you're past the peak.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 06:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408420</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Human characteristics and qualities</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33982-human-characteristics-and-qualities/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408417</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13487-nistake/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="13487" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13487-nistake/" rel="">@nistake</a> Every creature has a unique personality. Do not confuse this primordial personality with ego or with social conditioning. This primordial personality will remain even after total enlightenment.
</p>

<p>
	Even cats and dogs have these primordial personalities. No two cats have an identical personality.
</p>

<p>
	Because every brain is unique, just like every computer hard drive is unique.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 06:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408417</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What am I doing wrong?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33981-what-am-i-doing-wrong/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408414</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15633-dlenger1/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="15633" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/15633-dlenger1/" rel="">@Dlenger1</a> The intellectual questions are a good beginning point, but ultimately you have to graduate from that to basically just sitting in silence with a calm mind and focusing intensely on "the seer" or consciousness itself. Just sit and kinda stare at consciousness itself.
</p>

<p>
	The problem with asking too many questions is that the mind then gets in the mood of giving verbal answers, which is never going to be enough.
</p>

<p>
	The Neti Neti method is helpful here. Anything you identify as yourself, you must negate by realizing that that thing or property cannot be the True Self.
</p>

<p>
	What you're really looking for is formlessness. "The seer" is formlessness. So any from you think you are cannot be it. And you have to be very careful about not thinking "I am formlessness" because that is still form!
</p>

<p>
	This is supposed to be frustrating process and it takes intense concentration to break through. You will not break through if you do this process without intensity and consistency. 20 minutes of inquiry is just not going to produce enough intensity for a breakthrough. It's very important to schedule some long periods of time for nothing but inquiry. Like a solid week of full-time 12-hours-per-day inquiry. That is how people break through in practice. You must concentrate on it like an obsessive psychopath.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 06:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408414</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazing BatGap Interview - Harri Aalto (Enlightened Since 4)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33857-amazing-batgap-interview-harri-aalto-enlightened-since-4/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408401</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408398" data-ipsquote-contentid="33857" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1555995207" data-ipsquote-userid="7840" data-ipsquote-username="kieranperez">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		32 minutes ago, kieranperez said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Towards?... and I donâ€™t just mean God... donâ€™t play coy <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The only thing you will ever find in the universe is yourself. Deeper and deeper layers of yourself.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 05:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408401</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazing BatGap Interview - Harri Aalto (Enlightened Since 4)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33857-amazing-batgap-interview-harri-aalto-enlightened-since-4/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408395</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="408381" data-ipsquote-contentid="33857" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1555986579" data-ipsquote-userid="8874" data-ipsquote-username="Serotoninluv">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Serotoninluv said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Do you think that once the egoic noise dissolves that psychedelics can heightened oneâ€™s natural spiritual abilities? After 60 or so trips, there seemed to be a shift in my mind/bodyâ€™s relationship with reality.Â 
		</p>

		<p>
			I donâ€™t contact beings or go omniscient - yet I often get taken to hyper empathic paranormal zones. A couple times, itâ€™s like I have a type of magic wand.Â 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yeah, something like that. Trips definitely change you and open you if you do enough of them. It's not just a temporary high, it's an upwards arch.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 04:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408395</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amazing BatGap Interview - Harri Aalto (Enlightened Since 4)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33857-amazing-batgap-interview-harri-aalto-enlightened-since-4/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408394</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7840-kieranperez/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7840" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7840-kieranperez/" rel="">@kieranperez</a>Â Definitely don't go chasing mystical perfection.
</p>

<p>
	Do you! Just do you.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 04:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408394</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, did you need a wingman to have success in dating?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33899-leo-did-you-need-a-wingman-to-have-success-in-dating/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408382</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="407232" data-ipsquote-contentid="33899" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1555837712" data-ipsquote-userid="10053" data-ipsquote-username="billiesimon">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 4/21/2019 at 2:08 AM, billiesimon said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			But can I get good results if I choose to practice solo?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Sure, but will you actually do it? That's the issue. Solo is much harder emotionally.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 02:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408382</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Craving for women</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33723-craving-for-women/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408380</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="404245" data-ipsquote-contentid="33723" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1555397925" data-ipsquote-userid="13752" data-ipsquote-username="luqqzr">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 4/15/2019 at 11:58 PM, luqqzr said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Why I'm so EXTREMELY addicted to sexy bodies of women, I don't know either.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You and every other man on the planet. LOL
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 02:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408380</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>I am not good enough to get a girlfriend</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/33779-i-am-not-good-enough-to-get-a-girlfriend/?do=findComment&amp;comment=408379</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="406028" data-ipsquote-contentid="33779" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1555646583" data-ipsquote-userid="11839" data-ipsquote-username="theking00">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 4/18/2019 at 9:03 PM, theking00 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I approached 5 girls in the last 3 monthsÂ 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's the problem. You should be approaching twice that number per day.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 02:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">408379</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>