<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=content&amp;type=forums_topic_post</link>
<description><![CDATA[Leo Gura - Actualized.org Forum]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 12:28:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Banning Any Critique on Actualized.Org?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30425-banning-any-critique-on-actualizedorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=354300</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/596-smd/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="596" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/596-smd/" rel="">@smd</a> I received various private messages from people who were hurt by Rali's cult.
</p>

<p>
	It's very easy for stuff like this to get out of hand, so don't take it for granted.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">354300</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, did you see this coming?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30371-leo-did-you-see-this-coming/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353702</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7840-kieranperez/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7840" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7840-kieranperez/" rel="">@kieranperez</a> It sounds to me like you need to focus on handling some of your basic survival needs. Learn to survive in the world a bit more so that you develop a knack for success and getting stuff done. As you meet those lower level needs, you'll be ready to move up into higher needs.
</p>

<p>
	A skyscraper must be built on a solid foundation. Don't worry about spending a few years learning how to do business. Business is important to learn. Practical skills are important to learn. You want to handle all of your survival needs so that then you have lots of free time to delve into spirituality, art, etc. It's kinda hard to do art when you can't pay your bills.
</p>

<p>
	Learning to get practical stuff done is part of your developmental growth. I had to learn a lot of practical stuff before I could get Actualized.org off the ground. Actualized.org runs due to practical know-how, not airy-fairy spiritual ideas.
</p>

<p>
	Go learn to be a programmer or whatever you need to move you along towards your dreams. I learned lots of scripting and programming because it is so useful.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 06:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353702</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Views on God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30445-views-on-god/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353700</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="353679" data-ipsquote-contentid="30445" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547614818" data-ipsquote-userid="9510" data-ipsquote-username="Angelo John Gage">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, Angelo John Gage said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			The reason why I say "believe" is because I'm trying to be unbiased in the video, (I say In my opinion, etc) and not act like I know for a fact,
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	I get that.
</p>

<p>
	Then again, it's almost a lie then. Because in fact for you it is more than a belief.
</p>

<p>
	But maybe I'm just splitting hairs here.
</p>

<p>
	The trick when talking about God is that you're damned if you do and damned if you don't. If you say it's just your opinion or belief, that is untrue and gives the wrong impression. If you say that it is Absolute Truth, that makes you sounds like a fundamentalist nutcase, and also gives the wrong impression.
</p>

<p>
	It's like we are afraid to say the truth because we know no one would believe us. So we play coy.
</p>

<p>
	Just food for thought.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 06:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353700</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Views on God</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30445-views-on-god/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353669</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9510-angelo-john-gage/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9510" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9510-angelo-john-gage/" rel="">@Angelo John Gage</a> A decent explanation of a very tricky topic.
</p>

<p>
	I noticed you saying several times that you "believe" this.
</p>

<p>
	What is your direct experience of God?
</p>

<p>
	If I was shooting a video like this (and I do have this topic planned for the future as a video), I would make sure to stress that God is not a belief, or a theory, or a speculation, but a direct experience which the viewer can have. This is what's most amazing about God: you can realize it for yourself! This is what most people misunderstand. A newbie watching your video would walk away with the idea that what you're talking about it is just a philosophical theory of God. The viewer would think, "Well, how does this guy know? He's just theorizing. This is just his opinion."
</p>

<p>
	It's absolutely critical to plant the seed in the viewer's mind that consciousness of God is a real thing and requires doing concrete practices. Otherwise God forever remains an idea. The whole point of such a video would be to get people to realize that they must start doing the necessary practices.
</p>

<p>
	Other distinctions which might have been useful are realism vs idealism, and esoteric vs exoteric versions of religion. Really what your video was debunking were the exoteric versions of God. All mainstream religions are exoteric. Most religious people don't even know that esoteric religion is possible.
</p>

<p>
	It's a very tricky topic, so you did a decent job.
</p>

<p>
	The tricky thing about God is, it's both deeply personal and impersonal, encompassing every set of attributes.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 04:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353669</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The universe is a freaking miracle...</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30442-the-universe-is-a-freaking-miracle/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353658</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Indeed it is <img alt=":)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/smile.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/smile@2x.png 2x" title=":)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	The holiest of holies.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 04:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353658</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>*Important Question* Will these drug testing reagents work?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30447-important-question-will-these-drug-testing-reagents-work/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353652</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12243-aaron-p/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12243" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12243-aaron-p/" rel="">@Aaron p</a> The most important test is called Ehrlich. It mostly tests for psychedelic Indoles.
</p>

<p>
	Those other tests are be useful too for filtering out other harmful agents (you don't want to find meth in your psychedelic), but you need a positive test for Indoles.
</p>

<p>
	There is no test kit that's able to distinguish 5-MeO-DMT from other Indoles. And freebase vs HCl is not something you can test with a kit. The kit don't care.
</p>

<p>
	Test kits are not to be fully trusted. Which is why you always want to test new substances with very small doses to verify your batch is what it claims to be.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 03:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353652</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How evolved is Joe Rogan and people like him?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30451-how-evolved-is-joe-rogan-and-people-like-him/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353648</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Joe is a decent guy for what he's doing. You just have to understand that his show is not about spirituality or personal development or truth or consciousness or serious science. It's basically about mainstream gossip. It's a gossip show with some tidbits of wisdom. But also a lot of egotistical nonsense. It's not designed to be a spiritual path. It's designed to be fun gossip. And if you think of it on those terms, it's great. Not everything has to be ultra serious and profound.
</p>

<p>
	But if you expect to become deeply woke listening to his show, then you'll be disappointed.
</p>

<p>
	Relative to other talk show hosts, Joe is pretty wise & evolved. But then again, that's not the highest of bars to clear.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 03:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353648</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Banning Any Critique on Actualized.Org?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30425-banning-any-critique-on-actualizedorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353646</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="353643" data-ipsquote-contentid="30425" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547609455" data-ipsquote-userid="11730" data-ipsquote-username="TheAvatarState">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		11 minutes ago, TheAvatarState said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			"But Leooooo, you bash Sam Harris and Jordan Peterson all the time in your talks! Does that make you a hypocrite?"
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	If you think it's bad now, you have no idea how bad the bashing would be if I really let loose <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	I have never properly bashed them. So far I've only made minor counterpoints to stave off very basic ignorance that I see some of my viewers have learned from them.
</p>

<p>
	In the end, they cannot help being exactly who they are. So what would be the point of my ranting?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 03:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353646</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Banning Any Critique on Actualized.Org?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30425-banning-any-critique-on-actualizedorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353637</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="353636" data-ipsquote-contentid="30425" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547607669" data-ipsquote-userid="2824" data-ipsquote-username="Toby">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		36 minutes ago, Toby said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			That is not necessarily true. There are different teaching strategies. For example, if someone has an approach like UG Krishnamurti or Karl Renz the "bashing" (or making fun of) includes almost everything and everyone. "Unconditional hate" as Karl likes to say.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That is not masterful teaching. That kind of polarized teaching style does a disservice to students, as it makes them ideological and emotionally reactive. Teachers who teach like that are themselves not fully developed & conscious.
</p>

<p>
	I myself have had to back off that style as I become more conscious. It is a disservice to you guys. Because in truth, there is no one to blame for anything. Everyone is doing their best, even terrorists, Nazis, psychopaths, and cult leaders. They cannot help being who they are and the proper response to their situation is understanding and compassion, not hate or ridicule.
</p>

<p>
	For example, I've wanted to shoot a rant video against JP for a long time now. But I hold myself back because I would rather take the high road. Even though a rant video against JP would get me lots of views and clicks and approval -- it would also make you guys more ideological against him and distract from doing the inner work. So I bite my tongue.
</p>

<p>
	You see, the ego's whole game is to get you to avoid doing the inner work by any means possible. So ego loves to externalize the problem and make it about something "out there" -- some teacher, some teaching, some other group of people, some culture war issue, some political scandal, some latest outrage -- anything to avoid self-reflection.
</p>

<p>
	I have no interest in getting into public battles with anyone or defending my work. I just want to work on myself and be creative without any justifications for my work. My work speaks for itself. If you find my work useful, then use it. If not, then leave and pursue other things. Telling me you disagree with my work is unnecessary. I know better than most of you the flaws and limitations of my own work. I don't need guidance from a random cocky Youtuber who does not know anything about me. I get my internal guidance from a much higher quality, non-human source.
</p>

<p>
	And in the end if you feel my guidance is bad or wrong, don't follow me. I am not here to be right, or perfect, or the Buddha, or your daddy figure. From the very beginning the only function of Actualized.org was to catalogue various insights that I have that I find interesting. That's all this is. There is no pretense to Truth in my teachings since all teachings are concepts and by definition partial and untrue.
</p>

<p>
	Anything that you hear me say is ultimately nonsense. It was that way from day one, and it could not be otherwise. From the very beginning my work is was meant to be self-effacing. Like a snake eating its own tail, such that in the end, nothing remains.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 03:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353637</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Banning Any Critique on Actualized.Org?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30425-banning-any-critique-on-actualizedorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353632</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="353601" data-ipsquote-contentid="30425" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547599211" data-ipsquote-userid="6221" data-ipsquote-username="Matt23">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, Matt23 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a>, my question is how do you "smell" or know if someone has an ulterior motive?  
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	It's an intuitive high-level hunch based on subtle cues.
</p>

<p>
	Then again, often these people display their egotism in very obvious ways. For example, no serious teacher would make the core of his teaching the bashing of other teachers. That's an obvious red flag. That's ego reaction, not genuine teaching. People who spend a lot of their time and energy criticizing other teachers or teachings automatically reveal their own lack of consciousness, as all criticism is ultimately untenable and absurd. Reality cannot be otherwise, so there is nothing wrong and no one to blame. When you become deeply conscious, the desire to criticize anything falls away entirely, because it is an ego-game.
</p>

<p>
	The more conscious you become of the devil within you, the easier it becomes to spot Zen devils and their tactics. After years of doing this work you will smell ego from miles away because you've studied it so deeply within yourself.
</p>

<p>
	Watch out for people who make a lot of noise and stir up controversy needlessly, over and over again. This is a very popular online marketing tactic of late. People like Trump, JP, Mike Cernovich, Steven Crowder, Alex Jones, Sam Harris, etc. are master manipulators in this regard. Any cult leader wannabe is going to be a master manipulator & bullshit artist.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 02:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353632</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Banning Any Critique on Actualized.Org?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30425-banning-any-critique-on-actualizedorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353399</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	You have to understand the trickeries of running such a community.
</p>

<p>
	I crack down on stuff like this immediately because egos will not hesitate to exploit this community to build their own cults and brands.
</p>

<p>
	People like Rali and TJ turn criticism into a marketing strategy. The strategy is to stir up a fake controversy to gain views and free advertizing. In my book, this is unacceptable. What they are looking for is attention, which is why they are denied any air whatsoever.
</p>

<p>
	If you want to criticize me or Actualized.org, go for it. I don't care. But I am not going to let you turn it into a marketing strategy, nor will I allow you to poach members to start your own movement or brand because I do not trust your devilish ego to create a non-cult community.
</p>

<p>
	The mistake people make is they get a little taste of self-actualization or spirituality and then they think they got what it takes to teach or run a spiritual community. But they are so ignorant of the dangers involved.
</p>

<p>
	I take great care to make sure Actualized.org never becomes a harmful ideological organization. People who I judge to be building harmful ideological organizations are not allowed here. 
</p>

<p>
	There's nothing new here. This has happened before and it will happen again. Every year a new Zen devil comes here to start his cult. I spot such devils immediately. I smell them a mile away. I spotted Rali very early on. The trouble is, they cleverly exploit this because a healthy community must allow criticism. So it becomes a PR problem banning such people because it makes me look like an insecure tyrannt. So it's a tricky balance to strike because they will abuse this to craft their marketing strategy.
</p>

<p>
	The bottom line is, if you guys wish to criticize myself or Actualized.org in a serious way, go for it. I will not close such a thread, but if you do it as a marketing strategy or you are doing it from a place of ego as a distraction, then it will be shut down.
</p>

<p>
	The trick with criticism is that the ego loves to use it to muddy up the waters so much that people get lost and confused. It easily becomes a distraction from doing the work. It's so easy to create fake controversy and milk that cow. But even so, criticism and receptivity to feedback is necessary in any healthy community / organization.
</p>

<p>
	So I welcome constructive criticism and feedback which has no ulterior business motive.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 19:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353399</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Theosis: Non-duality in Eastern Orthodox Church?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30416-theosis-non-duality-in-eastern-orthodox-church/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353129</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Of course
</p>

<p>
	All religion is nondual teaching in some sense. The only question is, How much has the teaching been corrupted? And, How well is its original intention understood?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 10:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353129</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Another weed awakening.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30414-another-weed-awakening/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353126</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12243-aaron-p/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12243" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12243-aaron-p/" rel="">@Aaron p</a> Point to one thing which isn't the Truth. It is impossible because Truth has no opposite and non-truth doesn't exist.
</p>

<p>
	Truth is all around you. You're just failing to recognize it as such because you're holding Truth as a concept. Truth is not a concept, Truth is being.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 10:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353126</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pickup is being criminalized</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30393-pickup-is-being-criminalized/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353122</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13748-eric-tarpall/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="13748" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13748-eric-tarpall/" rel="">@Eric Tarpall</a> Enough of this Red Pill BS.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 10:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353122</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Best books on starting a business</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30392-best-books-on-starting-a-business/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353120</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/4497-taavi/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="4497" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/4497-taavi/" rel="">@Taavi</a> That kinds of detailed how-to information is gonna be found in courses and seminars, not books.
</p>

<p>
	Serious business training is never done through books. Books are too cheap for that.
</p>

<p>
	Try taking a $1000 course or $3000 seminar. That's where you'll learn practical stuff. No one is going to put that information into a $20 book.
</p>

<p>
	Serious business advice is very costly. Because if it's any good, it's worth tens of thousands of dollars.
</p>

<p>
	At $10,000 business seminar is not unreasonable.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 10:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353120</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Another weed awakening.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30414-another-weed-awakening/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353113</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11807-inflow/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11807" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11807-inflow/" rel="">@inFlow</a> God / Nirvana / The Absolute / Awakening, etc.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 10:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353113</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Another weed awakening.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30414-another-weed-awakening/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353108</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="353098" data-ipsquote-contentid="30414" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547543231" data-ipsquote-userid="11807" data-ipsquote-username="inFlow">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		47 minutes ago, inFlow said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Everything is a distraction from the truth. Family, friends, work, relationships, even my own wife is a distraction for me. But I really do mean <strong>EVERYTHING</strong>.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, but EVERYTHING is also identical to Truth.
</p>

<p>
	So here we are <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 09:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353108</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Opinion :-&gt; Judging</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30375-opinion-judging/?do=findComment&amp;comment=353078</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="352955" data-ipsquote-contentid="30375" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547512173" data-ipsquote-userid="12728" data-ipsquote-username="Shadowraix">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		6 hours ago, Shadowraix said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Judgment and opinion come down to the same thing.
		</p>

		<p>
			When people tell you not to judge it's a phrase loaded with meaning. it's basically saying your judgment has incomplete information due to not knowing someone in entirety. It's also asking to not project how you think on others as everyone has built their own perspective on the world.
		</p>

		<p>
			It's loaded with meaning to try and shun away negativity.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No, you are misunderstanding what judgment is.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 07:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">353078</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What are the traps with actualized.org?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30388-what-are-the-traps-with-actualizedorg/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352942</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8623-leo-kaminski/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8623" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8623-leo-kaminski/" rel="">@Leo Kaminski</a> Your biggest trap is going to be mistaking the map for the territory.
</p>

<p>
	See the episode: What Is Actuality?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352942</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>If it's all a fantasy, why even live it?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30330-if-its-all-a-fantasy-why-even-live-it/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352643</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	This entire conversation is devolving into masturbation and confusion.
</p>

<p>
	There is no difference between enlightenment in Buddhism and Hinduism or any other major religion.
</p>

<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12971-emanyalpsid/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12971" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12971-emanyalpsid/" rel="">@Emanyalpsid</a> Stop spreading misinformation.
</p>

<p>
	Stop talking about nonduality on this forum and do the work.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 11:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352643</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, did you see this coming?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30371-leo-did-you-see-this-coming/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352640</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="352569" data-ipsquote-contentid="30371" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547448833" data-ipsquote-userid="7840" data-ipsquote-username="kieranperez">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 hours ago, kieranperez said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			do you think you could’ve predicted this kinda personal growth, consciousness, understanding to the degree that you feel?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Not in the slightest.
</p>

<p>
	But I did have a powerful vision for my life, I was very ambitious, and I was following my heart. Which is really all that matters.
</p>

<p>
	You are young. You've got many years to put all of those things in place. Obviously don't waste time sitting around on your ass, but don't panic either.
</p>

<p>
	Right now what you're missing is hope and faith in your vision.
</p>

<p>
	Vision is useless if you don't have rock-solid faith in it. You need to train yourself to believe in it. Visualize it every day with a hopeful vibe. Do not visualize it pessimistically, negatively, full of fear. That is terrible. That is counter-productive.
</p>

<p>
	Holding a big vision is not easy. It is scary. Your mind will not believe it is possible. I used all sorts of mind programming techniques to reinforce my vision and overcome various doubts. But the most important thing is HEART! You must have HEART! That is what carries you through everything. Your life purpose must be non-negotiable. You are doing it no matter what. There should be no option for failure because you already know there is nothing else you'd rather do.
</p>

<p>
	There will hundreds of doubts in this journey. You have to really cultivate hope. Not in luck, but in your hard work. Your vision will get actualized through honest labor.
</p>

<p>
	And remember, a big vision requires lots of patience. You don't need to be Buddha by next month. Recalibrate your exceptions and split your vision up into smaller chunks, so you are not evaluating your progress based on whether you are like Ralston or Buddha. That may not happen for 40 years. And that's okay, you don't need that to enjoy your life.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 11:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352640</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Opinion :-&gt; Judging</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30375-opinion-judging/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352638</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6386-alex-balex/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6386" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6386-alex-balex/" rel="">@Alex bAlex</a> Contemplate: What is judgment?
</p>

<p>
	Locate judgment and observe it in your direct experience.
</p>

<p>
	You guys need to start locating all of terminology in your direct experience.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 11:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352638</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Red Pill on what attracts women: Looks, Money, Status: BRUTAL</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/20193-the-red-pill-on-what-attracts-women-looks-money-status-brutal/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352636</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Locking this because Red Pill is toxic garbage.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 11:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352636</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How can I have a glimpse of awakening?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30356-how-can-i-have-a-glimpse-of-awakening/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352633</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/174-bazera/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="174" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/174-bazera/" rel="">@bazera</a> You've been told exactly what to do. You're just not doing it. And there's no solution to that other than to do it.
</p>

<p>
	Being desperate for a glimpse is only going to get in the way.
</p>

<p>
	Discipline yourself to do the work.
</p>

<p>
	Or don't and suffer.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 10:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352633</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What country(s) allows you to live rest of your life as if you were living in a cave?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30344-what-countrys-allows-you-to-live-rest-of-your-life-as-if-you-were-living-in-a-cave/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352529</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11312" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/" rel="">@CreamCat</a> Study some political history. You have no idea what you are talking about and you take government completely for granted.
</p>

<p>
	Without government you'd be a slave right now feeding some dictator grapes after he cut off your balls.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 03:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352529</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is it a good idea to do Lsd alone if it’s your first time?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30139-is-it-a-good-idea-to-do-lsd-alone-if-it%E2%80%99s-your-first-time/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352285</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Tripping alone is my fave.
</p>

<p>
	125ug of LSD is about as powerful as 2-3g of dried mushrooms.
</p>

<p>
	Of course potencies can vary. A lot of LSD dosages are exaggerated. So if your source isn't good, a 125ug dose could actually be 70ug, which would be a weak trip. 125ug is a nice solid trip for me, but still very managable, still possible to walk around.
</p>

<p>
	At 300ug you probably wouldn't be able to walk.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 19:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352285</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Eckhart tolle teaching a way to enlightment ?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30343-is-eckhart-tolle-teaching-a-way-to-enlightment/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352277</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13574-shugendora/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="13574" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13574-shugendora/" rel="">@ShugendoRa</a> The issue is: What daily practices are you doing? For how long? How seriously are you doing them?
</p>

<p>
	Nothing else really matters. That is the key. Without serious practices you will never get enlightened.
</p>

<p>
	Which teacher you listen to doesn't really matter if you don't have your practices down. And once you have your practices down you hardly need a teacher at all. That is the paradox of spiritual work. No one can do it for you.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 19:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352277</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Insights into &quot;Truth&quot; from psychedelics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30299-insights-into-truth-from-psychedelics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352272</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="352253" data-ipsquote-contentid="30299" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547405567" data-ipsquote-userid="5317" data-ipsquote-username="How to be wise">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		22 minutes ago, How to be wise said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> ‘Truth’ is a concept. All words beget ideas. Truth included.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	"Truth" is a pointer to actuality or Being, which is not a concept.
</p>

<p>
	If you hold truth as a concept, then yes, for you it is a concept, but that is not was pointed to by the word "Truth".
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 19:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352272</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>are you one with the universe or just the room you're in?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30346-are-you-one-with-the-universe-or-just-the-room-youre-in/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352270</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1608-isabel/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1608" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1608-isabel/" rel="">@isabel</a> Both!
</p>

<p>
	First you will realize you are the whole room.
</p>

<p>
	Then you will realize you stretch out in all directions and dimensions forever.
</p>

<p>
	You are every room that has ever been or will ever be.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 19:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352270</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What country(s) allows you to live rest of your life as if you were living in a cave?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30344-what-countrys-allows-you-to-live-rest-of-your-life-as-if-you-were-living-in-a-cave/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352257</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7932-moreira/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7932" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7932-moreira/" rel="">@Moreira</a> Yes, there are many hippies and bums in Hawaii. But I did not say living on the beach like a bum. I said buying your own land and building a small shack. That is very doable if you save up some money. In Hawaii you can even live off the grid using solar panels and a rainwater catchment tank. Heating and A/C are virtually unnecessary there.
</p>

<p>
	See my Hawaii solo retreat blog videos.
</p>

<p>
	Also, you don't need to slave. Learning how to make money is not hard. There many ways to earn six figures per year and enjoy the process. You just need a vision to do it. You can't be doing it out of a desire to become a bum. Cultivate a desire to genuinely contribute to humanity. It is so much more fulfilling and pays well when properly designed.
</p>

<p>
	Learn some business, sales, and marketing skills. This is easily acheieved online through courses, workshops, audios, and books.
</p>

<p>
	You also need a plan for getting old. Your health will worsen and so will your ability to work. Healthcare ain't cheap. Don't take stuff like healthcare for granted. Without government you'd probably die in your 50's or 60's due to lack of healthcare, disablity, etc.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 18:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352257</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Struggling to accept Spirituality as Real</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30342-struggling-to-accept-spirituality-as-real/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352251</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7997-mm1988/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7997" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7997-mm1988/" rel="">@MM1988</a> Like I said before, the problem is you have not had your first serious mystical experience, so you are doubtful.
</p>

<p>
	The solution is to have it.
</p>

<p>
	This can be done easily with 1 hour using psychedelics. Which is precisely why they are such an important tool. Advanced practitions do not need psychedelics because they are aleady had many mystical experiences and are fully bought in. Newbies need psychedelics to show them what they are missing, what it would take them 10 years of harcore practice to glimpse.
</p>

<p>
	Psychedelics are the scientific way of finding God. They are totally empircal and easily replicatable. Clinically proven beyond any placebo or doubt. That's what makes them such useful tool. Never before in human history has there such an easy route to spirituality for newbies as with today's modern psychedelics.
</p>

<p>
	This issue of doubting mysticism is utterly unneccessary in today's age. You might as well be doubting kangroos. If you doubt so much, why not just go to the zoo and pet a kangroo? It costs $30 and takes 1 hr.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 18:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352251</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>If it's all a fantasy, why even live it?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30330-if-its-all-a-fantasy-why-even-live-it/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352244</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="352005" data-ipsquote-contentid="30330" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547380369" data-ipsquote-userid="11567" data-ipsquote-username="Sockrattes">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		6 hours ago, Sockrattes said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			So would you say Buddhas teachings about Nirvana and Jesus teaching about the kingdom of God are wrong?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	No, you are just misunderstanding their teachings.
</p>

<p>
	THIS is the kingdom of God! Heaven is EVERYWHERE! Just lose that ego.
</p>

<p>
	There is no salvation elsewhere unless you find it right here, right now.
</p>

<p>
	Nirvana is ego-death.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 18:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352244</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What country(s) allows you to live rest of your life as if you were living in a cave?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30344-what-countrys-allows-you-to-live-rest-of-your-life-as-if-you-were-living-in-a-cave/?do=findComment&amp;comment=352237</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="352132" data-ipsquote-contentid="30344" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547395038" data-ipsquote-userid="12246" data-ipsquote-username="non_nothing">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		2 hours ago, non_nothing said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			But the obstacle is "governments" and their stupid taxes such as property/income/breathing/farting taxes. I won't be ever contributing to society and neither do they to me.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	This is extremely ignorant thinking.
</p>

<p>
	Without government you would not even be able to live in a house in the forest because some gang would come slit your throat in the middle of the night or enslave you and seize your house. Without goverment you would not even have enough education to know what a country is! You would not have the internet, or property rights, you would not even know how to read or write, and many other things that you take for granted.
</p>

<p>
	Hawaii has very low property tax and the land there can be very cheap on the Big Island. You can buy plots of land for $30,000 and Hawaii weather is so nice you can basically live in a tent or a yurt and grow your own fruits and have chickens for eggs. Although food and construction in Hawaii costs about 1.5x more than mainland USA.
</p>

<p>
	But don't expect survival to be free. That is just ignorance.
</p>

<p>
	Rather than planning to be a leech, think of ways you can contribute to society. You will be much happier that way. It is not that hard for example to set up your own farm and meditation retreat center.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 18:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">352237</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Taking an antidepressant during the dark night of the soul</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30272-taking-an-antidepressant-during-the-dark-night-of-the-soul/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351992</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14417-ninie/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14417" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14417-ninie/" rel="">@Ninie</a> You can't think you way out of this problem. You must make a distinction between thinking this stuff and observation of actuality. Less thinking, more observation is necessary. Learn to sit and observe without emotionally reacting to anything at all. Stop judging things, stop fantasizing about the future or the past. Stop thinking about yourself. Stop thinking about your life. Just sit and observe the present moment. In the present moment there is nothing sad or bad.
</p>

<p>
	Start to notice when you are conscious vs when you are reacting emotionally to anything at all.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 11:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351992</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>If it's all a fantasy, why even live it?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30330-if-its-all-a-fantasy-why-even-live-it/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351987</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9720-f-a-b/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9720" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9720-f-a-b/" rel="">@F A B</a> There's no choice really. If you kill yourself, you'll just end up right back here. There is no end to it.
</p>

<p>
	Oneness means, there's nowhere else you can go.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 11:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351987</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Michael Shermer on Rogan</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30303-michael-shermer-on-rogan/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351984</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5651-space/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5651" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5651-space/" rel="">@Space</a> But here's the kicker: earlier in his life he used to be Born Again Christian. LOL
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 11:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351984</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is the Dark Night of The Soul the same as Ego Death?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30250-is-the-dark-night-of-the-soul-the-same-as-ego-death/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351890</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7424-girzo/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7424" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7424-girzo/" rel="">@Girzo</a> You should also read the encyclopedia to learn that whales are not fish <img alt=":P" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue@2x.png 2x" title=":P" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 07:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351890</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How often to Trip on LSD</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30320-how-often-to-trip-on-lsd/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351889</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Every 2 weeks is good as long as you're integrating the insights well. You will naturally not want to trip that often after a while because the trips should get too deep.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 07:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351889</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cyclical Consciousness? (Help?)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30317-cyclical-consciousness-help/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351850</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14201-brenzo2/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14201" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14201-brenzo2/" rel="">@Brenzo2</a> That's right. The "substrate" is Groundless Ground (AKA, Emptiness).
</p>

<p>
	The substrate is no-substrate <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	If it seems mysterious, unknowable, unspeakable, ineffable, and paradoxical -- that's right! It is!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 05:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351850</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cyclical Consciousness? (Help?)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30317-cyclical-consciousness-help/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351842</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	P.S. The shortest articulation of a cycle is a single dot.
</p>

<p>
	<img class="ipsImage ipsImage_thumbnailed" data-extension="core_Attachment" data-fileid="8445" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/monthly_2018_04/Yin-Yang.gif.c53f5d405bf190900b4faef01f35f26e.gif" alt="Yin-Yang.gif" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 04:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351842</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cyclical Consciousness? (Help?)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30317-cyclical-consciousness-help/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351838</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Sounds like you're describing Samadhi: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samadhi" rel="external nofollow">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samadhi</a>
</p>

<p>
	Which is basically a mild version of nondual consciousness / mystical experience.
</p>

<p>
	But you are only feeling the tip of the iceberg now. With more practice it will go much deeper. It can even go so deep that your body and the entire universe will disappear!
</p>

<p>
	It feels timeless because it is! Time is a concept created by the mind. When the mind is still for long enough, time will cease to exist.
</p>

<p>
	In fact, every moment, every experience you've ever had, has been, and currently is, timeless.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 04:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351838</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A problem with opening up and connecting with people</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30315-a-problem-with-opening-up-and-connecting-with-people/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351828</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14067-conceptually-made/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14067" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14067-conceptually-made/" rel="">@Conceptually-made</a> Given your age I would attribute this mostly to lack of experience. Socialization is a skill set. Being intimate with women is a skill set. You need many hours of practice to get good at it, especially if you're shy, awkward, under-socialized, autistic, or very introverted.
</p>

<p>
	Put yourself into a lot more social situations/relationships and practice being very authentic, vulnerable, and intimate. Not sexually, but conversationally, emotionally, etc.
</p>

<p>
	Do not confuse sex for intimacy.
</p>

<p>
	A little game you could play with yourself is to try to see how fast you can get real intimate with a total stranger. Like, walk up to a random person at a Starbucks and try to get intimate with them within 15 minutes of conversation. The trick is to do it without creeping them out. The first few times you try it you will come across weird and creepy. But through experience you will learn how to make it feel natural and positive for the both of you.
</p>

<p>
	Oh, and BTW, the whole trick to sleeping with women quickly is building intimacy quickly. You can do it within 1 hour of meeting her through lots of training. There are many tricks to speed this along, like being fully present, having very strong eye contact, speaking slowly, smiling, being warm and friendly, and touching her body frequently in a non-creepy manner.
</p>

<p>
	It's amazing when done right. But requires enormous practice unless you're "a natural." Which obviously you aren't otherwise we wouldn't be having this conversation.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 03:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351828</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>What is ego-death?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30266-what-is-ego-death/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351821</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	In the very moment of ego-death it is realized that your biological birth was just a story. It is realized that you are not a physical or a biological object, but an idea. This idea is eliminated, as though it never existed. Not only that, it becomes almost impossible to imagine how you ever thought you existed.
</p>

<p>
	Imagine life minus you.
</p>

<p>
	That's ego death. Everything stays the same. But you are missing!
</p>

<p>
	In other words, absolutely nothing changes! Just its always been, and how is right now!
</p>

<p>
	There is no you reading this sentence. The sense that there is a you reading this sentence is a fantasy. The end of this fantasy is ego-death.
</p>

<p>
	Ego-death is not an idea or a belief, it is state of consciousness. Accessing this state of consciousness requires intense concentration and stillness of the conceptualize mind. The conceptualizing mind is what is sustaining the fantasy of a you in the same way that a video game console sustains the appearance of Super Mario. If the console is unplugged, Mario disappears.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 03:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351821</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Self-Love the highest form of Love?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30304-is-self-love-the-highest-form-of-love/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351810</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="351808" data-ipsquote-contentid="30304" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547347280" data-ipsquote-userid="8090" data-ipsquote-username="Joseph Maynor">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		9 minutes ago, Joseph Maynor said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			So you really need both self-love and love of others.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Yes, because self and other are identical in the end.
</p>

<p>
	See video: The Theme Of Things Going Full-Circle
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 02:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351810</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>This Week's Video Delayed</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30314-this-weeks-video-delayed/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351806</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	I had a bad allergic reaction this week to the medicine (penicillin) for my sinus infection, which made me feel even worse and covered me in red rashy burning spots from head to toe. So video will be late, depending on when this clears up.
</p>

<p>
	Don't worry for me, I'll be fine. I just can't shoot videos in this state. It should pass soon.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 02:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351806</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can someone explain art to me?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30294-can-someone-explain-art-to-me/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351801</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	If you were awake you would realize the entire Cosmos is one epic work of art, from the galaxies to the viruses to the terrorists to the homeless person begging for coins on the side of the road.
</p>

<p>
	It's easier to ask, what isn't art?
</p>

<p>
	And the answer is nothing.
</p>

<p>
	If you don't see infinite artistry all around you it's because you're way too self-involved, hypnotized by satisfying your basic survival needs.
</p>

<p>
	The solution? Daily spiritual practice.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 02:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351801</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Self-Love the highest form of Love?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30304-is-self-love-the-highest-form-of-love/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351787</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="351753" data-ipsquote-contentid="30304" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547338679" data-ipsquote-userid="5689" data-ipsquote-username="PretentiousHuman">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, PretentiousHuman said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> Firstly, you're one of a kind human being.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	As is every human being <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		Quote
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			If that's the case, are you worshipping God by doing some meditation, yoga, exercise, eating healthy? Is it not too selfish to do that?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Since YOU are God, you'd be worshipping yourself. That is okay as long as you're aware that you are worshipping yourself. Then it becomes like a cosmic masturbation session. And since you are the only thing in existence, all action is ultimately masturbation.
</p>

<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="351753" data-ipsquote-contentid="30304" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547338679" data-ipsquote-userid="5689" data-ipsquote-username="PretentiousHuman">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, PretentiousHuman said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			What is pseudo-love? And i think i have a hard time accepting or loving the evils of the world. 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Loving only those parts of reality which serve you or make you feel good.
</p>

<p>
	Of course, like I said, ego (you) is incapable of true love. True love requires eliminating ego. This requires some serious spiritual practices like Kriya yoga or self-inquiry or psychedelics.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 01:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351787</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>My gf doesn't let me do any spiritual work</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30261-my-gf-doesnt-let-me-do-any-spiritual-work/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351740</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Best excuse EVAR!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 23:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351740</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>SPIRITUALITY ANGAINST PHILOSOPHY KNOWLEDGE</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30290-spirituality-angainst-philosophy-knowledge/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351739</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13009-giulio-bevilacqua/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="13009" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13009-giulio-bevilacqua/" rel="">@Giulio Bevilacqua</a> Be careful, that might be the attraction of the devil, trying to distract you from the Greater Jihad.
</p>

<p>
	As a general rule of thumb: stop fucking around and get on with the Greater Jihad!
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 23:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351739</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is Self-Love the highest form of Love?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30304-is-self-love-the-highest-form-of-love/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351738</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Since all is one and there is nothing but The Self, self-love is really the only kind of love.
</p>

<p>
	But this not the self you imagine you are. I am speaking of loving the entire universe unconditionally, especially all the evil stuff your self hates. That is true Self-Love.
</p>

<p>
	The ego is not capable of real love. It only knows pseudo-love. Ego only cares about gets it needs met. That is not real love. That is egotism.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 23:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351738</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Michael Shermer on Rogan</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30303-michael-shermer-on-rogan/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351718</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Oh good God... not him again...
</p>

<p>
	It really takes effort to be that dense.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 23:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351718</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Taking an antidepressant during the dark night of the soul</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30272-taking-an-antidepressant-during-the-dark-night-of-the-soul/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351711</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14417-ninie/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14417" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14417-ninie/" rel="">@Ninie</a> The ego is not going to die quietly. Taking antidepressants will only make things worse. It's like you're pressing the gas pedal and then slamming the parking break.
</p>

<p>
	What you need to do is become conscious of what this depressed feeling is about. Why it is happening? Not on a personal or psychological level but in an existential level. Why do you suffer at all? What is suffering about? What is sadness? Why purpose does it serve? Why are you creating it?
</p>

<p>
	In this work you must suffer consiously, otherwise you aren't really learning anything, you are just acting out unconscious egoic patterns. You could do that for 50 years and not come out any wiser or awake.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 23:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351711</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Insights into &quot;Truth&quot; from psychedelics?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30299-insights-into-truth-from-psychedelics/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351645</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Psychedelics have been used by all cultures for over 20,000 years for this purpose. So there is no disputing it. Not to mention the clinical studies.
</p>

<p>
	The distinction between objective and subjective does not exist. There is no such thing as subjective experience really. That is an illusion created by the ego. All "subjective experience" is actually Absolute Being if the ego is absent.
</p>

<p>
	Being is prior to proof. Truth is prior to proof. Proof is a concept, Truth is actuality.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 20:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351645</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why do I fall asleep while meditating?!?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30289-why-do-i-fall-asleep-while-meditating/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351639</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14227-ingurix/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14227" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14227-ingurix/" rel="">@ingurix</a> It's an ego defense mechanism. The ego is not just gonna let you meditate. The more you push yourself to meditate the more you will overcome this defense mechanism. It will get better.
</p>

<p>
	One trick that works well for me is to meditate right after taking a nap.
</p>

<p>
	Also, meditate with your eyes open.
</p>

<p>
	You could also switch to Kriya yoga instead of meditation. It's very hard to fall asleep doing Kriya yoga even if you are sleepy because it involves more activity.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 20:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351639</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can't meditate without missing a single day</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30292-cant-meditate-without-missing-a-single-day/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351634</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12718-eternalforest/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12718" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12718-eternalforest/" rel="">@EternalForest</a> Well, if you don't actually want to meditate every day then obviously you are getting exactly what you want.
</p>

<p>
	The question is, what do you want here?
</p>

<p>
	If you DO want to meditate every day but you are still struggling, that's a problem of self-discipline and integrity. You are making the commitment but then breaking your own word, which hurts your self esteem.
</p>

<p>
	Spirituality usually requires developing hardcore discipline because otherwise the ego is too tricky and will never allow itself to be significantly undermined.
</p>

<p>
	Maybe try some strong determination sits. Bordem and extreme suffering during meditation is par for the course. Some of the greatest suffering I've ever had was during my solo meditation retreats. You cannot even imagine how much bordem and suffering happens there. Imagine bordem so bad it is literally killing you.
</p>

<p>
	Meditation is not all rainbows and peace. Meditation is hell from the ego's POV.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 20:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351634</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Technical error post: Anybody else experiencing issues connecting to the server?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30238-technical-error-post-anybody-else-experiencing-issues-connecting-to-the-server/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351599</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Okay, then its been fixed.
</p>

<p>
	Thanks for your reports.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 19:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351599</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is the Dark Night of The Soul the same as Ego Death?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30250-is-the-dark-night-of-the-soul-the-same-as-ego-death/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351594</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="351498" data-ipsquote-contentid="30250" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547309530" data-ipsquote-userid="11125" data-ipsquote-username="kev014">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		15 hours ago, kev014 said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="1" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/1-leo-gura/" rel="">@Leo Gura</a> If the ego does bounce back and does not fully die, can/will it be reconstructed again so that someone has to go through the same process over again? My question is basically if you are progressively surrendering your ego, your emotions and the idea that you ever existed more and more but do not fully surrender/die, will you have to 'start over' in this die off process or is it just the final surrender you have to endure?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The ego is relentless.
</p>

<p>
	It's sort of like reeling in a giant fish. You reel it in a few feet, then it runs out a few feet of line. A long tug of war ensues. If the fish is big enough it might even break the line and escape. You must slowly wear it down and the deliver the final blow.
</p>

<p>
	Any course of spirituality or development can become pathological.
</p>

<p>
	But it is also possible to land the fish. You must become a good fisherman.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 19:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351594</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>SPIRITUALITY ANGAINST PHILOSOPHY KNOWLEDGE</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30290-spirituality-angainst-philosophy-knowledge/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351592</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13009-giulio-bevilacqua/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="13009" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/13009-giulio-bevilacqua/" rel="">@Giulio Bevilacqua</a> Most of Western philosophy is mental masturbation and will take you further into delusion.
</p>

<p>
	If you are already into spirituality and nonduality why waste your time with Western philosophy? Why not invest that time deepening your spiritual practice?
</p>

<p>
	Be careful not to do things just because other people are doing them. Be independent and don't do useless things with your life. Be highly selective with how you invest your time.
</p>

<p>
	Maybe spend your time studying something more practical.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 19:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351592</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Technical error post: Anybody else experiencing issues connecting to the server?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30238-technical-error-post-anybody-else-experiencing-issues-connecting-to-the-server/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351209</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Okay, try again now. It should be better.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 04:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351209</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is the Dark Night of The Soul the same as Ego Death?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30250-is-the-dark-night-of-the-soul-the-same-as-ego-death/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351191</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10512-victorb02/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10512" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10512-victorb02/" rel="">@VictorB02</a> No, Dark Night Of The Soul is the ego's backlash & resistance to ego-death. It is the ego going through its final death throes. The ego can still bounce back with a vengeance and not complete the ego death.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 03:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351191</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Technical error post: Anybody else experiencing issues connecting to the server?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30238-technical-error-post-anybody-else-experiencing-issues-connecting-to-the-server/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351190</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Okay, thanks. That will help us track down the problem.
</p>

<p>
	And how long has this been happening for you guys? When did this first start for you?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 02:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351190</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Technical error post: Anybody else experiencing issues connecting to the server?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30238-technical-error-post-anybody-else-experiencing-issues-connecting-to-the-server/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351149</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	It's hard to replicate this issue. Most of the time the site and forum load fine for me and others. But at the same time, for example on my mobile device, sometimes the site and forum fail to load.
</p>

<p>
	If you guys are still experiencing this problem could you please check the site and forum on multiples devices/connections and report back under what circumstances there are loading problems. Is this an intermittent thing?
</p>

<p>
	We're still trying to pin-point what the issue is.
</p>

<p>
	Please mention which device/OS/browser you're experiencing these issues under. For example I do not experience any issues on Windows Firefox or Windows Chrome. But I have been having issues on Android.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 21:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351149</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Message to Leo and his disciples.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30228-message-to-leo-and-his-disciples/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351146</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14341-paul92/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14341" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14341-paul92/" rel="">@Paul92</a> You cannot will your way to a state of no-mind. That requires decades of patient, serious practice.
</p>

<p>
	Now is the time to discipline yourself and start doing the practices.
</p>

<p>
	Re-calibrate your expectations. This is a marathon, not a sprint.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 21:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351146</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Psilocybin Trip Report - 2.5g</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30249-psilocybin-trip-report-25g/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351145</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="351136" data-ipsquote-contentid="30249" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547237278" data-ipsquote-userid="14223" data-ipsquote-username="billytblack">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		1 hour ago, billytblack said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			NEXT STEP: 4g Psilocybin
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	You're in for some serious mindfuckery <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 21:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351145</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Technical error post: Anybody else experiencing issues connecting to the server?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30238-technical-error-post-anybody-else-experiencing-issues-connecting-to-the-server/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351063</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	It's being looked into.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 10:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351063</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Impossible Nothingness Beyond Absolute Infinity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30217-the-impossible-nothingness-beyond-absolute-infinity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=351028</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14365-ethankahn/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14365" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14365-ethankahn/" rel="">@Ethankahn</a> The way you are speaking it strikes me that you have not directly experienced the Absolute deeply enough. Otherwise such questions and issues would not arise. Maybe you got a taste of it, but not the Full Monty. You need to go back and directly experience the Fully Monty.
</p>

<p>
	To say there is something beyond the Absolute is silly. The Absolute is Absolute and there is nothing beyond it because it is total.
</p>

<p>
	You are still holding Nothingness and Infinity as distinct things, which is a duality, which must be further collapsed, thus resolving this entire thread.
</p>

<p>
	What more is there to say if you are fully conscious of the Absolute? The Absolute is all there is. There is nothing but the Absolute.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 02:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">351028</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Counter-intuitive voting strategy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30213-counter-intuitive-voting-strategy/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350866</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12536-andreas/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12536" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12536-andreas/" rel="">@Andreas</a> By that logic we shouldn't educate children, since they are not fully ready for change, and change is stressful.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 03:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350866</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Impossible Nothingness Beyond Absolute Infinity</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30217-the-impossible-nothingness-beyond-absolute-infinity/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350861</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14365-ethankahn/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14365" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14365-ethankahn/" rel="">@Ethankahn</a> Absolute Infinity = Nothing
</p>

<p>
	Form is formlessness. Fromlessness is form.
</p>

<p>
	You are creating a duality out of nothing and infinity.
</p>

<p>
	Also, there is an infinite number of different systems of logic. So which ever logic you're using is arbitrary and relative. Absolute Infinity is not limited to logic because it created logic and holds an infinite number of logical systems within it, including all the stuff you deem illogical. The very distinction you create between logical and illogical means there is logical stuff and illogical stuff, which the illogical stuff being greater in quantity than the logical stuff.
</p>

<p>
	YOU are creating all of these distinctions between logic/illogic, infinity/nothing, life/death, self/other, true/false, etc. Ultimate nonduality is the realization that all of these distinctions are relative and impermanent.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 02:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350861</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Counter-intuitive voting strategy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30213-counter-intuitive-voting-strategy/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350860</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12536-andreas/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="12536" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/12536-andreas/" rel="">@Andreas</a> It strikes me that your cure is worse than the disease.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 02:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350860</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From &quot;Universe does not exist&quot; to &quot;You are the universe and it's intelligent&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30189-from-universe-does-not-exist-to-you-are-the-universe-and-its-intelligent/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350840</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="350743" data-ipsquote-contentid="30189" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547034083" data-ipsquote-userid="2835" data-ipsquote-username="Anton Rogachevski">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		11 hours ago, Anton Rogachevski said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			<em>"The fool who persists in his folly will become wise."</em> 
		</p>

		<p>
			William Blake
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	William Blake hadn't met Donald Trump <img alt=":P" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue@2x.png 2x" title=":P" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350840</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Help Me Build A Jedi Academy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30151-help-me-build-a-jedi-academy/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350839</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="350801" data-ipsquote-contentid="30151" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547064464" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		3 hours ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Well, at least we already know what the audition process will be... <img alt=":D" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin@2x.png 2x" title=":D" width="20" /> 
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	And the end result <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 23:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350839</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Counter-intuitive voting strategy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30213-counter-intuitive-voting-strategy/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350838</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	How about you just vote for the person who is most conscious and Spirally developed?
</p>

<p>
	Might work better than voting for Hitler <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 23:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350838</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>- Parmenides -</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30200-parmenides/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350832</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	The Greeks had some badass philosophers. A shame what has become of philosophy today.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 22:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350832</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>10mg 5-MeO-DMT Trip report</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30209-10mg-5-meo-dmt-trip-report/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350829</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8773-igor82/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="8773" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/8773-igor82/" rel="">@Igor82</a> That's a tip of the iceberg dose. Get ready for an epic mindfucking at 20mg and above.
</p>

<p>
	Sounds like you've realized no-self so far, but not Absolute Infinity or God or Mu. Keep going down the rabbit hole.
</p>

<p>
	Plugging is far, far superior to snorting.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 22:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350829</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Did Osho had sex with many women and sniff nitrous oxide?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30214-did-osho-had-sex-with-many-women-and-sniff-nitrous-oxide/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350828</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Par for the course when you run a cult <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 22:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350828</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Being born in the ancient Samaritan tribe, and how actualized.org saved my life</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30210-being-born-in-the-ancient-samaritan-tribe-and-how-actualizedorg-saved-my-life/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350827</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11487-gaben/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11487" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11487-gaben/" rel="">@GabeN</a> Good to hear <img alt=":)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/smile.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/smile@2x.png 2x" title=":)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	Welcome to actualized living.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 22:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350827</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Help Me Build A Jedi Academy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30151-help-me-build-a-jedi-academy/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350726</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="350724" data-ipsquote-contentid="30151" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1547013745" data-ipsquote-userid="826" data-ipsquote-username="Emerald">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		51 minutes ago, Emerald said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			Not everyone can be a Jedi.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	That's why you test 'em for midichlorians <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	<img alt="2019-01-08_2253.png" class="ipsImage ipsImage_thumbnailed" data-fileid="13623" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/monthly_2019_01/2019-01-08_2253.png.4c3ce294b26843ebe2f60317950c29f5.png" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 06:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350726</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Help Me Build A Jedi Academy</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30151-help-me-build-a-jedi-academy/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350715</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5344-jcent/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="5344" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/5344-jcent/" rel="">@Jcent</a> It is wise, before you go breaking down a system, to learn the system from the inside.
</p>

<p>
	Only a fool hastily disassembles a complex piece of machinery without first studying its inner workings.
</p>

<p>
	A common problem with young revolutionaries is that they end up creating a worse system than the one they rail against because they underestimate the practical realities such a system must contend with.
</p>

<p>
	Success requires striking a delicate balance between the old and the new, the status quo and the cutting edge, between the practical and ideal.
</p>

<p>
	Otherwise you easily end up with something like a cult, a communist revolution, or Bioshock: a dystopian abomination.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 05:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350715</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>&quot;The Dark Side of Meditation&quot; Video Question</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30198-the-dark-side-of-meditation-video-question/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350712</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10512-victorb02/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="10512" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/10512-victorb02/" rel="">@VictorB02</a> Well, you gotta appreciate that people have mystical experiences and even enlightenments just out of the blue, sometimes with little to no practice.
</p>

<p>
	Meditation is everywhere all of the time! Meditation is reality. You don't have to be sitting on the cushion to be aware of stuff. Some people are naturally meditating all the time without even giving it a label or using any formal techniques. So yeah, side-effects are to be expected out of the blue in some people. Some people even have spontaneous kundalini awakenings.
</p>

<p>
	The harder you meditate the more side-effects you are likely to have.
</p>

<p>
	It's sort of like if I told you that by doing weightlifting you can get sore muscles, and some people respond in the comments: "But Leo! I don't do any weightlifitng and I still get sore muscles."
</p>

<p>
	Yeah, of course! Because weightlifting is not the only way to get sore muscles.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 04:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350712</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question about Karma and Day Trading Stocks( Leo ? :-)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30045-question-about-karma-and-day-trading-stocks-leo/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350709</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="350251" data-ipsquote-contentid="30045" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1546948691" data-ipsquote-userid="9966" data-ipsquote-username="captainamerica">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		16 hours ago, captainamerica said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			My main intention is to "stand on my own feet" so that I can start providing value to the world (I mean I will already start it but I do need some capital for the expenses and early-stage growth/momentum) ...Is it all right if I do day trading to keep up with with the expenses while doing so? 
		</p>

		<p>
			I also do not have any other way to get capital for this project of mine for the next 5-10 years and if I wait the opportunity cost would be very, very significant.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	The universe has no rules. You are free to do whatever.
</p>

<p>
	Survival is often messy and dirty. If you can actually use this opportunity to help awaken mankind, then that would be wise to do, otherwise what's the alternative for you?
</p>

<p>
	But be careful not to fall into the trap of using a noble purpose to justify all sorts of selfish behavior, the way that cults like to do. That comes with a high karmic cost.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 04:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350709</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Infinity or our lack of understanding or is that the ego?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30196-infinity-or-our-lack-of-understanding-or-is-that-the-ego/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350702</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Mu <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 04:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350702</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From &quot;Universe does not exist&quot; to &quot;You are the universe and it's intelligent&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30189-from-universe-does-not-exist-to-you-are-the-universe-and-its-intelligent/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350700</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6564-winter/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6564" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6564-winter/" rel="">@Winter</a> You can of course enjoy playing the game. What else is there to do?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 04:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350700</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>From &quot;Universe does not exist&quot; to &quot;You are the universe and it's intelligent&quot;</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30189-from-universe-does-not-exist-to-you-are-the-universe-and-its-intelligent/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350627</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Universe = everything that is. The sum total of everything.
</p>

<p>
	The universe is a dream-like hallucination, an illusion. It is form. All form is an illusion because form is identical to formlessness or Nothingness. So in a sense the universe both does and does not exist simultaneously.
</p>

<p>
	Notice that existence/non-existence is a duality. As you should know by now, all dualities ultimately collapse into an undifferentiated unity.
</p>

<p>
	The reason it doesn't make sense is because you are trying to use the mind to grasp nonduality, but the mind only understanding things via dualistic categories like good/bad, true/false, part/whole, life/death, etc.
</p>

<p>
	What's required is a nondual mystical experience. You must actually become nondual, not just think about it or talk about it. BE IT! To be it you must eliminate all thinking. When all thinking stops, what remains is the Truth.
</p>

<p>
	Just think of it like this: you are inside a video game. The video game world is not real, but it appears real to you because you are hypnotized by it. If you realize you are in a video game, the video game world will instantly lose all of its reality. You will say of it: "It isn't real" and yet despite that, the video game world still has a certain form and certain rules which must be obeyed so long as you are in it.
</p>

<p>
	Another way to put it: you could kill yourself right now and it wouldn't make any difference. But you would never do that because you believe too much that this is real. It's not actually real. But you are too scared to find out. So you stay stuck in the illusion, at least until death, at which point you'll realize your entire life was just a hallucination with zero import or reality.
</p>

<p>
	Your whole sticking point here is that you absolutely refuse to admit that your life isn't real. And no amount of logic will convince you of it because your fear of death is totally irrational and insane. You are literally insane and you don't want to admit. So here we are! How much longer are you gonna keep denying your insanity?
</p>

<p>
	It is not possible to understand nonduality without facing your own death. But you should not mistake what I am saying as an invitation to harm the physical body.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 01:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350627</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo, is the product you're planning to release in 2019 your self-deception book?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30171-leo-is-the-product-youre-planning-to-release-in-2019-your-self-deception-book/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350555</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	No, the book is a very long-term project.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 22:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350555</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Absolute Infinity and Non Duality</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30165-absolute-infinity-and-non-duality/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350553</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Any word out of my mouth is a reference to Absolute Infinity, since there is nothing but it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 21:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350553</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>David R. Hawkins' 101 Ways To Happiness</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30166-david-r-hawkins-101-ways-to-happiness/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350552</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	Good stuff <img alt=":)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/smile.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/smile@2x.png 2x" title=":)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 21:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350552</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>PUA and RSD: Should I really follow these communities?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/29772-pua-and-rsd-should-i-really-follow-these-communities/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350152</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/3-dating-relationships-sexuality/">Dating, Relationships, Sexuality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="350058" data-ipsquote-contentid="29772" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1546917102" data-ipsquote-userid="11006" data-ipsquote-username="brugluiz">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		4 hours ago, brugluiz said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			I wonder why he's so attached to this pick-up culture. He seems to be a very kind man.
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	There is nothing more addictive to the ego-mind than an ideology which brings in $$$, fame, and pussy. That's a lethal combo.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 08:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350152</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>UNspirituality</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30157-unspirituality/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350149</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	When someone calls himself "unspiritual", what more do you need to know? <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	Railing against spirituality is the new religion, LOL. It's sort of like those non-conformist kids in school who all non-conform so conformly.
</p>

<p>
	Someone should start a YT channel called UnUnSpirituality <img alt=":P" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/tongue@2x.png 2x" title=":P" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 07:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350149</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kim Jung Gi shows us how to apply mastery process and cure perfectionism.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30121-kim-jung-gi-shows-us-how-to-apply-mastery-process-and-cure-perfectionism/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350147</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11312" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11312-creamcat/" rel="">@CreamCat</a> Don't look for people to hold your hand. Just do it.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 07:51:32 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350147</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leo's SKINNY neck</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30154-leos-skinny-neck/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350145</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/2-self-actualization/">Self-Actualization</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	We already have a Joe Rogan thread.
</p>
<iframe data-embedcontent="" frameborder="0" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/28736-joe-rogan-taking-a-dig-at-leo/?do=embed"></iframe>

<p>
	 
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 07:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350145</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding the definition of &quot;purpose of life&quot;.</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/29873-understanding-the-definition-of-purpose-of-life/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350144</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11218-equanimitize/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11218" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11218-equanimitize/" rel="">@Equanimitize</a> That is the crack spot <img alt=":D" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/biggrin@2x.png 2x" title=":D" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 07:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350144</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question about Karma and Day Trading Stocks( Leo ? :-)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30045-question-about-karma-and-day-trading-stocks-leo/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350143</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/3673-d0ornokey/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="3673" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/3673-d0ornokey/" rel="">@d0ornokey</a> Do you want "arbitrage" written on your tombstone? Then why are you doing it?
</p>

<p>
	Do stuff that you would feel proud to have written on your tombstone.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 07:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350143</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Business toxifying my PASSION/LIFE PURPOSE</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30015-business-toxifying-my-passionlife-purpose/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350135</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7387-optimize/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="7387" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/7387-optimize/" rel="">@optimize</a> First of all, these are quality problems. Acknowledge how far you've come. You've build something rare and you ain't done yet.
</p>

<p>
	Secondly, yeah! Welcome to survival! Survival is a cut-throat activity. It is not easy to balance between business & art. It is not easy to run a conscious business. Which is why virtually no body does it.
</p>

<p>
	Yes, your business can get fucked at any time, and if you neglect it for too long, it will probably die. Such is life. There is no life without death. The solution is to accept it and face your fear of failure/business-death. I used to get these fears a lot. I still get them to some extent but a lot less so after my many mystical experiences, which teach me that death is inevitable and nothing to be afraid of. After you experience a few physical deaths, business death doesn't seem so serious any more.
</p>

<p>
	That said, if you are going to be running a business you should run it well, strategically. Think about ways to make your business more future-proof and self-sustaining. You can do that without being paranoid about it. Make the distinction between being strategic and proactive vs being paranoid. You can do one without doing the other and vice versa.
</p>

<p>
	Of course your survival is tied to your business performance. Business IS survival. The solution here it is not get too wrapped up in survival. Yes, survival is necessary but don't make your entire life about survival. Don't make your entire business about survival. You must skillfully evolve your business beyond survival to incorporate play, artistry, beauty, and consciousness. This must be done while still keeping one eye on your finances. Just like how an artist cannot paint all day long without eating food. But it would be a mistake for him to get so paranoid about food that all he does all day is eat food and never paints. A balance must be struck between eating food and making art. Likewise between business and art.
</p>

<p>
	Most successful entrepreneurs end up workaholics. You should probably make time for other stuff like relationships, travel, spirituality, etc. Do that without neglecting your business. If you're earning $100,000 you should have enough money to hire a bit of extra help. Consider hiring an online contractor to help you out. Consider how to align your art with your biz.
</p>

<p>
	Yes, I always feel a desire to grow and expand my biz. But I have to be disciplined and say NO! to lots of opportunities because biz is not as important as spirituality, for example. I pass up on a lot of opportunities because biz cannot be your #1 priority in the end. That way lies disaster.
</p>

<p>
	How do I handle fears of my business getting fucked? At this point I've basically stopped caring. I've almost stopped caring if I die. This was made possible through spiritual work and profound mystical experiences which show me that biz and life are just a hallucination. None of my life or work really matter. This is all just a game. It's being done for fun and artistry. You could get run over by a bus tomorrow. So why worry about it? Getting over the fear of loss of my business took many years of work. It also helped that I saved up a comfortable nest egg. My YT channel could die tomorrow and I would still be able to live for 15 years without working. I strategically designed it this way. You can too. Not in a week, but in a few years time you could.
</p>

<p>
	Sometimes I still think of the business aspects of things, but at this point in my life, career, and development I spend more time thinking about living in a cave than running a business. You are not at this point yet. Maybe you'll get there in 5-10 years of work. It all depends on what your goals are for your life. For me, the point of business is to enable my passion and artistry. Design your business such that it allows you to do your art. Artsy fartsy stuff is not waste of time if it part of your life purpose and your life purpose is fueling your biz. The whole point is to align all these things in a balanced way.
</p>

<p>
	If you set up your business properly, you should be able to take time off to pursue spirituality, travel, leisure, art, relationships, etc. That will take some years to actualize, but it's worth it. The first few years of building a business usually requires LOTS of hours of non-stop work. But the whole point of all that work is so that in the future your business is more or less on auto-pilot.
</p>

<p>
	Tie the artsy-fartsy stuff to the success of your biz.
</p>

<p>
	Remember the importance of dynamic balance. See my balance video.
</p>

<p>
	Have a long-term strategic plan.
</p>

<p>
	Automate, outsource, and streamline stuff as much as you can.
</p>

<p>
	Fear is always a psychological self-deception game. Your fear is something you want to contemplate and face head on. Just building your biz more is never going to solve the fear of losing your biz. Your biz could be making $1 billion per year and you'd still fear losing it. Even more so! Because fear is never based in reality, it is purely mental. So explore that. To really overcome fear you must do deep spiritual work. Fear is inevitable without enlightenment.
</p>

<p>
	Overall, you're on the right track. Just fine-tune things and take it to the next level. Next level does not necessarily mean: more money & bigger biz. Next level means: a new balance, or action at a higher level of consciousness.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 07:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350135</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Question about Karma and Day Trading Stocks( Leo ? :-)</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30045-question-about-karma-and-day-trading-stocks-leo/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350120</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9966-captainamerica/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="9966" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/9966-captainamerica/" rel="">@captainamerica</a> There is a deeper problem here. If daytrading offers no value, setting yourself up as a trainer of daytraders is just doubling down on the problem, you see? You are effectively creating a pyramid scheme. The whole point of a pyramid scheme is that it takes a product or service of no genuine value and makes it appear to have short-term value by convincing other people that it has value.
</p>

<p>
	If you realize that daytrading has little to no value, why are you positioning yourself to teach it to other people? You just geometrically multiplied your bad karma. It's as if I told you that robbing people's houses created bad karma so you come back to me and say, "What if I don't do any robbing myself but instead I train hundreds of people how to rob houses?" Lol
</p>

<p>
	Go create something which you know offers massive genuine value for mankind. Teach that!
</p>

<p>
	Do you really want to spend your precious time on this Earth teaching daytrading? Is that what you want your life to be remembered as: the daytrading guy? Is that really the best thing you can think of?
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350120</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>LIVING WITH PARENTS FOR LIFE PURPOSE</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/29894-living-with-parents-for-life-purpose/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350116</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/9-life-purpose-career-entrepreneurship/">Life Purpose, Career, Entrepreneurship</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6606-djdumoul/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6606" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6606-djdumoul/" rel="">@Djdumoul</a> When I started by first biz I was 24 and I moved back in with my parents for a short time (about 3 months). It was a bit humiliating and stifling but a necessary step towards actualizing my life purpose. After about 3 months I was making enough money to move out and live on my own. And I was even able to help pay for my Mom's apartment after she separated from my Dad.
</p>

<p>
	The key is to hustle and make shit happen. Don't be dicking around. Create results!
</p>

<p>
	Teach yourself how to survive in this world.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 06:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350116</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why do I run away from inquiring and sitting down?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30126-why-do-i-run-away-from-inquiring-and-sitting-down/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350111</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11463-pouya/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11463" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11463-pouya/" rel="">@Pouya</a> It depends on how much they do it. 2-3 trips is usually not enough for the average person to get a profound nondual experience (when snorting/plugging). Most people need a rather large dose of it to break through, and the problem is, they are too afraid to do it. They do 1 or 2 small trips and call it quits before the breakthrough happens. Because the ego is hellbent on preventing enlightenment.
</p>

<p>
	Psychedelics do not work on people who are not metaphysically curious and serious. This is not a pursuit for lazy people just dicking around. You have to be serious about reaching Truth. You have to be willing to try and fail many times. I have no respect for people who do 2 trips and call it quits.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 06:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350111</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is it dangerous to have many sex partners bc your body absorbs memory?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30150-is-it-dangerous-to-have-many-sex-partners-bc-your-body-absorbs-memory/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350109</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6801-haloman/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="6801" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/6801-haloman/" rel="">@Haloman</a> You are also programmed to shit, eat, and kill. The key is to keep your base desires well-regulated via consciousness and wisdom.
</p>

<p>
	In other words, you can shit, but don't shit where you eat.
</p>

<p>
	You can have sex, but do so responsibly, authentically, and consciously.
</p>

<p>
	Or be an animal. It's up to you.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 06:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350109</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Is it dangerous to have many sex partners bc your body absorbs memory?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30150-is-it-dangerous-to-have-many-sex-partners-bc-your-body-absorbs-memory/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350042</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14120-sqaad/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="14120" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/14120-sqaad/" rel="">@SQAAD</a> I would be more worried about absorbing viruses or sperm than memories <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	Seriously though, the problem with people who have multiple partners is that they do not know how to relate consciously with 1 partner, nevermind 3 or 5.
</p>

<p>
	It's sort of like those parents who don't know how to raise or feed 1 child, yet they have 5. <img alt="¬¬" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/dry.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/dry@2x.png 2x" title="¬¬" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	Classic case of biting off more than you can chew. It's a form of greediness.
</p>

<p>
	What is so lacking in you that you need any of that at all? << that's what you should contemplate.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 02:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350042</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Why do I run away from inquiring and sitting down?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30126-why-do-i-run-away-from-inquiring-and-sitting-down/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350041</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<p>
	<a contenteditable="false" data-ipshover="" data-ipshover-target="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11463-pouya/?do=hovercard" data-mentionid="11463" href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/profile/11463-pouya/" rel="">@Pouya</a> There is no way to do the work without doing the work.
</p>

<p>
	P.S. Well, maybe 5-MeO-DMT <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 02:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350041</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reflections on Self-delusion + why chase Truth?</title>
<link>https://www.actualized.org/forum/topic/30108-reflections-on-self-delusion-why-chase-truth/?do=findComment&amp;comment=350037</link>
<description><![CDATA[
<span>in <a href="https://www.actualized.org/forum/forum/4-meditation-consciousness-enlightenment-spirituality/">Meditation, Consciousness, Enlightenment, Spirituality</a></span>

<br />


							
							
<blockquote class="ipsQuote" data-ipsquote="" data-ipsquote-contentapp="forums" data-ipsquote-contentclass="forums_Topic" data-ipsquote-contentcommentid="349421" data-ipsquote-contentid="30108" data-ipsquote-contenttype="forums" data-ipsquote-timestamp="1546822658" data-ipsquote-userid="12146" data-ipsquote-username="Benoit Jazy">
	<div class="ipsQuote_citation">
		On 1/6/2019 at 4:57 PM, Benoit Jazy said:
	</div>

	<div class="ipsQuote_contents">
		<p>
			why on earth would we chase truth when it’s the end of you? What’s left after all of you is gone?
		</p>
	</div>
</blockquote>

<p>
	Precisely because it is the end of you.
</p>

<p>
	Since you are the problem, the end of you is the solution <img alt=";)" data-emoticon="" height="20" src="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink.png" srcset="https://www.actualized.org/forum/uploads/emoticons/wink@2x.png 2x" title=";)" width="20" />
</p>

<p>
	Can't you see that the only problem in the world is you?
</p>

<p>
	What's left is: nothing!
</p>

<p>
	No self, no problem.
</p>

<p>
	It's a rather ingenious counter-intuitive move, akin to a queen sacrifice in chess. Takes vision and boldness to make such a move.
</p>

						
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 02:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">350037</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>